<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="ifoam-activities" dstore:index="43" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-11-11T15:40:38+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-03-18T09:20:55+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-BonnVR8726-2.1.7.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excursions to exemplary PGS sites</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excursions abroad are foreseen to principally take place from late Y2/early Y3 onwards once PGS stakeholders in the OM4D countries collected first experiences with PGS processes and can best profit from a learning exchange. In Ghana preparations for an excursion to visit PGS in South Africa have been initiated in April 2019 by the Market-Oriented Agriculture Programme (MOAP) of GIZ in Ghana. MOAP has a source of funding from outside the OM4D project. The PGS team of OM4D is supporting the excursion, e.g. by helping so select sites to visits and connecting the MOAP team with PGS experts in South Africa. Also the participants foreseen by MOAP to join the excursion are the members of PGS committee in Ghana that is supported/initiated by the OM4D project including the OM4D PGS Coordinator in Ghana. In project year 3, the organisation of the two PGS visits continued, with a visit planned for Burkina Faso during the last week of March 2020, and another visit planned for South Africa during 4 -11 May 2020. The PGS visit in Burkina Faso has been unfortunately postponed due to the current Covid-19 pandemic, and it is very likely that also the South African trip will need to be postponed for later this year.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
