<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" dstore:dataset="danida-all_4" dstore:index="2103" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-22T04:39:48" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-22T04:39:51" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-238337</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark&apos;</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRS activities in relations to the ebola crisis in Sierra Leone, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Health Organization (WHO) and the Department for International Development (DFID) have the lead in the Ebola response in Sierra Leone. It is agreed between WHO and DFID that DFID would fund and construct 700 Ebola treatment beds in Sierra Leone via international non-governmental organisations (NGO). As one of the partners DFID charged the international NGO GOAL to construct an Ebola Treatment Centre (ETC) in Port Loko as one of several ETCs in the country. In that connection, DFID requested the International Humanitarian Partnership (IHP) for assistance to support the Ebola response by providing accommodation of health workers and other personnel working as part of the DFID newly created treatment facilities for Ebola patients in Sierra Leone. The request from DFID included the establishment of two base camps one in the town of Moyamba and one in Port Loko. Internally within the IHP countries, it was agreed that Norway took responsibility for establishing the base camp in Moyamba and Denmark via Danish Emergency Management Agency (DEMA) took responsibility for the camp needs of Port Loko.
DFID initially requested the base camp in Port Loko to have a capacity of approximately 80 beds for the Ebola responders in Port Loko. It has been agreed, that if the base camp has surplus capacity, then other than Ebola responders can use the base camp. The aim of the base camp is to ensure safe accommodation for the Ebola responders including the provision of health security support in the form of a fabricated medical holding facility for the management of staff presenting with fever and awaiting Ebola screening tests.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014-25306</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>NA</telephone>
   <email>NA</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic health infrastructure</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-238337-29246" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
