<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="156" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-05T09:56:07" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-05T09:56:07" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020- 2020000243</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accelerating SDG implementation in East Africa</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kestavan kehityksen tavoitteiden toimeenpanon vauhdittaminen Ita-Afrikassa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The world is not on track in achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). This is also the case with the project countries The Republic of Tanzania Uganda and Kenya. As the Covid-19 pandemic has most recently shown we need to understand the interlin
kages between the goals and strenghten the resilience of societies especially the most vulnerable groups and people. Empowerement of women and girls and gender mainstreaming are key and gender equality is taken into account in project&apos;s activities. The pro

ject offers effective peer-to-peer learning opportunities and capacity development through multistakeholder workshops for Parliamentarians municipal leaders key civil servants CSOs and journalists. Participation in international (UN) processes is encourage
d especially through African regional forums which will also strenghten the regional SDG cooperation. One of the key goals is to build the capacity of decision-makers to find integrative solutions and implement SDGs through strategies at national and local

 level. In addition to building the capacity of key actors for strategic multistakeholder SDG work we believe that there must be space for new actors and innovations. Young people are the key drivers of the transformation needed and as the project countrie
s have some of the youngest populations in the world youth groups are natural partners and beneficiary groups in the project. The project&apos;s goals are threatened by shrinking space of critical civil society and journalism. Promoting  social innovations such
 as whole-of-society approaches in SDG implementation can work to counter this trend. Training of journalists on SDGs and mobile course production will serve to spread the message and we also aim at bringing youth together with municipal leaders to solve p
roblems and support community level activities. Community activities empower vulnerable groups and are directly linked to the other activities of the project such as training of journalists and advocacy work.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kestavan kehityksen tavoitteita ei tulla saavuttamaan ilman merkittavia lisaponnistuksia. Tilanne on nahtavissa myos projektin kohdemaissa Tansaniassa Ugandassa ja Keniassa. Kestavan kehityksen tavoitteet linkittyvat vahvasti toisiinsa kuten koronavirusepi
demiakin on osoittanut.  Yhteiskuntien resilienssia tulee vahvistaa ja tukea etenkin kaikkein haavoittuvimmassa asemassa olevien ryhmien ja ihmisten kykya sopeutua ja selviytya vaikeista tilanteista. Naisten ja tyttojen aseman vahvistaminen seka sukupuolin

akokulman valtavirtaistaminen ovat tassa avainasemassa.Projekti tarjoaa tehokkaita vertaisoppimisen mahdollisuuksia seka valmiuksien kehittamista tyopajatyoskentelyn kautta. Kohderyhmina ovat kansanedustajat ja kuntapaattajat seka avainasemassa olevat virk
amiehet kansalaisjarjestojen edustajat ja toimittajat. Kansainvalisiin prosesseihin osallistumista rohkaistaan erityisesti YK:n Afrikan alueellisten foorumien kautta mika edesauttaa myos alueellista tyota kestavan kehityksen tavoitteiden parissa. Yksi paat

avoitteista on paattajien valmiuksien vahvistaminen seka sektorirajat ylittavien ratkaisujen loytaminen jotta kestavan kehityksen tavoitteet voidaan toteuttaa seka kansallisesti etta paikallisesti. Sen lisaksi etta vahvistamme avainasemassa olevien sidosry
hmien tyota kestavan kehityksen parissa uskomme etta myos uusia toimijoita ja innovaatioita tarvitaan. Erityisesti nuoret ovat muutoksen aikaansaamisessa tarkeassa roolissa varsinkin naissa kohdemaissa joissa asukkaiden keski-ika on maailman nuorimpien jou
kossa. Nuoret ovat luonnollinen yhteistyoryhma ja samalla ryhma joka myos hyotyy projektin tuloksista. Kriittisen kansalaisyhteiskunnan ja journalismin tila kaventuminen uhkaa tuloksia projektimaissa. Pyrimme muuttamaan tata kehitysta positiviisen kautta v
akuuttamalla paattajia laajan osallistamisen hyodyista. Myos kestavan kehityksen mobiilikurssin tarjoaminen toimittajille ja paattajille auttaa viemaan viestia eteenpain. Tavoitteenamme on myos tuoda nuoret ja kuntapaattajat yhteen ratkomaan ongelmia ja tu
kemaan tyota kuntatasolla seka tukea suoraan yhteisoja tyossa kestavien ratkaisujen ja naisten ja tyttojen oikeuksien puolesta.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomen YK-liitto</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Kenya;Tanzania;Uganda"></location>
  <sector code="43081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="17.17" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">110000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">185000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2099-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">195000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">675000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
