<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="331" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-05T09:56:07" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-05T09:56:07" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020- 2020000320</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting Transformative Resilience in Area C East Jerusalem and Gaza</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Transformatiivisen Resilienssin tukiohjelma C-alueella Ita-Jerusalemissa ja Gazassa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">More than 50 years of Israeli occupation have caused regional fragmentation and separated Palestinian communities from each other. This fragmentation and lack of Palestinian sovereignty in Area C Gaza and East Jerusalem have led to a particularly precariou
s and continuing vulnerability that characterizes the daily lives of these communities. As a result there are growing development gaps in Palestine and trust between the Palestinian people and the government is undermined without a clear political and econ

omic vision.At the same time the challenges brought by Covid-19 are plaguing Palestine&apos;s already weak economy and raising poverty and unemployment rates as well as further complicating the lives of the most vulnerable communities especially women and youth
.The long-term aim of the Supporting Transformative Resilience in Area C East Jerusalem and Gaza program (Transformative Resilience Program TRP) is to promote resilience of Palestinians in the most vulnerable circumstances. The immediate objectives of the 

program are: 1. to improve access to services and economic opportunities in Area C East Jerusalem and Gaza especially for women and youth; 2. to strengthen political cultural economic and social cohesion and improve the inclusion of vulnerable groups in pa
rticular women and youth; and 3. to support institutional and behavioral change to reduce socio-economic inequalities including gender inequality.The program is in line with Finland&apos;s country strategy and supports the country program (2021 - 2024) by stren
gthening the resilience of Palestinians in the most vulnerable circumstances.The program is managed by UNDP and the total budget for 2021-2024 is 40 MUSD. Finland supports the program with 3 MEURO in 2021-2024.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Yli 50 vuotta kestanyt Israelin miehitys on aiheuttanut alueellista pirstaloitumista ja erottanut palestiinalaisia yhteisoja toisistaan. Tama pirstaloituminen ja Palestiinan itsemaaraamisoikeuden puute erityisesti C-alueella Gazassa ja Ita-Jerusalemissa on
 johtanut yleiseen epavarmuuteen ja jatkuvaan haavoittuvuuteen joka luonnehtii naiden yhteisojen jokapaivaista elamaa. Taman seurauksena Palestiinassa on kasvavia puutteita kehityksessa ja palestiinalaisvaeston ja hallituksen valinen luottamus heikkenee il

man selkeaa poliittista ja taloudellista nakemysta.Samanaikaisesti Covid-19:n tuomat haasteet kurittavat Palestiinan jo ennestaan heikkoa taloutta nostavat koyhyys- ja tyottomyysastetta seka vaikeuttavat entisestaan kaikkein haavoittuvimmassa asemassa olev
ia yhteisojen elamaa erityisesti naisten ja nuorten. Transformatiivisen Resilienssin tukiohjelmassa C-alueella Ita-Jerusalemissa ja Gazassa (Transformative Resilience Program TRP) pitkan aikavalin tavoitteena on edistaa heikoimmassa asemassa olevien palest

iinalaisten kriisinsietokykya ja resilienssia. Ohjelman valittomina tavoitteina on: 1. parantaa palvelujen saatavuutta seka taloudellisia mahdollisuuksia C-alueella Ita-Jerusalemissa ja Gazassa erityisesti naisille ja nuorille; 2. vahvistaa poliittista kul
ttuurista taloudellista ja sosiaalista yhteenkuuluvuutta ja parantaa haavoittuvassa asemassa olevien ryhmien erityisesti naisten ja nuorten osallistamista; seka 3. tukea institutionaalisia ja kayttaytymismuutoksia sosioekonomisen eriarvoisuuden mukaan luki
en sukupuolten epatasa-arvon vahentamiseksi. Ohjelma on linjassa Suomen maastrategian kanssa ja tukee maaohjelmaa (2021 ? 2024) vahvistamalla heikoimmassa asemassa olevien palestiinalaisten resilienssia. Ohjelma on UNDP:n hallinnoima ja kokonaisbudjetti vu
osina 2021 ? 2024 on 40 MUSD. Suomen tuki ohjelmalle on 3 MEURO vuosina 2021 ? 2024.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n kehitysohjelma</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="25030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the secondary priority area in t
his activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.4" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="1.5" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="4.4" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="4.7" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="8.6" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="7.2" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">3000000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">3000000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
