<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="320" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-12T16:05:40" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-12T16:05:40" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2016160013</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding Facility for Immediate Stabilization in Iraq (FFIS) UNDP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Irakin vakauttamisrahasto FFIS UNDP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project concerns COVID-19 prevention.Iraq is struggling with a multitude of challenges. These include the 1.4 IDPs the presence of terrorist groups the ongoing political crisis and the crashing oil prices. The spread of COVID-19 pandemic will further erode
 the economic social and national health situation. The health sector of Iraq is estimated to be in a poor condition incapable of facing a severe pandemic. The uncontrolled spread of the virus could threaten the stability of the country and lead into a soc

ietal collapse.UNDP is leading the stabilization efforts in Iraq and supporting the Iraqi government in its response to the pandemic. In line with the WHO-led Iraq?s Country Strategic Preparedness and Response Plan Against COVID-19 UNDP will strengthen the
 health sector; support the crisis management efforts of the government as well as support the government to assess the impacts of COVID-19 to enable the drafting of recovery strategies for the country.The expected results include: Output 1: The healthcare

 system in Iraq is strengthened to prevent the spread of COVID-19 Output 2: Integrated crisis management and response is strengthened to enable the Government of Iraq to maintain core functions and manage1 its response Output 3: The social and economic imp
acts of COVID-19 are assessed to enable Government of Iraq define shortand medium-term recovery strategies for IraqThe project will be implemented under UNDP?s Funding Facility for Immediate Stabilization (FFIS/FFS) utilizing its management structures. Sin
ce 2016 Finland has allocated 9 MEUR to the facility. FFS aims to support the Iraqi government to address the immediate stabilization needs in newly accessible areas allowing the sustainable return of IDPs. The Fund is an integral part of the Government?s 
national stabilization efforts. The fund implements projects through the following windows: 1) Public works and light infrastructure rehabilitation in areas occupied from the ISIL; 2) Support to jump-starting livelihoods and jobs creation initiatives; 3) L
ocal governance capacity building. The COVID-19 response will become an independent output in FFS programme document.The budget for the project is 22.4 MUSD. By May 2020 UNDP has secured around 9 MUSD funding. The department for Africa and the Middle East 
proposes 2 MEUR funding for the project. The one-off disbursement will be done as soon as the funding decision and the financing agreement have been signed.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kyseessa on covid-19-vaikutusten vahentamiseen kohdistuva hanke.Sisallissodasta toipuva Irak kamppailee monien haasteiden kanssa. Naihin kuuluvat 1.4 miljoonaa sisaista pakolaista aarijarjestojen sortotoimet sisapoliittinen kriisi seka oljyn hinnan romahdu
s. Covid-19?pandemian aiheuttamat poikkeusolot lisaavat taloudellista sosiaalista ja terveydellista ahdinkoa. Maan terveydenhuolto on heikossa tilassa eika kykene kohtaamaan pandemiaa. Pandemian hallitsematon leviaminen Irakissa voisi horjuttaa kv. yhteiso

n tuella saavutettua haurasta vakautta ja johtaa yhteiskunnan romahtamiseen. Irakin vakautustoimia koordinoiva UNDP tukee Irakin valmiutta kohdata pandemia. UNDP vahvistaa WHO:n tuella laaditun kansallisen pandemia-strategian (Iraq Country Strategic Prepar
edness and Response Plan Against COVID-19) mukaisesti terveyssektorin toimintakykya hallinnon kriisinhallintatoimia seka sen arviointi-/suunnitteluosaamista kriisista poispaasyn mahdollistamiseksi. Hankkeen tavoitteet keskittyvat: 1. Terveydenhoitojarjeste

lman vahvistamiseen epidemian leviamisen ehkaisemiseksi (mm. suojavalineiden tarjonta ja potilaiden turvallisen asioimisen mahdollistaminen sairaaloissa/laboratorioissa.2. Hallinnon ja YK:n maatiimin kriisinhallintatoimien vahvistamiseen jotta kriisiin voi
daan vastata tehokkaasti.3. Viruksen aiheuttamien sosiaalisten ja taloudellisten vaikutusten arviointiin ja kriisista poispaasy-strategioiden luomiseen.Hanke toteutetaan UNDP:n hallinnoiman Irakin vakauttamisrahaston (Funding Facility for Stabilization FFS
) alaisuudessa hyodyntaen sen hallintorakenteita. Suomi on tukenut rahastoa yhteensa 9 MEUR vuodesta 2016 lahtien. Rahasto on keskeinen osa Irakin kansallisia vakauttamistoimia. Sen toiminta tukee Isilta vapautettujen alueiden vakauttamista mahdollistaen v
aeston paluun koteihinsa. Hankkeita toteutetaan 1) infrastruktuurin jalleenrakentamiseksi; 2) elinkeinojen elpymisen ja tyopaikkojen synnyn tukemiseksi; ja 3) paikallishallintojen kehittamiseksi. Pandemian vastaisista toimista luodaan oma output-tulosalue 
rahaston ohjelmadokumenttiin.Hankkeen kokonaisbudjetti on 22.4 MUSD (n. 20.7 MEUR). Kevaalla 2020 rahoitusta on koossa ennen Suomen rahoituspaatosta noin 9 MUSD (8.5 MEUR).  Afrikan ja Lahi-Idan alueosasto esittaa hankkeelle rahoitusta 2 MEUR vuoden 2018 m
aararahasta. Maksatus tehdaan kerralla heti rahoituspaatoksen ja sopimuksen allekirjoitusten jalkeen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n kehitysohjelma</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2016160013" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-19" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12250" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.D" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2016160013" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
