<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="120" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-10-09T13:12:58" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-10-09T13:12:58" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2015151858</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Nepal&apos;s School Sector Development Plan (SSDP) Covid-19 response</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Suomen tuki Nepalin opetussektoriohjelmalle 2-vaihe COVID-19 lisamyonto</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In spring 2020 the Nepal Ministry of Education and the Nepal Education Cluster have jointly developed a separate COVID-19 adaptation plan (COVID-19 Education Cluster Contingency Plan - Nepal Education Cluster 2020) for the education sector programme SSDP (
The School Sector Development Plan). The Ministry of Education made a general request for all donors including Finland of additional funding for covid-19 emergency response.The overall objective of the Education Cluster Contingency Plan is to prevent the s

pread of COVID-19 from education institutions into local communities by providing safe learning environments by putting in place appropriate prevention measures in Nepalese schools. To achieve this objective the immediate response of the Education Cluster 
will focus on a) Ensuring adequate capacity for management and coordination during the response period b) Strengthening prevention and resilience within the school system and among students teachers parents and caregivers and c) Support Continuity of Educa

tion/Learning for all children in all areas including children with disabilities and from marginalized backgrounds.Finland&apos;s financial contrbution for the implementation of the Education Cluster Contingency Plan for COVID-19 is EUR 2 514 999. The support w
ill be channeled and monitored as part of Nepal School Sector Development Plan (SSDP) programme. The School Sector Development Plan (SSDP) program covers the entire basic education system in Nepal and is funded jointly by the Government of Nepal and its De
velopment Partners. The program is implemented during the years 2016-2023. Finland supports the program with a total of 20 million euros in the years 2016-2020.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Suomen COVID-19 lisamyonnon tarkoituksena on vastata Nepalin tekemaan apuvetoomukseen ja edesauttaa Nepalin opetussektorin mahdollisuuksia turvata opetuksen jatkuminen COVID-19 pandemian aikana ja valittomasti sen jalkeen seka tukea nepalilaisten lasten pa
asya takaisin perusopetukseen. Hankkeen tavoitteina on 1. Riittavan hallinto- ja koordinointikapasiteetin varmistaminen 2. tartuntojen ennaltaehkaisy ja resilienssin vahvistaminen 3. inklusiivisen opetuksen jatkuvuuden turvaaminen. COVID-19 hankkeen tavoit

teet taydentavat SSDP- ohjelman toimintoja mutta lisatoimilla keskitytaan torjumaan COVID- 19 pandemian tuomia riskeja opetussektorille.Koulutus- tiede- ja teknologiaministerio (MOEST) ilmoitti 16. maaliskuuta 2020 kaikkien koulutuslaitosten sulkemisen val
takunnallisesti COVID 19 -pandemian vuoksi. Paatoksen seurauksena arviolta 82 miljoonaa nepalilaista lasta on poissa koulusta. Koulujen sulkemisen suorina seurauksina luokkavuosien 10-12 paattokokeet jaivat pitamatta. Lisaksi pandemian aikana kouluja on ka

ytetty yleisesti karanteenitiloina (provinssitasolla 50-82 prosenttia karanteenitiloista sijaitsee kouluissa) ja niiden uudelleen avaamisen ajankohta on hyvin epavarma ja vaatii vahintaan tilojen desinfiointia ja mahdollista kunnostamista. Tilanteen jatkue
ssa ja pitkittyessa koulujen sulkemisella tulee arvioiden mukaan olemaan monia negatiivisia vaikutuksia. Kevaalla 2020 Nepalin opetusministerio ja Nepalin opetusklusteri ovat yhdessa laatineet SSDP ohjelmalle erillisen COVID-19 sopeutussuunnitelman (COVID-
19 Education Cluster Contingency Plan - Nepal Education Cluster 2020). Opetusministerio teki toukokuussa 2020 yleisen lisarahoituspyynnon kaikille avunantajille ml Suomi. Esitetaan Suomen rahoitukseksi yhteensa 2 514 999 euroa  COVID-19 sopeutussuunnitelma
n toimeenpanoon. Rahoitus kanavoidaan ja toimeenpanoa seurataan osana Nepalin opetussektorin kehittamisohjelman SSDP (School Sector Development Plan) ohjaus- ja seurantamekanismeja.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recipient Government</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kehitysmaan julkinen sektori</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2015151858" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">6215000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">6499000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2050000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">4800000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2015151858" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
