<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="510" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-12T16:05:40" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-12T16:05:40" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020- 2020000617</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joint Evaluation of UN System Wide Response to Combating Covid19 and Support to Recovery Actions</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Yhteisevaluointi YK jarjestelman toimista Covid-19 pandemian ehkaisemisessa ja seurausten lieventamisessa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The object of the evaluation is the UN Covid-19 Response and Recovery Multi PartnerTrust Fund (MPTF) an initiative launched by the UN Secretary General on 31.3.2020. The  funding mechanism is a UN action that is aims to help low and middle income countries
 in their response to the pandemic and recovery from it. The MPTF has three main objectives: 1) respond to the acute health sector crisis 2) promote the recovery of societies and economy 3) help rebuild more equal inclusive and sustainable economies and so
cieties. Finnish contribution to the Fund is 35 M?. The purpose of the evaluation is to also to find out to what extent the MPTF promotes UN inter-agency cooperation and coherence of its response to the pandemic. Moreover it will asses the role of UN Resid
ent Coordinators and UN country teams their local knowledge and ability to react local circumstances . The initiative to evaluate the matter has been made by the UN Secretary General who has given the responsibility to recently established UN System Wide E
valuation Office. The evaluation requires that a thorough evaluability assessment will be made to establish the final objectives scope and evaluation questions.   Evaluability study is supported by Denmark Norway Sweden and Finland. The evaluation of proje
cts funded from Covid-19 Response and Recovery Multi-Partner Trust Fund will be covered from the fund capital but for the evaluability study requires a separate 300 000 euro allocation that will be channeled through the MPTF. The Unit for Development Evalu
ation proposes to use 44 800 euros of its 2020  budget and 55 200 euros of unspent 2019 budget.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Evaluoinnin kohde on YK:n paasihteerin 31.3.2020 lanseeraama YK-jarjestojen valisen koronaviruspandemian seurauksiin vastaava rahoitusmekanismi jonka avulla autetaan matalan ja keskitulotason maita pandemiavasteessa seka kriisista palautumisessa. Rahastoll
a on kolme paatavoitetta: 1) vastata akuuttiin terveyskriisiin; 2) edistaa yhteiskunnan ja talouden elpymista seka 3) auttaa jalleenrakentamaan kriisin jalkeen tasa-arvoisempia inklusiivisempia ja kestavampia talouksia ja yhteiskuntia. Suomi on myontanyt r
ahastolle 35 M?. Evaluoinnin tarkoitus on samalla selvittaa missa maarin rahasto edistaa YK-jarjestojen valista yhteistyota ja johdonmukaisuutta pandemiavasteessa ja pohjaa YK:n maakoordinaattorien seka YK:n maatiimien toimintaan niiden paikallistuntemukse
en ja kykyyn reagoida paikallisiin olosuhteisiin.  Aloitteen evaluointiin on tehnyt YK:n paasihteeri joka on vastuuttanut jarjestelmatason evaluoinneista vastaavan toimiston (UN System Wide Evaluation Office). Evaluoinnin kaynnistaminen edellyttaa kuitenki
n huolellista evaluoitavuusselvitysta jonka jalkeen tarkennetaan evaluoinnin sisalto laajuus ja evaluointikysymykset. Evaluoitavuusselvitysta tukevat Tanska Norja Ruotsi ja Suomi. Jatkossa rahaston (Covid-19 Response and Recovery Multi-Partner Trust Fund M
PTF) rahoittamien hankkeiden arviointiin tarvittavat rahat voidaan irrottaa rahaston maaraahoista mutta evaluoitavuusarviota varten kerataan erillinen 300 000 euron maararaha joka kanavoidaan MPTF:n kautta. Kehitysevaluoinnin yksikko esittaa etta tarkoituk
seen myonnetaan yksikon kuluvan vuoden maararahoista 44 800 euroa ja vuoden 2019 siirtomaararahoista 55 200 euroa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n kehitysohjelma</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not defined</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ei maaritelty</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430667" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation and internal audit of development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kehitysyhteistyon evaluointi</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.D" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
