<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-honduras" dstore:index="10" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-HON087</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Holistic Quality Care for People Living with HIV and HIV Prevention with Children in the Sula Valley</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is the continuation of HON065.
Honduras is one of the poorest countries in Latin America, with the largest concentration of HIV and AIDS in Central America. Puerta Abierta (Open Door) works with people living with HIV and AIDS (PLWHA) and their families in conditions of poverty and inequality. Puerta Abierta was created in 1997 by the Catholic Congregation of the Vincentian Fathers to respond to the needs of PLWHA in the Sula Valley, in which San Pedro Sula is located. Their aim is to provide a holistic and effective response to the HIV and AIDS pandemic in San Pedro Sula, opening coordination spaces at Church level and with other local and national institutions and providing processes of holistic care to people with HIV and their families - medical, psychological and social care -; home visits; education - and preventive work with PLWHAS, parish communities and general public.  Activities focus on the personal, family, social, psychological and spiritual aspects of living with HIV and AIDS, with both formal and non-formal education components. The formal component includes educational classes and medical care, including the provision of some drugs where needs are identified; the non-formal components include more varied activities. Examples are educational-entertainment activities including exhibits and games in schools and a Puerta Abierta programme (called Children&#x2019;s Window - Ventana del Ni&#xF1;o), awareness raising talks in classrooms in schools and in parishes. Activities for adults include workshops and training sessions with PLWHAs. And the provision of grants to families of PLWHA to allow for children to attend school, covering school fees and materials, and food supplies. The project also supports the voice of PLWHA in Honduran society. They assert people&#x2019;s rights within the public health system when they are not provided with treatment. It also includes networking with other organisations providing support to PLWHAs. Now, in the context of COVID-19</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="HON087" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="HON087" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puerta Abierta</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HON087" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">13000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54607">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-15">13000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69235">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-15">13000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puerta Abierta</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
