<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="wcuk-activities" dstore:index="76" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-11T17:18:31+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-11T15:58:56+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1071659-PROJAFG028</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Take Two - War Child UK Response to COVID-19 in Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of individual protection assistance (multi-purpose cash grant) targeting extremely vulnerable households who lost their livelihoods, returnees from Iran, victims of protection incidents (cases referred to and followed by the case management team). The IPA will be considered to address specific needs of people affected by the COVID-19 emergency. A total of 380 households selected from Herat and Badghis provinces based on their level of vulnerability due to COVID-19 will benefit from provision of IPA. The project will be complementary to WCUK existing project in Herat and Badghis where assistance is provided to Unaccompanied Minors (UAMs) crossing the border from Iran. UAMs are provided with Child Protection services and reunified with their families. As support under this project ends after reunification, this project will fill this gap and provide much needed additional assistance for children and their families who have experience significant loss of livelihoods and struggle with many new challenges due to COVID-19, to help them to cope with the impact of the crisis, preventing adoption of negative copying mechanisms and reduce risk of getting infected by the virus. Criteria for the selection of most vulnerable groups who will benefit from IPA will include households who are female headed, child headed households and those households who lost their income due to COVID-19 crisis who were previously engaged in informal or daily labour works. The grant will also support households in Herat and Badghis through provision of Covid-19 hyginen kits for 380 household with families of 7 members which means 2800 househld memebrs will benfit from the project (based on the WASH Cluster recommendations). The kit include bathing soap, Laundery Soap, plastic soap case, plastic jerry can (rigid 10liter, 2 liter ewer, cotex/sanitary pad).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">84000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-30">5761.07</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
