<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-lebanon" dstore:index="13" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-LEB082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support platform for formal and non-formal civil society groups</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon is undergoing multiple crises - political deadlock and economic near-collapse on top of COVID-19 and the disastrous Beirut blast - and over half the population is now believed to be struggling to earn sufficient income to meet basic necessities.  Lebanese civil society has traditionally been very dynamic; indeed the weaknesses of the state in providing basic services to the population led to the emergence of NGOs trying to offset this absence or lack of services. Following the Syria crisis, new associations or non-formal groups, were established to provide basic support to Syrian refugees in Lebanon or in Syria.  Recognising that the kinds of support on offer by other INGOS were too often insufficiently tailored to smaller organisations to add real value, especially in relation to the needs of small organisations with limited financial and human resources, Mada established its platform initially in 2005 to fill the gap.  CAFOD funding from 2017 enabled Mada to re-launch and reactivate its Platform, and in the changed context of the Syrian Civil War and mass influx of Syrian refugees into Lebanon, to work with both Lebanese and Syrian NGOs and non-formal groups to  achieve their mission and objectives without leading to a change in the spirit, values or characteristics of these organisations.  This project, which is now moving into a second phase, forms part of CAFOD&apos;s support to peace building work in Lebanon by facilitating collaboration between Lebanese and Syrian civil society groups, thereby contributing to increased social cohesion between these communities.  It will also support the development and strengthening of a strong and vibrant Syrian civil society able to contribute to peace building in Syria in the future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="LEB082" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="LEB082" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mada Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="LEB082" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">40000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54747">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-01">40000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69476">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-01">20000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mada Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
