<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-mozambique" dstore:index="11" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-MOZ396</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Melhorando a Resili&#xEA;ncia dos deslocados de Guerra de Cabo Delgado na Prov&#xED;ncia de Nampula</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The escalation of armed conflicts associated with serious acts of terrorism (which began in October 2017) in the northern areas of the country (Cabo Delgado Province) caused the displacement of 424,202 people (IDPs) and caused 2,000 deaths, 60% of whom are civilians (CIP, October 2020). 
As a result, Mozambique is currently experiencing a multiple humanitarian emergency, aggravated by the repercussions of the global Covid-19 pandemic. Considering that at the end of 2018, Mozambique had 15,000 displaced people, including the northern and central regions, there has been a 2,700% increase in recent months. There are 36,936 IDPs present in Nampula Province in November 2020 (UNHCR, 16 November 2020). Among the displaced, only 3,981 (4.6%) are welcomed in the reception centres set up by the Government (INGC) and the United Nations. The conditions in the reception areas for families are precarious. Many displaced persons are taken in by relatives and acquaintances, but in most cases they are unable to guarantee their survival. The multiple and widespread emergency has led to a worsening of the already precarious socio-economic condition: rising commodity prices, negative impact on the informal economy, trade and small businesses. This has led Diocesan Caritas of Nacala to implement a six-month humanitarian assistance project (June-December 2020) with two main activities:
- Distribution of food kits, hygiene supplies, household utensils;
- Creation of &quot;child-friendly spaces&quot; for psychosocial support to displaced children.
Caritas Nacala intends now to continue with a post-emergency assistance by adapting its strategy to the current circumstances with a view to encourage the IDPs who received the first emergency aid to start rebuilding their lives in a more sustainable way. With this Project we are targeting these main needs:
- the loss of the means of production make economic independence and therefore food security impossible for them;
- the host families are also in a critical situation due to the shortage of seeds because of the scarcity of the last harvest;
- some of the Districts are planning to allocate land for resettlement and farming;
- the &quot;child-friendly spaces&quot; were well participated by all the children registered and offered a great opportunity for the most vulnerable</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="MOZ396" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Diocesana de Nacala</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="MOZ396" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MOZ396" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">83185.4391</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54589">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-08">83185.4391</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69103">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-08">39228.09</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Diocesana de Nacala</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
