<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-democraticrepublicofcongo" dstore:index="57" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC693</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Engagement for Peace and stability forum</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the North Kivu province and much of eastern DRC, the situation is still affected by insecurity and political instability, combined with ethnic conflicts, armed group activism and wars that have serious consequences on the living conditions of the population, youth unemployment and illiteracy. 
Governance problems in the DRC at all levels with its corollaries such as corruption, impunity, poor management of public resources, a lack of trust between ethnic communities, a leadership and confidence gap between young people and leaders exacerbate the limited involvement of young people in the democratic space and limit their participation as citizens. Many youths are faced unemployment and are exploited by political leaders. Others are recruited into armed groups and this increase harm in most disadvantaged communities in North-Kivu Province.
Supporting this project expects to increase youth&#x2019;s peace and citizenship awareness, to reduce ethnic and political manipulation and provide opportunities for youth to become change agents, and to engage in peace work and governance as key actors in nonviolent way. Project also expects empowering young people as genuine actors for change and peace in the region, informing them and raising their awareness as to their role and responsibility for building peace and political stability within the country.
The project plans to organize music festival and cultural activities as well as open space and workshops on topics related to Peacebuilding, leadership, entrepreneurship, civic and democratic participation, communication and dialog mechanism to build relationship as well as raising awareness in preventing and dealing with the corona virus pandemic (COVID-19). Faith leaders and key persons from local civil society and officials will mentor, share experiences and best practices with youths during the forum. 
Project activities will be cofounded by Goma&#x2019;Diocese and implemented by CDJP Goma&apos; staff and &#x201C;Maison des Jeunes&#x201D; with support from CAFOD peace building program Officer. The youth peace forum will be held in Goma and will bring together about 15000 youths from Goma Diocese and neighbouring dioceses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC693" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC693" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commission Dioc&#xE9;saine Justice et Paix du Dioc&#xE8;se Goma</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC693" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-02-16">7299.27</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54751">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-02-21">7299.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69363">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-02-21">7299.27</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commission Dioc&#xE9;saine Justice et Paix du Dioc&#xE8;se Goma</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
