<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-brazil" dstore:index="25" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BRA611</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Support for the Indigenous People of Roraima Against COVID-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over 514,992 cases of COVID-19 have been confirmed in Brazil, making it the country with the 2nd highest number of infections in the world. Over 206,000 people have recovered from the disease and over 29,000 people have died. As only half a million tests have been carried out, scientists estimate these numbers to be under-estimated by a factor of 15, meaning that 5.6 million infections and 345,000 deaths likely. The Amazon region has been particularly badly hit, with health infrastructure being completely overwhelmed by the end of April 2020. There have been grave concerns for the survival of indigenous communities, and campaigners have declared that unless action is taken, we will witness a genocide.

This project will have two lines of action. Firstly, ISA will support two ethnic groups to self-isolate in the forest for up to 3 months to protect themselves against the spread of COVID 19. These groups are the Wai Wai and the Yanomami.  The Yanomami will remain in the forest for two to three months living off forest food and fishing plus some processed food (which will be provided by ISA) to secure basic nutrition. The Wai Wai families will travel to areas in the forest where they usually harvest Brazil nuts (the harvest runs from the end of May until August). This will provide them with additional livelihoods options, post-pandemic. The third group to benefit from this project are Macuxi, Wapichana and Taurepang people with support going to acquisition of COVID tests and PPE to indigenous communities based in Eastern Roraima who have constructed sanitary barriers at the exit and entrance of communities.  The other line of action is to carry on providing accurate information about the Covid to the communities and ensuring information from the communities are reported to the authorities (FUNAI and SESAI) in case of COVID infection and threats such as illegal mining and logging in their territories.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA611" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA611" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto SocioAmbiental</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BRA611" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-15">50000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54095">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-04">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68506">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-04">50000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto SocioAmbiental</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
