<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-sudan" dstore:index="28" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SDN117</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security and Livelihoods assistance to vulnerable host communities in El Salam locality, White</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to provide basic lifesaving Food Security and Livelihoods (FSL) support to at least 15,000 people (about 3,000 HHs) in four villages/communities (El Radis 1, El Radis 2, Jouri and Um Sangor) in El Salam locality, White Nile State.
Affected population to be targeted by the project will be vulnerable host communities (HCs) members, with specific focus on Female Headed Households (FHH), People With Disability (PWD), families with members who are elderly, children under five and families worst affected by COVID-19 crisis. 
Key considerations will be made to ensure specific safety, privacy and security needs of women, girls, men, boys and people with special needs are addressed during delivery of project activities.
Project activities will specifically seek to provide and enable vulnerable HCs members access lifesaving FSL support, which will include provision of agricultural inputs (winter season seeds and tools through vouchers and DiNER Fairs) and services (training, and field extension services); provision of quality veterinary (vaccination and treatment) and extension services (training, and field extension services); provision of emergency livelihoods (restocking, fishing) start up packages (through vouchers) and activities (establishment of Saving and Internal Lending Committees - SILCs - trainings and networking) and; cash for work (digging of drainage tunnels and soil silos in preparation of the rainy seasons). Community Pest Scouts (CPS) will be trained on identifications of nymphs, fall army worms and other common crop pests and diseases to strengthen community early warning systems and preparedness. The CPSs will also support on alerts such as floods during the agricultural season.
The project will integrate messages on COVID-19 and cholera/AWD (in view of the on-coming rains starting from July/August) infection, prevention and control during community awareness sessions and field extension services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN117" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN117" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Sahara International Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SDN117" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">-0.0001</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54415">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-14">55895.7917</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="54507">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-14">-55895.7918</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
