<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-nigeria" dstore:index="51" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR439</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project to curtail the spread and impact of Covid 19 in communities of Adamawa State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The COVID-19 pandemic is the defining global health crisis of our time. (it could be said to be the greatest challenge we have faced since World War Two). Since its emergence in China in December 2019, the virus has spread to 213 countries (including Nigeria) with the number of confirmed cases rising daily in Africa, the Americas, and Europe. Countries are racing to slow the spread of the virus by testing and treating patients, carrying out contact tracing, limiting travel, quarantining citizens, and cancelling large gatherings such as sporting events, concerts, and schools.
The wide increasing spread of Coronavirus across the globe has dominated global attention. In Nigeria the Government at all levels is committed to the fight against its increasing spread. The presidential task force on containment of COVID-19 has from time to time brief Nigerians on the current trends of activities and efforts put in by the Government, organization and individuals to contain the spread of the Coronavirus. The spread of the virus has tremendously increased in the last two months (from Feb. to date 2020). The Nigeria Center for Disease Control (NCDC) has reported 12,801 confirmed cases as at 11:55pm, 8th of June 2020. Nigerian government is faced with hard choices about how to manage the virus. State Governors in Nigeria have already imposed border restrictions. Many are placing partial or blanket bans on public gatherings or insisting that citizen&#x2019;s shelter at home. These are necessary but also costly measures.

In Adamawa State, the governor imposed series of lockdown to contain the spread of the virus. Despite, the effort put by the government and other institutions such as the NCDC, there is a widespread notion by general public mostly in remote communities that Coronavirus is a lie and the perception that it is a foreign and rich persons&#x2019; sickness. Preventive measures such as social distancing, regular washing of hands or the use of hand sanitizers and other guidelines stipulated by the relevant authorities such as the NCDC are not properly adhered to. This project seeks to address &#x201C;Knowledge and attitude on Coronavirus among IDPs and Host communities assessed&#x201D; in 3 LGAs of Adamawa State (Yola North, Demsa and Girei). In line with SDG Goal 3, good health and well-being, Goal 4, Quality Education, Goal 5, Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls AND Goal 16, Promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development, provide access to justice for all and build effective, accountable and inclusive institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR439" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR439" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Yola, Justice and Peace Commission</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR439" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-01">11800.3786</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54136">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-27">11800.3786</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68810">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-27">11800.38</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Yola, Justice and Peace Commission</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
