<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-guatemala" dstore:index="16" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-GUA186</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Covid Humanitarian support plan for families from indigenous communities in rural areas of Verapaz</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Objective/Goal: Pastoral Social Caritas Verapaz (PSCV) will contribute with the mitigation measures before the COVID-19 through the humanitarian aid in the municipalities of intervention of Pastoral Social-C&#xE1;ritas Di&#xF3;cesis de la Verapaz. 
Outcomes
O1. Timely medical care is provided to 6,167 families (representatives of families who will receive food and health care) benefiting from the Caritas Social Pastoral, affected by the COVID-19 emergency under the modality of direct and telephone consultation.
O2. Increase health measures for 576 community health workers and leaders through the provision of hygiene kits, in the intervention municipalities, to prevent the spread of COVID-19.
O3. 40 PSCV staff apply prevention measures (mask and vehicle disinfection tool) under the necessary hygiene protocols during the delivery of supplies in the intervention areas which implies direct contact.

The proposal of humanitarian support consists of:  To provide direct support to the communities in the area of health care during the delivery of food and by telephone in their consultations or doubts about health; to support primary health care workers who provide medical care, to representatives of women&apos;s networks that provide accompaniment to cases of violence against women and to youth from the Pocom area of the diocese, through Wash Programmes (water and soap) and protective supplies, in the communities prioritized by the Pastoral Social - Caritas Diocese of Verapaz projects and in accordance with the principles established in the institution&apos;s Security Plan; to ensure the protection of 19 men and 21 women who are the Pastoral Social staff and who will deliver the supplies. This was identified through constant monitoring with the leaders of the communities.  All of this was done with the aim of reducing the vulnerability of families, especially women, the elderly and children, to COVID-19</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GUA186" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GUA186" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pastoral Social - Caritas, Diocesis de la Verapaz</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="GUA186" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-01">14805</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54086">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-29">14805</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68497">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-29">14805</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pastoral Social - Caritas, Diocesis de la Verapaz</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
