<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-democraticrepublicofcongo" dstore:index="49" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC688</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisectoral emergency assistance to the most vulnerable people affected by storms in  Salamabila r</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The expected impact of this intervention is the reduction of suffering by improving the living conditions of the beneficiaries as they will access food, NFI, shelter, etc. The cash that beneficiaries will receive will allow them to buy essential household items and/or rent houses. This will allow them to be sheltered from the weather and reduce the likelihood of becoming sick. HHs will as likely be able to access at least two meals per day and repsond to other needs.  The project will empower the community as we will do a survey prior to the cash distribution to assess the power dynamic within HHs and carry out sensitisation where needed, especially as it will be largely women who will be receiving the cash on behalf of the HHs. Priority will be given to the most vulnerable households  affected by the storms and wind, including widowed women, children heads of households, elderly people, people with disabilities, chronically ill, and / or other people who are unable to buy food and goods of their choice that meet the need of their households. 
We will organize the mobile banking  through which each affecte household will receive &#xA3;147.28 and the host families will receive &#xA3;58.14, the head of the household will receive the cash for the HH. This amount has been advised by the Food security and NFI/shelter clusters groups. Throughout the project, we will take into account the vulnerabilities of certain groups. For example, in order to avoid pregnant women, the elderly and people living with disabilities standing for too long, beneficiary lists will be categorised in order for them to quickly recognise their names. The cash will be done through mobile money which means people will not have to wait in long queues to receive their cash.

It is expected that this project will enable people to meet their basic need including food, NFI/shelter, etc.  CAFOD and Caritas Kasongo will target 520 HH (3120 people) with the cash and 12240 people with the awareness raising on COVID-19.  Feedback and complaints mechanisms will be put in place in the affected communities .  CAFOD/Caritas Kasogo&apos;s safeguarding principles will be explained to all in the affected communities (Kindu, Kama, Byenge, Du marche and Namoya).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC688" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC688" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Kasongo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC688" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-11">82973.4341</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54455">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-22">82973.4341</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68907">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-22">82973.43</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Kasongo</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
