<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-liberia" dstore:index="8" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-LIB096</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Food Distribution for COVID-19 (Reprogrammed SDG Funds)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the Corona Virus Pandemic emergence, the funds were diverted to respond to the pandemic in Liberia. The initiative intends to provide emergency food assistance during the COVID-19 pandemic to 158 most vulnerable families in five counties in the Diocese of Cape Palmas to reduce hunger. Training and public awareness on COVID-19 signs, symptoms, mode of transmission and preventive measures will be conducted for participants and will also cover wide range of the targeted counties.

-----------------------

The 2030 Agenda for Sustainable development calls on member states to conduct regular and inclusive reviews of implementation progress at the National and Sub-National level. The processes should be country-led and country driven. The UN High Level political forum provides a global and central platform for follow up and review of UN Member states&#x2019; SDG implementation. The international community has been involved in the HLPF for the last 4 years and it has provided an important opportunity for governments, major groups and other multi-stakeholders to reflect, learn and improve on projects, processes and policies that feed into the achievement of the global goals.
Today&#x2019;s development challenges are complex and greater than any one government can solve. A multi-stakeholder approach is critical for countries to ensure that no one is left behind in the development Agenda. Faith Based entities such as Caritas are moral , social and political agents for the promotion of integral human development and for achieving sustainable peace and security within their respective countries and communities through collaboration with governments in the national and subnational level. There is therefore a need to harness the unique capabilities of a wide range of actors through multi-thematic and multisectoral partnerships to achieve the Sustainable Development Goals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="LIB096" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="LIB096" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Commission of Justice, Peace and Caritas</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="LIB096" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-01">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="53808">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-21">30000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68349">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-21">30000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Commission of Justice, Peace and Caritas</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
