<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-nigeria" dstore:index="57" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR449</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livelihood and recovery support for population affected by violent crisis in Southern Kaduna</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is implemented in a consortium with Christian Aid. CAFOD is focusing in Kaura and Kauru LGAs of Kaduna state. The intervention will alleviate immediate suffering for the crisis affected people that will be targeted for this response while more resources are being mobilized from other partners and government stakeholders such as the State Emergency Management Agency (SEMA), National Emergency Management Agency (NEMA), Kaduna State Peace-Building Commission. Start agency interventions would be able to meet the immediate needs of the affected population while any mobilised resources from the government would also support further recovery processes and or possible scale up.
The IDPs have migrated to a safe area from which they will move out and return to their homes as they still try to attend to their farms. This intervention will serve as mainly a lifesaving to stabilize them for the initial period before they feel safe to return as is the typical disposition of those in the middle region of Nigeria. 
Based on the assessment that has been conducted so far by Red Cross and local partner in the location, the needs are quite varied due to the nature by which households were displaced. The key sectors identified in the assessment findings were: Food, NFIs and WASH. More specifically, they included access to food and medication, NFIs, Blankets, hand-sanitisers, nose-masks, mattresses, toiletries, toilets, mosquito nets, sanitary items like sanitizers. There is also a need for risk communication intervention around sensitisation on the COVID-19 pandemic and protocols in disaster expecially as the targetted population are considered more vulnerable in the context and reality of the attacks and consequences. This needs-based, accountable and inclusive project will focus on the following key areas: 
1. Cash grants to the 1,657 most vulnerable individuals to address food insecurity needs
2. NFI and WASH distributions to 15,000+ displaced individuals 
3. Community sensitisation on EWS, Disaster Management and COVID-19 protocols to 15,000+ individuals
Note the WASH intervention will focus on the camps and host communities will also be strengthened to promote some basic guides and practices to forestall community transmission of the virus.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR449" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR449" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR449" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-22" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-08">57178.1182</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54336">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-27">57178.1182</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68778">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-27">13337.15</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68819">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-27">43840.97</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
