<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="gb-chc-220949-activities" dstore:index="50" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-18T09:45:34.2265376+01:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-14T12:32:24.287" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-220949-P7848</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SGBV Prevention and Response in Disasters - Asia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to prevent and reduce the occurrence of sexual and gender based violence at the community level, particularly in times of crisis. As gender based violence is closely linked to harmful gender based norms and beliefs, it will also seek to change attitudes toward violence in order to decrease the tolerance of sexual and gender based violence. &#xC2;&#xA0; In the Philippines the project will be piloted in between four to six communities, in Tacloban city and Aklan province. The chosen communities will be confirmed, based on planning mission reports, and agreed to once at the inception workshop at the start of the project. &#xC2;&#xA0; In Indonesia, the project will be piloted in between three to six communities in Aceh province and Bima City. If successful and dependant on the level of funding available the project could then be scaled-up, rolled out to other communities, and potentially implemented in other countries in the region. &#xC2;&#xA0; This project will primarily work with women and girls as they are disproportionally affected by SGBV. However, we know from experience that exclusion of men and boys in such programmes distorts household dynamics and results in more violence towards women and girls and as such men and boys will also be engaged as key participants in this project. &#xC2;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesian Red Cross Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-21018" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFRC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippine Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>Performance&amp;Accountability@redcross.org.uko</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="720" percentage="20" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="121" percentage="20" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="740" percentage="20" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="998" percentage="20" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="998" percentage="20" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="GB-CHC-220949-P7848-001-002">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-04">44582</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to a lack of progress within PMI, and the effect of COVID-19 on the project overall, it has been agreed with the donor, IFRC, PMI and PRC, to extend the timeframe of this project by one year. This is a no cost extension from the donor and will allow completion of all project activities as originally intended. Therefore, rather than end on the 31st December 2020, this project will now end on the 31st December 2021.
&#xC2;&#xA0;

Since the project has been extended for one year to 31st December 2021, the BRC has agreed to fund the programme management position which maintains oversight of this project for the extension period. The PGI officer is the main link between BRC and PMI and PRC on this, and so the position it critical to the continuation of the project. The BRC, IFRC and donor agree to utilise a small underspend on the project (14, 732 CHF) towards this position, and BRC will contribute a further 53,148 CHF equivalent of GBP 44,852 in order to fully fund the position from the end of the previous period 31st December 2020 until the 31st December 2021. This position extension will therefore be from the 1st January 2021- 31st December 2021.
&#xC2;&#xA0;

Regarding reporting, interim reports shall be submitted in December 2020, April,2021 and October,2021. The final narrative and financial reports shall be submitted on 31st March,2022, (with the narrative outcomes and impacts only for SGBV project). The financial report would reflect total amount of expenses against full amount of pledged funds for all respective projects under cash pledge M1812018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-220949-P7848-001" ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-21018">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFRC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="3"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="GB-CHC-220949-P7848-001-001">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-11">159999.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final tranch for SGBV.&#xC2;&#xA0;
All docs present - PMN and GAD Addendum are for multiple positions / programmes, of which this grant is one. Documents at&#xC2;&#xA0;https://pims-live.redcross.org.uk/entity/6/P7848-001/documents?folderPath=Final%20Tranch</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-21018">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFRC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="3"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
