<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-southsudan" dstore:index="116" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SSD231</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial support for the position of General Secretary and Finance officer.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The South Sudan Council of Churches (SSCC) has been implementing Action Plan for peace (APP) since the the development of APP through statement of intent which developed delivery of 4 programme outcome relating to advocacy, neutral forum, reconciliation, and institutional development. Through this church based nation wide and multi-stake engagement action, the SSCC envisage the realization of a peaceful resolution of conflicts and restoration of peace in South Sudan. The first phase of the the APP 2016-2017 has ended and SSCC is now implementing a new phase 2018-2021 through annual funding from all its partners including CTP, and Christian Aid, and PAX, all church Aid, working collaboratively under the structure core Group whose work is to mobile funding and provide technical support to SSCC in the implementation of APP
South Sudan like many other countries is constrained unprecedentedly by social and economic systems breakdown because of COVID-19. Not only is the COVID-19. Not only is the COVID-19 pandemic a threat to physical health and the economy. it has a well affected funding for partners and SSCC is not an exception. Given the peace agreement signed is seemly taking shape continue the SSCC would like to continue scaling up its operation in Equatorial and Greater Upper Nile Regions. The council under capacity strengthening outcomes would like to request CTP to support the General Secretary and Finance officer (Accountant) in the secretariat. 
The position of the General Secretary existed before when the Action Plan for peace (APP) was launched and it manages all the functions in the SSCC Secretariat. This position is covered solely supported by SSCC through its assets which is also badly affected by the economic setback leaving all percentages for support of SSCC secretariat whose financial support tremendously reduced due to reduction in its retained income.
The stability in all regions is paying the way for full implementation of APP activities in all the location, SSCC has also already recruited a Finance officer who is based at the head office. The finance officer is responsible for managing all financial records of the regions including partners and donor funds for implementation of activities in the regions and gives support to the finance department at the head office. The finance officer will report directly to finance manager at SSCC headquarters and shall administration have supervised by regional coordinator equatorial region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD231" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD231" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Council of Churches</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSD231" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54697">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-02-08">12000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="54696">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-02-08">18000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69392">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-02-08">15000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Council of Churches</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
