<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="acf-id" dstore:index="1" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2019-02-22T15:29:50+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2019-02-22T15:29:50+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-28"></period-start>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-18">
   </value>
  </budget>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>j.birmingham@actionagainsthunger.org.uk</email>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">James Birmingham</narrative>
   </person-name>
  </contact-info>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1"></country-budget-items>
  <crs-add>
   <loan-status currency="GBP"></loan-status>
  </crs-add>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On Friday 28 September, an earthquake measuring 7.4 on the Richter scale hit the Indonesian island of Sulawesi, triggering a tsunami that reached 18 feet in height and left a trail of destruction in its wake. Tens of thousands of homes have been destroyed and entire communities have been decimated. As of 24th October 2018, BNPB confirmed 2,077 fatalities, 4,400 persons have been seriously injured and at least 1,700 people are reported as missing. There are currently over 211,000 displaced people staying in 980 settlements across Central Sulawesi. Thousands more have left Sulawesi or found refuge with host families. An estimated 15,000 houses and land have been totally destroyed. Some 17,000 houses are heavily damaged; however, the sites may allow for reconstruction.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority needs include logistic support, economic recovery, medical assistance, clean water, sanitation and hygiene, recovery of infrastructure and public services, shelter, protection, including women and children&apos;s protection, and education. The Joint Needs Assessment (HFI-led) also found that nearly half of the surveyed population face food shortages. Debris and damaged structures need to be removed to reduce risk of further accidents. Most Water and Sanitation infrastructure was affected either by the loss of springs during the quake, or by destruction of the pipes and civil engineering. Liquefaction has also affected many wells and bore holes. Of the 142 IDP sites, many remain with inadequate access to latrines and water supply. Sanitary conditions have significantly deteriorated since the disaster, leading to an increased risk of communicable diseases such as diarrhoea or skin infections. Planned outcomes: 1. People affected by disaster in Central Sulawesi have recovered access to clean water, proper sanitation facilities, and basic hygiene practice promotion. (within 3 months) 2. People affected by disaster in Central Sulawesi have increased food and nutritional security (within 6 months) Action Against Hunger are proposing a multisectoral intervention with WASH, nutrition and food security components, to be delivered through Yakkum Emergency Unit, a local NGO partner, and Aquassistance, a French partner specialising in water, sanitation and waste management. Action Against Hunger will provide 2 water treatment units, with technicians supporting the installation of the units, and te training of YEU, local government and BNPM staff on their operation and maintenance. YEU will provide water trucking services to 10 affected areas and install two temporary water networks as well as hygiene kits for 1000 household and hygiene promotion activities. YEU will also install disability-accessible latrines in the displacement sites. Environmental cleaning will be enabled through distribution of tools to targeted households to permit the affected population to clear rubble and damaged structures. Nutrition and Food Security: YEU will implement daily community kitchens in each of the displacement sites for two months. The Posyandu health centre will then be supported to provide supplementary feeding to children under 5 that have been identified as in need through active screening by YEU staff - trained nurses and protocols. Further to this, all intervention areas will receive counselling on health and Infant and Young Child Feeding.</narrative>
  </description>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.MS-WORD.DOCUMENT.MACROENABLED.12" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/AAH_DEC_ITA18_Ph1-Plan-20181218111251.docx">
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposal for Phase 1</narrative>
   </title>
  </document-link>
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1047501-DECIndonesia</iati-identifier>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1047501" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1062638" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disasters Emergency Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre La Faim</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <related-activity ref="GB-CHC-1062638-ITA-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1047501" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="43081" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEC Indonesia Tsunami Appeal: Phase 1</narrative>
  </title>
  <transaction>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1062638-ITA-2018" ref="GB-CHC-1062638" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disasters Emergency Committee</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1047501-DECIndonesia" ref="GB-CHC-1047501" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-19">
   </value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
