<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="helpage_international-activities" dstore:index="166" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-12T14:47:55" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-12T14:49:53" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1762840-JOR030-UN99-01</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1762840" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing the emergency COVID-19 response through improving access to basic needs and protection services for the most vulnerable and marginalised older women and men with and without
disabilities during the winter months in 4 governorates of Jordan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed 4-month emergency response project aims at improving access to basic needs and
protection services for the most vulnerable and marginalised older women and men with and without

disabilities during the winter months and to help them cope with the secondary impacts of COVID-19, in
Amman, Mafraq, Zarqa, and Irbid.

The project will provide cash assistance to support 800 of the most vulnerable older people (70% of
older women) and their family members in meeting their basic needs, in particular food, medication for
chronic disease as well as heating costs for the winter months. Through cash assistance, the project
will help mitigate the negative impact of the pandemic. Protection will be mainstreamed throughout the
project implementation to ensure safe and meaningful access to cash for older people, while preserving
their dignity. In addition, the project will put a special focus on PSEA and age and gender based
violence; it will ensure that all staff and volunteers involved in the project and members of target
communities are well aware of PSEA and age and gender-based violence, as well as safeguarding
concerns, and how reports can be made safely. At least 50 staff and volunteers will be trained on PSEA
and safeguarding. 1000 community members, including 800 older men and women (70% of women),
will receive direct information related to PSEA, age and gender-based violence, and safeguarding.
HelpAge will promote the use of the referral mechanism for survivors of SEA and age and genderbased
violence. Referrals to UNHCR focal points for PSEA, in Irbid and Mafraq, or to other specialised
agencies when they exist in the local area, will be supported by the project when needed. All
components of the project will adhere to the humanitarian principles and the core humanitarian
standards.
This project meets the goals and standards of the allocation, the COVID-19 and the Global HRP by
targeting one of the most vulnerable and neglected groups, older men and women. The project is
designed around the HRP strategic priority: This project will create synergies with the local
organizations, communities, and strengthen prevention and PSEA awareness in response to the JRP. It
will also highlight the lessons learnt and advocate for the inclusion of older men and women with and
without disabilities in various humanitarian programmes, mainstreaming gender and PSEA. This project
will address the gaps in services regarding older men and women and highlight the needs. This
advocacy work will be throughout the duration of the project and beyond and will be shared with the
various clusters (protection, basic needs), working groups and the Jordan INGO forum.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1128267-8" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1762840" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Enquiries</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>iatiinfo@helpage.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tavis House, 1-6 Tavistock Square, London WC1H 9NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="SS" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://helpage.sharepoint.com/:w:/s/Operations2/Edb-pIuRExFOh4VJef0FD3gBda8kj_jAGwxAEcGyUw1Xag?e=W5dO2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe &amp; secure</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-01">82745</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-01">62058</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-31">69489</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds for period 2020/009</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-31">4870</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for period 2020/009</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
