<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="pri-activities" dstore:index="7" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-17T10:53:45+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-17T10:10:37+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-04154075-GB-COH-04154075-PRI-007</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-04154075" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PENAL REFORM INTERNATIONAL</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance the capacity of Female Police in Yemen: Mainstreaming a gender-based approach within the law enforcement</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Introduction Nov. 2018 - October 2019: 
On November 2018, a contract (reference No. AVT16/BZ120646A) was signed between the state of the Netherlands, represented by HE the Minister for Foreign Trade and Development, legally represented by HE the Ambassador to Yemen and Penal Reform International. To implement a project titled &#x201C;Enhance the capacity of Female Police in Yemen: Mainstreaming a gender-based approach within the law enforcement&#x201D;. The project overall goal is to Enhance peace and security efforts in Yemen through building the capacity of the female police unit at the MoI. Through achieving the following outcomes. 1) 700 female police officers in the female police unit are better able to maintain law and order according to human rights standards and rules of administration of justice. 2) A gender sensitive approach in the work of MoI is mainstreamed through improved safeguards for female police officers. 3) Barriers to women reporting crimes are removed. 4) Improved international standards and best practice in ensuring equal opportunities for women in the police force. The target groups of this project are MoI, 700 female police officers that were hired in the South, the Police Academy. While the final beneficiaries of the project are: society at large in Yemen, with a focus on vulnerable groups including women, children, marginlised groups. To achieve the overall goal and the specific results of the project, PRI worked closely with relevant governmental stakeholders including (MoI, female police unit under the family protection department at MoI). &#x201C; MoI- PRI MoU governing the project implementation&#x201D; PRI has a strong partnership with the MoI and our contact person for the project from MoI side is the Deputy Minister, colonel Ali Al-Aksha, who provides full support to the project content and activities. This working relation was governed by the project theory of change outlined below in Figure No.1. which illustrates how the sequence of events, activities and interventions taken within the course of the project, are expected to contribute achieving the project goal. The theory of change is reviewed regularly in light of the political changes and local context with the aim of reviewing its validity and viability to reach the project outcomes. Up till the end of the first year, it still valid and achievable despite political challenges. The report will be divided into two sections, section I Project Problem Statements and Political Overview, and Section II Achievements of Project Results and Activities. Section I: Problem Statement and Political Overview: This section will include a brief account of the political situation in Yemen; it shows the degree to which those political conditions have affected the project implementation. Since the war started in 2015, the political and security situation in Yemen continued to be a major challenge for the criminal justice system. The ongoing instability in Aden and the southern governorates, and the clashes led by different groups including Al-Qaeda, and the Southern separation council against the official government, caused a challenge and slowed the implementation of the project activities. But despite that, the MoI continued to express the full political support for the project and its objectives, and the determination to deploy female police to serve in several locations with the aim of facilitating justice access and enhancing the access of females to the police and the justice system. A closer scene of the political situation in Yemen during the current reporting period showed a very volatile and unpredictable situation due to the on-going active armed conflict in the country. During this period, political campaigns were seeking to resolve the internal conflict which lasted for the past five years. Those political campaigns have created tensions which eventually turned into intermittent armed clashes, long and short-term interference, moreover leading to creation of active frontlines. PRI interventions were designed to target the Southern region, which over the past months has remained a point of focus, most of its governorates were relatively calm, but very uncertain due to the various spread of armed actors representing various political angles with different agendas. Although the numbers of incidents have gradually decreased, acts of terrorism remain very high, and the threat is still assessed as extreme due to the presence of Al-Qaeda in Arabic Peninsula and IS operatives. Other threats related to the on-going armed conflict continue to hinder a lot of operations in the south region and the country as a whole. Politically, both the International Recognized Government (IRG)and Southern Transitional Council (STC) made progress during the period by signing a Southern Peace Agreement (commonly referred as Riyadh Agreement). The agreement was set on the 5th of November 2019, where both parties &#x2013; IRG and STC agreed on the framework, therefore to end the tensions between the two actors. On the onset of the agreement, both stakeholders formed integrated committees to release the control on military camps and other government facilities that are currently under the Southern Transitional Council (STC) control. Despite the formation of the committee&#x2019;s members from both parties, the implementation of this agreement is very slow, and nothing significant has taken place on the ground, despite the committee presence and both parties&#x2019; commitment. This has a direct impact on one component of the project, that is related to the location of the female police Academy. Since the building that was chosen by the MoI to be the location of the academy still under the control of the STC, and not yet handed to the Ministry of interior , which resulted in slowing the process of establishing the physical logistical building of the Academy. PRI was informed by the MoI to wait till April 2020 to solve this issue. Otherwise, a new building that is in Hadhramaut might be chosen. However, we do prefer to keep the location in Aden, for the academy to be closer to the MoI, taking into consideration that the majority of recruited female officers are in Aden, the temporary capital. Which on the long term will have an impact on making the decision for joining the police force easier for women who for social reasons prefer not to travel between governorates alone. In conclusion, the tensions continue to hinder a lot of operations in the country; due to the bureaucratic impediments from various actors. The absence of the International Recognized Government (IRG) in the South &#x2013; and particularly in Aden Governorate which serves as the interim capital city of IRG, has led to the closure of several Ministries including the Ministry of Interior. During the current reporting period, a positive and negative effect were noticed in the key two institutions in the current project represented by the Ministry of Interior-(MoI) and the Women Police as follows: &#xF0D8; Ministry of Interior Situation: Tense security situation, which increased in August 2019, between the International Recognized Government (IRG) and the southern Transitional Council (STC) has led to the closure of several line Ministries including the Ministry of Interior. On the 5th of November 2019, both Government (IRG)and Southern Transitional Council (STC) made progress by signing Southern Peace Agreement (commonly referred as Riyadh Agreement) therefore to end the tensions between the two actors. Integrated committee formed to oversee the handing over of the military camps and other government facilities that are currently under the control of Southern Transitional Council (STC). This committee faced challenges to make progress on the ground. The above situation and the absence of the Ministry of Interior decision-makers which led to slower coordination mechanisms with the government and caused delay in some activities&#x2019; implementation like Female Police Academy rehabilitation work. &#xF0D8; Female Police Situation in Yemen: After signing Riyadh Agreement, life started back normally on the ground, and Female Police started going back to their workplaces where they are employed like the airport, migration offices, Prisons, coastguard &#x2026; Before the war and according to official records of the MoI before 2015, Women constituted 1.7 % of police forces, with the total number of 2868 female officers. Women started joining the police forces in 2001 after graduation from the Police Academy in Yemen. When the first group of officers graduated, they were sent to serve at all locations, similar to their male colleagues. However, as Yemen is a very conservative society and security forces are controlled by male attitudes, policewomen faced several levels of harassment and discrimination that led many of them to leave the service and stay at home. Consequently, the figures above do not reflect the real representation of women within the police force. In 2017 the numbers of female police in Aden increased to 300 female police officers. Another registration happened during 2018 were the 700 female police officers has been registered so the total number now is 1000 female police. Those females are working now in Aden in Several government places , female police working in 23 police station in all Aden districts, in , Migration Directorate, Prison Directorate, coastguard and Airport. Challenges faced by policewomen in Yemen: Female police officers in Yemen face many challenges that are rooted in prejudice regarding distinctions between genders. Gender discrimination and harassment (sexual and verbal) of female police officers along with continued displays of negative attitudes by male police officers led to many women leaving the police forces. In addition to male negative attitudes, female police officers still face &#x201C;barriers&#x201D; that hinder their career advancement opportunities within the organization. These include discriminatory policies, a management that does not believe in their role, barriers to their career development path, and equipment and facilities&#x2019; inadequacies--including material conditions at work &#x2013; for example, locker rooms, changing facilities, lavatories . . . Additionally, policewomen face a number of other social problems that are inherent in the larger society. These include family responsibilities, role strain and role conflict, doubts about competence and self-worth, sexual harassment, and a concomitant fear of complaining about abuse. The current project is working in partnership with MoI senior management to eliminate and reduce the effect of these challenges. The first step in achieving this was done during the first six months, through creating a structure within MOI ( female Police Unit) that is assigned the task of managing this force based on international standards, and with a clear framework that sets out their duties; including the development of terms of reference (TORs) that clarify their work at various levels and locations. With the aim of creating an encouraging working environment for the 700 newly hired women police officers, enabling them to deliver their work effectively, and with dignity and pride. It is expected that the added value of the Female police unit will be, promoting gender equality within police forces, enabling women&#x2019;s access to justice / protecting women&#x2019;s rights during conflict and post conflict periods and effective response to Gender based Violence.&#x2003; 




I. Introduction Nov. 2019 - Apr. 2020: 

On November 2018, a contract (reference No. AVT16/BZ120646A) was signed between the state of Netherlands, represented by the Minister for Foreign Trade and Development, legally represented by the Ambassador to Yemen and Penal Reform International. To implement a project titled &#x201C;Enhance the capacity of Female Police in Yemen: Mainstreaming a gender-based approach within the law enforcement&#x201D;. 
The project overall goal is to Enhance peace and security efforts in Yemen through building the capacity of the female police unit at the MOI.
Through achieving the following outcomes.   
1)	Female police officers in the female police unit are better able to maintain law and order according to human rights standards and rules of administration of justice. 
2)	A gender sensitive approach in the work of MoI is mainstreamed through improved safeguards for female police officers &#x2013;(For the management of the female
3)	Barriers to women reporting crimes are removed
4)	Improved international standards and best practice in ensuring equal opportunities for women in the police force

The target groups of this project areMOI, 700 female police officers that were hired in the South, the Police Academy. While the  final beneficiaries of the project are: society at large in Yemen, with a focus on vulnerable groups including women, children,  marganlised groups. 
To achieve the overall goal and the specific results of the project, PRI worked closely with relevant governmental stakeholders including (MOI, female police unit under the family protection department at MOI) PRI has a strong partnership with the MOI and our contact person for the project from MOI side is the Deputy Minister, colonel Ali Al-Aksha, who provide full support to the project work.  This working relation was governed by project theory of change outlined below in Figure No.1.  which illustrates how the sequence of events, activities and interventions taken within the course of the project, are expected to contribute to achieving the project goal.    
The report will be divided into two sections, section I Project Problem Statements and Political Overview, and Section II Achievements of Project Results and Activities. 
Section I: Problem Statement and Political Overview:
This section will include a brief account of the political situation in Yemen; it shows the degree to which those political conditions have affected the project implementation.
Since the war started in 2015, the political and security situation in Yemen continued to be a major challenge for the criminal justice system. The ongoing instability in Aden and the southern governorates, and the clashes led by different groups including Al-Qadeh, and the Southern separation council against the official government. Caused a challenge and slow down the implementation of the project activities.  But despite that the MOI continued to express their full political support for the project and its objective and their determination to deploy female police to serve in several location with aim of facilitating justice and enhancing the access of females to the police and the justice system.  

A closer scene of the political situation in Yemen during the current reporting period showed a very volatile and unpredictable situation due to the active armed conflict and clashes between the international recognized government (IRG) and the transitional council (TC) The clashes have started on March 2020 and continued till Ramadan holy month. On the same period, natural disasters have encountered the country, heavy rains and flooding which started in mid-April continued across the country. Flooding has damaged roads, bridges and the electricity grid, and contaminated water supplies, cutting access to basic services for thousands of people. In Sana&#x2019;a, flooding caused widespread disruption to services as the city was overwhelmed by floodwaters. In Aden, power cuts have continued since the floods of 21 April. There is heightened risk of diseases such as malaria and cholera. 

Similar to other countries around the world, Yemen has been suffering from the impact of COVID-19 during the reporting period yet with a magnified effect or impact, due to the effect of the war on the Yemeni health system, as since five years of war has shattered the country&apos;s health system, leaving it incapable of coping with a pandemic. Many of Yemen&apos;s medical facilities have been damaged or destroyed in air strikes, and only half are thought to be fully functioning. Clinics are reported to be crowded, and basic medicines and equipment are lacking - in a country of 27.5 million people there are only a few hundred ventilator machines. COVID has also an impact on slowing down the work, were the work on renovating the police academy had to stop due to the pandemic and the lockdown forced by the authorities, training workshops had to be suspended till the lockdown is left. 

Challenges faced by policewomen in Yemen: 
Per PRI&#x2019;s Interviews with the female police officers enrolled in the PRI capacity building interventions that took place during the first year of the project,  the female officers have expressed that they have experienced many setbacks because of the lack of training due to the lack of resources given to them, and as Yemen is a conservative society,  they didn&#x2019;t give much attention, or chances to the fact that woman police needed continuous training, the need to expand their resources through enrolment and through on ground practical training, and theoretical knowledge which would help them to increase their expertise and increase their ranks to be leaders in the police forces . The need for the police academy to be built and maintained at high expectations is a need to compensate for the lack of experience and knowledge that the women police force needed. Some Officers felt left out long time ago, and felt that they were not given the equal right of men to perform their tasks, and duties, yet they remain excited, and eager to earn knowledge, and gain experience to enable them to perform at their highest capabilities in order to serve their country, and their cause. The trainings organized by PRI as part of this project did give them a good head start, but the continues need for extra knowledge and training skills is still an obstacle due to the lack of resources.
 

Theory of change 
The project theory of change was affected by the political, natural disinters and the impact of COVID-19, and some changes needs were introduced at the outcomes level to response to that. The original plan was that the project target the all of the 700 police officers, however, due to the delays in finalizing the academy that was impacted by the ongoing conflict and the division at the government level in Aden, the floods and the COVID-19. All of the 700 officers will not be able to benefit from the training before the end of the project, it is expected that the project will be able to target around 400 officers, only at this phase. While the training of the rest of the officers can be resumed during 2021. However, it should be mentioned that due to the difficult financial situation that the government in Aden is facing, more financial support will be needed till the academy is able to function smoothly and based on annual plan. The logic behind the theory of change is still valid and follow the logic and the project approach that was chosen when the project started. It worth to mention that the project team have a process of continuous revision of the theory of change and the risks on the ground and acted on adopting mitigating factors that aimed at reducing these risks to be able to achieve the results of the project and its outcomes. However, the political situation and all the delays were beyond PRI control.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project final beneficiaries: The final beneficiaries of the project are: society at large in Yemen, with a focus on vulnerable groups including women, children, marginalized groups. Direct beneficiaries: are MOI, 700 female police officers that were hired in the South, the Police Academy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Goal and Achievements of Project Results and Activities Nov. 2018 - October 2019:
 The project aims at achieving the following goal: enhance peace and security efforts in Yemen through building the capacity of the female police unit at the MOI. During the reporting period this goal was the major message that was used to promote the establishment of the Women police unit and the academy. In all the correspondence with the Yemeni authorities, PRI stressed on the importance that the female police will play a major role in terms of securing peace and security in Yemen. A goal that was welcomed by the Yemeni MOI who confirmed their willingness to work towards achieving the project goal. The indicators for this goal by their nature can&#x2019;t be assessed at this stage of the project life, measuring these indicators will be only possible once the female officers are deployed to their duty stations. Goal indictor NO.1: Percentage of the public reporting feeling safer since the introduction of the female police unit Goal indictor NO.2: Percentage of the public who are satisfied with the work of the female police unit and its contribution towards peace and security efforts. II.II Project outcomes: While the outcomes identified by the project, are considered a work in progress, at this stage we can report about the outputs. A detailed report about the outcomes can be done once all the outputs are achieved in the upcoming report. 1. 700 female police officers in the female police unit are better able to maintain law and order according to human rights standards and rules of administration of justice. 2. A gender sensitive approach in the work of MoI is mainstreamed through improved safeguards for female police officers 3. Barriers to women reporting crimes are removed 4. Improved international standards and best practice in ensuring equal opportunities for women in the police force II.III project outputs: Output 1.1: Structure of the female police unit developed and meets the needs of the unit and allows officers to properly respond to the security situation across Yemen This output was achieved during the reporting period, under this activity. PRI developed the mandate of the Female Police Academy; as a development of a clear structure of the Female Police Academy in Yemen was achieved, kindly see figure No.2 below which included the Academy vision and mission, institutional values, objectives, organizational structure entailing job descriptions for each post which defines roles and responsibilities, duties that should be delivered by the female officers according to the different locations to which they will be assigned along the line of authorities and management. Also, a manual of procedures and mechanisms was developed for the internal management of the academy A roundtable was organized in Malaysia on February 17 &amp; 18, 2019, that was attended by 17 participants, who represent the top management of the MOI MoI, including the head of the female police unit. the roundtable discussed the role expected from the female police unit and discussed in details, how the unit should be functioning and secured in securing the top political will for the unit, including the full support for the unit from the Human Rights Minister who attended the roundtable and highlighted the value of the unit to secure more protection for the rights of Yemeni women when they come in contact with the law. The Output indictor, identified to measure the progress on this activity was fully achieve &#x2018;Extent to which job descriptions properly define roles and duties of female police officers depending on location, assignment and rank&#x201D;. Output 1.2: Draft training plan for female police unit adopted by the Yemen Police Academy During the reporting period PRI approached the Dutch police Academy to provide technical support in developing the training plan and be involved in the training process. However, the Dutch police Academy declined the request and informed PRI that by their law they can&#x2019;t cooperate with NGOs. So, PRI had to look for other options, the Swedish police academy was approached, and PRI never heard an official reply from them. As a result, PRI approached the Jordanian public security department who welcomed cooperation and started working with PRI on developing the training plan and agreed to provide training for the Yemeni female police at the Royal police Academy and female police Academy. &#x201D;. As outlined in the training plan. Female police officers will receive a one-month training at the police academy in Jordan that includes field work, as traffic police, at the family protection department and at the investigation crime department. It is anticipated that this training will give all the essential and needed skills for the officers to go back to Yemen able to share and train other fellow colleagues on what they received in Jordan. It should be mentioned that an MoU for cooperation is at the prime minister office in Jordan wating to be signed and approved by the ministerial council. After the signing of the MoU the training will start immediately. Before developing the plan with the police in Jordan and to be able to identify the needs and map the capacity that exists within the team of officers who will be assigned the task of providing the training at the academy in Yemen , PRI organized in Malaysia during October 2019 ,two workshops which mainly discussed the priorities and necessities of the female police in Yemen, and analysed the officers needs and capacities, with the participation of the head of training department at the Jordanian police and the head of the female police force in Jordan. As a result of those workshops the training plan was developed to adapt with the needs of the females police officers with the representation of the senior commanders of the Yemeni Ministry of Interior and the Female Police Unit as well as Jordanian independent expertise. A participatory approach between the direct beneficiaries of the training plan-(Yemeni female police officers) as well as their senior commanders-(Mr. Ali Naser Lakhsha from the MoI and the Head of the Female Police Unit), with the Jordanian expertise-( Director of Police Training Department in Jordan , Women Police Department Head in Jordon)which will be representing the supply side of the delivery of the trainings. This approach adopted for the development of the training plan was an essential method, to ensure a demand based and a structured process during the development of the training plan, as a result this will affect the success during trainings implementation and delivery. The training plan includes two sections: the first is general training courses of all female police officers, which includes all the basic skills in policing as it takes into account the latest trends in international standards adopted in the police sciences. The second is specialized training courses established for the top management of the academy that focus on how to run the academy and deliver their work. The training plan will be covering topics related to policing work standards, management skills, communications skills. Other specialized topics such as Criminal Investigation, community policing, Criminal Intelligence, specialised courses for women police forces. Output1.3: Training courses developed for the Yemen Police Academy PRI started the work to develop the teaching courses for the Police Academy in Yemen to be used by them in delivering the training for the officers. The teaching courses will include: Criminal Law, Patrol Procedures, investigative procedures, Report Writing, Defensive Tactics, Leadership, Ethics, Community Policing, Police, Vehicle Operations, Traffic Enforcement, Accident Investigation, Handling Emotional Situations and First Aid/CPR, GBV investigation, dealing with crimes of human trafficking and crimes of exploitation. These will guarantee the ability of the unit to deliver its work on the ground. Output 1.4: Female officers and trainers at the police academy are trained on and able to deliver a variety of courses dealing with gender specific issues for female recruits via a Training of Trainers (ToT) The TOT workshops were not delivered yet. However; two of the specialized training workshops were implemented in Malaysia in October 2019. Under this output we are providing more information and analysis of the two workshops and the findings that resulted from the assessment of the female officers needs and capacities, their educational level, their level of knowledge of the policing work. That are outlined as follow; The first workshop was organized on October 23rd -25th of 2019 and attended by twenty participants (13 Female &amp; 7 Male) representing the police officers in Yemen. The launching of this workshop was under the patronage of the vice minister of Interior in Yemen and Yemen Ambassador to Malaysia, Jordanian experts and trainers as well as representatives from the Women Police Department and Director of Police Training Department in Jordan, in order to benefit from the Jordanian expertise in strengthening the women police officers capabilities in Yemen. The workshop discussed the priorities and necessities of the Female&#x2019;s police in Yemen including the following topics: &#x2022; Women police work ethics &#x2022; Girls and women in detention (police, prisons and insurance requirements). &#x2022; Treatment standards for girls and women who come in contact with the law enforcement agencies. &#x2022; Protection measures for girls and women in detention (treatment of girls and women in prison, and protection requirements). &#x2022; Alternatives to detention. &#x2022; The current situation of Women&apos;s Police in Yemen challenges and needs. The second workshop was organized in Malaysia between the 27th -29th of October 2019 and attended by twenty participants (13 Female &amp; 7 Male) representing police in Yemen. The launching of this workshop was under the patronage of the vice minister of Interior in Yemen and Yemen Ambassador to Malaysia. The workshop aimed at providing the participants with the knowledge and mechanisms related to empowering and strengthening the role of the female&apos;s police work in Yemen and mainstreaming gender aspects. The main topics which were discussed during the three days workshop were: &#x2022; Mechanisms for dealing with violence cases and abuse against girls and women (domestic violence, protection measures during police procedures). &#x2022; Mechanisms for enhancing women&apos;s police work in Yemen and gender mainstreaming. &#x2022; The importance of integrating female police officers into the police work (current difficulties and strengthening opportunities). &#x2022; The use of force in the women police work. &#x2022; Investigation techniques with women and girls who come in contact with law. &#x2022; Basics of arresting and inspecting techniques of women in police procedures (the current situation and strengthening opportunities for the purpose of protecting women and girls during the riots procedures and search). The targeted audience chosen for both workshops were police officers who have elementary to mid-level expertise in the policing sector as well as holding higher educational degrees in order to build their capabilities in a series of trainings until we reach a Training of Trainers to equip them with the needed skills of being a trainer. PRI have targeted in the following training, Police officers who are in a junior to mid-level roles mainly clustered around female police officers who have experience between (1-5) years as 56% lies in this category , 6% with (5 to 10) years of experience contributing to 62% of the trainees in the junior-mid level, the minority of the trainees are of senior level. The majority of the trainees hold bachelor&#x2019;s or Masters Degrees contributing to a total of 95% of the trainees, only 5% of the trainees holds a diploma degree. 65% Trainees Profile Desegregated by Sex 35% PRI have integrated Men and women in the same training for two main purposes: 1) Males colleagues have certain capabilities and skills related to the operations such as arresting and searching techniques which their females colleagues will benefit from. 2) Male colleagues will start to observe the challenges that their females counterparts are facing and what are the barriers that they face in order to be deployed .As a result, the male counterparts attitudes of the non-acceptance of the importance of the female officers will start to shift positively and the male police officers will be the gender champions for their females colleagues. Also, it was observed that 61% of the trainees in both workshops have not been enrolled into the police academy nor graduated from it, only 39% of the total participants have joined the police academy and graduate when the academy was functioning at Sanaa According to the baseline survey distributed in the beginning of the two workshops, it is noticed that around half of the trainees-exactly a percentage of 47 were not enrolled into trainings related for police work before, and this is the first time they were introduced to such trainings, where a 53% have took some trainings before. A Baseline Survey was distributed on the trainees to assess the following dimensions: 1) Workplace Does Workplace Satisfy female police officers&#x2019; needs? According to the surveyed sample, the response results were 1:1 ratio of satisfied versus not satisfied of workplace conditions-in other words 50% of the respondents believes that the workplace is not suitable and does not satisfy their needs and the other 50% believes that the workplace does satisfies their needs. 2) Procedures and polices Do you perceive that the current procedures and policies are gender sensitive -? According to the surveyed sample, 1:1 ratio believes that both of the procedures and policies are gender sensitive versus aren&#x2019;t gender sensitive &#x2013;in other words 50% of the respondents believe that procedures and policies are not gender sensitive and the other 50% believes that they are gender sensitive. 3) Senior Management Role in Promoting the importance of integrating police females&#x2019; officers Phrase Yes No I have full knowledge of international human rights standards. 13% 87% I have the potential to apply international human rights standards. 17% 83% I have full knowledge of the standards of women&apos;s policing and gender aspects. 15% 85% I have the potential to apply the standards of women&#x2019;s policing and gender sensitive aspects 25% 75% Women&apos;s police officers play a useful role in promoting gender sensitive treatment 40% 60% I have a full knowledge of the ethics of policing, and the principles for the treatment of women who come in contact with the police. 22% 78% I have the potential to apply policing ethics, and to apply the principles for the treatment of women who come in contact with the police. 44% 56% 63% of the respondents believe that role of senior management is poor or does not exist at all, and 37% believes that the senior management have an effective role. Also, the Baseline assessment survey served as a tool to assess the trainees&#x2019; knowledge, those results will be vital to be integrated in the designing and planning phase for developing the training curricula for the Academy. Main findings of the baseline assessment are summarized in the table below-for more details. The results of the baseline assessment ensure the need for the implementation of the current project, which is to strengthen the capabilities of the female police officers through having a female police unit and Academy to deliver a set of specialized trainings. As noticed from the results in the above table, the majority of the females lack the basic knowledge of the main principles of the policing work. A pre and post training assessment was conducted for the trainees in order to assess the degree of change in the level of the learning gain by using different set of questions: Trainees were asked to assess their agreement with a set of concepts and beliefs related to human rights and international standards of treating females who come in contact with the law on a Likert scale The results show an average learning gain equal to (+) 24 % were perceived, the following formula was used to compute the learning gain value: Learning Gain Formula= (Post test Score-Pre-Test Score)/ (Maximum Score-Pre-test Score) Also, a satisfactory survey was distributed to ensure the quality of the service delivered for the trainees which contributes to the success of the training delivery , three main dimensions were assessed as follows: Dimension Training Material and Content Training Facilities- (Venue and Equipment) Trainer Performance 86% 95% 96% Average 92.3% The overall satisfaction rate was computed using the following Equation: Overall Satisfaction Rate= (Weighting Factor * Training Material and Content Satisfaction Score) + (Weighting Factor * Training Facilities Satisfaction Score) + (Weighting Factor *Trainer Performance Satisfaction Score) 0.923 = (0.33*0.86) +(0.33*0.95) +(0.33*0.96) Likert Scale Key-(4 Scale) 1 Very low performance 2 Good performance 3 Very good performance 4 Excellent performance Also, an anecdotal evidence was gathered from the trainees and their senior commander (Head of the female Police Unit) with regards to the following domain of change: &#xF0D8; Change in attitudes and confidence of participants The trainees were asked a set of questions to assess the above-mentioned domain of change as follows: 1) To what extent do you feel you are willing and able to be deployed as a member of the female police officers? A sample of the trainees&#x2019; responses were as follows: Head of the female Police Unit response 2) To what extent do you feel you have the skills / knowledge to be deployed as a member of the female police officers? A sample of the trainees&#x2019; responses were as follows: Head of the female Police Unit response 3) Also, the trainees were asked about their senior commanders&#x2019; attitudes towards them in the ability and readiness for deployment as follows: What do your immediate senior commanders feel about you being ready for deployment? The sample taken agreed that their senior commanders are supportive and encourage the female police officers&#x2019; deployments. PRI have also asked the female police officers senior commander- (Head of the female Police Unit ) about her feelings; response is as follows: Certainly, managers encourage women police officers, and seeks to enroll them into trainings which will enable the female police officers to be deployed actively in police work and to deliver the work/operations in a better manner. Yet, in return, managers have a crucial role in building the capabilities of their employees through providing the needed support, including support from senior management of the Ministry of Interior, this will contribute to the enhancement of the policewomen performance. 4) Have there been any other developments &#x2013; positive or negative &#x2013; as a result of your participation in the trainings delivered in Malaysia? A sample of the trainees&#x2019; responses were as follows: They agreed that the workshop delivered by PRI gave the female police officers skills and knowledge which they get for the first time. All of them declared they need more workshops in different topics. Head of the female Police Unit response The positive change brought beyond the training is very clear through the improved performance of police officers in their work facilities. Female police officers became more enthusiastic: We hope that there will be further trainings for the rest of the females working in the women&apos;s police. We also wish to expand in the field of exchanging experiences with other countries that have preceded Yemen in the matter of women&apos;s police and the nature of its work. This will increase the capacity of female police officers and improve their performance. How does the Trainees Feel with regards to the workshops? Different quotes were gathered from the direct beneficiaries a sample of those quotes are as follows: 1. This workshop had a great positive impact, and during the training days I learned new skills such as arrest, search and women&apos;s police role. 2. Through this workshop I learned about the experience of women&apos;s police in Jordan, and I am excited to pass this experience on to my colleagues in Yemen. 3. I have benefited a lot from this course but I still need more to build my capacity in the various fields of women&apos;s police work. 4. The exchange of experiences and skills in this course has had a great impact in building my capacity. 5. I can return to my work facility now and I am aware of many international treaties and laws on the preservation of the dignity of women accused and convicted in prisons. The Head of the female Police Unit declared the following: Certainly the training has contributed to raising the capacity of female police officers and improving performance in their workplaces, but women police officers need a longer training periods (e.g. three months in a row) to gain deep training experience. Training for 3 days and 3 other days gives broad lines and concepts. Yet long-term training of up to three months will give more benefit in the long run.&quot; Output 2.1: Technical support is provided to the police unit to support mainstreaming of gender into the MoI. During the reporting period a gender expert was hired to draft the policy on how gender should be mainstreamed at the MoI work, structure, procedures and services. And she started the process on doing desk research, one to one interview and drafting the policy. However, up till the reporting period the policy was not approved by the MoI yet. However. Several advocacy meetings to promote the policy and gender mainstream within the MoI was organized, including the following; 1. May 2019, Coordination Meeting with the Vice Minister of the Interior to discuss project activities and coordination with the MoI, and the plan to deploy women officers. 2. June 2019 Coordination meeting with the General Director of Training in the MoI and Head of Female Police to discuss the criteria of participants of the ToT Training, their backgrounds, skills and the roles that they will be assigned in managing the academy. 3. June 2019, Meeting with the General Director of Training in the MoI and Head of Female Police to approve the participants list and review applications and approve the structure and the tasks of each trainee. 4. July 2019, Meeting with the Vice Minister of the Interior to discuss rehabilitation of the Female Police Academy to discuss the gender policy and the guidelines for work. The documents were submitted to the minister for approval after their amendment in line with the vice minster comments and feedback. 5. July 2019, Meeting with the General Director of Training in the MoI and Head of Female Police for arranging the workshop&#x201D; Priorities, necessities and policies of women&apos;s police work in Yemen&#x201D; which targeted 20 participants from the Female police in Yemen. 6. Aug 2019, meeting with the MoI to starting in the technical study of Female Police Academy. Output2.2: Improved infrastructure of the unit and training locations for female police officers During the reporting period the work started on finding a location for the unit and the academy, however, this process was a major challenge for the project due to the conflict. A number of locations were identified, and a committee was organized by the MoI and PRI to assess these locations. However, for security reasons many of these locations were excluded, and the other locations were excluded because they are completely destroyed and need more money for their renovation than what is included in the budget. Based on the committee report, PRI approached the deputy minister of interior to identify other locations that are suitable. PRI team have conducted a mutual meeting with all the MoI, family protection directorate and the women policing department representatives to agree on the required rehabilitation needs and technical constructive aspects. This meeting was held by the management teams of both parties and technical expertise represented by a construction engineer from PRI side and another construction engineer from the Yemeni side, according to this meeting the specifications of the proposal were drafted and PRI issued two procurements as follows: 1) A call for procurement for infrastructure work of the female police academy to be conducted in Aden was released on August 2019 in the official newspaper, the total number of bids received were 10. 2) A call for procurement for the infrastructure work of the female police unit in the MoI to be conducted in Aden was released in July 2019 in the official newspapers, Three bids were received and an internal committee have evaluated the bids. The bid was awarded for a construction company which have started the designing work and provided PRI with a proposed sketch of the renovation work to be done Output 3.1: The role of the unit is promoted, and the public is informed of its mandate and roles During the reporting period noting was achieved under this output, since its linked to achieving the other outputs of the project. Output 4.1 Dissemination of the lessons learnt and good practice from the project at an international level Nothing was achieved under this activity yet. 


Section II. Achievements of Project Results and Activities, Nov. 2019 - Apr. 2020: 


II.I Overall Goal 
The project aims at achieving the following goal, enhance peace and security efforts in Yemen through building the capacity of the female police unit at the MOI. During the reporting period this goal was the major massage that was used to promote the establishment of the Women police unit and the academy. In all it correspondence with the Yemeni authorities, PRI stressed on the importance that the female police will play in terms of securing peace and security in Yemen.  A goal that was welcomed by the Yemeni MOI who confirmed their willingness to work towards achieving the project goal. 
The indicators for this goal by their nature can&#x2019;t be assessed at this stage of the project life, measuring these indicators will be only possible once the female officers are deployed to their duty stations. Noting that at this stage some of the police officers were deployed to work at the prison department and other locations and they received training from PRI as part of this project to enhance their skills and needed knowledge that will enable them to do their jobs as outlined below. 
Goal indictor NO.1:  Percentage of the public reporting feeling safer since the introduction of the female police unit
Goal indictor NO.2: Percentage of the public who are satisfied with the work of the female police unit and its contribution towards peace and security efforts.
At the end of the project a survey will be conducted in the locations that have female officers to assess the impact and the general public views about their involvement to be able to respond to the success in reaching these indicators  
II.II Project outcomes: 
While the outcomes identified by the project, are considered a work in progress, at this stage we can report about the outputs. While a detailed report about the outcomes can be done once all the outputs are achieved.
1.	Female police officers in the female police unit are better able to maintain law and order according to human rights standards and rules of administration of justice. 
2.	A gender sensitive approach in the work of MoI is mainstreamed through improved safeguards for female police officers.
3.	Barriers to women reporting crimes are removed.
4.	Improved international standards and best practice in ensuring equal opportunities for women in the police force.
II.III project outputs:
Output 1.1: Structure of the female police unit developed which meets the needs of the unit and allows officers to properly respond to the security situation across Yemen
PRI developed the mandate of the female police academy in the first year of the project  a clear structure of the female police academy in  Yemen was  developed, the structure of the academy  includes each of the academy&#x2019;s vision, mission, and institutional values, along the key objectives. Also the academy&#x2019;s organizational structure was developed, for the purpose of defining the arrangement of interaction between resources, people and tasks within the academy. The organizational structure is represented in the form of a chart, with roles, titles and positions listed in a cascading fashion. In additions to that , job descriptions  for each post was developed defining the roles and responsibilities, duties that should be delivered by the female officers according to the different locations to which they will be assigned ,with the  responding  line of authorities and management. Also, a manual of standards of procedures and mechanisms was developed for the internal management of the academy- to ensure that the female police officers will be able to  carry out their  jobs ,according to a standardizes mechanisms.
Output 1.2: Draft training plan for female police unit adopted by the Yemen Police Academy
During the first year of the project  PRI approached the Dutch police Academy to provide technical support in developing the training plan and be involved in the training process. However, the Dutch police Academy declined the request and informed PRI that by their law they can&#x2019;t cooperate with NGOs. So, PRI had to look for other option, were the Swedish police academy was approached and PRI never heard from them. As a result, PRI approached the Jordanian public security directorate who welcomed cooperation and started working with PRI on developing the training plan and agreed to provide training for the Yemeni female police at the Royal police Academy and female police Academy. An MOU was signed to start that training in March. However, due to the COVID and the lockdown in Jordan that training was postponed to take place in October 2020

Output1.3: Training courses developed for the Yemen Police Academy
PRI have been working on developing the training courses during the reporting, 11 Training courses were developed during the reporting period, One Basic Introductory course and 10 specialized training courses a brief of the elven training courses developed are listed below, the training materials were in the process of revision by the MOI. 
Foundational Course for preparing the trainers 
The foundational course was developed to equip the female police officers with the required set of skills to be able to become trainers and deliver the required set of trainings for the female police officers, as the trainers is expected to deliver a set of trainings in an organized and planned effort to develop the knowledge, experience and attitudes of the trainees by making them more effective in carrying out their tasks. The  Foundational Curricula is focusing on equipping the trainer with the needed  training dynamic to bring about changes in information, experiences, and attitudes of the trainees in order to enable them to take advantage of their potentials and which helps to raise the efficiency in the practice of their work in a regular manner and high productivity . It is also a continuous process centred on the individuals as a whole that aims to bring about specific mental behaviour changes to meet current or future needs that the individuals require to perform the work need to be done.  The trainer is the base of the training and the first pillar of the success of the training process, which means any shortage or      deficiency in their knowledge or personal abilities or mental behaviour will negatively affect the result of the training process, Accordingly the basic foundational curricula is of a great asset for having a solid foundation for the personal who are nominated to become trainers. 
 Working on Borders, and Foreigners Affairs Course 
 This course is intended to equip the female police officers with the needed knowledge for dealing with citizens across borders including foreigners affairs regulations,  This course It is evident that each state has its own law in regulating the entry, and residence of foreigners on its territory, but it is known that the movement of foreigner&#x2019;s entry, or exit of any country must be characterized by adequate legal, and administrative regulation to facilitate the movement of people between countries, which means that the states commit to join through treaties and conventions to regulate the movement and residence of foreigners in any country. Therefor in this  curse, a presentation of the most important aspects in international agreements governing the security of land, sear, and air borders, and then the general rules for organizing foreigner&#x2019;s residency before we detail the provisions of Yemen law No. 47 of 1991 regarding entry and residence of foreigner&#x2019;s  for the female police officers. 
Security Media Course 
The following course will equip the female police officers with the main content of the role of media, where media plays a vital role in influencing the various fields of life, as security is influenced by the media. The course is designed according to the philosophy of the relationship between the media and Security. In this Course, the trainees will be introduced on how  media is based on addressing the feeling, and security is a feeling through which the individual feels safe and reassuring, so addressing this feeling through the media affects profound and rapid impact on security, this effect might be positive for the citizens to feel safe, secure, and give prestige, respect, and appreciation to the security personnel. The opposite would be creating a negative impact which does not serve security but leads to reduce the importance of the security services and showing them without their true appearance, which leads to disturbance and lack of confidence in the ability of the security services to achieve their goals. Therefore, the trainees will introduced to the importance for which the security services in the modern states had to enter into a positive relationship of cooperation and integration with the media in order to serve the human goals for which these agencies are working and to ensure that the media take advantage of information from their original sources from these agencies exaggerations that exceed the fact of events and cause fear and confusion among the society.
Community Police Foundational course
This course will highlight the importance of  balancing between the authority of the police, as police is one of the most prominent manifestation of power in the state, according to the development of the idea of the public authority referred to above as its concept evolved from the idea of the authority of the state, and that the authority is represented for applying the law to a community service to preserve the security of the individual and society in order to achieve its well-being and preserve the rights of public freedoms and the difference is vast and clear between those who believe that it is an authority on society and those who work for society as a servant of their security and stability ,therefore the current course will highlight that police have become in modern international trends providing a security service to the society and in this sense it is not as authority on society which means police individuals will be working for serving  the society according to the legalized frameworks within the police agency. 
Basics of Criminal Investigations Course 
This course is concerned to introduce the female police officers for what are the standardized best practices for Criminal Investigations ,as investigation is the realization of the truth, and it comes in the sense of searching for the truth, and it could be summarized as &#x201C;The set of legal procedures that the competent authority undertakes to discover the crime, and collect interferences that established the relationship between the crimes, and its perpetrators, arrest them, and present them to the public prosecution&#x201D;. In the current course an emphasis on the need of  the investigation procedures must be legitimate, and do not violate the law, that is the means of criminal investigation are not inconsistent with the principles of the law, and are difficult to confine to the continuous development, and renew scientific discoveries in this field.
Criminal Intelligence Foundation Course
In the current course, the female police officers will be introduced for the basics of the criminal Intelligence, as Intelligence training on criminal work needs to build accumulated knowledge, and skills which are foundation rules, and the basic skills that are built on in advanced courses, and will not be inclusive of all the skills, and knowledge of intelligence trainings. It is also necessary to indicate that the training material here is for criminal intelligence only, and it differs greatly from training in intelligence related to state security.
Special Operations
The special police units evolved in the early sixties, and increased its burdens, and duties to be responsible for combating terrorist acts, local and international organized crime. Special Operations teams are the striking force of major police operations, receive careful and special training, and have as many means, and weapons as they can in order to carry out their duties in the best manner possible, this will be depending on two main domains which are: 
1-	Force: Mostly in dangerous arrests, hostage release, and/ or VIP protection
2-	Speed: Such teams are distinguished by the speed of carrying out the duties assigned to them, as the first pillar of their work is to have the need attributes to deal with surprising events, and this requires Intelligence speedy responses. 
This course will serve as a foundational course, specialized topics such as advanced courses in marksmanship (especially sniper shooting), the use of explosives, and prevention of what is known in the science of security operations as &#x201C;fool traps&#x201D;.
Traffic Control Course 
In this course, the practical importance of the traffic police is the core, as police traffic officers are totally concerned with monitoring, and organizing road traffic, supervising, and achieving traffic safety. It is inconceivable that traffic officers will be law enforcers without training, and know the basics of the law, and traffic safety procedures, and rules.
Foundational Drug Control Course 
In the current course, the female police officers will be introduced on the main definition of drugs, as originally the drugs were unprescribed medications, and due to their psychological, physical, and mental effects, they became very popular, despite its dangerous, and deadly effect, and they are obtained illegally without the medical need for them, and without consulting a doctor, where the drug is called street medicine in some cases.
Also, the female officers will be introduced to the effects of the drugs, as the drugs have different, and unexpected effects, which may lead to the suffering of their users from serious health complications, especially among young people, and adolescents. These effects, and complications depend on several different factors, such as the amount, and type of drug used, the number of drugs used at the same time, the health status, weight of the user, and the situation in which the drugs were consumed.
Also they will be introduced to the legalized approaches for controlling drugs according to the Yemeni-law along the best international practices as drugs have many types, and are not limited to drugs only as they include other materials that are not used in legal ways such as inhaling paint materials, glue intentionally and in large quantities. 

Foundation Principles for Prisons Course 
The intellectual basics of modern theories in punishment is that the goal of punishment is reform, not punitive. The concept of punishment changed from deterrence, cruelty for inmates to attempting to reform, refine, and re-adapt to their community. The deprivation of liberty as a punishment was a goal itself. For this reason, prisons in the past were a place to achieve this goal, as they were adopted in a way that causes fear, depression, and the convicts were consigned to them without regard to the principles of classifications, as they were treated cruel. In the current course the female prison officers will be introduced for the international standards for dealing with prisoners according to human rights principles. 
Output 1.4: Female officers and trainers at the police academy are trained on and able to deliver a variety of courses dealing with gender specific issues for female recruits via a Training of Trainers (ToT)
A memorandum of understanding (MOU) was signed between Penal Reform Intranational and the Public Security Directorate in Jordan on March 2020, for the purpose of delivering  a set of training courses based on the training plan and training courses developed for a group of female police officers from the Republic of Yemen, who will be teaching the other officers at the academy in Yemen. 
It was supposed that the first training took place immediately after signing the agreement, but due to the COVID-19 the workshop was postponed. 

During the process of signing the MOU, PRI were sustaining a continuous communication channels, effort were done over the past months through several consultations with the MOI in Aden, represented by the Deputy Minister, Mr. Lakhsha and the head of female police unit, to agree on the time frame for delivering the remaining activities of the project and the feasibility for delivering them, in light of the ongoing conflict and COVID-19.PRI  had a couple of meetings with the head of the female police Unit in Jordan and the Head of training within the Police to discuss the possible time frame to proceed with the training of the Yemeni police at the Royal police academy and the female police training centre in Jordan. That was postponed due to the COVID-19 and the lockdown on travel.
It was agreed with the Police department in Jordan, that when the borders are open and the lockdown on travel is left. Two workshops will be organized each one of them is one month for the benefit of the selected group of Yemeni police officers who will manage the training at the police academy in Yemen. The Jordanian authorities pledged to priorities this and start the training immediately considering that the course have been designed and participants have been selected and agreed by the two parties MOI in Yemen and Jordanian police. PRI expect that the time frame for this will be between Mid-August after Eid holiday till Mid October. 

With regards to the specialized workshops; and during the reporting period a specialized training workshop for the benefit of the female police officers working at the prisons took place in Amman -  Jordan on March 2020; at the aim of  the role of female police in prison administration, the importance of gender-responsive treatment . 14 officers working in Yemeni prisons participated in this workshop, the workshop was carried out along three days from the 15th -17th of March 2020 

Several aspects were discussed such as women&apos;s police duties in prisons as well as guarantees for the protection of female prisoners, hygiene and health care for women prisoners and the role of the police women care for pregnant prisoners, mothers and children accompanying their mothers and girls in prisons. The role of female police in prisons in implementing effective programs for the rehabilitation of women and girls who are imprisoned, including psychological and social rehabilitation programs, as well as programs to prepare for life outside of prison for women prisoners.

Output 2.1: Technical support is provided to the police unit to support mainstreaming of gender into the MoI. 
The gender expert is working on  drafting the policy on how gender should be mainstreamed at the MOI work, structure, procedures and services, the process is entailing  a desk research, one to one interview to guarantee a rigorous policy based on the current facts and needs of the sector. 

PRI have managed to have a strong relationship with the senior management of both the MOI and the female police unit through organizing different sets of meetings as follows-The total Number of meetings, roundtables with senior management at the MoI  and the female police unit to promote gender mainstreaming in the police force during the current reporting period are two meetings as follows:
1)	A meeting with the vice president of the ministry of interior was organized on the February 29th , 2020, for the purpose of discussion of the site hand over of the female police academy. 
2)	A meeting with each of the General Director of projects in the MOI along the General Director of training in the MOI ,and secretary of the vice minister of interior on the first of  March 2020 was held for the purpose of the discussion of  the developed training courses, and  the delivery of the courses methodology for the police officers. Also, during the same meeting a discussion about the infrastructure work was raised, concerning the implementation methodology of the work on the female police academy through the current circumstances of conflicts and an agreement on a six locations to be renovated to meet women needs were identified.


Output 2.2: Improved infrastructure of the unit and training locations for female police officers
Output 2.2: Improved infrastructure of the unit and training locations for female police officers
Female Police Academy: 
At the beginning of the reporting period, the decision of choosing the contractor to work on the renovation of female police academy was taken by a committee of representatives from the MOI, Female Police Unite and PRI; however due to the conflict in Yemen the site handover delayed until the 19th of March 2020. (Please see annex No. 1) 
Since November 2019, PRI conducted a mutual meeting with all of the MOI, family protection directorate and the women policing department representatives to agree on the required rehabilitation needs and technical constructive aspects, and kept following up with the MOI to handover the site, the approval form the MOI to start the work on the renovation sent on the 24th of February; Two follow up meetings were conducted to discuss the  handover the site of the female police academy, the first meeting was on the 29th  of February 2020 with the vice  Minister of Interior , the second meeting was conducted on 1st of March 2020, with the purpose of  the discussion of the implementation methodology of the renovation work in the academy, this meeting was held with each of the director of together foundation in Yemen and the director of planning, general director of projects and general director of training and secretary of the vice Minister of Interior, affiliated for the police directorate in Yemen. 

Accordingly, on March 19th, 2020, a hand over of the site for the purposes of construction, and renovation of the female police academy in (ADAN, KHOUR-MKASAR / ALNASIR) has delivered, and the work started and accomplished 50% of its infrastructure till 22nd  of April; (please see attached annex No.2 - the report) 

Challenges encountered during the implementation of the renovation and rehabilitation work of the female police academy 
- The most important challenges that met the work of the academy is the political tension in Aden in addition to the destruction of most buildings and organs of the Ministry of Interior in Aden, where no building or suitable site for the project was found until August 2019 and after the identification of the current location in August 2019 there were military confrontations between the legitimate government forces in Aden and the forces of the Transitional Council and therefore PRI were not able to start working until March 2020.
- the cost of the reinvention got higher than we expected due to the raise of the prices of the row materials, and the severe damage that was caused for the selected building by the conflict, and the security cost that the contractor had to pay to secure his equipment
- After the completion of 50% of the renovation work and after the date of April 22, 2020 the city of Aden swept large torrents and rain and did not affect the academy site being far from the torrential streams, but the rains made the contractor stop working temporarily and then got the new tension resulting from the political conflict and announced the Transitional Council on April 25 autonomy for Aden and the southern provinces as the outbreak began. In addition to the fact of  work in Ramadan, which resulted in a fewer working hours, where many construction workers prefer not to work during Ramadan, where the contractor have submitted an official  letter requesting to postpone the renovation, and rehabilitation  of the female police academy in Aden.
- Due to COVID-19 the work on renovating the academy was stopped.

On the other hand; during the meeting on  the 1st of March; also discussed the identification of six locations to be  renovated to meet women needs to be friendly for the female police officers; The six locations have been agreed with MOI, including points at the borders, the port, largest police 


Output 3.1: The role of the unit is promoted, and the public is informed of its mandate and roles
The promotion of the role of the department, some of the promotional materials were developed and sent to MOI for approval before their distribution, the documentary will start after finishing the work on the academy and the six locations, however, some filming started to document the work on the infrastructure and will be ready in both English and Arabic before the end of the project. 

Output 4.1 Dissemination of the lessons learnt and good practice from the project at an international level
The dissemination of the lessons learnt and good practice from the project at an international level  was intended to be delivered  through an international advocacy, unfortunately two major global events in which the Yemeni experience of the project was supposed to be presented and Yemeni MOI was supposed to participate were postponed due to COVID-19, the crime commission in Vienna, were a side event was supposed to be organized to talk about role of Yemeni female police during conflict and their contribution to building peace and security in Yemen, and the crime congress in Japan, were a side event were supposed to be organized to discuss the establishment of Yemeni female police department and its impact of peace and security. The two events were postponed till 2021. However, from here till the end of the project the following international advocacy events will take place; a side event in Geneva in Sept during the human rights council meeting, a side event in New York during the security council meeting, and a policy paper that highlights the role of the female police in Yemen in building peace and security will be issued.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk Assessment Nov. 2018 - October 2019:
 1) Political instability in Yemen Aggravated political instability leading to violent armed conflict, causing lack of security and threat to lives will have high impact on the project. Activities will have to be postponed or moved to secure areas, setting new priority locations depending on developments on the ground, and the potential effect of armed conflicts on the future of the geographic location. Political instability resulting in changing of governmental bodies, laws and regulations but not affecting people&#x2019;s safety and security will have medium impact on the project. However, such changes might have short-term negative effects and cause delays in delivering the project activities. On the other hand, they may create a favourable environment to advocate for overall justice reforms and the promotion of human rights for the long term, when new laws and regulations are in development. A regular risk assessment done by MENA regional office on a monthly basis according to consultation between the project team based in Yemen with MoI. PRI will tolerate low-medium range of risks inherent in field work, and in districts where high risk is associated with field work, relevant activities will be moved to safe areas, as a way to mitigate the risk, and make sure that the project goal and objectives are not jeopardized by temporary developments on the ground. One of the key examples, is shifting the location of the police academy into a safer place will be taken as a mitigation action by PRI management in order to be able to implement the project activities. PRI mitigation response were taken as a result of the continuous engagement and consultation done between PRI and the MoI . Where the MoI informed PRI to wait till April 2020, and promised to solve the issue which hindered to have the academy in Aden. Otherwise, a new building that is in Hadhramaut might be chosen. Regional offices have the experience and expertise in many geographic areas in the MENA region, Asia, Africa, central Europe, to determine when work is safe to be carried out and will adapt their work accordingly to achieve the sought-for results. Additionally, PRI will work through local staff who are well trained and neutral, and not targeted, with a low risk to their safety and security. In relation to regional and international experts, PRI will use all safety procedures followed by the UN, including staying in safe hotels and avoiding high risk areas; additionally, the MoI is willing to provide security and guards for the experts if needed. 2) Access to professional development for women police officers: A barrier to the career advancement of women in policing may take the form of inequitable access to training courses, due to the unavailability of the needed facilities and expertise to deliver the needed courses for the females, and eventually to promotion in their career. A male dominated work may affect the equal opportunities offered to women. In addition police employees, including women, living in remote and rural communities have less opportunities, especially if the course involves an extended residential component. women with both family and career responsibilities may be less inclined to apply for training. PRI&#x2019;s project objective is to provide the right for women to join the police forces and receive adequate training for a range of different work responsibilities. PRI will also work on deploying the women in different field areas. However, as part of the sustainability of the project goal and objectives, through regular meetings with the senior officials of the MoI , PRI will build a curricula that will require involving the women police in the future training and academic course . The training by PRI will empower women to become a significant number and an asset in the police units. PRI will also provide best practices related to equal training opportunities for women in distant areas from the center. 3) The led coalition unwillingness to cooperate and setting obstacles in the deployment of female police in the different areas controlled by their forces. This risk is considered Medium in Yemen, as one of the major impacts of Arabic coalition support to the International Recognized Government (IRG) was a control on the buildings of the official ministries and their movements, yet PRI developed the project proposal in consultation with their allies in the MoI and got approval from the Deputy Minister of Interior on the project activities. PRI signed an MOU with the MoI before starting the implementation. Over the last 6 years PRI has built strong working relations with the Ministry of Interior in Yemen, through working with them on juvenile justice and prison reform. PRI ensures a continues coordination with the senior management of the MoI and the women police and use its good relations with senior officials and decision makers, in addition to its previous cooperation with many ministries of the coalition countries, six coordination meetings were conducted between PRI and the senior management of both the MoI and women police to facilitate the organisation of activities , and the deployment of trained female police, in addition to facilitate their daily duties , and mandate. 4) Lack of social support The lack of social support can be another barrier for women to succeed in their duties in the field. A police woman required to intervene at the different levels of the justice sector might face the strain and the effects of environmental or external barriers. women trained might not sustain their jobs. PRI previous experiences in the justice sector in Yemen, including at high managerial institutional level , showed a high social support for women equal participation. Historically Yemen, was leading in women participation as judges, and even as police officers. Prior to the conflict two thousand women officers were part of the police units, the armed conflict and the humanitarian situation forced them to leave (only sixty stayed). A societal angel of the Yemeni Context including-(Female police officer family members , or husband), women is not accepted to work in certain fields such as the security field especially in operational roles, where there is a stereotyping for her role based on being a female. This will have a burden on females. Females needs to challenge the society were she is working in and to proof her ability for such roles in security sector and operational roles in specific. The project will build on previous successes, and social support to re-introduce the female element to police, empowered by professional training. PRI will also conduct advocacy campaigns with senior opinion leaders in the society, and will build the capacity of the media outlets to gain support of the different components of the society, including a follow up by media to the efficient interventions of women police in fields of women justice , and children in conflict with the law. Any negative strains will be tackled and criticised by the media, and partners from opinion leaders</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-COH-04154075-PRI-007" ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, The Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-COH-04154075-PRI-007" ref="GB-COH-04154075" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Penal Reform International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project started on the 1st of November 2018</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It was supposed that the project ends on the 31st of October 2020</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to the political situation and the COVID-19 Pandemic; a two months non-cost extension till the 31st of December sent was sent to the Dutch embassy and they approved it.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taghreed Jaber</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00962799611163</telephone>
   <email>priamman@penalreform.org</email>
   <website>https://www.penalreform.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15132" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-01">928279</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-31">843320</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">470.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-22">930000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount Received from Dutch</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001994" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="4000001994" ref="GB-COH-04154075" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-27">400</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.1.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-06">3000.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.1.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-06">699.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.1.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">47011.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-09">7390.78</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">3475.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.11</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-22">37658.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">1095.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">5.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">5000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-29">2500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">5999.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-21">5004.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.9</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">3586.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-29">23890</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.5.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">17590.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">2709.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-24">2198.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.7.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">789.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">1344.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">4534.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">145.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-09">758.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">147.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-12">5000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">6500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">6586.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">1964.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">2234.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-25">3040.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-30">4664.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">1375.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-27">1030.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">1000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-30">6000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-12">442.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-24">1759.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">400</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-15">753.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">778.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">5000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">554.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">740.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">308.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">5725.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">5738.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-30">333.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">3004.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">550.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">383.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">5760.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-01">5028.39</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">5599.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">4120.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">2993.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">3778.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-27">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">4530.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">3000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-27">350</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-30">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">650</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">1000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-05">862.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">557.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">5398.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">2729.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">1028</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">1011</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">1341.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">2073.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">369.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">867.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">370.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">2523.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">1224.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">2108.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">3118.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">1128.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">1151.78</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">1660.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">3459.99</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">994.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">1081.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">972.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-12">2000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">2638.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  1.2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-28">2500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">457.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">6858.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">15000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">5667.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">1433</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-21">1000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-29">1185.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">616.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">357.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.6.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">3697.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-06">699.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.1.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">5567.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">1500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">2139.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">1892.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">2281.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">384.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">4171.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">3000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">1041.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">2701.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">2632.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">2698.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">2417.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">2389.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">2486.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">2505.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">5287.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.6</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">1001.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">3220.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">1535.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">2017.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">1245.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.7</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">1160.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">644.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.8</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">1668.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">1816.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-30">792.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">985.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">3768.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   3.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">836.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">1072.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">1278.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">4923.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">1952.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">1548.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">1610.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">1460.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">1214.44</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">1215.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.2</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">370</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">1650</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">10119.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">3737.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">301.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">157.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">125.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line  3.3</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">34809.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">8736.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.1.4.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-31">8731</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 1.3.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-30">1004.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-31">500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line    2.4</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-31">500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-28">900</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">budget line   2.5</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/PRI-Narrtive-report-to-Embassy-of-Netherland-Yemen_Nov-2018---October-2019-20200318030343.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative Report Nov. 2018 - Oct. 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-No-20200318040358.-1---MoI---PRI-MOU_Female-Police-Project.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 1 - MOU PRI &amp; MOI</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-No-20200318040342.-2---Job-Description-for-Each-Post.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 2 - Job Description for each post</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-No-20200318040332.-3-The-Training-Plan.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 3 - Training Plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-No-20200318040330.-4---Findings-of-Baseline-Assessment.xlsx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 4 - Findings of Baseline Assessment</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-11-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-No-20200318040309.-5---Bid-for-Renovation-of-Police-Academy.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 5 - Bid for Renovation of Police Academy</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-No-20200318040335.-6---Bid-for-Female-Police-Unit.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 6 - Bid for Police Unite</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Audit-report-20201102011128.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Audit Report - Nov. 2018 - Dec. 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Auditor-Letter-20201103081130.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Auditor Letter</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Dutch-Yemen-Project_Financial-Report_1-20201103081133.11.2018-31.12.2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial Report 1 Nov. 2018 - 31 Dec. 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Management-Letter-20201103081136.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Auditor Management Letter</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-11-03"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Yemen-female-police-unit-logframe-28-01-2020-20200318040325.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Logical Frame work</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Project-Plan_2nd-Year-PRI-project-with-dutch-embassy-in-yemen-20200318040352.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2nd Year Project Plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/PRI-Narrtive-report-to-Embassy-of-Netherland-in-Sanaa_Nov-2019-Apr-2020_Clean-20200916080914.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative Report_Nov. 2019 - April 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-1_Delivery-of-the-Academy-Site-20200916080920.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 1 - Report Nov.19-Apr.20_Delivey of the Academy  site</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-2_Police-Academy-Achievment-Report-20200916080911.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex 2 - Report Nov.19-Apr.20_Achievements Report for the Academy renovation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OMA.POC.DETAILED-PROGRESS-REPORT+XML" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Updated-Theory-of-Change-20201011091055.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Updated Theory of Change</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
