<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-southsudan" dstore:index="113" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SSD223</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operational support for Covid19 response in Juba, South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is raised to support the response to COVID19 in Juba, South Sudan. South Sudan&#x2019;s first confirmed case of COVID-19 was on 5 April 2020, by 24 July 2020 cases had surged to 2,258 with 45 deaths. Cases are reported from 16 out of 78 counties, with Juba, being most affected. Insufficient testing limits the ability to accurately assess the scope of the pandemic . COVID-19 infections are expected to increase significantly and more significantly impact urban poor and IDP camp residents due to factors including high density living conditions (preventing social distancing and making isolation difficult), levels of risk awareness and adoption of prevention and control practices are low, access to WaSH and health care facilities are low and prevalence of existing health conditions (including malaria, diarrhoea), food insecurity and malnutrition is high, particularly at this time of year. The elderly, people with disabilities and women carers (higher exposure risk) are particularly vulnerable, with women more likely to be health workers, community mobilisers or IDPs. CAFOD will implement the project with its local implementing partner Titi Foundation. The project will be implemented in Juba city and strive to deliver safe, accessible, and dignified COVID-19 risk communications, protection services, and food security, as well as foster and enable good hygiene, and sanitation practices for the most vulnerable. The overall programme design and implementation will be guided and underpinned by accountability, protection mainstreaming, inclusive and conflict sensitive approaches. This response plan is designed in line with the revised Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) of South Sudan, developed taking COVID-19 risk into account.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD223" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD223" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSD223" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-01">2078.75</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54383">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-22">2078.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
