<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-palestineopt" dstore:index="6" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-PAL050</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Caritas Jerusalem COVID-19 health care response in Gaza</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There was an unprecedented surge in COVID-19 in the Gaza Strip in November and early December; active cases have doubled in the oPt overall and tripled in Gaza.  The delivery of essential routine health services continues to be affected by the pandemic. The health authorities in Gaza announced the closure of all public outpatient clinics and the temporary suspension of elective surgeries for two weeks on November 24, while maintaining urgent and life-saving surgeries only. 

Therefore, preventive measures like social distancing, hygiene practices, hand hygiene, and strengthening the immune systems of vulnerable people, many of whom are food insecure are of paramount importance. 

This project will provide medical care in the homes of people who have tested positive for Covid-19 and/or people who need emergency primary heath care.  It will also provide nutritional supplements to help improve the immune systems of people at risk in poor, over-crowded and multi-generational homes. The project, coordinated by the Ministry of Health in collaboration with Caritas Jerusalem, is designed to prevent spread of the virus and relieve pressure on the under-resourced and overcrowded public hospitals. The five medical teams will visit homes and assess the possibility of keeping the infected isolated in their own homes. If their houses are not suited for isolation, Caritas Jerusalem will refer to MoH isolation centres.  Caritas Jerusalem will also provide non-COVID-19 related primary health care e.g. dressing changes, provision of medication as necessary. 

In addition, Caritas will give hygiene kits in order to keep the homes virus free as much as possible as well as distributing flyers to raise awareness and the Caritas Jerusalem hotline number for additional enquiries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="PAL050" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Jerusalem</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="PAL050" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="PAL050" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">40000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54604">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-17">40000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69124">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-17">40000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Jerusalem</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
