<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-nigeria" dstore:index="54" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR446</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Emergency Intervention for vulnerable households in 2 states: FCT and Kano</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposed intervention intends to address water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH), food and nutritional insecurity as a result of COVID 19. Radio phone in program will be carried out to raise awareness among the populace. The COVID-19 pandemic is a health and human crisis pandemic threatening the food security and nutrition of millions of people in Nigeria. Hundreds of millions of people were already suffering from hunger and malnutrition before the virus hit and, unless immediate action is taken, we could witness acute food emergency in Nigeria. In the longer term, the combined effects of COVID-19 itself, as well as corresponding mitigation measures and the emerging global recession could, without large-scale coordinated action, disrupt the functioning of food systems. Such disruption can result in consequences for health and nutrition of a severity and scale unseen for more than half a century. 

The intervention is also proposing to provide Preventive Protective Equipment (PPE) to one hospital in each of the target location of Abuja (FCT) and Kano state. The PPE will help the hospitals to be better protected and thus more disposed to support COVID patients. Shortage of PPE is one of the major challenge health care workers are faced in this pandemic. The Catholic church donated to the Nigerian government some centres across the country as isolation centres for the management of COVID. Two of these facilities will be benefit from these PPE.

The involvement of faith-based organizations in responding to health epidemics cannot be overemphasized. As revealed in a press statement by CAFOD; Christian and Muslim Leaders played, essential role in tackling the Ebola virus especially in dispelling rumours and promoting authentic health messages. With COVID-19 pandemic, in Nigeria, a lot of people still do not believe that the virus is real, thus resulting in neglect of government prevention messages.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR446" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR446" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR446" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-13">62262.6267</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54285">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-01">62262.6267</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68808">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-01">62262.63</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
