<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="amrefha-et" dstore:index="1" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-01T08:54:23+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-01T08:54:23+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-261488-ETA61GK</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-261488" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amref Health Africa - UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrating TB and malaria services into Maternal and Neonatal Child Health</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Ethiopia, approximately 68% of the population is at risk of malaria with nearly a million people detected annually. The TB incidence in 2018 was 151 per 100,000, with yearly detection exceeding 110,000.  More than three million women give birth annually in Ethiopia and are equally or more at risk of acquiring malaria or TB. The aforementioned complexities of these diseases in maternal and child health apply to all parts of Ethiopia. However, the four regions of Afar, Benishangul-Gumuz, Gambella, and Somali are more likely to be affected due to relatively weak health systems and poor health seeking behaviours. These regions have vulnerable communities due to their pastoralist and semi pastoralist lifestyles and are also affected by calamities such as droughts and disease outbreaks.


Amref operates in these areas to mainly implement Reproductive Maternal Neonatal and Child Health programs. Through an existing Amref-led Transform HDR project, Amref will contribute towards tackling these challenges. The existing project aims to increase health access and address vulnerable communities. The first intermediate result of Transform HDR focusses on access to healthcare, mainly maternal and child health (MCH) and malaria, in the developing regional states of Afar, Benishangul-Gumuz, Gambella and Somali. 


Through this programme, Amref will continue to address the gaps in malaria and TB in mothers and children, in order to build upon current achievements and maximise impact. Additionally, to combat the detrimental effects of COVID-19, each activity will consider preventative measures such as physical distancing, hand hygiene and appropriate use of face masks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme&#x2019;s overall objective is to improve prevention, detection, diagnosis and management of TB and malaria among mothers and children in developing regional states of Ethiopia. Specific objectives are: (1) Improve the capacity of frontline health workers for effective diagnosis, referrals and treatment of TB and malaria among women and children by integrating with MCH activities; (2) External Quality Assurance (EQA) on laboratory services for malaria, TB and lab services for ANC; (3) Knowledge management to improve integrated programming to strengthen PHC as a means to UHC. Project outcomes will be (1) 80% of targeted health workers can effectively diagnose and manage TB and malaria among ANC and under 5 clinic followers, (2) 95% EQA Concordance rate for malaria and TB diagnostics in over 80% of health facilities, and (3) 80% of data completeness from targeted health facilities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme will train 320 health workers on malaria diagnosis/management, 375 health workers on TB diagnosis/management and 70 lab technicians on proper diagnosis and EQA mechanism. The project will also directly reach 72 health centres, 3 hospitals and 295 community health posts for EQAs/diagnosis quality assessments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GlaxoSmithKline (GSK)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="ET-MFA-0001989741" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amref Health Africa in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12250" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-07">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-07">400000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-07">168919</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
