<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="mrg-activities" dstore:index="4" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-21T10:14:20+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-28T10:21:38+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-282305-All4All</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-282305" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minority Rights Group</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;All4All&quot; October-December 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Update on MRG&#x2019;s activities within the &#x2018;All4All&#x2019; project

The PADs continued collecting cases of discrimination between October and December and the team also received the cases collected through the Observatory. During these three months, we (PAD and O3DT) collected a total of 156 cases, which they can be grouped as follows: 105 based on SOGIE, 32on the basis of nationality and skin colour (Sub-Saharan migrants), 6 on the basis of skin colour (Black Tunisians), 10 based on disabilities and 3 cases of intersectional discrimination (skin colour and SOGIE). Most of these cases were collected in Tunis (81) followed by the Sahel (22).
Our lawyers provided legal support to 41 persons between October and December 2020, including legal consultancies and defence in hearings. For instance, we supported 2 cases where black women were victims of racial assault, 1 case of discrimination based on freedom of religion and belief, 2 cases defending 5 people with disabilities, 6 legal consultancy and 1 case of discrimination against 18 Sub-Saharans and 6 cases defending 15 persons based on SOGIE.
As part of our continuous support to the lawyers of the clinic, and in light of the role that lawyers play to strengthen our advocacy efforts, MRG organised an online meeting with lawyers to debate the challenges related to the implementation of law 50-2018 and how to address them. Highlighting the importance of these activities, meetings on a variety of topics will be held regularly with the lawyers to support our legal and advocacy efforts. Furthermore, our team holds regular meetings and follow-ups with the CSOs in charge of implementing the advocacy projects that were selected in the previous reporting period to guide them in their projects.
In November, a Communication Officer and a Programmes Assistant joined MRG to support our work in Tunisia. In November, we also recruited a team of 2 consultants to conduct a baseline study on the situation of minorities in Tunisia. A group of 3 consultants was commissioned in December to conduct a research on the impact of Covid-19 on minorities and other marginalized groups in Tunisia.
In late December, we launched a call to recruit 2 tutors for the Arabic and French versions of the free online journalists&#x2019; training on &#x2018;Non-Discrimination and Diversity in the Media&#x2019;. We are also receiving applications from candidates to participate in both Arabic and French version of the training. 
Since the beginning of &#x201C;All for All&#x201D; in July, our Facebook page &#x201C;Points Anti-Discrimination&#x201D; gained 500 new likes which led to more public engagement with our posts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Update on the O3DT&#x2019;s activities under the &#x201C;All4All&#x201D; project

&#xF076;	4 Trainings in intersectionality for the benefit of the Observatory&#x2019;s partners (80 participants: 49 NGOs: 54 women/26 men) as follows:
-	23rd-25th of October(2 groups) for partners located in the Center East and West, which took place in Hammamet. 30 participants benefited from the training: 17 NGOs, 20 women and 10 men 
-	28th-29th of November for partners located in the North East and West, which took place in Bizerte. 23 participants benefited from the training: 16 NGOs, 18 women and 5 men 
-	18th-29th of December for partners located in the North East, which took place in Tunis. 27 participants benefited from the training: 16 NGOs, 16 women and 11 men

&#xF076;	82 cases of discrimination were reported between October and end of December and sent to MRG for analysis.
&#xF076;	A participative mapping of needs was conducted and elaborated by a consultant for the benefit of the Observatory&#x2019;s partners.
&#xF076;	A Participative diagnosis was conducted.
&#xF076;	15 associations joined the Observatory between October and December.
&#xF076;	2 Newsletters (of October and November) were published and sent to our partners.
&#xF076;	https://o3dt.org/ in its new design as well as the Platform dedicated to Partners are revealed.
&#xF076;	A call for projects was shared with the Observatory&#x2019;s partners and 22 projects were received. The Observatory will be supporting financially 14 selected projects.
&#xF076;	A parliamentary day, an advocacy event, is being currently organized in partnership with MRG and is to take place soon.
&#xF076;	The logo of the project All for All is being finalized.
&#xF076;	Between July and December 2020, the Observatory&#x2019;s Facebook page saw an increase in the number of its followers by +516 new subscriptions.
&#xF076;	Since the creation of the Instagram account in July 2020, 165 followers subscribed to the page.
&#xF076;	A call for scripts was published in Jamaity.org and the Observatory&#x2019;s social media to produce two awareness-raising videos about the right to difference. The project&#x2019;s team is currently selecting contractors. 
&#xF076;	59 out of 72 associations signed the charter of values of O3DT.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association for the Promotion of the Right to Difference</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
