<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="beis-gb-gov-13-ukri" dstore:index="634" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2019-07-25T11:01:21+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2019-09-18T11:22:02.999997+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-20">59340.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-20">112800.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2004 Sumatra-Andaman tsunami killed around 15,000 people on the Eastern coast of India, especially from vulnerable communities who were also deeply affected economically as a result. In 1945, between 300 and 4,000 people, including in India, were killed by a tsunami on the Western coast of India, and this coast is possibly exposed to another event soon, potentially larger. The question is then: how do we protect the communities settled on the Western coast of India from a future tsunami? In the long term, only wise planning can reduce exposure, as early warning systems only mitigate the tsunami consequences. The answer to this question will be examined through a better scientific  understanding of the tsunami hazard using Geology, numerical simulations, and Statistics. The land use and planning decisions, that should ideally prevent people from settling in zones prone to the dramatic impacts of possible future tsunamis, need to be implemented, strengthened and communicated efficiently based on the science at hand. There is currently no or very little planning for tsunami risk in these regions. These decisions will have to be made under great uncertainties and must reflect local attitudes towards risk, account for the economic value of decisions, and respect the ethical views of the authorities and the communities.  The three central aims will be to: 1.                  Analyse the tsunami risk arising from earthquakes and quantify the uncertainties regarding eventual coastal inundations that it causes. 2.                  Understand how urbanisation processes, and in particular land use and planning decisions, contribute to the impact of coastal inundation on communities 3.                  Assess the uncertainties regarding these impacts, the value put at risk by them and the information required by stakeholders to develop mitigation and response strategies that reflect these considerations. This project will take an interdisciplinary approach that brings together natural scientific modelling of hazards, social analysis of urban development dynamic, and decision-theoretic (including ethical) evaluation of the aims of mitigation policies. In this first short-term study, we will focus on two coastal towns in India, with the intent of laying down the foundations for a more ambitious future study. By doing an initial study of this kind we can assess the feasibility of in depth mitigation planning that is sensitive to scientific uncertainty and to community values, and trial a multidisciplinary approach to managing natural hazards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will investigate tsunami risk to coastal India in order to improve the scientific basis for planning aimed at preventing severe losses (in both lives and livelihoods) and increasing community resilience to catastrophic natural events. The three central aims will be to: 1.                  Analyse the tsunami risk arising from earthquakes and quantify the uncertainties regarding eventual coastal inundations that it causes. 2.                  Understand how urbanisation processes, and in particular land use and planning decisions, contribute to the impact of coastal inundation on communities 3.                  Assess the uncertainties regarding these impacts, the value put at risk by them and the information required by stakeholders to develop mitigation and response strategies that reflect these considerations. The project will take an interdisciplinary approach that brings together natural scientific (geology-statistics) modelling of hazards, social-scientific understanding of underlying risk factors and risk communication, and decision-theoretic (including ethical) evaluation of mitigation policies. In this first short-term study, we will focus on two or three particular coastal towns in India, with the aim of laying down the foundations for a more ambitious future study. By doing an initial study of this kind we can assess the feasibility of in depth mitigation planning that is sensitive to scientific uncertainty and to community values, and trial a multidisciplinary approach to managing natural hazards. We will first investigate tsunami risk arising from giant earthquakes on the Makran Subduction Zone (MSZ). Tsunamis from this source threaten the West coast of India including major cities such as Mumbai. The best documented historic tsunami from the MSZ occurred on the 28th November, 1945 when around 300-4000 people were killed in several countries with Arabian Sea coastlines, including India, at a time when these coasts were much less populated than today. However, large uncertainties in the possible sources of tsunamis around India are key issues for tsunami risk assessment for the coast of India. In 2004, the lack of awareness and preparedness to a possible tsunami arising from the Sumatra-Andaman (S-A) fault unfortunately contributed to the death of around 15,000 people on the Eastern coast of India, with a catastrophic economic impact on poor and fragile local communities. The prospect of similar losses for a future event on the Western coast compels scientists,  specialists of humanities, and social scientists experts in planning for natural hazards, to jointly investigate the risk as proposed here.  In order of priority, this proposal&apos;s first objective is to improve the scientific understanding that underpins prevention strategies such as hazard mapping for urban planning. Its second objective is to explore the processes that will enable the incorporation of scientific assessments into policies and practice, in order to ethically and efficiently protect vulnerable and poor communities from future tsunamis. Its third objective is to identify the hurdles that would hamper the integration of science, policies and practice, and propose specific strategies towards pragmatic decision-making under severe uncertainties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FP016367%2F1">
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-16"></document-date>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
  </document-link>
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE/P016367/1</iati-identifier>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <related-activity ref="GB-GOV-13-GCRF-UKRI" type="2"></related-activity>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tsunami risk for the Western Indian Ocean: steps toward the integration of science into policy and practice</narrative>
  </title>
  <transaction>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE/P016367/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-20">172140.93</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
