<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="beis-gb-gov-13-ukri" dstore:index="278" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2019-07-25T11:01:21+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2019-09-18T11:22:02.999997+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">
   </value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">
   </value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">
   </value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">
   </value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1"></country-budget-items>
  <crs-add>
   <loan-status currency="GBP"></loan-status>
  </crs-add>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The response to the Ebola virus has exposed major weaknesses in the health systems of the affected countries. In part this is because of institutional weaknesses at national and district level but the behaviour of global actors in the response has also attracted criticism. The situation has been particularly acute in Sierra Leone as many progressive reforms such as Free Health Care and other governance initiatives may have been undermined by the epidemic and the nature of the response. To date, the evidence on the impact of international Ebola-response assistance in Sierra Leone, and the way it has enabled or hampered local responses, is almost non-existent. For example, it is not known how, why and in what ways local health systems were used, or not used; and it is not at all clear whether international assistance has strengthened local health systems, or weakened them by building parallel structures and bypassing local institutions and relationships. The longer term implications of this kind of assistance, especially beyond the immediate crisis, are thus unclear.  Documenting and understanding how and why national and international endeavours to care for the sick and interrupt the transmission of Ebola struggled to produce expected results, is paramount for improving future responses and ensuring health systems are not weakened by future emergencies. Our study will explore a range of factors including: the extent to which responses were informed by local concerns and perceptions of emergency-response systems; whether external interventions sought to work within or with local systems (and whether this resulted in the building of parallel response structures); whether external interventions ultimately weakened and made the health system less resilient by, for example, taking locally qualified staff away from public sector systems or by diverting resources from other ongoing health requirements (including routine maternal and child health and common preventable diseases). Specifically, we ask the following research questions: In what ways has the international Ebola-response affected Sierra Leone&apos;s health system and its ability to withstand future shocks?  How can international, national and local emergency response mechanisms be utilised to build a resilient health system in Sierra Leone, and what lessons emerge? We bring together several different disciplinary and thematic perspectives, including health systems/systems strengthening, policy and implementation science; disaster risk reduction/emergency preparedness; and the anthropology of global health and medical humanitarianism. Explicitly bringing together these often separate bodies of learning will enable us to more fully and effectively answer our principal research questions, identify transferable lessons and contribute to generating substantive health systems research evidence relating to what promotes resilient health systems.  Specific benefits of the project will include: * Identification of characteristics of resilient health systems that need to underpin health systems strengthening efforts, in Sierra Leone and other similar settings, and how these can be incorporated in national health systems development.  * Identifying the key issues influencing village level responses to Ebola and reflecting on the implications of these issues for understanding and building more resilient health systems.  * Suggestions for revising the existing guidelines for emergency responses, including those of the WHO drawing on the experiences of the recent Ebola epidemic in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our aim is to assess the impact of international interventions on health systems at national, district and village levels and learn lessons for how future emergency responses can be provided in a manner that strengthens, rather than undermines, the existing health systems, and makes them more resilient. Research Question 1: How has the international Ebola-response, in its interaction with national and local responses, affected Sierra Leone&apos;s health system and its ability to respond to future shocks? Objective 1: To examine the extent, nature, motivations and drivers of the policy response to Ebola in Sierra Leone and their perceived effect on the epidemic progression and on health system strength and resilience Objective 2: To examine the level of coordination, oversight and regulatory mechanisms for the international response and explore their perceived effect on health systems strengthening and resilience.  Objective 3: To explore what actions were implemented at the district, why and how, and the extent to which they were affected by (or perceived to be affected by) international/national actions. Objective 4:        Determine the local issues which shaped what happened during the Ebola epidemic (e.g. structural factors, material conditions, cultural perceptions, actual behaviour). Research Question 2:  How can international, national and local emergency response mechanisms be utilised to build resilient health systems in Sierra Leone, and what are the lessons for other settings?  Objective 5: Develop conclusions, in the context of Sierra Leone, on what constitutes a resilient health system and how this may change in the face of an emergency. Objective 6: Identify lessons on how to respond to emergencies without undermining existing health systems capacities and strengthening initiatives. Anticipated Project Outputs: Identification of characteristics of emergency-resilient health systems to enable health systems strengthening to take place, in Sierra Leone and other similar settings, and how these can be incorporated in national health systems strengthening and development processes. Testing of findings against existing guidelines for emergency responses, including those of the WHO to identify the extent to which these can be expanded upon based on the experiences of the recent Ebola epidemic in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </description>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN015754%2F1">
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></document-date>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
  </document-link>
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/N015754/1</iati-identifier>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <related-activity ref="GB-GOV-13-GCRF-UKRI" type="2"></related-activity>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building resilient health systems: lessons from international, national and local emergency responses to the Ebola epidemic in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </title>
  <transaction>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/N015754/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">
   </value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
