<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="beis-gb-gov-13-ukri" dstore:index="1869" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-09-03T14:19:35.510000+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-08-27T15:40:15.000001+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V026038_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving COVID-19 and pandemic preparedness and response through the downstream of multi-hazard early warning system</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Many countries are now suffering after years of insufficient attention to warnings about the need for improved pandemic preparedness. The WHO has declared COVID-19 a pandemic, but its underlying factors, vulnerabilities and impacts go far beyond the health sector, and in Sri Lanka, it is overwhelming government and response agencies. This study will address two, inter-related challenges: How will countries cope if a major natural hazard occurs while the COVID-19 pandemic is ongoing? How can pandemic preparedness make use of the existing infrastructure for tackling other hazards? The project team will attempt to understand the potential impact of a pandemic-natural hazard hybrid scenario. It will also seek to improve early warning and preparedness for such an event, as well as the availability of and access to multi-hazard early warning systems (MHEW) and disaster risk information that include pandemic/biological hazards, which is also Target G of the SFDRR [1]. We will address these challenges by examining how public health actors be better included within a MHEW environment and how pandemic threats are integrated within national and local DRR strategies. We will explore the impact of COVID-19 on the response capabilities for other hazards, either multiple simultaneous events, or cascading impacts, and consider how COVID-19 and public health surveillance can be synergised with &quot;the last mile&quot; of MHEW. Pandemic is global, but the preparedness and response is local, and that response is very dependent on governance, laws, culture, risk perception and citizen behaviour. The study has been designed in close collaboration with Sri Lankan health and DRR agencies who identified the key gaps that need exploring. The team will develop and disseminate guidance to better incorporate pandemics and other biological hazards into national and local DRR preparedness and response</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This international, multi-disciplinary project team will attempt to better understand the potential impact of a pandemic-natural hazard hybrid scenario and seek to improve early warning and preparedness for such an event. It will support the availability of and access to multi-hazard early warning systems and disaster risk information in Sri Lanka that include pandemic and biological hazards, which is also Target G of the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction (SFDRR). These challenges will be addressed through six key research questions: 1. Who are the key actors and what are the processes involved in the preparation of COVID-19 and other pandemic warning and dissemination processes?  2. How are COVID-19 and other pandemic threats integrated within national and local disaster risk reduction strategies? 3. What is the impact of COVID-19 on the response capabilities for other hazards, either multiple simultaneous events, or cascading impacts?  What components of early warning system (key &amp; cross-cutting) are greatly affected due to dual challenges associated with COVID-19 (risk knowledge, monitoring, warning &amp; forecasting, communication &amp; dissemination, response capabilities, governance, gender &amp; diversity, etc)?  4. How can public health actors be better included within a multi-hazard early warning environment? 5. How would social distancing and other pandemic response measures impact the downstream response to other hazards, including mass evacuations with increased capacity of shelters, camps, etc? How could we overcome these tensions in an emergency situation? 6. How can the COVID-19 and public health surveillance system be synergised with &quot;the last mile&quot; of multi-hazard early warning systems, where community networks, communication systems, and citizen behaviours can be utilised for pandemic EWS at the community level?</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Huddersfield</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-14">28058.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-14">56571.7</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-14">168806.056</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Huddersfield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V026038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Huddersfield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FV026038%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-07-20"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
