<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="IDR" dstore:dataset="elsam-activities" dstore:index="2" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-31T12:00:24+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-31T06:59:32+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ID-KHH-AHU17AH0107-ID-KHH-AHU17AH0107-4000002029</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ID-KHH-AHU17AH0107" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Policy Research and Advocacy</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="ID">Lembaga Studi dan Advokasi Masyarakat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual Narrative Report II


Strengthening the Role of the Government in Developing the National Sustainable Development Agenda based on UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The COVID-19 pandemic that has hit Indonesia since March 2020 has changed people&apos;s lifestyles. Activities that were originally carried out face-to-face decreased as the number of infected people increased. People are also forced to do many activities from home to avoid the disease. The formation of this new habit was reinforced by a government policy known as Large-Scale Social Restrictions (PSBB).
The COVID-19 pandemic and the policy to limit face-to-face interactions have affected the implementation of the ELSAM&#x2019;s program in this second year. Changes in advocacy and training activities that were previously carried out face-to-face can no longer be done. Instead, advocacy is done online. Changing the way the program is implemented from offline to online, however, requires a large amount of adaptation time. The problem of adaptation to digital technology is also experienced by ministries / state institutions, corporations, and civil society organizations being the advocacy stakeholders. The significant impact is that the results of ELSAM&#x2019;s advocacy are not optimal.

This report was written to see the results of the implementation of the information dissemination and knowledge-building program on the principles of Business and Human Rights for the period of January-December 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ID.ELSAM02" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="ID-KHH-AHU17AH0107" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Policy Research and Advocacy</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="ID">Lembaga Studi dan Advokasi Masyarakat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The narrative report covers the project implementation for the period of January - December 2020.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Policy Research and Advocacy (ELSAM)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy Unit</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="ID">Andi Muttaqien</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>62217972662</telephone>
   <email>office@elsam.or.id</email>
   <website>http://elsam.or.id</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="ID">Jl Siaga II No 31 Pejaten Barat, Pasar Minggu, Jakarta Selatan 12510</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Strengthening the Role of the Government in Developing the National Sustainable Development Agenda based on UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights (UNGPs) officially began on 1 November 2018. The program has a goal in order that State integrates the principles of UNGPs into its law and policy framework, and the related parties can well practice various initiatives for business to respect human rights.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annual-Report-BHR---NL-2020_ELSAM_iati-20210329040341.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual Narrative Report for the period of January - December 2020.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This report was written to see the results of the implementation of the information dissemination and knowledge-building program on the principles of Business and Human Rights for the period of January-December 2020.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-03-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
