<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="1244" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-10T23:40:16" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-10T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05718-27:SO</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Joint Response 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia&#x2019;s population is currently experiencing multiple shocks (&#x2018;triple threat&#x2019; &#x2013; locust, drought, COVID-19): the Desert Locust upsurge that started in late 2019  and continues to threaten the food security and livelihoods of pastoralists and farmers in many parts of the country; riverine and flash floods that affect the food security, livelihoods and safety of farmers and people living in flood-prone, populated areas; the novel coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic that is having severe health and socio-economic impacts both in Somalia and globally; and the extended impact of previous shocks (flooding, drought, displacement, etc.) on livelihoods.
Assessments by the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO), Food Security and Nutrition Analysis Unit (FSNAU) and Famine Early Warning Systems Network (FEWSNET) also indicate that, in the absence of humanitarian assistance, up to 2.1 million people across Somalia are expected to face food consumption gaps or depletion of assets indicative of Crisis (IPC Phase 3) or worse outcomes through December 2020.In addition, 849 900 children under the age of five are likely to be acutely malnourished through August 2021 . Crisis (IPC Phase 3) outcomes are expected from June to September in parts of central Somalia, where livestock holdings are lowest, and in northeasternSomalia, where the economy is more dependent on livestock, seafood, and frankincense exports. The socioeconomic impacts of COVID-19have led to a 30-50 % decline in annual external remittances, an anticipated 25-35 % decline in annual livestock exports, lower labour demand, and above average imported staple food prices.
Besides adverse weather conditions and conflict resulting in food insecurity and hunger, other prevailing challenges in the project areas Oxfam and partners Candlelight, Havoyoco and KAALO work are poor access to water and inadequate hygiene and sanitation conditions, as well as displacement. Against this backdrop,  the proposed activities aim at assisting both IDPs and host communities. Access to clean and safe water is a major area of concern in our intervention areas in Somaliland and Puntland.Our proposed activities focus on relieving the distress suffered by affected families, preventing their situation from getting worse and strengthening collective resilience mechanisms. In terms of sectors we will focus on Food Security &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Livelihoods (FSL), Water, Sanitation &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Hygiene (WASH), Protection (PRO), Multi-Purpose Cash (MPCT) and Accountability (ACC).Oxfam and partners Candlelight, Havoyoco and KAALO will work in the following regions and districts/locations: Awdal (Baki), Sool (Las Anod, Xudun, Bocaame), Sanaag (Eerigavo), Bari (Bossaso), Mudug (Jariiban). Partners have been implementing SOMJR activities in these regions and locations since 2019 (Awdal, Sool, Sanaag) and 2020 (Bari, Mudug), and were able to invest in the resilience building of target communities. Bocaame in Sool has been added as a new location to the SOMJR: it has already been targeted by partner KAALO during the DRA-funded Desert Locust Joint Response (May to October 2020), however, needs remain high as Bocaame is highly affected by insecurity and recurring waves of desert locust invasions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kaalo Aid and Development</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAALO Aid and Development is a non-profit humanitarian and development organization established in Somalia in 1991 just after the collapse of the central government. KAALO works in Nugal, Mudug, Bari, Sool, Sanaag and Karkaar regions and plans to expand services to cover more regions of Somalia.

KAALO#s vision is a #Society free of ignorance and poverty# and its mission is to improve the livelihoods of communities in Somalia by supporting the provision of basic needs in a sustainable and environmentally sound manner. Currently the key program areas for KAALO are education and research, democracy, human rights, governance and rule of law, livelihood and community empowerment, agriculture and rural infrastructure, health water and sanitation. Current funding partners for KAALO include UNHCR, UNHABITAT, National Endowment for Democracy (NED), Diakonia, Danish People#s Aid (DPA), Oxfam Novib and Caritas International Belgium.KAALO has been in partnership with Oxfam since 2006. They were an implementing partner with Oxfam Novib for several long term development projects among them the Human rights program #2006-2008# which was funded by the EC, they are also currently implementing on two big projects both funded by the EC: #Strengthening capacity of civil society organisations to provide life skills and vocational training for the youth# and #Support to Artisanal Fisheries and Coastal Management in Somaliland and Puntland#KAALOhas registered the following key achievements to date:# Undertook the largest program that a Civil Society Organization implemented in Puntland. This involved distribution of about 60 tonnes of books, journals, hospital beds, other hospital equipments, wheelchairs, crutches e.t.c. to Somali communities across Somalia in 2001. Counterpart International in Washington USA contributed the shipment.# Carried out the first public building relocation program since the collapse of the last Central government in 1993 - 94 in Nugal region of Somalia.# Established the first professional training institute, Garowe School of Management, in Puntland in 1999. Renamed Puntland Community College in 2001 and grew to become Puntland State University in 2004.# Implemented the first Puntland administration funded community project (Drought Relief Program) during the 2003 # 04 drought in Puntland.# Developed human rights curriculum and a HIV/AIDS curriculum and had them integrated in the Puntland State University curriculum.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.40456 48.48600</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-10">252000</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-01">126000</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">100800</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">25200</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05718-27:SO">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007052"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Somalia HECA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05718"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Somalia Joint Response"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001696"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2700"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2300"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2700"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2300"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
