<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2825" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-07-18T23:30:13" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-18T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06390-03:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YSAT COVID-19 Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YSAT - Youth Social Advocacy Team, Ywill work in Rhino (and Omugo) Refugee settlement for COVID 19 Risk Communication and CommunityEngagement activities. Oxfam has worked with YSAT since 2018 on engaging South Sudan refugees as agents of peace project and Empowering the refugee and Host Communities on conflict transformation. Their presence and networks in the refugee settlement make them a critical ally to support large scale community engagement for social and behaviour change approaches that will ensure preventive community and individual health and hygiene practices, in line with the national public health containment recommendations

YSAT will mobilise the refugee communities in Arua to prevent COVID-19 infection and support any efforts to control it through the following activities:  Provision of transport means in terms of bicycles for follow up and information dissemination within the community.  Capitalize on the fact that the refugee leaders were given phones by UNHCR and then provide airtime for leaders for purposes of information sharing and feedback.  Empower women groups to make local masks and then buy from them if it is allowed for people to use masks.  Sensitization of the community in the local languages through;# Boda-boda talk passing through the communities with messages# Record messages to move with a police officer so that people do not come.# Shot a two minutes video in the local languages  Conducting massive handwashing i.e.# Identification of useful spots and make handwashing mandatory.# Installation of handwashing facilities and leaders shall help in monitoring the practices in the villages.# Any 10 steps there should be handwashing within the villages# Making handwashing mandatory at the water points (before fetching water, one should first wash their hands).  Recognition and awarding the idea homestead through a Role model challenge (in terms of prices # soap and jerricans).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Social Advocacy team YSAT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2014, we saw Refugee Youth being the victims of the conflict and all forms of violence#s in South Sudan while escaping the 2013 Crisis, during transits, in reception Centers and in the clusters where they were settled by Office Prime Minister. We understood that Peaceful coexistence, love hope and recovery was vital given the high level of trauma, communities need to have a strong voice tostand for their needs. The gap between NGOs and Refugee Youth in the communities has to be bridged in a conflict sensitive manner as well as recognizing the Youth as potential partners for Peace and that led to the foundation  of Youth Social Advocacy Team.
 In June 2015, Five Young people (John Jal Dak, Amuna Vivian, Jacob Nhial Bol, Tabule Geoffrey, Narcisse Bakouroua) came up with an idea of Advocating for Youth Voices calling for Peace in Rhino Camp luckily our Team leader john Jal Dak was nominated for the UNHCR  Global Refugee Youth Consultations (GRYC) and while the final report was released, we got our organization name was add the word #Youth# that excite us given our founders being all young people, we resolved to rename Social Advocacy Team as #Youth Social Advocacy Team# . In July 2016 Full constitution was drafted, membership was established and key Voluntary Positions of Chairperson, Vice, Secretary General, Treasurer and Information were fully established. In March 2017, we got our registration as a community based organization and during the Word Refuge Day 2017, we were offered Office Space by DRC,UNHCR and OPM Jointly in Ocea A Village behind CatholicChurch of Nationals, this was our first recognition as one of the first refugee led CBOs in Rhino to start freshly in Uganda. In September 2017, we got our first partnership with r0g Agency in Berlinto implement #defyhatenow project. The organization attracted 26Youth Volunteers but with only 4 Female Volunteers the lowest ever# but now we are happy that we have more than 10 females and Advocate for more in order to close the gap. YSAT is in a process of registering as a National NGO in Uganda and South Sudan.
2. ACHIEVEMENTSWe have created awareness about peaceful coexistence to over 10,000 Youth, Women and Children through open air Music concerts,Dialogues, and conferences since 2017 in RhinoCamp and Omugo Extension. YSAT initiated the resolution of Tika Refugee Conflict, calling for the first ever Inter Cultural Dialogue for South Sudanese Refugees targeting the 64 tribes of South Sudanese Refugees as Non Violent Action to reconcile and heal the broken relationship between the communities that fought, as we talk now, Tika was announced during the Peace Campaign we held in Ocea Zone in January 2019 as #Peaceful Zone# by OPM/UNHCR jointly. We were able to partner with 6 Renown National &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; International Organizations including Oxfam Novib, Norwegian Peoples Aid (NPA), and r0g Agency for Open Culture in Berlin, African Non Profit Chore (ANCHOR), The Nexus Fund, PeaceTech Lab. We were able to record 80,000 USD Grant Fundsin the 2018/19 Fiscal Yearfor YSAT. In 2018 we completed the development of YSAT major policies that governs the Organization including appointment of YSAT Board of Directors and had several capacity building of our members by our partners NPA and r0g Agency for Open Culture.3.   INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE# Mission: To create a Platform for Youth advocacy where SGBV, Youth - Unemployment, GenderInequality will No- longer be a threat in our Society while integrating the Culture of Peaceful Co-existence among the Refugees &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; between them with Host Community Youth What is the current purpose of the organisation?# Institutional objectives: To Contribute To Peace Building And Harmonious Living Among The Youth In West Nile# To Contribute To The Reduction Of Youth Unemployment AndEmpower Them With Life Skills to Produce Quality Leaders, Successful Entrepreneurs And Useful Citizens Of The Society.# To Reduce Social Discrimination And Conflicts Amongst The Refugees And Host Communities.# To Champion Girl Child Education ThroughChanging Attitudes And Harmonizing Various Cultures# To Contribute To The Reduction Of SGBV Cases In The Settlement And Increase The Level Of Community Awareness Towards All Forms Of Violence# To Achieve The Global Seven Core Actions For Refugee Youth  (GRYC Outcomes)# To Connect Youth Of Rhino With The Stakeholders And Share Relevant Information Concerning Young People To Update Partners Planning For The Youth# Contributes To The Educational Integration, Supports Of The Various Academic Backgrounds To Suit The Current Demands Of Global Educational Standards.# To Contribute To Percentage Reduction Of Illiteracy Rate Among The Refugees And Host Communities Through Functional Adult Literacy  (FAL)# To Provide Access To Dialogue, NetworkingAndExchange Of Knowledge And Experiences Among Our Youth And Their Regional And International Peers To Enable Learning.# To Advocate For And Monitor Commitment To Local And NationalPolicies And Programs For Our Youth To Enable Their Participation In Local And National Development And Decision MakingField(s) of activity: Peace Building &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Conflict Transformation ,Youth &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Women Empowerment, Advocacy (Gender Equality, Girl Child Education, SGBV Awareness, Children &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Youth Rights.), Community integrity building, Environmental Protection, Innovations  withfield Offices in Rhino Camp, Omugo Extension and Kiryandongo Settlements with possible extension to Imvepi and Bidibidi SettlementsTarget GroupWe at Youth Social Advocacy Team (YSAT) mainly target all the Youth aged (12-30) in primary, secondary, tertiary and Vocational Institutions as well as those un engaged in the communities, while influencing stakeholders including  community leaders as the tool to cause the change to the Refugees and Hostcommunities in Uganda,4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGYouth Social Advocacy Team (YSAT) is located in the Refugee Settlement of Rhino Camp and Omugo Extension where we operate in the fragile environment where conflict, poverty, poor health situation and Environmental crisis affect the daily life of the people that fled conflict in their variouscountries of South Sudan, Sudan, Rwanda, Kenya and DR Congo. Office of the prime Minister relocating and settling refugees by giving land, UN Refugee Agencies registration of refugees, issuing identity cards, ration and food, International and National as well asCommunity Based Organizations have been supporting the Refugees and Host Communities with various life savings and integration services to foster resilience among Refugees. With limited access to social services and economic crisis hitting hard on people, the situation becomes more challenging and services provided by the NGOs can#t always be sufficient. Other great actors include Refugee Welfare Council (RWC)Local Council Leaders (Host Communities), Youth Social Advocacy Team has been playing a neutral role in closing the gap between Partners and Refugee Communities as well as Various South Sudanese Communities.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.97271 31.39571</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-18">34001</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-01">3400</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">30601</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">30601</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Social Advocacy team YSAT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06390-03:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06390"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="UG Covid-19 prep and response Apr-Jun20"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002092"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5200"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4800"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5200"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4800"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
