<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2444" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-08-12T23:30:39" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-08-12T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05868-08:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOT Saving Lives now &amp; future Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Covid-19 door to door Campaigns will be used to create awareness and training on peace building and conflicts management will strongly equip the refugees with knowledge on the issues mentioned. Besides the campaigns, are dialogues involving recorded drama programwhich can be played on radio to educate the communities with regards to Covid-19 and Peace Building, trainings will be held in the seven villages of Ofua Zone. All selected locations for these dialogues will be carefully chosen based on the proposal guideline. These interactions will be documented, recorded and played in other parts of the country through radio stations/media outlets.
APINO will work in collaboration with the aforementioned community structures to undertaken follow up action plans, recommendation and promoting peace among the refugees various refugee settlements in Uganda.  APINO will train the religious leaders through the establishment of religious networks from the project sites to ensure that the messages are standardized, effective and clear. The trained members will use the key messages to carry out awareness and sensitization on Covid -19 and Peace Building and conflict management.
The peace building is particularly well-suited to undertaking advocacy because it is comprised of multiple organizations and individualswho can speak with one voice on a particular issue. A collective voice is often much stronger than a solitary voice, and speaking out collectively avoids backlash being directed at a lone individual or organization, especially when an issue is controversial or difficult. The media network will be used to help in conveying accurate information on Covid-19, peace issues, expose injustice, promote accountability, and generate dialogues, increase trust and confidence among the refugees, fulfill donor#s obligation, make APINO as an organization visible, educate the local community about available gender based violence services, communicate advocacy messages and raise awareness about issues and problems in the communities in which we work and the media also Say things we cannot. The Media Network established with the support of APINO as this will engage them in airing of jingles on radio stations and playing recorded drama in the mentioned project sites. The APINO will also work with local leaders, youths, men and various women Groups included in awareness and sensitization on Covid-19 through recorded drama, forums, focus groups discussions, Jingles and Workshops.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Action for Transformation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. HISTORY:
          Community Action for Transformation or CAFOT is started in August of 2017 desired to engage the refugees youth in particular and the host community in comprehensive peace building, Hygiene and sanitation promotion and advocating for a quality education as a mean of building resilience and health living among the south Sudanese and host communities. The organization was started by a group of young people with the vision; to create a safe and peaceful atmosphere for human race including his God-given plan, domestic and wild- life and to deliver socio-economic development. So far the organization has improved since its formation andit also has taken gender mainstreaming as co in achieving its vision through programming, planning, andimplementation.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS:       So far there is a resilient building among the refugee and the host community through the public forums that CAFOT already carried on since the beginning of 2018.There is trust building among the young people, youth are already getting into groups to start up small business as a means to fight poverty and building a stronger relationshipThrough our established school, the children are progressively moving in a right direction to face the future, this is meantto ensure illiteracy in removed completely in our society.3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE:Mission:  To see a reduced rate of the prevailing trauma, conflict and to build a health livingamong the refugees and host communities by provision of education, creation of awareness on hygiene and sanitation through participatory drama (forum theatre) and music.  a. Institutional objectives:1. To Open Adult literacy classes, Nursery and lower primary classes2. To empower the rural women by providing trainingson basic business entrepreneurship skills, and creation of income generating activities3. To create a flat form for communities to interact on societal issues that affect their living and adopt on the dynamics of the modern change as relates to positive resilience in community development.4. To promote Hygiene and sanitation, as wellas unity, equality with gender sensitivity, justice and everlasting peace in the community through advocacy and other measures where necessary5. To create awareness oncorruption, gender-based violence, promote leadership and good governance6. To promote social understanding among, youth, women, elderly, children and families as a whole, through creation of forum theatre, debates and dialogue this gives them an opportunity to share their own experiences7. To build the capacities of organized youth groups, drama groups, women associations, RWCs, religious leaders, Boda Boda associations, Taxi Drivers and brokers association, Market management committee, football clubs, local artists, water management committees, Hygiene promoters, Village girl child education promoters (VGCEP) among others through networking meetings and trainings to increase awareness to the grass root   a). Field(s) of activity:         1. Education: We use Physical education which is an integral part of educational program design to promote the optimum development of an individual physically, socially, emotionally, mentally, and spiritually through total body movement in the performance of properly selected physical activities. It is a process by which changes in the individual are brought about through movement#s experiences and it aims not only at physical development but is also concerned with education of the whole person through physical activities.       2. Hygiene and sanitation: Sanitation refers to public health conditions related to clean drinking water and adequate treatment and disposal of human excreta and sewage. Preventing human contact with feces is part of sanitation, as is hand washing with soap. Sanitation systems aim to protect human health by providing a clean environment that will stop the transmission of disease, especially through the fecal#oral route. For example, diarrhea, a main cause of malnutrition and stuntedgrowth in children, can be reduced through sanitation. There are many other diseases which are easily transmitted in communities that have low levels of sanitation, such as ascariasis (a type of intestinal worm infection or helminthiasis), cholera, hepatitis, polio, schistosomiasis, trachoma, to name just a few      3. Peace building awareness programs: Peacebuilding is an activity that aims to resolve injustice in nonviolent ways and to transform the cultural &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; structural conditions that generate deadly or destructive conflict. It revolves around developing constructive personal, group, and political relationships across ethnic, religious, class, national, and racial boundaries. This process includes violence prevention; conflict management, resolution, or transformation; and post-conflict reconciliation or trauma healing, i.e., before, during and after war.We are currently in Imvepi refugee settlement, but with a plan to reach Rhino and Bidibidi settlementsWho are the social actors that benefit from the work? We target youth, (men, women, girls and boys)4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING:       We work directly with the office of the prime minster who is a principle representative of the government on ground, the church leaders, and local chiefs andalready established associations including the line ministries. These actors are supporters of our programs and they act like technical advisors in the day today running of community activities.5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART       In the current board of director, out of seven members, the three are female. We have the Director who is a male and the program manager, while the position of the finance is a female , While the community mobilisers are a mixture of both male and female altogether.6.CURRENT BALANCE SHEET/FINANCIAL POSITION       We have not yet received much funding as a newly established organization apart from being funded on activities basis. This means we always relay on the contribution of our members and the volunteers.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-88136411" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-12">8000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">8000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-88136411" ref="DK-CVR-88136411">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">8000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Action for Transformation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05868-08:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05868"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Saving lives now &amp;future thru education"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001728"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
