<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="plannlno-ao" dstore:index="7" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-29T10:18:56.2534779+01:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-29T09:08:28.3804646Z" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ100087</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH First: Scaling up WASH SDG efforts: the first line of defence against COVID-19- Mozambique</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY
The WASH First programme in Mozambique started in 2020 and is part of the scaling-up efforts of the WASH SDG Consortium. Its main objective is to prevent further spread of COVID-19. Plan International Mozambique started the implementation of the programme in Mogovolas district, Nampula province. This area has been hit hard by the pandemic. The programme will organise awareness raising campaigns on COVID-19. It will also promote direct messaging and information sharing. Through the programme we will improve access to water, sanitation, handwashing facilities and (menstrual) hygiene products.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On March 22 2020 the Ministry of Health declared there was an outbreak of COVID-19 in the country. The virus was spreading quickly and Nampula province was severely affected. Located in the North, it is the most populated province and among the poorest with the lowest district-level WASH facilities. Cholera outbreaks and diarrhea are often reported. Hygiene practices are poor and only 10% of the population has access to handwashing facilities. Schools were closed, affecting almost eight million students across the country. Since July schools started reopening but the lack of sufficient WASH facilities was an obstacle to a safe opening of the schools.  
The COVID-19 crisis has exacerbated the pre-existing inequalities and poverty, affecting especially the most vulnerable and marginalised people. While it is acknowledged that good hygiene can slow the spread of the virus, the communities in the intervention area have poor access to WASH. This puts families at higher risk of infection and increases vulnerability of girls and women when they go to collect water. Women and girl do not have access to public health messages because they are not linked to information networks and their levels of literacy are low.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the program is:
Promotion of health-related hygiene practices to prevent further spread of COVID-19 in at-risk countries through awareness raising and improved access to WASH services

Result areas:
1.  Enhanced understanding of individuals, communities, health workers, schools and WASH service providers about  mitigation measures against COVID-19 transmission
2. Population at risk of Covid-19 have sufficient and constant access to commodities and consumables (i.e. handwashing facilities, disinfection equipment, soap, hygiene kits including menstrual health products) and personal protective equipment (PPEs)
3. Population at risk of COVID-19 have safe (considering safeguarding and security) access to Water and Sanitation services through the construction of new and repair of non-functional water facilities or through temporary/mobile services/supplies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Mozambique, through the Nampula Programme Unit, has a proven track record of supporting programmes across 24 communities in Mogovolas district. Plan has a strong experience in implementing WASH-related interventions.  A WASH consultant provides technical support on the implementation of Plan WASH projects. In addition, Plan will leverage on previous project experiences being implemented in Nampula in areas of hygiene, MHM and SRHR. The Nampula Programme Unit is carrying out COVID-19 prevention and hygiene awareness and community sensitisation on SRHR, as per its country COVID-19 response plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The end beneficiaries will be the most poor and vulnerable people living in  Mogovolas district, Nampula province that boarders Cabo Delgado province where violent incidents have been recorded causing a refugee flow into Nampula province.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique will implement the following activities on the 6 intervention strategies:

Intervention strategy 1: Awareness raising (campaigns and mass media campaigns) on COVID-19
&#x2022; Based on the rapid assessment, a hygiene behaviour communication plan will be developed. Careful
attention will be given when developing the messages to ensure they will trigger the emotions of people
and not just raise awareness. The messages developed will focus on positive emotions, highlighting the
health benefits if handwashing is done correctly and frequently and the benefits of protecting others
and not spreading the coronavirus.
&#x2022; Develop communication materials, including radio and TV spots. Mixed methods for mass messaging
will be used, including community radio, visual materials and TV spots, ensuring the communication
campaigns will expose vulnerable people at least three times to the messages, to increase their
capability and motivation to acquire good habits. The communications materials will contain illustrative
graphics focused on the geographical context (Nampula province settings &#x2013; houses, clothes, daily
activities) but discouraging stereotypes ( such as gender stereotypes).
&#x2022; Training sessions will be delivered to key hygiene promoters (government staff, community health
workers, community radio producers, teachers, community leaders) on the communication plan
and campaign approaches. The training will be conducted outdoors, respecting the government
regulations and Ministry of Health advices on social distancing and the number of participants.
&#x2022; The campaign will use stories, songs and demonstrations. It will be phased, focusing first on mass
communications to comply with the movement restrictions and social distancing.

Intervention strategy 2: Direct information sharing and messaging through home visits, courtyard
meetings and community meetings, where possible and in line with do no harm principles
&#x2022; Rolling out gender sensitive and inclusive communication campaign through outdoors sessions (when
schools re-open) and community sensitisation
&#x2022; Priority will be given to aligning the messages with the Ministry of Health to avoid confused
communications and disinformation. Adapt hygiene messages to promote positive gender relations
and avoid exacerbating negative gender stereotypes.
&#x2022; Do no harm promotion and support of existing child protection referral mechanism. We will promote
and protect the rights of children, especially girls, strengthening the existing referral mechanisms
(existing toll free hotlines), making use of community radio to raise awareness and promote no harm
practices wherever possible, using same platforms for HBC campaigns

Intervention strategy 3: Improving access to safe drinking water and water supply for handwashing, as
well as menstrual health and sanitation (including safe disposal of waste)
&#x2022; Geophysical studies will be carried out to assess suitable locations for drilling water boreholes.
&#x2022; Provision of water access in three communities.
&#x2022; For each borehole, a water committee will be formed and community members (half women and
half men) trained to maintain the water point and collect fees. This activity will be conducted in
collaboration with public works technicians. A training package on gender based violence and child
protection will be also provided.
&#x2022; Ensure that access is organised in a gender friendly and social inclusive way while taking in consideration
social distancing.

Intervention strategy 4: Improving access to safe handwashing facilities
&#x2022; Plan will promote no-cost or low cost handwashing stations such as tippy taps that families can set up
easily in their home. Tippy taps will allow family members to wash their hands with soap and poured
water for the right amount of time and using the correct technique.

Intervention strategy 5: Access to hygiene products such as soap, disinfectant, PPE and menstrual hygiene
products
&#x2022; Purchasing and distribution of hygiene kits and dignity/MHM kits reaching the most vulnerable.
Immediate intervention is needed for distribution of soap and hygiene kits for the poorest families.
These will be identified in coordination with the authorities, community leaders and local partners. Poor
adolescents girls and young women will receive dignity kits, including menstrual hygiene management
products, to boost their confidence and ensure dignity.

Intervention strategy 6: COVID-related coordination meetings with local government and other
stakeholders
&#x2022; The sub-programme interventions will be implemented in close coordination with the government and
formal and informal community leaders.
&#x2022; The sub-programme will also coordinate with government for consistency in messaging on COVID-19
prevention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional:
The program interventions will be implemented in close coordination with the government and formal and informal community leaders.
The program will also coordinate with government for consistency in messaging on COVID-1 prevention

Social:
The active participation of the target groups is essential to ensure that we respond to their specific needs.  The overall goal of this program is the &#x201C;promotion of health-related hygiene practices to prevent further spread of COVID-19 through awareness raising and improved access to WASH services.&#x201D; The intervention will ensure that the achievement of the SDG 6 goals does not come to a standstill in the intervention areas.
The program is inclusive and will adapt hygiene messages to promote positive gender relations and avoid exacerbating negative gender stereotypes.
It will further promote do no harm promotion principles and support existing child protection referral mechanism. The rights of children will be promoted and protected, especially girls&apos; rights, strengthening the existing referral mechanisms (existing toll free hotlines), making use of community radio to raise awareness and promote no harm practices wherever possible, using same platforms for HBC campaigns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-C" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water, Sanitation &amp; Hygiene</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 5" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THRIVE -Early Childhood Care and Development (including WASH) (ECCD)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">327406</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">22289</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="UB1291">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-29">200000</value>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-12-31T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">1562</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="kosten oktober 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-31">1491</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-11-30T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-30">1775</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41198890-Wash First" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0=Not measured; 1=Gender unaware; 2=Gender Neutral; 3=Gender Aware; 4=Gender Transformative. For measurement of KPI-6: Percentage of running programme activities that are gender-aware or gender-transformative</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.06" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="3.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of boys reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.04" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young women</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.07" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender transformative marker - design</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoring of the project design by the gender transformative marker of Plan International; 
gender blind (1), gender neutral (2), gender aware (3), gender transformative (4)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.11" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young men</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.08" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of girls reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.03" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender transformative marker - implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoring of the implementation phase by the gender transformative marker of Plan International; 
gender blind (1), gender neutral (2), gender aware (3), gender transformative (4)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.12" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to handwashing facilities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Estimated number of at risk population who have access to handwashing facilities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.2.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Estimated number of at risk population who have access to handwashing facilities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="8500.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 prevention &amp; response</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of PPEs that have been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Personal Protective Equipment includes protective items such as gloves, facial mask, detergent.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.5.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of PPEs that have been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="120.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hygiene kits (including menstrual health products) that has been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hygiene kits (including menstrual health products) that has been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4092.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="60.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached directly with awareness raising activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached directly with awareness raising activities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20000.00">
      <location ref="--"></location>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new, repaired, temporary and/or mobile handwashing facilities that are provided to the at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.2.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new, repaired, temporary and/or mobile handwashing facilities that are provided to the at risk population</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2092.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="60.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached through mass media</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.1" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached through mass media</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="24500.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of soaps, disinfection equipment that has been provided among at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.1" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of soaps, disinfection equipment that has been provided among at risk population</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2000.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of at risk population who are provided with soaps, disinfection equipment</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.2" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of at risk population who are provided with soaps, disinfection equipment</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2000.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of at risk population who were provided with hygiene kits</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of at Risk Population who are provided PPEs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.5.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity training for service providers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="60.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="60.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to drinking water</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of water point constructed of rehabilitated using programme funds</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="3.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of water point constructed of rehabilitated using programme funds</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using the water points constructed or rehabilitated</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="3.1.2." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using the water points constructed or rehabilitated</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="750.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using the water points constructed or rehabilitated</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="3.1.2." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using the water points constructed or rehabilitated</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="750.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
