<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="1520" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-23T23:40:28" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-23T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05868-07:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">APINO Saving Lives now &amp; future Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action for People in Need Organization(APINO) and DANIDA Strategic Partnership project will promote positive social change among South Sudanese refugees and host communities in Uganda and back in South Sudan. Peace building is a core agenda because without it society cannot be productive. Many South Sudanese were traumatized because of the conflicts that negatively affected them in various ways ranging from losing their livelihood as well their beloved one who got killed or died on the way from South Sudan as they try to find safety in the neighbouring Country Uganda.
To address the challenges, in 2016 South Sudanese Musician &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Activist Lupai Moses Cisona founded Lupai Music Foundation, a first initiative that worked to provide trauma healing and peace building activities inRhino settlement  Camp and Bidi Bidi through live music concerts and the first concert was held in Ofua 3, in Rhino Camp, it was a historical moment that later led to transformation of Lupai Music Foundation into Action for People In Need Organization that is whythe main office was established in Ofua 3, Rhino settlement Camp Arua district West Nile Region of Uganda. From single and informalinitiative, Lupai Music Foundation was transformed in  to community based organization now known as APINO, it has incorporated Men and Women, Girls and Boys who now own APINO.To balance gender, APINO focused more on women more especially on our livelihood component and education.
APINO#s thematic areas are Peace Building, Trauma Healing &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Reconciliation, Livelihood and Economic Empowerment. With its main Office in Ofua 3, Rhino Camp, APINO have field volunteers in Imvepi and Omugo Refugees Settlements in Arua District hence the areas of operations includes Rhino, Imvepi and Omugo. The beneficiaries of its interventions includes Women, Men, Youths, community leaders who are refugees and the host communities.This project aims to engage, inform, and create awareness among therefugees and equip them with knowledge on peace building and conflicts management, COVID-19 awareness and prevention measures through training of community peace and covid-19 volunteers, conducting community sensitization through awareness creation/sessions, radio talk shows, radio drama, conducting community engagement with refugees welfare councils and religious leaders, youths, men and women.The project implementation will be overseen by the Executive Board while being implemented by the Executive Director (ED), Program Coordinator, Project Officer (PO), and the Peace and Covid-19 Community Volunteers (PCVs), and Finance Officer. All these individuals have extensive experience in working with the communities and supervising programming, documentation. The implementing partner (APINO) will require funds from the donor to facilitate activities and procurement of project items. APINO will coordinate and facilitate all other project activities as listed above under each objective. All the project beneficiaries will be mobilized to assist and participate in the awarenesscreation on Covid-19 and engagement on Peace Building and Conflict Management among refugees# members.Covid-19 door to door Campaigns will be used to create awareness and training on peace building and conflicts management will strongly equip the refugees with knowledge on the issues mentioned. Besides the campaigns, are dialogues involving recorded drama program which can be played on radio to educate the communities with regards to Covid-19 and Peace Building, trainings will be held in theseven villages of Ofua Zone. All selected locations for these dialogues will be carefully chosen based on the proposal guideline. These interactions will be documented, recorded and played in other parts of the country through radio stations/media outlets.APINO will work in collaboration with the aforementioned community structures to undertaken follow up action plans, recommendation and promoting peace among the refugees various refugee settlements in Uganda.  APINO will train the religious leaders through the establishment of religious networks from the project sites to ensure that the messages are standardized, effective and clear. The trained members will use the key messages to carry out awareness and sensitization on Covid -19 and Peace Building and conflict management.Thepeace building is particularly well-suited to undertaking advocacy because it is comprised of multiple organizations and individuals who can speak with one voice on a particular issue. A collective voice is often much stronger than a solitary voice, and speaking out collectively avoids backlash being directed at a lone individual or organization, especially when an issue is controversial or difficult. The media network will be used to help in conveying accurate information on Covid-19, peace issues, expose injustice, promote accountability, and generate dialogues, increase trust and confidence among the refugees, fulfill donor#s obligation, make APINOas an organization visible, educate the local community about available gender based violence services, communicate advocacy messages and raise awareness about issues and problems in the communities in which we work and the media also Say things we cannot. The Media Network established with the support of APINO as this will engage them in airing of jingles on radio stations and playing recorded drama in the mentioned project sites. The APINO will also work with local leaders, youths, men and various women Groups included in awareness and sensitization on Covid-19 through recorded drama, forums, focus groups discussions, Jingles and Workshops.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTION FOR PEOPLE IN NEED ORGANISAT APINO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Many South Sudanese were traumatized because of the conflicts that negatively affected them in various ways ranging from losing their livelihood as well their beloved one who got killed or died on the way from South Sudan as they try to find safety in the neighboring Country Uganda.

To address the challenges, in 2016 South Sudanese Musician &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Activist Lupai Moses Cisona founded Lupai Music Foundation, a first initiative that worked to provide trauma healing and peace building activities in Rhino Campand Bidi Bidi through live music concerts and the first concert was held in Ofua 3, in Rhino Camp, it was a historic moment that later led to transformation of Lupai Music Foundation into Action for People In Need Organization that is why the main office was established in Ofua 3, Rhino Camp. From single and informal initiative, Lupai Music Foundation was transformed in to community based organization now known as APINO, it has incorporated Men and Women, Girls and Boys who now own APINO. To balance gender,APINO focused more on women more especially on our livelihood component and education.2. ACHIEVEMENTSWhat have been the principal results in the past three yearsthat contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys sufferingfrom poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?Over the three years from 2016 to 2019, APINO implemented number of activities in the refugee settlements, and these included education, women economic empowerment and trauma healing projects. Education project, APINO supported 10 unaccompanied children in private schools, 15 women with small scale business loan with no interest who are now carrying on their business, APINO further supported and distributed sanitary pads to 89 adolescent aged girls and reaches 5,000 others with information on sexual reproductive health through peace concerts. Peace building, Trauma healing and reconciliation APINO implemented peaceful co-existence aimed at promoting spirit of dialogues among the refugees and the host communities through music concerts, dramas. In addition to that, trauma healing and restoration of hope among the refugees was also conducted. A total of 15 live music concerts were conducted in six refugee settlements (Ofua, Ocea, Imvepi, Omugo, Swinga, Bidi Bidi and Koboko reaching 50,000 refugees and host communities. APINO further conducted 4 radio talk shows in Arua Uganda and Juba which discussed issues of youths, women and community leader#s involvement in peace building, promoting access to basic education, livelihoods and economic empowerment of women with business skills. As it was APINO#s first initiative to promote peace building initiative through Music and art, we arehappy to see many CBOs now adopting the same methodology which is really impacting positively among the South Sudanese refugee and host communities.3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSEMission: What is the current purpose of the Organisation?APINO#s purpose is to promote positive social change among South Sudanese refugees and the host communities in Uganda and back in South Sudan. Peace building isa core agenda because without it society cannot be productive.Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?APINO seek to achieve peaceful South Sudan communities who shall regard one another as brothers and sisters, live peaceful and be able to engage in economic activities to promote self-reliance among themselves and be ableto live decent lives. In addition, the institution seek to promote Art and film production build music centre that offer training and mentorship for upcoming talent as well the community members who shall share experiences and build resilience against negative practices that will take people back to the old dark days.Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areasin which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?Peace Building, TraumaHealing &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Reconciliation, Livelihood and Economic Empowerment among others are our principal thematic areas. With its main Office in Ofua 3, Rhino Camp, APINO have field volunteers in Imvepi and Omugo Refugees Settlements in Arua District hence the areasof operations includes Rhino, Imvepi and Omugo. The beneficiaries of our activities includes Women, Men, Youths, community leaders who are refugees and the host communities.4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGAnalyse the environment in which the organisationworks? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?A scan of the environment through the use of PESTEL has enabled APINO tounderstand the global, regional, national and local context hence the environment for the organization#s operation is safe and secure.APINO will closely collaborate with Office of the Prime Minister, Refugee Desk, Office of the Camp Commander, and other government institutions such as the Local Government and Arua District authorities. They will be empowered to conduct on site visits and give recommendations. APINO will also involve refugees and host communities# business community who shall play role in providing goods and services. In addition to the government institutions, APINO will collaborate with both International, national and local organizations (OXFAM,YSAT, Civil Society Organizations, learning institution, media groups and other UN agencies to share project#s progress, share information and potential synergy areas. The uniqueness of APINO is that, the organization is a community owned and community based.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-88136411" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.97271 31.39571</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-23">6000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-23">15000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-01">6000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-88136411" ref="DK-CVR-88136411">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-01">6000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTION FOR PEOPLE IN NEED ORGANISAT APINO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">8000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-88136411" ref="DK-CVR-88136411">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">8000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTION FOR PEOPLE IN NEED ORGANISAT APINO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">7000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-88136411" ref="DK-CVR-88136411">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">7000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTION FOR PEOPLE IN NEED ORGANISAT APINO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05868-07:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05868"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Saving lives now &amp;future thru education"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001728"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
