<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2015" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T23:30:16" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-18:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NUWOSO COVID-19 Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NUWOSO and ODOWOL consortium will implement the below activities under COVID-19 project:

1. Sensitize estimated 27,272 people on COVID-19 virus    Project shall use media approach by partnering with Local FM radio station TEMBO FM for talkshow, radio spot Messages and Road drive using van with public address system and Boda-Boda talk using megaphone to educate public on COVID-19 virus prevention and case management.2. Procure and install  20 hand washing facilities in public places to promote hygiene and  prevention of  COVID-19 virus infections    Project shall procure and establish hand washing facility in public places like, markets, health facilities, water points, Boarder points, meeting places, Police office, Army barracks and disinfectors (jik) and soap to promote handwashing practices for hygiene and prevention of COVID-19 virus spread and infections.3. Procure and allocate protective gears to 70 COVID-19 virus task force teams and project staffs.    The project shall procure and allocate the protective gears including Gumboots, Gaggles, apron, disinfectors, Face Masks, Antiseptics for hand hygiene, Spray pump, Gloves to 70 COVID-19 virus task force teams and  project staffs  to prevent them from COVID-19 virus infections risk and vulnerability during conducting project activities4. Support District established referral services and networks for effective and timely COVID-19 virus response and case managementProject shall support established District COVID-19 virus referral services  and networks from community-heath facility for effective and timely COVID-19 virus response and case management through facilitation  for the operation of the District Ambulance 24/7, facilitation for health worker Incharge of referral services, Facilitation of  District officials for support supervision to  the established COVID-19 virus treatment centers in Padibe health center IV and Madiopayi health center IV for quality COVID-19 virus services delivery.5. Support  2 established COVID-19 virus  treatment centers with necessary logistics for effective and quality care and response servicesProject shall provide necessary logistics in the 2 targeted established COVID-19 virus treatment centres in Padibe health center IV and Madiopayi health centre IV for effective and quality care and response services.6. Support established District and sub-county level COVID-19 virus response coordination, communication and networking for effective and timely COVID-19 virus response services.Project shall support the District officials for support supervision and enforcement of the COVID-19 virus regulation, support monthly District and sub-county COVID-19 virus taskforce coordination meetings,  support function of the COVID-19 virus taskforce team for effective and timely COVID-19 virus response and case management.7. Conduct 2 hours Project Inception and orientation meeting.Project shall organize 2 hours inception and orientation meeting targeting District Health Officer(DHO), District Education Officer(DEO), Chief Administrative Officer (CAO), LCV, District Health Educator(DHE), District Water Officer(DWO), Incharge of Padibe H/C IV and Madiopayi Health Center  IV, District Health Inspector(DHI), Resident District Commissioner(RDC) and District Internal Security Officer (DISO) and District Police Commander(DPC) and NGOs partners, NUWOSO &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; ODOWOL Board of Directors to share the project implementation plan and their roles and responsibilities in the project implementation.8. Conduct 1Join project performance Monitoring, Evaluation and LearningProject shall conduct 1 join performance Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning with the District monitoring team including  assessing  the project achievements and best practices employed in theproject implementationin order to achieved the project desired goal and objectives</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NORTHERN UGANDA WIDOWS &amp; ORPHANS SU NUWOSO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Uganda Widows and Orphans Support Organization (NUUWOSO) was formed to address the challenges affecting women and childrenin Northern Ugnada in areas of Health, Poverty, Disaster and Rights Issues, NUWOSO was formed in 2005 by the Late Mother ATARO JULIAN and other 12 Women who were affected by HIV/AIDS and Northern Ugnada conflict in Agago County. NUWOSO started as community groupsin 2005 with the name Patongo Widows and Orphans Support Group (PWOSG) who came out to support themselves in order to address the impacts of HIV/AIDS and War on women and children,  later the group though of extending their memberships and services to other sub-counties and communities by registering with government and this make them to think border for the name touse for registration at district level  as CBO, them chosen to used the name #Widows and Orphans Support organization(WOSO)#, the group completed their registration with Pader District local Government  Reg. No. 014 and they  became CBO, after when Agagodistrict was coved out of Pader in 2010 by act of parliament , The group registered with Agago District Local Government in 2017 as CBO Reg. No 087. After when the groupthough of expanding their services countrywide, they started the registering the organization with Ministry of Internal Affair but during the NGO name preservation with the office of Ministry of Internal Affair the name WOSO is already existing/ being used by another organization, then the group decided to change the name to be Northern Uganda Widows and Orphans support Organization (NUWOSO) and was approved and preserved and late group applied to NGO Board for national registration in January 2019 and in July 2019 the organization got registered as NNGO with registration No:  INDR138721925NB and mandated to operate countywide with the programmes of health, Economic and livelihoods, Education, Social protection, Environmental  conservation and Disaster management

2. ACHIEVEMENTSWhat have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?2018 NUWOSO in consortium with FOKAPAWA, AVCT, and PCCO implemented WASH in Agago district in flood affected sub-counties (Patongo, Omot, Lirapalwo andAdilang), with funding from OXFAM. 750 severely affected H/H supported, 4 primary school supported, 1 institution (Prison) supported, estimated average of 7268 peopleserved (4894 Females and 2374 Males)2017/2018 NUWOSO with support from PEPFAR-Uganda 642 prisoners in Patongo Government prison served (456 Males and 2374 Females).2012-2015 with funding support from JCRC-CSF reached out to 28,456 people (17,297 Femalesand 11159 Males) with HIV/AIDS prevention, care, treatments and support services in 4 sub-counties (Patongo, Adilang, Lirapalwo and Omot) in Agago district3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSEMission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit fromthe work?NUWOSO MissionNUWOSO exist to empower and build resilient women and children in Uganda through Health Services, Economic and Livelihood Support, Education Support, Social Protection, Environmental Conservation and Disaster ManagementNUWOSO Objectives1. To increase access and utilization of HIV prevention services among most at risk key population (MARPS) in Uganda.2. To increase access and utilization of HIV/AIDS care, treatment and support services among adults, adolescent and children living with HIV/AIDS in Uganda.3. To increase access and utilization of Sexual and Reproductive Health (SRH) Rights and services among adolescent#s girls and young women age 10-35 years in Uganda4. To empower women, OVC households and youth with sustainable economic and Livelihoods for improved  income, nutrition and food security  in Uganda5. To provide social protection services and support to women and children in Uganda6. To provide formal and non-formal education services and support to OVC/youths in Uganda.7. To promote and protect environment in Uganda.8. To sensitize community on disaster preperness and response to crisis  to save-lives and alleviate suffering of women and children in Uganda9. To improve organizational effectiveness and efficiency for a better quality servicesNUWOSOProgramme THEMATIC areas1. Health Program2. Economic &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Livelihoods Program3. Social Protection Program4. Education Program5. Environmental Conservation Program6. Disaster Management ProgramNUWOSO Geographical areasAgago, Pader, Oyam. Omoro, Oyam, Lamwo, Amuru, Abim, Karenga, Nwoya,Social actors that benefit from the NUWOSO work# Women, Children, Youths and Men# Community members# Local leaders# Cultural and religious institutions# Community groups# Government# Private sectors# Development  partners4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGAnalyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?1. Private sectors (Medias, Business communities)2. Government3. Development partnersThe private sectors like media play roles ineducating public on NUWOSO services and issues affecting them, business communities support NUWOSO with good and services provisions, Government provide technical support, partnerships, resources , development partners play role in provision of support both technical,human resources, finance and logistic etcThe position of NUWOSO is unique in a sense that, NUWOSO have the shared vision  and mission with these social actors, good partnerships and coordination/ working relation , resource sharing5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)How are authority and responsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number of people in each position, and if they are men or women.General Assembly (GA) is asupreme governing organ of NUWOSO which comprises of 36 members (26 women and 10 Men), they meet once every year to get feedback on the organization achievements, review constitution and policies and make amendment where necessary, approve annual work plan andbudget.Board of Directors comprise of 9 members (6 women and 3 men) headed by Chairperson (Female) assisted by Vice Chairperson and they meet quarterly, they key formulate policies and implementation, oversee the management staff and organizationdevelopment, they report to the General Assembly annually.Management staff or secretariat comprise of 3 staff (2 Males and 1 Female) , they are  headed by Programme Coordinator, their roles is to ensure organization programmes day-to-day running/implementation and management, resource mobilization for organization development,  they report to Board of Directors, relevant stakeholders and Donor(s) quarterly and annually.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-04">27138</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">27138</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">27138</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NORTHERN UGANDA WIDOWS &amp; ORPHANS SU NUWOSO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-18:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16363"></target>
     <actual value="24327"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10909"></target>
     <actual value="30909"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16363"></target>
     <actual value="170289"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10909"></target>
     <actual value="216363"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
