<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2404" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-08-05T23:30:58" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-08-05T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-20:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NUWOSO Acholi HRGF COVID-19 project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Uganda Widows and Orphans Support Organization(NUWOSO) in a consortium with Organisation for development of women in Lamwo(ODOWOL) will continue implementing the Covid-19 project in the districts of Pader, Agago and Lamwo and also providing support to Hosting PLATFORM FOR ACHOLI HUMANITARIAN ACTORS (PALHAs) through coordination and collaboration.

The Project goal: Reduced risks andvulnerability to COVID-19 and GBV/land conflict  incidence in the 3 focused Districts in Acholi Region by end of September 2020Project objective 1:To sensitize and support community and stakeholders on COVID-19 and GBV/land conflict prevention and response services in Agago, Pader and Lamwo District in Acholi Region by end of September 2020Project outcome 1.1: Reduced risk and vulnerability to COVID-19 infections and GBV/land conflict incidence and it related death in the 3 focused Districts in Acholi Region by September 2020Project output 1.1.1:-Community and stakeholders sensitized on COVID-19 preventionand GBV/land conflict prevention and response in 3 focused districts in Acholi RegionThe consortium will support the following activities:Activity 1.1.1.1: Support Monthly(12) District Disaster Management Committee (DDMC)/COVID-19 Taskforce/GBV working groups Coordination meeting including enforcing COVID-19, GBV /land conflict prevention and response regulations.Activity 1.1.1.2: Provide soap to 5000 households for hand washing to promote hygiene and prevention of COVID-19 infections risk and vulnerabilityActivity 1.1.1.3: Support 60 lactating mothers and their babies in quarantine centres with supplementary feeding options for babies to improve the health and quality of life of babies.Project objective 2:To support the Platform for Acholi Humanitarian Actors(PALHAs) coordination, communication and networking for meaningful engagement in COVID-19 and GBV/land conflict  response in Agago, Pader and Lamwo District in Acholi Region by end of September 2020Project outcome 2.1: Active Platformfor Acholi Humanitarian Actors(PALHAs) coordination, communication, networking and  engagement in COVID-19 and GBV/land conflict response in the 3 focused Districts in Acholi Region by end of September 2020Project output 2.1.1: Platform for Acholi Humanitarian Actors (PALHAs) coordination, communication, networking and engagement in COVID-19 and GBV /land conflict response in the 3 focused Districts in Acholi Region supported.Activity 2.1.1.1: Conduct profiling of 20 PALHAs members to update the PALHAs members# data based. The project will profile the PALHAs members organization in the three focused districts in Acholi region, partners will include;- Forum or Kalongo Parish Women Association (FOKAPAWA), Patongo Community Counseling Outreach(PCCO), Acholi Volunteer for Transformation(AVCT), Child Hope Foundation, Agago Youth Network, Women and Youth Empowerment (WAYE), Friend of Orphans, Pader/Agago NGO forum, African Research for Development(ARID), Christian Counseling Fellowship(CCF)-Pader SURUDA, Organization for the development of women in Lamwo-ODOWOL, Lamwo District NGO network etc.Activity 2.1.1.2: Conduct one(1)PALHAs member coordination and information sharing meetings in project lifeActivity 2.1.1.3: Support creation and servicing of PALHAs website, Facebook and what-up group for coordination, communication and information sharing, networking and publication of PALHAs and it contribution in the COVID-19 and GBV/land conflict prevention and response in Acholi region. PALHAs shall conduct other meetings using social media means like phone conference, Skype, zoom, what-up to enhance PALHAs information sharing.Activity 2.1.1.4: Brand 3 Banners and 49 T-shirts for visibility and publication of PALHAs.Activity 2.1.1.5: Conduct two (2) radio talk shows and 4 weeksradio spot message on Local FM Radio to enable PALHAs publicize their work and sensitize estimated 96,422 people including refugee in Lamwo on COVID-19 and GBV/land conflict prevention and response. The district leaders and PALHAschairperson  will be brought on radio during talk shows and this will create a platform for interactions #Community-Leaders interaction#-social accountabilityActivity 3.1:Conduct half-a day project inception meeting with the District stakeholders to share the project plan and role of PALHAs in COVID-19 and GBV/land conflict  prevention and response in Acholi regionActivity 4.1:Conduct one (1) Project join  Monitoring, Evaluation and LearningMonitoring, Evaluation and learning will be conducted jointly comprises of representative of District leaderships, representative of NUWOSO Board member and OXFAM representative to share the project performance and learning but if COVID-19 persist, then the monitoring will be done only by the District leadershiprepresentative and NUWOSO Board while OXFAM will do through phone calls.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NORTHERN UGANDA WIDOWS &amp; ORPHANS SU NUWOSO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Uganda Widows and Orphans Support Organization (NUUWOSO) was formed to address the challenges affecting women and childrenin Northern Ugnada in areas of Health, Poverty, Disaster and Rights Issues, NUWOSO was formed in 2005 by the Late Mother ATARO JULIAN and other 12 Women who were affected by HIV/AIDS and Northern Ugnada conflict in Agago County. NUWOSO started as community groupsin 2005 with the name Patongo Widows and Orphans Support Group (PWOSG) who came out to support themselves in order to address the impacts of HIV/AIDS and War on women and children,  later the group though of extending their memberships and services to other sub-counties and communities by registering with government and this make them to think border for the name touse for registration at district level  as CBO, them chosen to used the name #Widows and Orphans Support organization(WOSO)#, the group completed their registration with Pader District local Government  Reg. No. 014 and they  became CBO, after when Agagodistrict was coved out of Pader in 2010 by act of parliament , The group registered with Agago District Local Government in 2017 as CBO Reg. No 087. After when the groupthough of expanding their services countrywide, they started the registering the organization with Ministry of Internal Affair but during the NGO name preservation with the office of Ministry of Internal Affair the name WOSO is already existing/ being used by another organization, then the group decided to change the name to be Northern Uganda Widows and Orphans support Organization (NUWOSO) and was approved and preserved and late group applied to NGO Board for national registration in January 2019 and in July 2019 the organization got registered as NNGO with registration No:  INDR138721925NB and mandated to operate countywide with the programmes of health, Economic and livelihoods, Education, Social protection, Environmental  conservation and Disaster management

2. ACHIEVEMENTSWhat have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?2018 NUWOSO in consortium with FOKAPAWA, AVCT, and PCCO implemented WASH in Agago district in flood affected sub-counties (Patongo, Omot, Lirapalwo andAdilang), with funding from OXFAM. 750 severely affected H/H supported, 4 primary school supported, 1 institution (Prison) supported, estimated average of 7268 peopleserved (4894 Females and 2374 Males)2017/2018 NUWOSO with support from PEPFAR-Uganda 642 prisoners in Patongo Government prison served (456 Males and 2374 Females).2012-2015 with funding support from JCRC-CSF reached out to 28,456 people (17,297 Femalesand 11159 Males) with HIV/AIDS prevention, care, treatments and support services in 4 sub-counties (Patongo, Adilang, Lirapalwo and Omot) in Agago district3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSEMission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit fromthe work?NUWOSO MissionNUWOSO exist to empower and build resilient women and children in Uganda through Health Services, Economic and Livelihood Support, Education Support, Social Protection, Environmental Conservation and Disaster ManagementNUWOSO Objectives1. To increase access and utilization of HIV prevention services among most at risk key population (MARPS) in Uganda.2. To increase access and utilization of HIV/AIDS care, treatment and support services among adults, adolescent and children living with HIV/AIDS in Uganda.3. To increase access and utilization of Sexual and Reproductive Health (SRH) Rights and services among adolescent#s girls and young women age 10-35 years in Uganda4. To empower women, OVC households and youth with sustainable economic and Livelihoods for improved  income, nutrition and food security  in Uganda5. To provide social protection services and support to women and children in Uganda6. To provide formal and non-formal education services and support to OVC/youths in Uganda.7. To promote and protect environment in Uganda.8. To sensitize community on disaster preperness and response to crisis  to save-lives and alleviate suffering of women and children in Uganda9. To improve organizational effectiveness and efficiency for a better quality servicesNUWOSOProgramme THEMATIC areas1. Health Program2. Economic &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Livelihoods Program3. Social Protection Program4. Education Program5. Environmental Conservation Program6. Disaster Management ProgramNUWOSO Geographical areasAgago, Pader, Oyam. Omoro, Oyam, Lamwo, Amuru, Abim, Karenga, Nwoya,Social actors that benefit from the NUWOSO work# Women, Children, Youths and Men# Community members# Local leaders# Cultural and religious institutions# Community groups# Government# Private sectors# Development  partners4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGAnalyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?1. Private sectors (Medias, Business communities)2. Government3. Development partnersThe private sectors like media play roles ineducating public on NUWOSO services and issues affecting them, business communities support NUWOSO with good and services provisions, Government provide technical support, partnerships, resources , development partners play role in provision of support both technical,human resources, finance and logistic etcThe position of NUWOSO is unique in a sense that, NUWOSO have the shared vision  and mission with these social actors, good partnerships and coordination/ working relation , resource sharing5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)How are authority and responsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number of people in each position, and if they are men or women.General Assembly (GA) is asupreme governing organ of NUWOSO which comprises of 36 members (26 women and 10 Men), they meet once every year to get feedback on the organization achievements, review constitution and policies and make amendment where necessary, approve annual work plan andbudget.Board of Directors comprise of 9 members (6 women and 3 men) headed by Chairperson (Female) assisted by Vice Chairperson and they meet quarterly, they key formulate policies and implementation, oversee the management staff and organizationdevelopment, they report to the General Assembly annually.Management staff or secretariat comprise of 3 staff (2 Males and 1 Female) , they are  headed by Programme Coordinator, their roles is to ensure organization programmes day-to-day running/implementation and management, resource mobilization for organization development,  they report to Board of Directors, relevant stakeholders and Donor(s) quarterly and annually.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.91629 33.35788</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-05">25269</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">25269</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">25269</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NORTHERN UGANDA WIDOWS &amp; ORPHANS SU NUWOSO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-20:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="57853"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="38569"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="57853"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="38569"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
