<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2125" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-14T23:40:59" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06509-02:SO</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-COVID-19 Pandemic II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Solarization of two existing water sources   in Baki and Saylac districts of Awdal benefiting more than 10,000 people and their livestock. Awdal is one of the regions affected by COVID19 as it connects Somaliland to Djibouti. The majority of people are dependent pity trades, small scale irrigation, and livestock, most of these activities have been affected, and communities reported a reduction of income. Existing water supply sources are mainly powered by a diesel generator that are purchased from the tariffs collected from the users. Associated water tariffs are sky rocking as access to diesel has reduced as restrictions are imposed on public transport. Out of the many strategic water sources, two sources are selected, supplying water for villages affected by COVID19 in Somaliland. Oxfam will install a solar system for these wells, and the action will reduce the cost of water tariff and increase community use of water for different purposes include handwashing.
# Build the capacity of the WASH committees managing the solarizedse water sources by providing necessary tools and training them on both technical skill and financial management. This action will be led by the ministry of water department of scheme management. As we mobilize for the two sources an additional two boreholes within the sameareas will also be invited for the training. These will help to maximize use of expert time, cover nearby villages with capacity building plan and increase value for money by targeting more with same budget.
# Support Somaliland Ministry of Water Development to ministry of water to finalize   the design and construction for WASH facilities to be shared with all WASH Cluster members in Somaliland. The national WASH cluster has prioritized this action as per the request from ministry and Oxfam will contribute for this action. The budget will be used to cover some of the consultancy fees or provide expertise to help them finalize the work.# Provide safeprogramming training for WaSH committees, district administrations, women groups other key stakeholders including traditional leaders    .# Protection awareness raising including community discussions on protection impact to address stigma and promotion of the call centre hotline   (already operational) to increase access to covid19 services for affected communities    .# Government capacity building/strengthen social safety net system in Somaliland : we will build the capacity of the government to be able to lead and coordinate Somaliland safety net program. Somalia launched safety net project called bahnano at Mogadishu but this has not been cascaded to Somaliland and Puntland. The government staff responsible for this are unable to run safety net due to their limited capacity. The project will target technical staff from the government and create enabling environment in the form of institutional capacity building including training of key staff, support implementation of beneficiaries selection and running coordination mechanisms smoothly.  Oxfam Somalia is implementing social safety net activity under GFFO top up. Under this activity the project aims improving supports to HHs in urban areas particularly COVID19 affected poorest or most vulnerable to prevent them to fall to poverty and destitution trap, manage COVID19 economic and social shocks and advance their lives &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; livelihoods. The government capacity in Somaliland on social safety net is to grow and as part of appeal fund, Oxfam will contribute to strengthening/establishing social protection system that leads COVID19 response project. Oxfam will partner with Somaliland Ministry of Employment, Social and Family as socialprotection responsible government body. Somaliland government capacity is yet to grow and this project will address this gap while also coordinating with other implementing agencies to strengthen their capacity to be able to lead social assistance and provide at scale in the future to its society as a right. The project creates an opportunity for governments to become the standard responders to large scale crises.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2004 Oxfam Novib set up a Liaison Office in Nairobi, Kenya in order to support the Strengthening Somali Civil Society Program, at the request of the EU. This request was based on Oxfam Novib&apos;s work in Somalia to date, but intended to be more widely directed atthe entire civil society sector and the specific context in which it is operating in a post-conflict country. The program started with consulting local organisations in Somalia and Somaliland to get a complete picture of the sectors and regions where they are active, the challenges they face and the relationship between civil society, local political structures and the private sector. A program was then developed to strengthen the institutional development of Oxfam Novib&apos;s partners and those of other Oxfams, as well as a range of new NGOs.
In the first year local consultants were trained in Somalia. They were then seconded to civil society organisations to build their capacity in financial and organisational management. Furthermore, workshops were organised on specific themes suchas human rights and the role of civil society in the Somali context. The Liaison Office is now going to support the expansion of the program, focussing on strengthening both organisation and project management, while facilitating more training in the fields of civic education, governance, human rights and women&apos;s rights, HIV and AIDS and child protection.
Over the years, the Somalia Country Office has expanded its intervention on short term humanitarian response as well as development development interventions. In 2015/2016, a decision was reached to move the Country Programme operation, which was largely in Nairobi, from Nairobi to Hargeisa. The country office has a small office in Nairobi , Kenya and large operations office in Hargeisa, Somaliland.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-14">166554</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-14">192016</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">166554</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">47495</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">144521</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">144521</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRA Programme Expenditures Country Offic</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06509-02:SO">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007052"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Somalia HECA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06509"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="COVID-19 Pandemic II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002195"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
