<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="atnf-activities" dstore:index="12" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-58279199-DGISQ3-2020-report</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-58279199" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS Q3 Activity Report 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNI has committed to deliver the following Core Objectives.

Core Objective 1
Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020.
Core Objective 2
Publish comprehensive analysis of companies&apos; breast-milk substitutes (BMS) marketing policies and practices in both Global and Spotlight Indexes.
Core Objective 3
Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2019. 
Core Objective 4
Publish Product Profiles for all India Spotlight Indexes. 
Core Objective 5 
Extend outreach activities for different stakeholder groups, particularly investors, to amplify impact.
Core Objective 6 
Develop action research activities to advance thinking and practice in key areas.
Core Objective 7 
Develop measurement and evaluations.
Core Objective 8
Conduct a feasibility study on expansion and innovation. 
Additional Objectives

ATNF also sees various options for expansion, on top of the Core Objectives, for which additional funding would be needed. These include:

Additional Objective 1 
Developing one or more Global Indexes that assesses the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g. retailers, food service companies, fast food chains.
Additional Objective 2 
Development of new Spotlight Indexes for other priority countries.
Additional Objective 3 
Further development of complementary verification-type activities, such as the Product Profile (that could be expanded to assess labelling compliance and marketing spending; more or wider BMS marketing assessments, etc.).

Extra activities 2020-2022

With the additional funding support from FCDO as per amendment No. 01/2020, signed April 16th 2020, to the ongoing Accountable Grant for this project (no. 300590) ATNI will embark on the following extra activities: 

1. Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020.
2. Private sector commitment monitoring hub supporting 2020 GNS/Nutrition for Growth (N4G), 2021 FSS and World Health Organization (WHO) starting August 2020. 
3. Investor coalition starting October 2020. 
4. Workforce nutrition action research starting January 2021. 
5. Action research to assess inequities in nutritional qualities of companies&apos; product portfolios across markets starting January 2021. 
6. Country approach starting July 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-58279199" crs-channel-code="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation (ATNF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This document presents the progress from July to September 2020 on the activities for which DGIS contracted the Access to Nutrition Foundation (ATNF, Grant reference number - 4000000128). It is structured in line with the Objectives for the Access to Nutrition Initiative (ATNI) as in the funding proposal.
In the upcoming quarterly reports, ATNI will provide an update on the development of the activities as applicable.
[Core objectives and additional objectives, which are not relevant for the timeframe of this activity report, have been marked with a * in the Objectives Overview and are further excluded from this report].

Objectives Overview
ATNI has committed to deliver the following Core Objectives.

Objectives highlighted with a * will not be reported on as they are not applicable for this reporting period. 

Core Objective 1	
Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020.
Core Objective 2
Publish comprehensive analysis of companies&apos; breast-milk substitutes (BMS) marketing policies and practices in both Global and Spotlight Indexes.
Core Objective 3
Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2019. 
Core Objective 4
Publish Product Profiles for all India Spotlight Indexes. *
Core Objective 5 
Extend outreach activities for different stakeholder groups, particularly investors, to amplify impact.
Core Objective 6 
Develop action research activities to advance thinking and practice in key areas.
Core Objective 7 
Develop measurement and evaluations.
Core Objective 8
Conduct a feasibility study on expansion and innovation. *

Additional Objectives

ATNF also sees various options for expansion, on top of the Core Objectives, for which additional funding would be needed. These include:

Additional Objective 1 
Developing one or more Global Indexes that assesses the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g. retailers, food service companies, fast food chains.
Additional Objective 2 
Development of new Spotlight Indexes for other priority countries.
Additional Objective 3 
Further development of complementary verification-type activities, such as the Product Profile (that could be expanded to assess labelling compliance and marketing spending; more or wider BMS marketing assessments, etc.).

Extra activities 2020-2022

With the additional funding support from FCDO as per amendment No. 01/2020, signed April 16th 2020, to the ongoing Accountable Grant for the DFID project &#x2018;Sustaining Action On Nutrition&#x2019; (no. 300590) ATNI will embark on the following extra activities: 

1. Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020.
2. Private sector commitment monitoring hub supporting 2020 GNS/Nutrition for Growth (N4G), 2021 FSS and World Health Organization (WHO) starting August 2020. 
3. Investor coalition starting October 2020. * 
4. Workforce nutrition action research starting January 2021. *
5. Action research to assess inequities in nutritional qualities of companies&apos; product portfolios across markets starting January 2021. *
6. Country approach starting July 2021. *
Progress on relevant objectives for &#x2013;June-September 2020

Core Objective 1: Progress Global Indexes
Global Index 
In the third quarter of 2020, selected companies for the Global Index 2021 continued engaging with ATNI. By the end of September, ATNI&#x2019;s data collection platform opened to 22 out of 25 companies. At this stage, 77% of these companies have directly engaged on the platform, either by providing comments or submitting additional evidence in response to the assessment. 
To further its regular engagement, ATNI organized three informative webinar sessions attended by a total of 33 participants. Moreover, ATNI set up several calls with companies who requested guidance on specific assessment-related topics. 
The Product Profile, which, in this iteration, will be integrated in Category B of the Index, progressed through several stages. Companies provided feedback on the scope of countries and product categories selected for the assessment. Based on this information, ATNI&#x2019;s research partner, The George Institute for Global Health (TGI), generated a list of products per company. The respective product lists were shared with companies during the month of September. 
Within a six-week period, companies are asked to verify the accuracy of the product list and to provide information on products that are missing. This verification includes the provision of nutrition information, and more specifically: Energy (kcal or kJ/100g), Protein (g/100g), Total fat (g/100g), Carbohydrate (g/100g), Saturated fat (g/100g), Trans fat (g/100g), Sugars (g/100g), Added sugar (g/100g), Sodium (mg/100g), Fiber (g/100g), Calcium (mg/100g), Sweeteners (Y/N). 
In order to increase data precision, companies are also encouraged to share additional nutrition content data beyond that on the label. The percentage of the product that is fruit, vegetable, nut or legume, which is necessary to calculate the Health Star Rating, can also be submitted as part of this additional information.
The last quarter of 2020 will be dedicated to the finalization of companies&#x2019; assessments. Moreover, ATNI will publish a Request for Proposals for PR agencies to support the communications around Global Index 2021.
Micronutrient enhanced nutrient profiling
Lastly, it is important to note that ATNI is using the opportunity of undertaking the Product Profile for Global Index 2021 to run a pilot to test a micronutrient-enhanced nutrient profiling system. This system enables products&#x2019; micronutrient content (initially folic acid, iodine, iron, vitamins A, B12 and D) to be assessed, in the context of addressing micronutrient deficiencies of public health importance. The pilot will be run in five countries (Mexico, India, South Africa, as well as Australia) and 17 companies selected for the Index. Companies are asked on voluntary bases to add information on the micronutrient content of the products that are assessed for the 2021 Global Index. These data will not be published or used in companies&#x2019; scores, just to test the effectiveness and validity of the enhanced NPS model.

Core Objective 2: BMS marketing policies and practices
The &#x2018;Breast-milk Substitutes -BMS- and Complementary Foods -CF- marketing&#x2019; sub-ranking comprises two elements: 
BMS/CF 1: Corporate Profile assessment &#x2014; designed to measure the extent to which the BMS companies&apos; marketing policies align to The Code , the strength of their management systems and the extent of their public disclosure.
BMS/CF 2: In-country assessments &#x2014; designed to measure companies&apos; compliance with The Code and/or national regulations (whichever is stricter) in two selected countries. The studies are conducted using the NetCode protocol; data is collected in healthcare facilities, retailers and various forms of the media.
BMS/CF 1: During Q3, ATNI reviewed companies&#x2019; input on the first round of analysis and gave them access for the second and final time to clarify any open questions and provide ATNI with any missing documents. ATNI also held calls with some of the companies to discuss these questions with them. The initial scores will be produced by early November, after ATNI has finalized all of the assessments. 
BMS/CF 2: Westat shared the final dataset for the Philippines in-country assessment. ATNI uploaded the findings and images of potential incidences of non-compliance to a new area of the research platform for the four global companies present in that market: Abbott, RB, Danone and Nestl&#xE9;. These companies reviewed the findings and provided their comments on them. This is a new step in for the in-country assessments. ATNI reviewed the companies&#x2019; feedback and is working to finalize the results. Regarding the second country, Westat was in close communication with ATNI and the local research partner, and due to the pandemic, it was decided to move forwards only with the elements of the study that were safe for the researcher to undertake, given the small likelihood that the situation would improve in the near future, and the timeline had already been extended. Interviews in the healthcare facilities will not be conducted nor the visits to the smaller retailers. However, all other elements will continue, as they can be done online or safely. Westat conducted the online training with the local team and the data collection has begun. It is expected to be completed by November. 
In terms of the collaboration between FTSE Russell and ATNI, PwC has been in close contact. It is preparing for calls with the three companies within the FTSE4Good Indexes to present the findings from the interviews at the companies&#x2019; headquarters and in the Philippines with local staff. The FTSE company reports that PwC will write will be ready in early November, to meet FTSE&#x2019;s deadline. A second round of company reports will be written once the second country data are finalized, early next year. 
Further to last quarter&#x2019;s report, the BMS Call to Action was published by WHO, UNICEF and several other NGO signatories on June 25th. The deadline for replies from the 19 companies to which it was addressed, and the industry associations, is 25th September. ATNI has been asked to evaluate the companies&#x2019; responses for the signatories and assess whether the companies make any of the commitments within the Call to Action. ATNI also facilitated a group of investors to write letters to the listed companies among those targeted by the BMS Call to Action to encourage them to respond and make the requested commitments.
During this quarter, ATNI distributed a social media package to partners and stakeholders for World Breastfeeding Week. Additionally, the BMS Principles page on the new ATNI website was redesigned and restructured, with new content to make it easier to navigate and give a deeper insight into ATNI&#x2019;s work on this important topic. A blog summarizing all of ATNI&#x2019;s work on BMS marketing was published in this period; it outlined how ATNI assesses companies in this area and set out the progress needed, including a reference to the BMS Call to Action.

Core Objective 3: Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2020
In February 2020, ATNI launched and published the main results of the India Spotlight Index 2020 and the detailed results and analysis of the scores of companies on the Category B which assesses the healthiness of their product portfolio and individual products (through the Product Profile).

The release of the thematic chapters of the Index (on marketing, labelling, governance, access &amp; affordability, healthy lifestyle support and engagement) was postponed due to the pandemic.

The chapters on healthy lifestyles/support to the workforce, and on labelling and health claims, will be launched online end of October 2020. Chapters on delivering accessible and affordable healthy foods and on influencing governments and policymakers, and stakeholder engagement will follow. ATNI attended the Delivering for Nutrition in India online conference on September 15-18 to stay up to date with the nutrition landscape in India ahead of the launch of the next chapters.

Core Objective 5: Outreach activities
1. Investors
The new ATNI Investor Expectations on Nutrition, Diets and Health were published on July 1st and shared with existing ATNI signatories to ask them to reconfirm their support. The majority of the signatories have done so. ATNI is following up with the remaining ones to ensure their support. In addition, ATNI is currently approaching other investment managers and asset owners in the Netherlands, UK and Japan and other markets to expand its pool of signatories, principally by organizing webinars with national social/sustainable investment forums; the next one planned is with the French SIF (early November 2020).
The Investor Portal will be finalised in the coming weeks (Q4 2020) and log-ins will be made available to the signatories. The investor-focused pages of the website are being reviewed to include more information about the work ATNI is doing with and for investors, and to provide links to investment relevant reports and articles on nutrition and health.
2. World Benchmarking Alliance &#x2013; Allies Assembly
ATNI had a call with WBA in September to discuss future collaboration on the development of the WBA Food and Agriculture Benchmark. WBA asked ATNI to think about which specific nutrition indicators could be incorporated. In October 2020, the two research teams of WBA and ATNI will meet to discuss this. Additionally, we are exploring ATNI&#x2019;s role in engagement with food and beverage manufacturers that are already in ATNI Indexes and in sharing/submitting nutrition data of these (and potentially other food and beverage manufacturers) for the WBA Food and Agriculture Benchmark.
3. Communications update
ATNI is in the process of hiring an agency to support with social media analytics and planning, as well as an agency to help develop and set SMART targets within the ATNI Communications Plan. We are assessing the feasibility of conducting a social media audit to ensure ATNI has consisting messaging and branding across each of our social media channels, and that it is aligned to the overall strategy. The agency selected may also support ATNI in creating a more in-depth content strategy utilising appropriate planning tools to improve the frequency and allow for more effective measuring of impact. This will be integrated into the new Monitoring and Evaluation framework currently under development. Martina Asquini, who recently joined the ATNI team as an intern, is supporting with the implementation of the communications plan and content creation. 

Core Objective 6: Develop action research activities
In 2019, ATNI started two Action Research projects related to the Indexes. Action Research is designed to deliver new insights on areas where conclusive evidence, international standards and/or company practice is weak or emerging. The goals are to feed into the methodologies for our Indexes, publish new information and analysis, and to contribute new insights on these topics to a wide range of stakeholders.
1. Action research on accessibility and affordability 
The goal of this research is to better understand why companies are struggling to perform well in Category C (on accessibility and affordability of healthy products) in the ATNI Indexes. ATNI contracted Carnstone Partners to do the first phase of this work. During the first quarter of 2020, Carnstone finalized its analysis and presented this to ATNI. 
The final draft of Carnstone&#x2019;s report has been submitted and ATNI has shared it with FCDO. The next step for ATNI is to consider how to use its findings and recommendations to inform future Indexes and other projects.
2. Action research on complementary foods
ATNI has contracted local partners in the two selected countries, who have started the research. For Country 1, the local partner will conduct a landscape analysis for commercially produced complementary foods and the current trends of infant and young child eating patterns. For Country 2, the same landscape study will be conducted, plus a Product Profile of the complementary foods identified and bought in the local market, using the WHO/Europe model for complementary foods nutrient profiling. Jayne Hutchinson, a Professor from the University of Leeds who worked with WHO/Europe to develop the nutrient profiling model, is providing advice to the local partner to ensure accuracy of the data and use of the model. 
Research on both projects is progressing well. The organizations undertaking the research will deliver their final reports later in the quarter. We will then edit and design them to be ready for publication in Q1 2021.

Core Objective 7: Develop Monitoring and Evaluation
ATNI&#x2019;s M&amp;E framework proposal was submitted to the ATNI Board in September 2020 for revision and approval. The purpose of this monitoring framework is to generate learning to improve ATNI program and project performance, to ensure ATNI is as effective as possible in driving private sector contributions to better nutrition. More specifically, the framework is designed to: ensure accountability to donors and other stakeholders; support project or program management (i.e. making immediate decisions to manage an existing project or program); generate learning to contribute to better planning and performance in current or future projects or programs; provide information that can be used for marketing, publicity or fundraising work; provide a basis for regular evaluations including independent impact assessment.

The framework is designed with Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning components in mind. ATNI will start developing key resources for each of the Monitoring and Evaluation components and will explore how they can be used for the future Learning component. The system is supported by different resources including human, financial and technological resources. The M&amp;E framework will be developed through an iterative process and as a living document. Feedback from users as well as external stakeholders such as donors will serve as a basis for continuous improvement.
The framework has served as a basis to design the Terms of Reference of an independent impact evaluation. The objective of the latter is to:
- assess the impact and changes brought about by ATNI&#x2019;s program; 
- assess the contribution of ATNI&#x2019;s intervention to any identified change; 
- identify the internal and external factors that hindered or enabled these changes; and 
- provide a combination of findings, recommendations and learnings to ATNI and other relevant stakeholders. 
The key evaluation questions of the assessment will be based on the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development&#x2019;s (OECD) Development Assistance Committee (DAC) criteria, as advised by FCDO: Relevance, Effectiveness, Efficiency, Impact, Sustainability. 
ATNI has consulted FCDO on both its M&amp;E framework and Impact Assessment design and will take into consideration resulting suggestions for improvement. The Independent Impact Evaluation will most likely be commissioned in the second quarter of 2021 (after the launch of the Global Index), while the selection process of the Evaluator and the actual Impact Evaluation will start in the first quarter of 2021.
&#x2003;
Additional Objective 1: Developing indexes that assess the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g. retailers, food service companies, fast food chains
ShareAction&#x2019;s funder, Guys &amp; St Thomas&apos;s Charity, has agreed to fund the development and publication of the full UK Retailer Index. The contract has been signed for a grant with the amount of &#xA3;209,632.50.  The Index will include 11 large retailers. As with other Indexes, retailers will be offered the opportunity to sign NDAs in order to provide ATNI with confidential information. In September, a kick-off meeting was held with ShareAction, and preparations were made for consultation webinars and processes on the methodology with retail companies and other nutrition stakeholders in the UK, including investors and CSO representatives. Company research will start in early January 2021. The agreement is to publish the Index in Q1 2022.

Additional Objective 2: New Spotlight Indexes
US Spotlight Index 
The US Expert Group met on July 2nd to review the main changes of the US Index 2021 methodology. The session was well attended, with five members participating in the live session and one member providing written inputs after the session.
Among the main items discussed, the integration of sustainability related indicators and in particular the concept of Food Loss and Waste generated a lot of discussion but did not result in any specific suggested change to the methodology. Furthermore, several propositions were made about how ATNI should credit the Children&#x2019;s Food and Beverage Advertising Initiative (CFBAI) nutrition criteria to determine marketing to children, as well as a company&#x2019;s own criteria. During the session, the ATNI COVID-19 report triggered a lot of interest within the US Expert Group with members providing input on key focus areas.
Following a discussion with the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (RWJF) in July 2020 about validation of the methodology, ATNI started a process to review it, led by its Research and Engagement Advisor and involving the Research team. Two main elements of a verification process are being explored:
- Externally: Cognitive interviews carried with US-based F&amp;B companies to test and improve the clarity of indicators and answer options; 
- Internally: The inter-rater reliability testing could be combined with an adapted first Peer-review phase of the Index 
ATNI has agreed with RWJF that the validation will start by the end of 2020.
&#x2003;
Additional Objective 3: Further development of verification-type activities
Nutrition Business Monitor project 
Since the last update, ATNI has updated the recommendations on the tool based on feedback from the companies, and improved the language as well as the layout in the recommendations. The total score and the score for each category was also included in the update document of the recommendations. During this quarter, a second round of testing of the tool was done in Nigeria with three additional Nigerian companies. Following their testing of the tool, a webinar was organized to get their input and hear about the impact of COVID-19 on their business. Their feedback shows that they prefer a simple tool that can be filled within one to two hours and that the Nutrition Business Monitor (NBM) specifically helps raising awareness and knowledge for small/micro enterprises, while for larger companies it confirms their areas of strength and need for training/knowledge exchange in specific areas (like certification, packaging, fortification). The next step of the project is the first round of testing in Bangladesh in September which will be followed by a webinar to get the companies&#x2019; feedback in early October. Subsequently, ATNI will have follow-up discussions with GAIN, SBN to discuss feedback and next steps in terms of capacity building.
Responsible Lobbying Framework 

ATNI has transposed the Responsible Lobbying Framework into an ATNI-style methodology which has been used to assess the ten largest baby food companies, with the help of a consultancy firm. ATNI organized calls with seven companies, excluding the Chinese companies with which ATNI has not been able to establish direct contact, to discuss their results and set out our recommendations for improvement. The companies were very interested in their results and the recommendations, and actively engaged with ATNI on this piece of work. In addition, ATNI has undertaken desk research on the feasibility of establishing a &#x2018;BMS lobbying observatory&#x2019;. ATNI is currently conducting interviews with selected stakeholders from CSOs, companies, academia, UN agencies and other selected stakeholders to learn from their experience and knowledge of how lobbying takes place, and to hear whether and how they see such an observatory working. This project is expected to be completed by the end of this year.
&#x2003;
Extra activities 2020-2022
Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020
The first COVID-19 report was published July 15, 2020. The focus of the first report was the research framework and key trends in the food and beverage sector as a response to COVID-19 between April and June 2020, including: 
- Changing business environment: changing consumer behavior, marketing practices, policies and regulations and investors&#x2019; responses;
- Attention to health of the workforce in factories, offices and supply chains; 
- Resilience risks in food supply chains; 
- Deteriorating marketing practices in the baby-food sector; 
- Company behavior with regards to product promotions. 
The report was published on the ATNI website, Twitter and LinkedIn and shared with all ATNI Indexes companies and key stakeholders, including the ATNI Board, ATNI Expert Group, funders, industry associations etc.:
- Full report: https://accesstonutrition.org/app/uploads/2020/07/First -quarterly-COVID-report-Final-version.pdf 
- Framework: https://accesstonutrition.org/app/uploads/2020/07/Final -Covid-19-framework-Footnotes.pdf
- News item: https://accesstonutrition.org/news/first-offour-reports-on-company-responses-to-covid-19-justpublished/ 
- Nutrition Connect: https://nutritionconnect.org/resource-center/blog-40- private-sector-accountability-more-important-eversupporting-positive
Organizations and individuals who shared content about this project include: 
Global Nutrition Report (GNR); One World, No Hunger; SUN Business Network; The Indian Nutrition Initiative (TATA Trusts); Scaling Up Nutrition; Susanna Stormer, Novo Nordisk; The Power of Nutrition; Helen Keller International; World Food Programme India (WFP India); FCDO; Westat; SDG2 Advocacy Hub; Corinna Hawkes, GNR; Charity Needs Foundation; Lawrence Haddad, GAIN; Sharon Bligh, Consumer Goods Forum; Consumer Goods Forum.
During July/August, analysts conducted company assessments of 39 ATNI companies (Global, US, India, BMS) following the ATNI COVID-19 framework and based on publicly available information. Companies were given the opportunity to share additional non-confidential information on top of this. Weekly monitoring of third-party publicly available resources on companies&#x2019; responses to COVID-19 continued during this quarter, including Consumer Goods Forum (CGF), Food Industry Asia (FIA) and monitoring on BMS news.
In September, quality checks were conducted by cross-checking the information gathered. As a result, key trends have been short-listed and the draft report was written. The second quarterly COVID-19 report will be published mid-October and shared with businesses and other nutrition stakeholders through email, social-media and webinars that will be organized end of October/early November 2020.
Private sector commitment monitoring hub supporting 2020 GNS/Nutrition for Growth (N4G), 2021 FSS and World Health Organization (WHO) starting August 2020

The Nutrition for Growth Summit has been postponed to December 2021. ATNI is still regularly advising the Business Constituency Group (BCG) on how companies start preparing SMART commitments including accountability elements. The last meeting took place in September 2020. Concrete next steps depend on the approval of the Government of Japan.
The UN Food Systems Summit will start in summer 2021 and might be spread over a period of weeks. ATNI is involved in discussions on alignment with N4G on nutrition commitments and accountability; this proves to be a difficult process. 
WHO Global Monitoring Mechanism: ATNI is continuing its dialogue with WHO on its expectations regarding developing a WHO Global Monitoring Mechanism. Initially, we will likely narrow the scope originally discussed and develop a report on IFBA-member commitments only on iTFAs, probably delivered by the end of 2020. 
World Benchmarking Alliance. The new director for the Food &amp; Agriculture Benchmark Viktoria de Bourbon de Parme and her team met ATNI team on September 10 and agreed on data exchange options and further alignment of indicators. There will be a follow up meeting with the research teams in October.


Planning of Q4 2020 (Oct-Dec 2020) and Q1 2021 (Jan-March 2021) reporting period

Changes in planning per project, in large part due to the impact of COVID-19, as well as activities planned for Q4 and 2021 are listed in this section. The draft Activity planning 2021 is attached in the Annex.

Core Objective 1 Global Index: By mid-November, all Global Index companies are expected to submit their feedback on the list of products that will be assessed in the Product Profile. All 25 companies will have engaged on ATNI&#x2019;s platform by early December. The second Peer Review will start in December and be continued into early Q1 2021. By the end of March 2021, the drafting of Global Index findings and chapters will be at an advanced stage. The launch of the Global Index is now expected in Q2 2021.  

Core Objective 2 BMS: As described earlier, BMS in-country work has been delayed due to COVID-19. The completion date for this work is now expected to be the end of Q1 2021. Based on the current plan, the data collection in the second country will finish mid-Q3 2020 and following that, reports will be written and the scores for each company will be calculated, using both BMS 1 and BMS 2. 

Core Objective 3 and 4: India Index 2020
The release of the thematic chapters of the India Index was changed due to the pandemic. The chapters on healthy lifestyle/ workforce nutrition support, and labelling and health claims will be launched online by the end of October 2020. Chapters on delivering accessible and affordable healthy foods, on influencing governments and policymakers, and on stakeholder engagement will follow in November/December 2020.

Core Objective 5: Engagement
Investors: In Q4 2020, ATNI will continue approaching potential new signatories directly and will arrange webinars with various regional and national investor networks for this quarter or the first quarter of 2021, to raise awareness of ATNI&#x2019;s work, the Investor Expectations and the engagement with companies we facilitate. We hope that through these events, we will attract new signatories in the medium term. 

The Investor Portal will be finalized in the coming weeks (Q4 2020) and log-ins will be made available to the signatories. The investor-focused pages of the website are being reviewed to include more information about the work ATNI is doing with and for investors, and to provide links to investment relevant reports and articles on nutrition and health.
The collaborative investor engagement around the results of the Global Index 2021 and US Index 2021 will also be organized and managed through this portal.

Core Objective 6: Action Research
Accessibility and Affordability: This report has been finalized. The next step of this activity for ATNI is to consider how to use its findings and recommendations to inform future Indexes and other projects.
Complementary foods: the final reports will be delivered later in Q4 2020. We will then edit and design the reports. In Q1 2021, they will be ready for publication. 
Core Objective 7: M&amp;E
ATNI has consulted FCDO on both its M&amp;E framework and Impact Assessment design and will take into consideration resulting suggestions for improvement. The Independent Impact Evaluation will most likely be commissioned in the second quarter of 2021, while the selection process of the Evaluator and the actual Impact Evaluation will start in the first quarter of 2021, concurring with the publication of the Global Index.

Additional objective 1: Retailer Index
UK Retailer Index: in October 2020, consultations will take place to discuss the methodology. The methodology will be finalized with the advice of the UK Retail Index Expert Group in November. In December, the data-collection platform will be prepared so that research can start in Q1 2021, as the plan agreed with ShareAction.

Additional objective 2: New Spotlight Indexes
US Index: In the last quarter of 2020, exit surveys as well as cognitive interviews will be carried out with the 11 US Index companies as part of the methodology validation effort. The outcome of the validation is expected to be reflected in the US Index updated methodology between December and January. The assessment of companies will be initiated in Q1 2021. ATNI plans to publish the US Index end of 2021.

Nigeria Index: ATNI is planning to start developing the Nigeria Index methodology in 2021 and to start research for the first Nigeria Index, due to be launched in 2022.

Additional objective 3: Additional verification tools
NBM: There have been some delays with piloting the tools in Bangladesh due to COVID-19. The next step of the project is the first round of testing in Bangladesh in September which will be followed by a webinar to get the companies&#x2019; feedback in early October. Subsequently, ATNI will have follow-up discussions with GAIN, SBN to discuss feedback and next steps in terms of capacity building for 2021.
Responsible Lobbying: This activity will be finalized before the end of 2020, as planned.

Extra activities:
COVID-19 monitoring: the second quarterly COVID-19 report will be published in October, followed by webinars for business and other stakeholders to discuss emerging trends. In November/December desk-research will be done to monitor trends in specific markets (China, Nigeria, Mexico). The third quarterly report will be published in late January 2021.

Private Sector Commitment monitoring:
- Nutrition for Growth Summit/UN Food Systems: these summits have been postponed for one year. Based on the next steps outlined by the Government of Japan, ATNI will start building the repository to monitor private sector nutrition commitments for the summits.

- WHO Global Monitoring Mechanism: this work has been delayed because of organizational changes in WHO and the pandemic. The next step is for ATNI to agree with WHO the commitments and performance data that ATNI will provide on IFBA (or a larger group of companies) related to their adoption of, and delivery against, WHO nutrition standards (Q4 2021). Subsequently, ATNI will collect data and report to WHO.  

- WBA: the ATNI research team will meet with the WBA Food and Agriculture Benchmark research team in Q4 to discuss collaboration in methodology development and research implementation (data sharing). This is according to plan.

Investors Coalition and Portal: this activity is as planned. See also the Engagement section. 

Workforce nutrition action research and research to assess inequities in nutritional qualities of companies&apos; product portfolios across markets will both start in January 2021. 

Budget 2021
ATNI will prepare the adjusted budget for 2021 in the next two months and can share this with FCDO by the end of November/early December, after all reforecasts have been made.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation Arthur van Schendelstraat 650 3511 MJ Utrecht, the Netherlands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="GOALS 2 (ZERO HUNGER) AND 3 (HEALTH AND WELL-BEING FOR ALL), SDG 12 (TARGET 12.3)" percentage="100" vocabulary="9">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goals 2 (zero hunger) and 3 (health and well-being for all), SDG 12 (target 12.3)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2400000</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/1D-INTERLEAVED-PARITYFEC" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/ATNI-Activity-report_DGIS_July-to-September-2020-20201221101223.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNI July to September Activity Report - 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNI has committed to deliver the following Core Objectives.

Core Objective 1
Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020.
Core Objective 2
Publish comprehensive analysis of companies&apos; breast-milk substitutes (BMS) marketing policies and practices in both Global and Spotlight Indexes.

Core Objective 3
Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2019. 
Core Objective 4
Publish Product Profiles for all India Spotlight Indexes. 
Core Objective 5 
Extend outreach activities for different stakeholder groups, particularly investors, to amplify impact.

Core Objective 6 
Develop action research activities to advance thinking and practice in key areas.
Core Objective 7 
Develop measurement and evaluations.
Core Objective 8
Conduct a feasibility study on expansion and innovation. 

Additional Objectives

ATNF also sees various options for expansion, on top of the Core Objectives, for which additional funding would be needed. These include:

Additional Objective 1 
Developing one or more Global Indexes that assesses the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g. retailers, food service companies, fast food chains.
Additional Objective 2 
Development of new Spotlight Indexes for other priority countries.
Additional Objective 3 
Further development of complementary verification-type activities, such as the Product Profile (that could be expanded to assess labelling compliance and marketing spending; more or wider BMS marketing assessments, etc.).

Extra activities 2020-2022

With the additional funding support from FCDO as per amendment No. 01/2020, signed April 16th 2020, to the ongoing Accountable Grant for this project (no. 300590) ATNI will embark on the following extra activities: 

1. Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020.
2. Private sector commitment monitoring hub supporting 2020 GNS/Nutrition for Growth (N4G), 2021 FSS and World Health Organization (WHO) starting August 2020. 
3. Investor coalition starting October 2020. 
4. Workforce nutrition action research starting January 2021. 
5. Action research to assess inequities in nutritional qualities of companies&apos; product portfolios across markets starting January 2021. 
6. Country approach starting July 2021.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
