<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="1964" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-10-17T23:30:45" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-10-17T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-14:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHEDI COVID-19 Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHEDI together with Arua district NGO Network and Manyak Anti Corruption Coalition will implement the COVID-19 project under ELNHA under the following activities:

The activities are aimed at enriching stakeholder knowledge on COVID-19 so as to influence their perceptions and beliefs on the pandemic and foster positive change for effective control of the disease. The action embraces two approaches:  behavior change communication and improved health promotional and personal hygiene practices. It extendsto cover prevention and response address the needs of those affected by the pandemic.A: Prevention1. COVID-19 aligned behavior change information communication, health education and personal hygiene promotion. This sensitization is intended to create awareness on COVID-19, the virus and the disease, how it spreads and its prevention. This will create the critical mass of knowledge for appropriate decision making and behavior change required to effectively fight the pandemic. Planned activities are:1.1. Conduct live spot community healthand personal hygiene education: Sensitization programs will be run to educate the community on COVID-19. This will involve:1.1.1.Door-to-door sensitization: The team will be equipped with key information on COVID-19 required for effective control of the pandemic. The educators will be examined prior to field excursion for assurance that they are not infected and will not pose a risk to thecommunity. They will be equipped with personal protection equipments like facial masks and sanitizers to protect them against risksin the field.1.1.2 Radio programs: Topical issues will be identified and aired on radio for mass sensitization. This will use both English and local languages most commonly used in the communitya. Radio talk shows will be organized and facilitated by health experts with grounding in public health and strong knowledge on COVID-19b. Radio spots messages will be constructed based on a mix of technical matters, community perceptionsand behavioral constructs and will be played on radio throughout the implementation period of the action. This will help to keep information on the pandemic alive throughout the implementation period. The messages may be reviewed and updated as and when new facts and perceptions arise so as to keep the spots message relevant.1.1.3. Boda boda talk-talk: Sensitization messages with detailed information on COVID-19 response protocol including statistical facts on prevalence of the pandemic as well as ministerial policy issues and guidance will be packaged, recorded and played on moving vehicles and motorcycles around town, in the villages and settlements to reinforce sensitization program on radio. This will help to reach the vulnerable communities thatcannot afford radios.1.1.4. Print and distribute public health information on COVID-19: This action will use the information already provided by international agencies, national authorities and health experts to:a. Translate advisories, protocolsandadvocacy messages COVID-19:  key messages made available by WHO, MoH, Oxfam and other humanitarian platforms on COVID-19 will be translated in to three (3) local languages namely: Arabic, Lugbara, Kakwa). This will localize the literature on COVID-19for easier and wider reading and reception among the lowly educated local population. The information will then be disseminated to communities both in print and on air:b. Print and distribute advisories, protocols and advocacy messages on COVID-19: Key messages on COVID-19 both in their original English version and translated versions will be printed and distributed to make information on COVID-19 available in the community at all times. This will continuously keep information on the pandemic alive in thecommunity and maintain community consciousness on COVID-19 at all timesi. Flyers will be printed for distribution to individuals. This will carry the message up to  household levelii. Banners will be produced on water-proof materials and displayed at public places like women centers, schools, markets, places of worship and offices. This will stay and carry information on COVID-19 displayed and visible for a longer time in the community. Its attractive nature will compel more people to read the messages.1.1.5. Social media engagement: Mass social media platforms will be created for targeted mobilization and sensitization.  Key advocacy messages made available on COVID-19 by WHO, MoH, Oxfam and other humanitarian platforms will be imputed and disseminated on the mass social media platforms.a. Bulk SMS messaging: An SMS platform will be created for mass mobilization, sensitization and surveillance on COVID-19. Community members will be recruited on to the platform and be sensitized on useof the platform. Pre-payments will be made under the Action for use of the platform, so sending messages on to the platform will be free of charge. This will enable vulnerable communities effectively use the platform for accessing and sending messages onCOVID-19. This is particularly important in surveillance since it will help communitiesin reporting suspected cases on time.b. Virtual conferences on COVID-19 topical issues:A multi-task social media platform will becreated for key actors notably members ofinteragency and district task forces on COVID-19, project staff and key local authorities.Virtual conferences will then be supported for targeted rapid mobilization and response among the members. It will be used to facilitate dissemination of new emerging issues and support discussion of status reports and reviews. In so doing it will help in effectual management of the pandemic while maintaining the physical distance recommendations by WHO, MoH and humanitarian platforms on COVID-19. In this action,Whatsapp, Skype and Zoomed platforms will be particularly used.1.2. Institutional health promotion and advocacy on COVIG-19: Once the government waives the suspension on public gatherings, places of crowd and social services remain high at risk becauseof the numbers of people and movement involved. The action will carry out targeted hygiene promotion, education and sensitization in schools market centers and places of worship.a. Health talks: Key messages on COVID-19 will be packaged for school children,market goers and followers in the various places of worship and delivered using the project team, and authorities in the facilities in coordinated mannerb. Distribution of advisories, protocols and advocacy messages on COVID-19: The printedcopies of thekey messages on COVID-19 will be distributed and displayed at schools, market centers and places of worship to make information on COVID-19 available in the public places at all times. This will continuously keep information on the pandemicalive inthe public places and maintain consciousness among the facility users on COVID-19 at all timesi. Flyers will be distributed facility users.ii. Banners will be produced on water-proof materials and displayed at the public places schools, market centers andplaces of worship. This will stay and carry information on COVID-19 displayed and visible for a longer time in the facilities and among the facility users.1.3. Public health and hygiene promotion1.3.1 Procure and distribute hygiene promotional facilities: In addition to the behavior change communication and education or sensitization for personal and institutional hygiene promotion, hygiene promotional facilities will be procured and distributed to schools, administrative centers, market centersand places worship as well as centers of high daily population concentrations like food distribution centers and community meeting centers. This will help to support required hygiene promotional practices notably hand washing and curb spread of coronavirus andother hygiene related diseases.a. Procure and install masshand washing cans: These will be distributed to schools, administrative centers, market centers and places of worship as well as centers of high daily population concentrations like food distribution centers and community meeting centers to help support hand washing in the centers.b. Procure and distribute water delivery jerry cans: These will be complimentary to hand washing cans and is intended to facilitate water collection from the nearest source for delivery to the hand washing point where the cans are installed.c.Procure and distribute soap and detergents: These will be complimentary to hand washing cans and help to clean and/or disinfect thehand. Preference will be given to liquid soapfor public use. Alcohol based sanitizers will only be delivered to key actors who continuously get engaged in response activities under COVID-19 response or other humanitarian responses like food destruction1.3.2 Cashtransfer to community members involved in installing mass hand washing cans: In consultation with the local authorities, women and youth will be identified among the community members to construct and install basements for the mass hand washing cans. This will foster women and youth involvement and participation in COVID-19 response.B: Response2 In the event COVID-19 strikes, several medical care, social and economic needs become eminent. Those affected will suffer stigma, emotional to physical violence and economic hardships andhumanitarian systems will be over stressed. Under this action, support will be given to those affected and their families/dependants in order to assist them access medical care and build resilience. Support will also be given to strengthen the existinghealth system for improved response2.1. Complementary support to existing health system in care and treatment of COVID-19 cases:2.1.1 Procure and distribute basic equipments and sundries for COVID-19 treatment: Key equipment and sundries will be procuredand distrusted to health facilities designated to manage COVID-19 cases.i. Procure and distribute anti-bacterial hospital mattresses: These will be distributed to health centers designated as COVID-19 treatment centers for the patients andthose quarantined after havinghad contacts with infected persons.ii. Procure and distribute N95 facial masts: These will be used to protect the health workers and other responders in the COVID-19 pandemiciii. Procure and install hand washing cans: These will bedistributed to health centers to support hand washing in the facilitiesiv. Procure and distribute water delivery jerry cans: These will facilitate water collection from the nearest source for delivery to the hand washing point where the cans are installed.v. Procure and distribute soap and detergents: These will be used to clean and/or disinfect the hand.2.1.2. Support to those directly affected by COVID-19i. Provide psychosocial support for those affected and their families:Once infected byCOVID-19, those affected and their immediate families willfall victim to discrimination and associated stigma. Psychosocial support will help to mitigate the negative impact of COVIC-19 on those affected by the disease and their dear ones.2.1.3. Surveillance: As contagious disease, information on all cases whether suspected or real will be collected and referred to designated health facilities for verification. Community perceptions and social behavior that are likely to propagate spread of thediseasewillalso be monitored and acted upon. The surveillance will involve close collaboration and coordination with the existing health system and task forces already built on COVID-19. Information gained from the communities will be followed for verificationand cases referred using the established referral system to designated facilities for further managementa. Data capture and follow-ups on cases reported from communities: The action will institute effective surveillance system for information capture and follow-upon cases reported from communities. This will partly use the mass SMS platform created under activity 1.1.5a.above. It will use the health structures in place to support the project team. Information captured will be recorded and updated regularly to produce weekly or monthly COVID-19status reportsb. Contact tracing: All persons established to have come into contact with confirmed COVID-19 cases (patients) will be followed and presented for screening. Similarly, persons suspected tohave come fromareas rated as high risk will be followed-up and presented for screening and/or quarantine3.  Other activities directly linked to the responseThis action will be delivered in close collaboration and coordination with local districtand interagencytaskforces, the local authorities and full involvement of the target beneficiaries in the Arua district.. The overall progress of the response and implementation of activities will be closely monitored and regularly reviewed toenable good follow-up actions to beinstituted and achieve the desired objective of preventing COVID-19 incidence in the community.3.1. Project inception: Project inception meeting will be held with members of the district and interagency task force,local authorities andrepresentativesof the beneficiary community.3.2. Monitoring and Evaluationa. Conduct routine field monitoring visits and follow-ups: A data base will be created to capture information on COVID19 and project implementation progress. Information on the status of COVID-19 will be routinelycaptured and entered on to the data base on daily basis. In case of any reported cases of coronavirus disease, the actions taken and findings will accordingly be updated on the database. This information may be received directlyfromthe community or through the project staff in the field. Similarly, information on the project implementation progress will be routinely captured and entered on tothe data base on daily basis and be used for makingprogress reports and corrective action memos.b. Conduct weekly reviews: The data captured in Activity 3.1 above will be collated and summarized to develop weekly reports. This will be used to facilitate weekly review meetings by the project team. Members of the interagency and district task forces may be invited to attend the reviews if the circumstance warrants so.c. Facilitate project team to attend interagency review meetings on COVID-19: Core project staffs (ProjectManager, Surveillance focal person and MEALOfficer) will be facilitated to attend interagency task force meetings on COVID-19.The team will also attend such meetings as may be convened by district task force on COVID-19.d. Conduct project end evaluation meeting:At the end, a terminal evaluation will be conducted to assess the contribution of the project towards managing the COVID-19 pandemic. This evaluation meeting will draw participants from the interagency task force on COVID-19, the district task force, key local authorities and the project team.Monitoring andEvaluation# weekly reviewso Stationeryo Refreshmentso Airtime for coordination# Interagency review meetingso Fuelo SDAo Air time for coordinationQuarterly stakeholder review meetingsPsychosocial supportIssueso Economichardship (people living on hand-to-mouth, economic growth affected by 3%)o Emotional violenceo Stigma (prevents peoplefrom showing up and declare their status)o Physical assault (5 women murdered # police report)# Contacttracingo Fuelo Air timeo SDAoDocumentation (stationery# Surveillanceo Fuelo Air timeo SDA</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTION 4 HUMAN RIGHTS &amp; EDUCATION I AHEDI</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHEDI- UG is an Organization formed by young university graduates in the field of law and social work in July 2008 to promote, defend and protect rights of every citizen regardless of tribe and nationality; #Justice for All#. The organization has mainstreamed itsactivities in the area of GBV/VAWG, PHA victims, Women and children in conflict with the law, Land rights, Legal and social consultancy for Local governments (on Policy and legal Issues) and other vulnerable persons, working towards improving the legal framework and awareness on human rights and fundamental freedom, land and property rights.
AHEDI-UG delivers holistic and citizen friendly programs with particular emphasis on GBV/VAWG,HIV/AIDs, emergency response to humanitarian issues, land rights/property ownership, psycho-social support, legal and social consultancy that leads to  sustainable development and livelihood.
AHEDI-UG works with a number of partners in the execution of its mission including political and technocrats at the districts of west Nile sub region and Uganda at large, members of parliament (MP), traditional leaders, central government representatives, other NGOs, CBOs and Faith base leaders among others.The turning point in the development of this Organization came in 2010 when West Nile civil society organizations identified the Organization to Coordinate We Can Campaign Project Funded by Oxfam in West Nile, (thus bringing all West Nile GBV actors together both state and none state Actors) a program that ran for 6 years in which AHEDI-UG mobilized and brought together 169 state and non-state GBV actors and with them, recruited 16,000 charge makers across all the districts of West Nile Nile. Although the project ended, AHEDI- UG  has managed to sustain this members through various advocacy engagements resulting to enactments of 7 (seven) district level ordinances to address a base line campaign findings carried in 2013 under Oxfam funded We Can Campaign.To date, AHEDI- UG has continued to build on this coalition to address GBV issues in the region and now, the Organization is, in Partnership with EU, implementing 923,730,000/ project to empower Women Market vendors in Arua District to end GBV, a project that arose out of We Can Campaign Base line survey supra.1.ACHIEVEMENTSToday AHEDI-UG in partnership with Arua district Local government is providing technical assistance to the District council and has being charged by council to guide and ensure production of Alcohol Control Ordinance, Charcoal and wood fuelcontrol Ordinance and Education Ordinance Amendment Bill 2018. The same partnership is with the districts of Maracha and Koboko on Education, Food security and Local Council Court Committee Development Training. This is an achievement for us in the area of Policy and legal support to Local Governments to address issues of GBV policy gaps.AHEDI-UG continued to work with ELNHA members to address emergency refugee issues in the settlement, with a support from Oxfam through CEFORD and played amajor role in the period when host communities rose against the relief aid workers in Oriama, Imvepi and Rigbo sub counties. This was successful interventions that restore peace and harmony among the actors. This intervention achieved AHEDI-UG strategic objectiveforpeaceful resolution of conflicts as opposed to court litigation and war in the region of operationToday with funding support from EU, AHEDI-UG targets to transform 14 VSLA#s in to cooperative societies so that they have legal status to compete and win funds from government programs and have capacity  to defend, protect and jointly advocate for their rights under one umbrella.3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSEMission: Mission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?AHEDI-UG vision is that all women, girls and men alike live in peaceful and just environment where enjoyment of human rights is promoted, defended and protectedInstitutional objectives: Five years vision for AHEDI-UG.CONTEXTIn the year 2020 greater acceptance and full inclusion by the community, improved services and more prevalence will be added socio-economic quality of women, children and other special interest groups of persons affected and infected HIV/AIDs, PWDs and indigent persons.At the same time, because of population growth, the ageing population and higher incidences of multiple diagnoses, the rights of women, girls, children and other indigent persons will remain extensive and varied.While significant strives will have been made in observance of the rights of women and girls, and to bridge the gap in implementation of Domestic laws and policies in protecting, promoting and defending the rights of women and other vulnerable persons in the community, there will be an ongoing push for community inclusion and participation.Finally women and other special interest groups of persons like affected and infected with HIV/AIDs, PWDs and indigent persons will control more resources and decisions about who provide them with help and support.Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisationworks?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?ROLE AND PROGRRAMME SERVICESAction for Human Rights and Education Initiative #Uganda is the lead in bringing up communities in identifying needs and all kinds of resources and services for her primaryand secondary beneficiaries to support full long term community inclusion of women and other vulnerable persons in determining their destiny and choice of life. Specifically AHEDI-UG will:-# Lead collaboration of providers and community groups /organizations, government departments and programs in the region and from surrounding areas, as appropriate, identifying needs and gaps in the services.# Directly provide cutting#edge, model services that meet identified gaps.# AHEDI-UG may not strive to provide comprehensive services itself BUT direct services it does provide are of the highest quality.# Collaborates with and make key referrals to  other high quality services providers and# Lead many advocacy efforts to ensure services are provided either by AHEDI-UG or other providers.# AHEDI-UG will play a leadership role in advocating at all levels of government, and with private sector and the public at largefor elimination of GBV and VAW, promote food security and nutrition, water and sanitation in the community and general awareness creation in human rights and fundamental freedoms of persons affected and infected with HIV/AIDs most especially women and children.# Encourage and support victims of GBV and VAW in pursuing this advocacy agenda.4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGAnalyse the environment inwhich the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? &apos;  In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?MISSION OF AHEDI-UGAchieving full personal human life for women, girls and other vulnerable community members and create an environment          1.  Addressing women and girls accessto justice and challenging the concept of socio- economic practices that perpetrate domestic violence and violence against women through application of religious, cultural and traditional laws.2. Strengthening the rights basedapproach and human rights monitoringcapacities for women groups/ organisation and persons affected and infected with HIV/ AIDS at grass root levels.3. Engaging district leadership in the West Nile region build capacity to reduce GENDER and other disparities in relation to increased access to and completion of quality basic education through promotion of girl child education.4. Engaging both political and civic leadership in West Nile region to address disparity between existing policies and domesticlaws with practices in the communities in specific reference to women#s socio economic rights.5. Recognising, supporting and protecting women working in the informal sector livelihood and promoting their economic roles in the society.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-22.488 -48.5693</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-17">26726</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">26726</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">26726</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTION 4 HUMAN RIGHTS &amp; EDUCATION I AHEDI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-14:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="73522"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="49015"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12254"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8169"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
