<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="1480" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-15T23:40:07" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-15T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-29:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS CTP Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS
Project Goal: To contribute to socio-economic protection and empowerment of disadvantaged women, men and children in North Karamoja (Kotido, Kaabong and Karenga).
Specific Objective 1: Enhance socio-economic empowerment of vulnerable women, men and Children (GBV survivors) using cash transferCaritas Kotido Diocese, Manna Development Agency (MADA) and Nakere RuralWomen Activists (NARWOA) will map out 360 vulnerable individuals, verify and assess the needs based on the areas of operation (Kaabong, Karenga and Kotido) respectively. Mapping, assessment, selection and Verification tool that will be developed by the three partners and done jointlywith the District officials,Consortia members will support the process of sourcing a cash transfer service provider; Mobilize thebeneficiaries and distribution of the cash to beneficiaries in the different areas of operation. The 360 beneficiaries will be supported with through the Mobile Money transfer amounting to UGX: 102,000/=. Per month Which is according to the Minimum Expenditure Basket (MEB) updated guidance for Cash Working Group- May, 2020. The items to be considered as per updated minimum expenditure basket for cash working group included; Food, Hygiene, Water, Energy (cooking and lighting), Transport, Communication, Clothing, Health Household items and personal expenditure, Livelihoods. The items listed above informed the amount to be transferred to the beneficiaries. (MEB updated on 12 May 2020).The project intends to use cash transfer modality in delivering the response that provides an opportunity to the affected people to make greater choices and dignity for empowerment in decision making to promote local markets. (Oxfam in Uganda SOPs on cash transfer). The delivery mechanism which is appropriate at the moment is through mobile money transfer to the beneficiaries. However much of the finance and programme roles during the cash transfer will be undertaken according the Oxfam inUganda Standard Operating Procedures of cash transfer programme implementation. The MEB Rates as at May are still relative and can still be used to determine the transfer value especially food items like Bean(kg),maize(kg),cooking oil(litre), salt(gms) have not changes so much and this has been the basis for the determination of the Transfer Value to the beneficiaries as indicated inConsortia members will support the post-distribution monitoring with the different stakeholders (district officials), to determine the effectiveness of the intervention and how it is promoting livelihood enhancement.The consortia members will support the process of project evaluation and conduct exit meetings.Kaabong (Loyoro and Lodiko),Karenga(Lokori,kawalakol),Kotido(Nakapelimoru,panyangara).Themapping, assessment will help in identification of beneficiaries. The selection and verification of the Beneficiaries to avoid biases, conflict of interest and duplication/double targeting of beneficiaries.The cash transferred will improve the household income levels and increased purchasing power, savings among others.The Cash transfer will be done through the Beyonic platform using the telecommunication networks such as MTN Uganda and Airtel Uganda depending on the contact number provided by the beneficiaries.The beneficiaries have identified the Mobile money as a good method of receiving support and this has been used also during the response to COVID-19.Gender considerations: The project will factor in a protection lens where the right and left lenses will all focus on the pertinent issues affecting women and men. Vulnerability assessment tool is very important is this undertaking. It is proven that women and children are always the most vulnerable in any emergency situation. Therefore, it&#x2019;s imperative that the project support will be biased towards vulnerable women and children who are worst hit by the impacts of the humanitarian crisis. We shall also target extremely vulnerable men.Age: Elderly and children are highly vulnerable during any humanitarian crisis. The project will target child headed households, Extremely Vulnerable women and men. The child protection policy will also guide the engagement of the children in the project and the Core Humanitarian standards. The child headed will benefit from the intervention while considering the Do No Harm principle relating to children and other beneficiaries.Conflict sensitivity and diversity: In conflict sensitivity the projectwill be hinged on the principle of &#x201C;do no harm&#x201D; as per the sphere standards and the international Red cross code of conduct. Keen/critical consideration will be employed to ensure that the intervention does not trigger/escalate occurrences of GBV in the communities so as to benefit from the project. An assessment will be done per proposed beneficiary to ascertain the cause of the violence. (protection Case management practices) The project will support all the vulnerable persons irrespective of tribe, ethnicity, sexual orientation, color, creed for as long as they are within the project area and targeted. The complaints handling and feedback mechanisms processes will be enforced as per the consortium partner policies. The different partners&#x2019; Prevention of Exploitation and sexualHarassment (PESH) will be one of the vital legal documents that the project team will use to guide the project intervention/activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Kotido is mandated with the task of assessing the needs of the people, designing and implementing developmental interventions with the aim of changing the lives in Kotido Catholic Diocese.  In the last two decades, Caritas Kotido has worked mainly in the areas of social economic development, particularly targeting poor farmers and pastoralists, women, and people living with HIV/AIDS, as well as orphans and vulnerable children.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-15">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-29:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="360"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="360"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
