<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2828" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-07-23T23:30:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-23T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06390-05:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">I CAN South Sudan COVID -19 Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">I CAN was founded in 2017 by refugee youths Stephen Wandu Bimo, Seme Ludanga Faustino, and Kyobutungi Angela. It was initially funded with a Good Will support grant from Misereor, Germany, which enabled us to help 20 children over 6 months. We have since developed our programme and are now helping 56 unaccompanied refugee  children now in Bidibidi Refugee Settlement in Uganda.
I CAN South Sudan is a registered, refugee-led Community-Based Organization (CBO) operating in the Bidibidi Refugee Settlement, Yumbe District, Northern Uganda.
We use social and musical education to help a particularly vulnerable group: unaccompanied refugee children. Our aim is three-folds:# To give these children meaning, purpose and hope in their lives# To develop their skills and talents for the future,# To provide them with a voice to express their trauma and their desire for peace.We use musical coaching with an emphasis on group work to build the children#s# confidence and to create friendships across the tribal divide that led to the South Sudanese civilwar. Storytelling and song are important elements in South Sudanese culture, so the musical program focuses on the preservation of traditional stories, songs, and musical traditions. This provides the children with a link to their own culture, and preserves a sense of normality: South Sudanese evenings often involve children learning songs and stories. By teaching across the usual boundaries of tribal culture, the aim is to support peace-building efforts, fostering understanding and empathy across a cultural divide.The organization that started in 2017 with only 3 founding members has grown to over 32 members. We first registered as a company limitedby guarantee with the Uganda Registration Service Bureau but with the advice from Oxfam in 2019, we registered the organization as Community based organization at Yumbe district and officially got clearance by OPM and operating in the Child Protection Department under OPM Bidibidi. We started the organization with only 20 unaccompanied refugee children, now we have 56 children in Uganda, 24 children in Tambura, 20 Children in Yambio and 20 Children in Ibba South Sudan, summing up to 120 Children under our program.The organization is well structured with seven (7) Prominent Board Members, (one from Norway, one US Citizen, one Ugandan and four South Sudanese) working in different International Organizations like UNHCR and UNICEF. The board is made up of 3 females and 4 males. The Executive is made up of between the age of 20-32 years, with females occupying 9 positions.With the ongoing implementation of Revitalized Peace Agreement in South Sudan, I CAN South Sudan has registered in South Sudan as a National None Governmental Organization (NNGO) and has expanded its work to Tambura, Yambio and Ibba in South Sudan with the aim of reaching out to children and single mothers orphaned and affected by the recent civil war to heal them of trauma and to support the integration of returnee into the community. We dream to establish our services in all states across South Sudan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">I CAN South Sudan</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">#According to Associated Press June 2017, Over 10,500 children arrived with strangers or relatives as they flee conflict from SouthSudan in 2016 that are not their parents and live in the Bidibidi and Imvepi refugee settlements in northern Uganda, according to World Vision, which has put more than 3,000 of them into foster care. The rest have been reunited with family, Talagwa said.
The children, referred to as unaccompanied minors, pose serious challenges for aid workers who quickly have to figure outwhat to do with them when they cross the border. Even when the children show maturity far beyond their years, they still need the care of foster parents who are vetted on many grounds, including a clear sense of kinship.#
It is upon the above report/article that we were motivated, inspired and touched to start I CAN South Sudan so as to engage the unaccompanied children in social and musical activities to heal them of trauma.Created by refugee youth, Stephen Wandu Bimo (founder), Seme Ludanga Faustino (cofounder) and a Ugandan, Kyobutungi Angela (cofounder) in October 2017, I CAN South Sudan initially selected 20 unaccompanied refugee children in Bidibidi Refugee Settlement Zone 1 with the help of the community and started its activities at Chrisco Church, in May 2018, I CAN South Sudan received a Good Will support of Euro 5,000 from Misereor Germany to help the 20 children over 6 months. This support helped I CAN South Sudan to record a music album and shot one video for the unaccompanied children,giving them voice to express their desire for peace, unity,forgiveness, reconciliation and coexistence among South Sudanese. The children were also taken out to Zoo and beach in Entebbe and Freedom City. The children were periodically provided with scholastic materials, body lotion and soapIn 2019, the organization hasgrown from 3 founding members to 14 members that includes 5 ladies most of whom are in strategic positions. Above 50 children come for the I CAN practices and activities.The organization has been registered both in South Sudan and Uganda and we have launched Artand drawing program in Rockland Primary school in Bidibidi Zone 1 that engage 40 children in art and drawing program and planting of fruits and distribute them to the households freely as a seed of peace.In 2014, Yumbe district#s recorded population numbered roughly 485,000 Ugandans. Yumbe is the historic land of the Aringa people, the majority of whom are subsistence farmers and followers of Islam. Yumbe is one of the poorest districts in Uganda. Schools and health centres are severely under-resourced and underperforming, infrastructure is underdeveloped, and economic opportunities lag behind the rest of the nation. The Aringa#s history of conflict,poverty, and Islamic faith provide a backdrop of perceived and actual marginalization of the Aringa inside Uganda. Unlike other communities in northern Uganda, the Aringa do not report sharing direct ethnic ties to communities across the border in South Sudan; however, many Aringa are aware of distant kinship with many groups of South Sudan. The Aringa language is part of the Central Sudanic family, which also includes South Sudan&apos;s Ma#di, Avokaya and Moro languages. Aringa is distinct but related to the Lugbara spoken inArua. Aringa is variously categorized as a dialect of Lugbara or as a separate language of its own. Many Aringa speak both Aringa and common Lugbara. There are no known indigenous Aringa populations in South Sudan. However, some Aringa feel an affiliation with their South Sudanese neighbours as marginalized groups with shared historical and kinship links.Relations between the host community and refugees are good due to the shared historical ties. Refugees and nationals are occasionally brought together for dialogues onpressing issues informing the response, which has also improved the delivery of services.Bidi Bidi settlement was established in September 2016 to host the rapid influx of South Sudanese refugees, primarily arriving from the Equatoriaregion. The settlement population increased rapidly to over 280,000 people, making it one of the largest refugee settlements in the world. As of December 2016,Bidi Bidi reached maximum capacity and stopped accepting new arrivals.According to RefugeeInformation Management System (RIMS) June 2018, The following are the gaps and challenges in Bidi Bidi Zone 1 and among the gaps and challenges, Child protection was reported as a significant gap in Bidi Bidi settlement. 96% of children PSNs need to be provided with individual case management, 21% of unaccompanied or separated children have not been provided with interim or long term care and 7% of cases in the past three months ofchild abuse or exploitation received age and gender servicesThere areonlyfew clean water sources available to the population in Bidi Bidi. Long distance to the water points, long waiting lines and high congestion are issues facing refugees collecting water. Thefew existing boreholes are of poor quality, nationals reported repairs of the boreholes are continuously delayed. The water supplied is insufficient, which is exacerbated by the dry season. As sources dry up, both refugees and nationals are forced to collect water from unprotected water sources. Furthermore, the poor latrine coverage in the settlement has led to increased open defecation, which further deteriorates the hygiene and sanitation in Bidi Bidi.Access to quality education is limited for both refugees and the surrounding host community. Schools are few with insufficient classrooms and insufficient teachers leading to low teacher per student ratios. This was reported to severely inhibit the students# learning environment. This is further deteriorated by the lack of schoolmaterials and lack of training for teachers. Moreover, the absence of vocational training institutions limits the opportunities available for students unable to access secondary school or those unable to access tertiary education. This significantly reduces theirchances to access livelihoodsopportunities in the future.Refugees were provided with non-food items (NFIs), such as saucepans, solar lamps, mattresses and jerry cans, upon arrival to the settlement. These have, however not been re-distributed since the refugees&apos;arrival, which therefore means they are for the most part worn out or broken. This forces refugees to share with their neighbors and take it in turns to cook. The lack of access to functional NFIs reduces the living standards of refugees.Both refugees and nationalsface important challenges in accessing livelihoods opportunities. Refugees, in particular, struggle to access land for agricultural activities. The land provided to them upon arrival is insufficient to cultivate crops and the cost of hiring land is expensive. Moreover, those that do have access to land struggle to harvest their crops as the land is infertile and they have not received improved seeds adapted to the harsh climate conditions. Nationals highlighted they also struggle to access livelihoods trainingopportunities preventing them from acquiring the skills needed for employment.Child protection was reported as a significant gap in Bidi Bidisettlement. Refugee#s highlighted child-headed households are not provided with the appropriate servicesthey need. Moreover, children, particularly young girls, are often sent to collect firewood for their families far from the settlement, which has led to cases of rape and sexual and gender based violence (SGBV). Additionally, theft was reported to be an issue in the settlement where food items are often stolen at night.Hence this is why we find our social services important in individual case management of the children, to provide interim and long term therapy care and advocate for children#s rights.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="5403" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-23">4500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">4500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">4500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">I CAN South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06390-05:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06390"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="UG Covid-19 prep and response Apr-Jun20"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002092"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5200"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4800"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5200"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4800"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
