<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2056" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-05T23:40:31" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-05T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06433-02:NE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-COVID-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tutoring students of primary schools in Tahoua and Maradi following the closure of schools due to the pandemic Covid-19
Oxfam in Niger with funding from SP DANIDA through Oxfam IBIS is implementing the Education For Active Citizenship (EFAC) project in 40 primaryschools in the Maradi and Tahoua regions. The objective of this project is to mobilize, through advocacy, the financial resources necessary to improve the quality of education and vocational training in Niger. These 40 primary schools have a total of 10,753 students, including 4,613 girls, who are suffering from the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic. To minimize the spread and impact of the disease in schools, the EFAC project redirected funds from certain activities to take action to combat COVID-19. An amount of 27,786 Euros is redirected for awareness-raising activities in schools and the purchase of hand washing devices and hydroalcoholic gels. These actions will be initiated when the schools reopen. As part of the fight against the COVID-19pandemic, the State of Niger has implemented several preventive measures to limit the spread of the disease. Among these preventive measures, there is the closure of allschools and universities in the country from March 19, 2020. Despite the reopening ofschools scheduled for June 1, 2020 for a period of 45 days, it will be very difficult to cover school time lost, therefore claiming to ensure a certain quality of teaching-learning. This gap, in terms of lost school time, will result in pupils in rural areas finding themselves with a significant drop in school levels compared to those expected in normal times. This drop in level is likely to jeopardize their transition to higher class thefollowing year.
&#xA0;Based on the logic in which the school year willbe validated, which means that pupils, despite their below normal levels, will move up to the higher class for the 2020-2021 school year. So if this situation which is inexorably looming on the horizon occurs, it is very likely that a situation of massive dropout of pupils will occur in schools, especially those from vulnerable rural families; because these children will not be able to hold on because they have not acquired the minimum required to appropriate the teachings / learnings of the passage classes.This situation of massive dropout of students could be more acute at the level of transition classes, in particular CM2 classes (last year of primary) and CI classes (first year of primary). That is to say, many CM2 students will go to college without having the required level, which would lead to frustrations which will result in dropouts and dismissals during or at the end of the school year. This will cause many children to lose their right to education, and would expose girls to another scourge,namely early marriage.To respond to this massive dropout situation linked to the COVID-19 pandemic in the intervention areas of the EFAC project, Oxfam in Niger is seeking funding through this concept-note to provide educational support to students ingrades 5 and 6 CI of partner schools of the EFAC project which are the most exposed.This intervention, which lasts two (2) months from June 15 to August 15, 2020, essentially aims to offer Support Courses to students in CM2 and CI classes to improve their levels to allow them to keep in the upper classes. The choice of these students is justified by the fact that they are in transition classes and those most exposed to wastage. A total of 4,115 students including 1,811 girls. These students are distributedas follows: 2010 CM2 students including 775 girls and 2105 CI students including 1036 girls.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib is one of the 17 national affiliates of the Oxfam International Confederation. It started life in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994. Working together in confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education for all, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies. Oxfam Novibs main office is based in The Netherlands, it supports the work of a network of local offices, the implementation of global projects, fund raising, campaigning and advocacy. The Hub Niamey Niger exists since 2006 as a humanitarian field office and since 2012 as the decentralized Country office for Oxfam Novib, dealing with all the development and humanitarian themes like Sustainable livelihoods, Right to Basic services, Humanitarian and resilience interventions, The right to be heard and the right to an Identity, including women&apos;s rights and sexual and reproductive health rights. The Country Office in Niger works with local partners to realize the vision of a Niger without poverty</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-05">55932</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-01">39861</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">1125</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">222</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">3828</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">7409</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">3487</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06433-02:NE">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007154"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Niger (SAWA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06433"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Tutoring students of primary schools"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002130"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
