<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2383" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-06-30T23:30:35" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-30T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-30">27108</value>
  </budget>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
  </contact-info>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPS together with the consortium members Vision for Humanity and People empowering people  will implement COVID-19 Project with the following activities:
Result 0.0 Startup and closeout activities


A0.1: Conduct stakeholder inception meeting

The Consortium partners will organize an inception meeting to introduce the project to stakeholders and secure their feedback to improve finalimplementation strategies. The district COVID-19 task force will participate at district level since meetings involving many peopleare prohibited. The same meetings will be cascaded to 2 sub counties of Odupi and Uriama with the respective Sub County COVID-19 task Force.

A0.2: Organize consortium Coordination meetings
The Consortium partners will conduct three monthly partnership coordination meetings. The meetings will be held to share progress and review plans for subsequent months. The meetings will be held in partner offices on rotational basis with clear compliance with social distancing requirements.

A0.3: Conduct joint monitoring field visits
Although all public and privately owned passenger vehicles are prohibited, PALM Corps received official taskforce movement stickers for two cars. This will enable the partners to conduct targeted field visits toselected households, VHTs, selected markets, kitchen gardens to monitor progress. The reports will be shared in the district task force coordination meetings.

A0.4: Attend COVID-19 Task force coordination meetings.
The consortium partners will attenddistrict and sub county covid-19 task force meetings toshare progress and review project performance.

A0.5: Organize end of project meeting
The project will organize a project close-out meeting that will involve district and sub county covid-19 taskforce and some selected beneficiaries to disseminate results and share the lessons learnt as detailing the unexpected benefits and impacts.

Results 1: Community level surveillance on COVID-19 response strengthened.
The project hopes to establish an effective surveillance system to detect and manage suspected cases effectively without stigmatizing the suspects or creating conflict in the community. The specific activities are:
Activity 1.1: Train VHTs, LCs &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; RWCs  on COVID 19 response.
VHTs, LCs andRWCs are front-liners in COVID 19 response. The project will collaborate with the task force to train the VHTs, LCs and RWCs on COVID-19 preparedness, risk mapping and response actions in line with MOH SOPs andProtocols. This will be a maximum of three-hourtraining sessions with 10 participants per session. In total five sessions will be held in three days to equip them to detect and report suspected cases for further investigation, distribute hand-washing facilities to targeted households, markets andhealth centres.

Activity 1.2: Conduct COVID-19 risk mapping.
This will be a basic data collection process on risky behaviors, hotspots, new arrivals, community suspected cases, etc. The project will provide VHTs with case definition tools and referral forms to enable reporting to health facilities for immediate action. Suspected cases will be documented and handled according to COVID-19 response protocol.

Activity 1.3: Procure and provide assorted items to COVID-19 task force for surveillance.
The project will provide one-off support in form of fuel, Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) and assorted sanitary items to facilitate district and sub county COVID-19 task force.

Result 2: Enhanced communication and social mobilization capacity to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic
The result will be achieved through community engagement, social and behavior change communication practices. The specific activities are as below:

Activity 2.1: Translate/Print and disseminate MOH approved IEC materials.
Visual charts will be translated in Arabic (and local dialect of the refugees) to bring on board the refugee population that may not be able to understand English. These will be distributed and disseminated by VHTs accordingly.


Activity 2.2: Installsign post with posters about COVID-19 control.
The project will erect 3 signboards at the 3 food markets in Rhino camp. The will bear messages and illustrations on COVID-19 in the commonly spoken local languages. The content will be derived from the approved MOH materials.
Activity 2.3: Conduct community perception tracking
The project will develop text, audio and video of community perception trackingtool (CPT) through which community rumors, beliefs, ideas, concerns etc. are collected, presented todistrict COVID-19 task force for discussion and response plan. This will ensure the task force develop a context specific behavior change strategy.

Activity 2.4: Conduct radio talk shows and spot messages in language on COVID-19 pandemic.
The projectwill support (district task force) to undertake radio talk shows, spots messages in the languages about COVID-19, preventive measures including hand washing, hygiene and social distancing practices to promote behavior change among the targeted communities. Advocacy sessions will be aired on radios to engage communities against gender based violence (domestic violence) and Governments on facilitating access to Reproductive Health services and commodities for women and adolescents during the fight against COVID-19pandemic.

Activity 2.5: Procure and distribute communication tools and equipment
The project will procure and distribute communication tools like megaphones and mobile phones for VHT coordinators and in addition profile district and sub county task force mobile phone contact inventory and share with VHTs and community leadership for risk communication and community engagement/feedback.

Result 3: Strengthened WASH campaigns in food markets (Ofua 3, Yelulu and Siripi)
To achieve the result,the project will empower market management committee to establish, manage and enforce hand washing at the market. The specific activities are:

Activity 3.1. Procure and distribute WASH materials to targeted food markets in the refugee settlement.
Theproject will procure and distribute WASH materials including liquid and bar soap and handwashing tanks with to sustain hand washing practice at food markets places, water points and food distribution points. The WASH materials will be managed by market managementcommittees (MMC).
Activity 3.2. Conduct market based WASH awareness campaigns on COVID-19 in three food markets.
The awareness campaigns will be a social and behavior change approaches. Based on the social risks in Rhino Camp refugee settlement, the project will collaborate with Health Assistants and VHT coordinators to conduct WASH awareness on market days in at three markets of Siripi, Ofua 3, and Yelulu to promote hygiene and hand washing practices.

Result 4: Enhanced safety nets (Social protection) for selected vulnerable households.

Two strategies will be used to achieve this result; first the project will work with the three groups supported earlier under HRGF I to support kitchen gardening to improve access to micro-nutrientrichvegetablesto build enhance immunity of the households. Nutrition education including cooking demonstration will be conducted toensure nutritive value is maintained. Secondly, the most vulnerable women will be identified and supported with soap and salt.   The specific activities are:

Activity 4.1: Train in Kitchen/ Back Yard Gardening (BYG).
The vulnerable population (PSNs) in Rhino Camp refugee settlement, like elsewhere are predicting hard times with the looming food crisis as a result of COVID-19 crisis. The project will promote backyard gardening in every household to grow quick growing and nutritious vegetables to complement diet. The extension support will be offered directly in mini groups of 3-5 farmers but also remotely to minimize congregating farmers in groups.

Activity 4.2: Procure and distribute agro-inputs
The project will provide one-off assorted inputs both food and commercial crops.  Vegetable seeds (nutrition pack) will be provided for targeted household to complement diet forboth the rainy and dry season.

Activity 4.3: Conduct nutrition education
The project will provide basic nutrition education (balanced diet, food hygiene, preparation and preservation). PALM Corps has already developed a standard chart on nutrition education tailored according to food needs for different social groups (children, pregnant and lactating mothers, the sick and elderly).

Activity 4.4: Provide hand washing soap and salt to selected vulnerable households using Cash Transfer Programming.
The project will identify 140 women and girls, elderly, disabled people and provide vouchers to enable access to 2 bars soap and two sachets of salt for three month in accordance with the minimum expenditure basket (MEB) principle. The price of salt had increased by 300% at the onset of COVID-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-13:UG">
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
  </document-link>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-13:UG</iati-identifier>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <location>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-41.102 175.1099</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPS LTD- GENERAL PCLO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM Corps is a not for profit company that was registered in 2014 arising from the increased demand for local NGOs to contribute and take charge of the development initiatives in the region. The subscribers (Directors) are Anyanzo Thomas Abbey, Albert Azu and Swadik Kasim. See attached article and Memorandum of Association. Before PALM Corps was registered the directors where providing consultancy services in the region under PALM Business Consult and Agric supplies Ltd (for profit company). Since its registration PALM Corps was implementing project in West Nile in the sector of Agriculture, Primary Education, WASH, Nutrition and Environment. In 2017PALM Corps embarked on setting governance system including establishment of board of governance and developing policies. With more solid governance system and policies in place, PALM is one of the rapidly growing local NGOs operating in West Nile.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS

PALM Corps in partnership with Horizont3000, Welthungerhilfe, SNV, Eleanor Crook Foundation, ZOA, Volkshilfe secured funds to provide services to the refugees and host communities in West Nile. A total of 1,619 pregnant and Lactating Women and 925 CU2 in Moyo district were directly supported under nutrition project funded by Eleanor Crook Foundation; 2500 pupils in Rhino camp refugee settlement were reached with school feeding and 480 parents of the children supported to improve their knowledge on good farming practices; 180 (75 female) youth are skilled through various trades including saloon, carpentry, building, motorcycle repair, bakery and vegetable growing with support of Welhungerhilfe and Horizont3000; 250acres of teak woodlots established in Rhinocamp and Imvepi refugeesettlements in Arua district with funds from BMZ (Germany); access to education is being improved for over 5000 school girls(refugees and host) in Rhinocamp and finally 50 agribusinesses  including SMEs and farmer groups were linked to market and finance.
3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE

Mission: To improve the quality of life of the poorest and most vulnerable communities through innovative, sustainable, evidence-based and people-centred programmes that transform their livelihood practices, attitudes and values.

Institutional objectives: PALM desires to see a world wherethe poorest and most vulnerable communities live a dignified, healthy, peaceful and productive life

Field(s) of activity: PALM Corps is permitted/Licenced by NGO Bureau to operate in West Nile, and Northern Uganda. But currently the operations are limited to West Nile.  The sectors are Agriculture and Livelihoods, Primary Education, Nutrition, WASH and Environment.
4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
The influx of refugees in West Nile has attracted a couple of humanitarian and development organizations who areproviding social services to the refugees and the host community to complement on government efforts. With the localization policy of the government of Uganda, this presents opportunities for local organizations to partner with theinternational organizations to participate in responding to the crisis and development challenges in the region. The demand for social services in huge especially in the refugee settlements where access to and quality of education, health services and food is a problem. WFP provides food or cash for refugees to buy food. The prices of food items increased as result of the influx and unfortunately the local population is not responding adequately to produce food to meet the demand. The region is still net importer of food itemsespecially vegetables, beans and maize from other regions of Uganda and DRC.  PALM has rich experience of value chain development and facilitation of multi-stakeholder processes which makes the organization attractive to several development actors.
5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)
The board is comprised of 5 members, 2 of who are female. The top three positions i.e. ED, Program Manager and FAM are all filled by males;3 Project Coordinator out of 5 are female. And at field level (Project Officer, 40% of the staff are female, 60% male.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <target value="720"></target>
    </period>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <target value="480"></target>
    </period>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <target value="804"></target>
    </period>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <target value="536"></target>
    </period>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
  </result>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPS COVID-19 Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <transaction>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">27108</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPS LTD- GENERAL PCLO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">27108</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
