<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="plannlno-ao" dstore:index="7" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-28T16:03:01.0531334+02:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-28T13:53:59.5231069Z" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-KEN100347</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH First: Scaling up WASH SDG efforts: the first line of defence against COVID-19 - Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY
The WASH First program in Kenya started in 2020 and is part of the scaling-up efforts of the WASH SDG Consortium and its main objective is to prevent further spread of COVID19.  Plan International Kenya started the implementation of the program in the urban informal settlements of Kibera and Kawangware of Nairobi and in Kilifi North (town), Rabai and Kaloleni. These areas have been hit hard by the pandemic. The program will organize awareness raising campaigns on COVID-19. It further will promote direct messaging and information sharing. And finally,  it will improve access to water, sanitation, handwashing facilities and (menstrual) hygiene products.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first cases of Covid-19 were detected early 2020 and government took the measures like promoting social distancing, handwashing and wearing face masks.  Quarantine centers were setup for people diagnosed with the disease and large gatherings were forbidden.  A lockdown and curfew were in effect during the first months. The project intervention areas were selected in coordination with Ministry of Health (MoH) and had already limited access to WASH facilities. Many of the residents of the  informal urban settlements Kibera and Kawangware of Nairiobi had already pre-existing medical conditions like tuberculosis and HIV. More underaged girls were forced to marriage and more teenage girls got pregnant. Lockdown and curfew also increased the risk of violence for women and girls when visiting public toilets at night. In the rural areas people have almost no access to water and sanitation. Because schools were closed children had less access to WASH facilities. Lockdown also caused more cases of Gender Based Violence.  
People with disabilities face challenges in accessing WASH services and prevention messaging. The fear of stigmatisation of being diagnosed with Covid-19 complicated the track and trace efforts of the MoH.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the program is:
Promotion of health-related hygiene practices to prevent further spread of COVID-19 in at-risk countries through awareness raising and improved access to water, sanitation and hygiene services
Result areas:
1.  Enhanced understanding of individuals, communities, health workers, schools and WASH service providers about  mitigation measures against COVID-19 transmission
2. Population at risk of Covid-19 have sufficient and constant access to commodities and consumables (i.e. handwashing facilities, disinfection equipment, soap, hygiene kits including menstrual health products) and personal protective equipment (PPEs)
3. Population at risk of COVID-19 have safe (considering safeguarding and security) access to Water and Sanitation services through the construction of new and repair of non-functional water facilities or through temporary/mobile services/supplies. Support adolescent girls living in urban informal settlements in having access to bathrooms by paying the public toilet use fee</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the start of the health crisis, the government was acting quickly and CSO&apos;s had no role in the decision taking process.  However, space for civil society to engage with government remained as government was actively seeking involvement. This program has been developed in coordination with the Ministry of Health. Local actors like community workers, WASH committees, sanitation workers, schools, WASH service providers and government officials will be trained on how to reduce transmission of COVID-19 virus. Plan Kenya has a presence in the intervention areas and has a working relationship with government and other stakeholders. Plan implements directly and through its local partner the Real Hope Youth and Community Organization (RHYCO), and has experience with the implementation of WASH programs. The program is fully aligned with the Emergency Response Program that had been prepared in the context of the pandemic.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The end beneficiaries of the programme activities will be the vulnerable and at risk groups living in the  low income  informal urban settlements Kibera and Kawangware of Nairobi and in Kilifi Noth and the rural areas of Rabai and Kaloleni.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Kenya will implement the following activities on the 6 intervention strategies:

Intervention strategy 1: Awareness raising (campaigns and mass media campaigns) on COVID-19
&#x2022; Raise awareness in communities on COVID-19 prevention, using different methodologies such as the
use of murals that have been strategically painted on walls and billboards
&#x2022; Use media and participate in the talk shows

Intervention strategy 2: Direct information sharing and messaging
&#x2022; Support the sensitisation of CHV/Ws in charge of COVID-19 prevention messaging and control
management.
&#x2022; Strengthen the capacity of girl&#x2019;s advocates for peer support on COVID-19 prevention and information
sharing and advocacy on issues concerning children and girls.
&#x2022; Raise awareness in schools using the COVID-19 prevention guidelines for schools that are currently
being developed.
&#x2022; Promote social distancing measures around WASH facilities and prioritise access for elderly/disabled/
pregnant people.
&#x2022; Work with CHW/Vs so they can distribute contextualised prevention messages.

Intervention strategy 3: Improving access to safe drinking water and water supply for handwashing, as
well as menstrual health and sanitation (including safe disposal of waste)
&#x2022; Support communities to access water for handwashing and consumption. Handwashing units will be
placed in strategic places.
&#x2022; Truck water to strategic water storage facilities for ease of access.
&#x2022; Support adolescent girls living in urban informal settlements in having access to bathrooms by paying
the public toilet use fee.
&#x2022; Ensure vulnerable people have access to WASH facilities.
&#x2022; Install handwash units in schools and make MHM products available for girls.

Intervention strategy 4: Improving access to safe handwashing facilities
&#x2022; Place handwashing units in strategic places with liquid soap that are also accessible for the disabled
and elderly.
&#x2022; Provide handwashing units and liquid soap in schools when they reopen in January 2021.

Intervention strategy 5: Access to hygiene products including soap, disinfectant, PPE and menstrual
hygiene products
&#x2022; Provide appropriate hygiene kits and sanitary towels for girls and support them in accessing bathrooms
for personal hygiene in urban informal settlements.
&#x2022; Ensure vulnerable people have access to hygiene products.
&#x2022; Collaborate with the MoH to procure infection prevention materials such as disinfectants, and
detergents in order to ensure there is adequate disinfection at critical areas including schools, public
transport facilities and health facilities. MoH guidelines on IPC will be followed.
&#x2022; Disinfect schools before the planned re-opening, as some have been used as isolation centres.
&#x2022; Where necessary, procure and supply sanitisers to health care workers and teachers.
&#x2022; Procure and distribute masks, both surgical and reusable, for health care workers and CHVs. Masks
will also be given to vulnerable people within the selected communities.

Intervention strategy 6: COVID-related coordination meetings with local government and other
stakeholders
&#x2022; Collaborate with the MoH and other partners to update information on the pandemic as appropriate.
&#x2022; Support national measures and initiatives to share more information on COVID-19 transmission
prevention and control.
&#x2022; Support the development of appropriate gender sensitive and inclusive messages for communities,
taking into consideration their literacy level and ability to understand.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional: By involving local government and local stakeholders, the ownership of the program will be anchored in the local institutional structure. 

Social: The active participation of the target groups is essential to ensure that we respond to their specific needs.  The overall goal of this program is the &#x201C;promotion of health-related hygiene practices to prevent further spread of COVID-19 through awareness raising and improved access to WASH services.&#x201D; The intervention will ensure that the achievement of the SDG 6 goals does not come to a standstill in the intervention areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="KE-NCB-218051924226" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-C" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water, Sanitation &amp; Hygiene</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 5" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THRIVE -Early Childhood Care and Development (including WASH) (ECCD)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">327406</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">22289</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="UB1264">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-21">200000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="KE-NCB-218051924226" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2021-02-28T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-28">1065</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2021-03-31T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-31">1349</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-12-31T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">1562</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="kosten oktober 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-31">1136</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-11-30T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-30">1349</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2021-01-31T00:00:00.000">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-31">1349</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41198890-Wash First" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0=Not measured; 1=Gender unaware; 2=Gender Neutral; 3=Gender Aware; 4=Gender Transformative. For measurement of KPI-6: Percentage of running programme activities that are gender-aware or gender-transformative</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.06" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="3.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of boys reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.04" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of boys reached (under 18)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="241306.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender transformative marker - design</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoring of the project design by the gender transformative marker of Plan International; 
gender blind (1), gender neutral (2), gender aware (3), gender transformative (4)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.11" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender transformative marker - implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoring of the implementation phase by the gender transformative marker of Plan International; 
gender blind (1), gender neutral (2), gender aware (3), gender transformative (4)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.12" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young men</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.08" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="72715.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of girls reached (under 18)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect beneficiaries</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.03" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of girls reached (under 18)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="261414.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct and indirect reach of young women</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="0000.07" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="74183.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Covid-19 prevention &amp; response</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hygiene kits (including menstrual health products) that has been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.1" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hygiene kits (including menstrual health products) that has been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="14500.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new, repaired, temporary and/or mobile handwashing facilities that are provided to the at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.2.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new, repaired, temporary and/or mobile handwashing facilities that are provided to the at risk population</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2400.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached directly with awareness raising activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached directly with awareness raising activities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="350000.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached through mass media</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that are reached through mass media</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="600000.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="638.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of PPEs that have been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.5.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of PPEs that have been provided directly to the at risk population</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15000.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained related to COVID-19 prevention and response</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="612.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to handwashing facilities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Estimated number of at risk population who have access to handwashing facilities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1865" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Estimated number of at risk population who have access to handwashing facilities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="77000.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity training for service providers</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specify capacity training</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="220.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.1" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of WASH service providers and suppliers supported/trained</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="230.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to drinking water</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using the water points constructed or rehabilitated</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="3.2.1." indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using the water points constructed or rehabilitated</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15000.00"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
