<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2024" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-07T23:30:47" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-07T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-27:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PICOT CTP Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PICOT
The proposed intervention is designed to address the critical Livelihood and WASH needs of refuges and Host communities through enhancing alternative livelihood options, adopting positive copping strategies and WASH.
Through the proposed activities, beneficiaries&#x2019; livelihood options will be enhanced by creating more opportunity to engage on IGA activities thereby securing their livelihoods and reducing vulnerabilities due to income shocks and risks. Once the livelihood options are diversified, dependence on food ratios will be reduced and households&#x2019; disposable income will be boosted and beneficiaries will have positive coping strategies.The Cash Transfer Program approach of the intervention will put money into beneficiary&#x2019;s packet and increase their dignity to spend on their most important needs as valued by them. CTP approach under this intervention is expected to boast the market systems by supporting other actors directly and indirectly along the chain.The Goal of the Project is; To enhance livelihood and self-reliance of refugees and Host community through alternative livelihood strategies and promotion of hygiene and sanitation practices in Lobule refugee settlement by Dec. 2020.The objectives of the project is;  To promote alternative livelihood options and positive copying strategies for refugees and Host communities through Cash Transfer Modality by December 2020. To promote good hygiene and sanitation practices among refugee and host communities in lobule settlement by Dec 2020 and To promote alternative livelihood options and positive copying strategies and promote good hygiene and sanitation practices. Hence it seeks to amalgamate Livelihood and WASH in efforts topromote self-reliance among the refugees and host communities while fighting the COVID-19 Pandemic and community infection through WASH Practices.To archive the proposed objectives the following activities will be conducted; PICOT and consortium members will work with OPM, UNHCR and other partners to identify and Support 250 Persons with special needs (PSNs) and extremely vulnerable individuals (EVIs) with multipurpose cash grant. The criteria for selection will be based on the PSN codes and multiple vulnerability (using the latest updated PSN List by UNHCR). The community will also be sensitized about the selection criteria and they will participate in validation of the selected beneficiaries to ensure that the most needy and vulnerable of the beneficiaries are supported.The identified beneficiaries will be supported with financial support amounting to a total of 96,000 shillings paid one off (But meant tolast for three months). The transfer value will attract a Transfer cost of 9% of transfer value. The Transfer value was determined using the March 2020 (updated in May) Minimum expenditure Basket (MEB) . The transfer value will contribute to Food (15,000), Hygiene (4,000), water (1,000), Health (1,000), HH items &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; personal expenditures (2,000) and Livelihood (10,000).The mode of cash transfer will be by use of a financial institution (preferably SACCOs because of a lower transfer fee) transferred either via mobilemoney  or direct cash with strict adherence to the Oxfam CTP SOP . The service provider will be identified following the PICOT Procurement and bidding procedure.Post distribution monitoring will be conducted after each distribution cycle to assess the effectiveness and use of the cash grant by beneficiaries.PICOT will use her Complaint and feedback mechanism throughout the project period to enhance feedforward, feedback and accountability to all the beneficiaries and community at large. The community will also be made aware of the various channels of complaints and feedback so that they can channel their complains and addressed by the project teamWhile there is no sufficient land to engage all refugees in agricultural production as informed by our need assessment, PICOT recognizes that there are various potential and diverse skills among refugees and host communities that can be transformed into viable business opportunities. A total of 5 groups of youth and women will be targeted for IGAs. Each group will comprise 5 members each for easy management and group dynamics based on past learning. For this component, consortium partners will target those with the required skills, experience and motivation and who have the potential to succeed in the livelihood support activities.PICOT will select 5viable IGAs to be supported with startup support kits or grants. Youth, women and PSNs will be sensitized on various business options that can be supported including; establishing and operating grain milling machines, hand operating groundnut-paste making machine, Hand crafts, small grocery shops/kiosks, vegetable vending, salons and barber shops to mention but a few. The grants will be competitive and the best business plans that demonstrate sustainability rather than profitability will be selected for funding. The 5 best business ideas will receive start up grants in kind or Cash worth from UGX 1,000,000-3,500,000 each depending on the business ideaand type a total 7,500,000 Ugx has been earmarked in the budget for the IGAs.The Project will provide 1000 Tip taps and 1 bars ofsoap for each house hold in the refugee settlement and host community through use of commodity voucher.PICOT in collaboration withSpirit FM and Lobule Women Group will Provide 1000 Tip taps and 1 bars of soap for households in the refugee settlement and host community to boost hand washing at household level through use of commodity voucher during a trade fair organized within the settlement. It was noticed during our need assessment and observation from the previous intervention that majority of households (over 65%) lacked handwashing facilities. According to the Uganda Bureau of Statistics (UBOS) population projection Statistics obtained from koboko district Planning unit and OPM office, Lobule refugee settlement and the Four refugee hosting parishes have a total 2,214 households (891 are refugees HHs). The 1000 tip-taps will contribute in closing the gap and increase coverage of hand washing facilities at HH by 45%.The hygiene promoters and selected Youths &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; women will be trained on making tip-tap handwashing technology who will be engaged in making and installing of the Tip-Taps through a Cash for work modality. 40 youth, women and PSNs will be engaged to make 5 Tip Taps per day for 5days at 5000 per man day. A days training on how to make the tip taps will be conducted for the youthand the hygiene promotors who will also continue to monitor the usage of the Tip Taps. The installation process will be done in thepresences of the beneficiaries so that they can learn how it is done which will be a sustainability strategy.This intervention is aimed at boosting hygiene at household level and prevents communicable diseases related to fecal and food contamination including COVID19. The Tip-taps will be branded with Partner Logos and COVID-19 Hand washing/Hygiene Messages as IEC materials.PICOT in collaboration with Spirit FM and Lobule Women Group will work with water user committee members, community members and local authorities toprotect the 19 community water points by engaging youths within to fence and greenish the water points through cash for work modality. Reference will be made to Oxfam&#x2019;s cash transfer programing SOP to effectively execute cash for work process. The Cash for work (CfW) activity will target unemployed youth and women informed by the labour market assessment reports and selection criteria with the objective of putting cash in the hands of the youth and women to improve household income. CfW activities will focus on water source protection, through establishing fences using local available materials, natural turf.Engaging both host and refugee youth and women will assist in promoting social cohesion and peaceful co-existence between the communities.  Selection criteria will include beneficiaries with no employment opportunities; no production assets; no/limited support from kinship in the settlement and members ofhigh dependency families (more than 6 members).The Cash for work value of 6,000 per day for two days per water point determined by the local labour cost for similar work will be used to execute this activity. A group of 5 people will work at each of the water point.Community members through the water user committees will be mobilized to cost share by contributing small amount of money as maintenance fee for future need. This intervention will enable ownership and protection of water sources thereby increasing their life spans. Communities can effectively prevent destructions caused by stray animals. The MEAL of PICOT together with consortium members will conduct Post-Work Monitoring of Cash Usage and Work Quality when the work is completed.PICOT in collaboration with Spirit FM and Lobule Women Group will hold 3 community radio dialogues/talk shows and community sensitization meetings to address poor community attitude and practices on hygiene and sanitation. These sensitizations will take the form of radio talk shows and community discussions in a group of 15 &#x2013; 30 led by hygiene promoters at village level. Content of the meetings will address general hygiene and sanitation practices at households, maintenance of water sources, gender issues, attitude change on hygiene and sanitation practices.An estimated number of 500 people is expected to be reached through community meetings and 3000 people through radio talk shows on hygiene and sanitation. Community radio dialogues will take the form of recording community voices on policy issues concerning hygiene and sanitation that directly affect the health of refugees, host communities and undermine local initiatives. Issues raised will be addressed during talk shows that will feature responsible duty bearers. Through the dialogue and 3 specific issues are either addressed instantly or ear marked for address in the next planning circle.Radio Spot massages will also be run Trice a day for three months in 3 different language of Kakwa, Lugbara and English on WASH, COVID-19 and to give more light on the project activities.CROSS CUTTING ACTIVITIESPICOT in collaboration with Spirit FM and Lobule Women Group will organize an inception meeting involving OPM,implementing partners at the settlement, local government leadership (district and sub county) and refugee leadership. This meetingwill mark the entry point for the intervention and detail the project, its objectives, activities, expected out puts and the approved budget. It will also be used to rally leaders and other IP behind the project for its success.PICOT a consortium member will work within the exiting guidelines to conduct a rapid needs assessment to ascertain the rightful beneficiaries in the settlement, market analysis, status of water sources and households without proper handwashing facilities in refugee and host communities in lobule Sub County.The assessment will provide baseline information and validate the available information.PICOT in collaboration with Spirit FM and Lobule Women Group will conduct post distribution monitoring and Post-Work  Monitoring of Cash Usage and Work Quality todetermine beneficiary certification, get feedback on the activities, document success and address immediate challenges. Through PDMwe hope to identify unmet needs of refugees and other emerging issues to inform our delivery mechanism.PICOT together with SpiritFM and Lobule Women Group will attend partner coordination meetings to update partners on the status of implementation, feedback and share experience. Through these meetings, we fore see strong partnership ties with OPM and other Implementing partners that meaningfully benefit consortia members.PICOT in collaboration with Spirit FM and Lobule Women Group will hold internal planning meetingsto discuss implementation progress, activity plans and address emerging implementation issues to ensure the team stay focused to the expected deliverables.PICOT in collaboration with Spirit FM and Lobule Women Group will document project result both in audio, video and pictorial formats to show case the intervention achievements, challenges and lessons learnt and share with stakeholders anddonors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners in Community Transformatio PICOT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners In Community Transformation (PICOT) is non-profit making Organization founded in 2005 by a group of progressive youth graduates as a CBO in the names of Koboko Youth In Development (KOYID).  The overall goal then was to address development challenges in health (HIV/AIDS) education and lack of skills among youths, women and other vulnerable communities in Koboko District specifically.Due to growth in capacity and programming, in 2013, the organization was registered with National NGO board as PICOT and licensed to work in west nile region. At this point strategic decisions were made to review the vision, mission and strategic objective, expand geographical coverage and thematic focus to include humanitarian response given PICOT#s geographical location along the border of three countries (Uganda, DR Congo and South Sudan). This strategic transformation witnessed changes in organizations# policies. PICOT embarked on a rigorous process of policy review and development. Most notably is the gender policy, work place HIV policy, safe guarding policy and the minimum humanitarian standards guidelines. It was also at this point that PICOT got its first female executivedirector. PICOT continues to pay special attention to gender integration in its institutional growth and program design and implementation to realize its overall vision of holistically transformed communities.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?Over last three years, PICOT has registered tremendous success in its major thematic areas. This can be summarized as follows1. Health programming0ver 6,367 people have been reached through our community programs, stakeholder meetings and digital media platforms in West Nile region. 2,830 of total population reached are females of different social characteristics.  This has increased youth access to SRHR services and information at community, school and facility levels. The graph below gives more details of the number people reached by category excluding social and electronic media.Successfully advocated for local governments, schools and health units to allocate budget for youth friendly services, as result schools recruited senior teachers, budget for girl child was improved, special capacity building for senior women and men teachers on managing adolescent were conducted, youth friendly corners were established in two health units to provide reproductive healthservices to youths.PICOT engaged over 2,526 youths of which 1,421 were females in and out of school in direct conversations on sexual reproductive health risks and prevention through forum theatre plays, Twogere (let&apos;s talk)## game, games and sports and outreaches to increase awareness on SRHR risks among young people, increase demand for reproductive health services and encourage parental involvement in SRH discussion with children at household levels. This has improved responsiveness, changed perceptions and assumptions regarding SRH information among youths, parents and community gate keepers.HIV Programming159 clients with suppressed viral load189 clients resumed care from the lost to follow list of21 TB contacts traced were found positive and are started on treatment.A total of 3290 people were referred for services from communities to different service points.Index testing services generated 18 positives tests of which were 7 females and 11 males.Governance and accountabilityWithin our project of social accountability implemented in Koboko and Maracha districts, PICOT engaged communities to donate land for putting up twin staff house for dranya health center staffs. In Wadra health center III maracha district, communities were mobilized to construct kitchen for the inpatient department. The coolest about this is how each community donated resources to have the kitchen constructed with now helping mothers in theward. A total 704 people reached of which 409 males and 295 femalesYouth Skilling ProjectPICOT skilled 1,500 youths of which 749 females and 751males in different non formal skills areas such as tailoring, carpentry and joinery, metal fabrications, netting, saloon and hair dressing, motorcycle mechanics among others  to empower the youths and boost their livelihood opportunities.3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSEMission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?Working with communities and development partners to identify, mobilise and utilize available resources for sustainable development.Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?1. To improve access to health services among 30,000 target vulnerable people in West Nile by 2022.2. To increase access to quality education and skills training for 7500 children and youths and capacity of6,000 SMCs, PTAs and teachers in primary and secondary schools in the target districts improved by 2022.3. To develop efficient relationships among 43,200 farmers in Farmer Groups so as to enhance their knowledge on: GAPS, post-harvest handling, create linkages with traders and processors that are engaged in commodity warehousing, processing and sales; and increase awareness about environmental protection through community dialogues, afforestation campaigns in West Nile.4. To contribute to improved living conditions of approximately 1,000,000 South Sudan and Congolese refugees by providing timely and adequate humanitarian interventions and response to emergency situations in West Nile.5. To enhance the institutional effectiveness, efficiency, responsiveness and sustainability in the provision of quality services in the communities we serve.Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?1. Holistic health promotion2. Education and Skills Development3. Livelihood and Environment4. Humanitarian Response5. Organizational capacity BuildingGeographical areas:By mandate PICOT is licensed to work in West Nile region however currently PICOT operates in four districts of Maracha, Koboko Yumbe and Arua.4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGAnalyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? &apos;In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?PICOT as an organization emerged from the very social, political and economic challenges vulnerable communities face on daily basis however these challenges have continued to affect lives of vulnerable people at different lengths and period often caused by social, economic and political factors and because of community#s vulnerabilities, they have not responded well to the shocks brought about by such eventualities hence their livelihood and social wellbeing is ever threatened.PICOT positions its self to mobilize local communities, empower and support them as chage agents to spear head and address their own challenges in the 9 districts (Koboko, Arua, Yumbe, Adjumani, Zombo, Pakwach, Moyo, Nebbi and Maracha) of West Nile sub region, with the aim of not just providing services, but more importantly setting out to influence the sector of health, WASH, agriculture and education to be responsive tothe local needs.Our five year strategic themes attest to our commitment to effectively deliver through our core functions of improved health services, education and skills development, improving Livelihood and environment and responding to humanitarian needs of the refugees and host communities.Together with its partners PICOT will respond to the West Nile regions# sector challenges in Health, Education, Humanitarian response, Livelihoods and environment, by addressing issues of inequality in access, weak sustainabilitymechanisms, low investment in the selected sectors and governance concerns by strengthening transparency and accountability. As such, in the next five years PICOT will position itself as an advocate and direct service provider to work with the most vulnerable of communities which include Children in and out of school,Women, Persons with Disability, People Living with HIV/Aids, Internally Displaced People and refugees, and the elderly. Specifically, PICOT will focus on pathways that lead to improved interventions, give equal opportunities for women and men and ensurecommunities have equal access to service provision in West Nile region.PICOT will continue working with meaningful partners with common values and principles at various levels among which include local NGOs, networks, governments, donors, private sector,academic and research institutions in a bid to achieve its vision. As an indigenous organization, PICOT has the potential and comparative advantage of mobilizing the communities to participate in their development process. The organization has the community trust and support with existing structures and a network volunteers who share the organizations# vision.5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)How are authority and responsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number of people in each position, and if they are men or women.PICOT has a written comprehensive organizational structure even though it has not been implemented fully due to resources. At the helm of it all is the general assembly (board of trustees) that comprises of 24 members. The major duty is to approve audited reports, annual work plans and annual reports and elect new board members once their term of office elapses. PICOT has 9 board members composed of 2 femalesand 6 males. The board members work through committees of human resource, finance and program. Two of these committees are headed by females. The board provide oversight role, fundraise, monitor and supervise the work of management. PICOT has management led by the executive director. The director works through the management team of four staff, a team of field staff, volunteers and interns that are taken in periodically.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-07">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners in Community Transformatio PICOT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-27:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1910"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1910"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
