<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2596" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-17T23:30:53" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-17T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06463-02:PS</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk Communications Dissemination</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESDC and in consultation with mobile clinic partners will coordinate and amplify the dissemination of Covid-19 public awareness andsensitization messages in remote and marginalized communities in the West Bank and online across the OPT.

The proposed intervention will ensure that people living in remote communities in the West Bank (particularly in Area C) have the life-saving information they need to protect themselves and others from the virus and to reduce its impact on their health, social and economic lives both through in person outreach and online outreach.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic and Social Development Cen</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESDC complies with Palestinian labour law; employees are covered with health insurance and the insurance to the offices; there is vehicle insurance and social insurance for guests ,The ESDC has a board of directors with a well-defined and written mandate. The board provides the organizations with oversight and accountability and does regular up-keep of business records. ESDC#s mission statement is also available. Finally, there are mechanisms and structures for ensuring participatory management by the organization&apos;s top management.

It is worth noting that ESDC was an ISO 9001 certified, which is a positive point for them in regards to governance structure.They are well organized in term of their procedures and policies. Some procedures are in place but not systemized. They havea written complaint system, although it needs further work. It also needs to develop an operational manual. ESDC is governed by an elected, multidisciplinary Board of Directors (BoD). The BoD consists of 9 members, 6 men and 3 women. The term of the BoD is two years, after which elections are held and the General Assembly elects the new BoD.ESDC is governed by the following core values: Equality, Democracy, Partnership, Cooperation, Transparency, Integrity, Social Justice, Civil Peace. ESDC staff consists of more than twenty full time employees specialized in capacity building of cooperatives and community based organizations (CBOs), agriculture, water and environment. The staff work from one of ESDC&apos;s three offices: Ramallah, Gaza and Tubas.ESDC#s general assembly consists of 26 members from both genders, where members are from different areas and specializations in the field of development. They meet at least one time every year. The board of directors consists of 9members elected by the general assembly members every two years.ESDC staff consists of more than twenty full time employees specialized in capacity building of cooperatives and community#based organizations, agriculture, water and environment based on three offices in Ramallah, Gaza and Tubas. For the complaint system: the system primarily uses emails and letters, as well as oral complains. All methods of communication are put into the complaint system. Vision: A Palestinian cooperative society that is economically independent and socially justMission: Eventuating Integrated Development in Palestine through Economic &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Social Empowerment for the target groupsESDC continues to align its organizational values withthe internationally-accepted co-operative principles. It also upholds the values of transparency, integrity and accountability, social justice, and peace. ESDC recognizes itself as a member of civil society in Palestine. Its stated strategic objective within the development programme:1. To contribute in the national endeavours in improving the livelihood &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; food Security for the target groups.2. To increase the capacities of  civil society organization, including cooperatives  in providing relevant services to their members &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; communities.3. To reinforce the gender equitable &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; equity in ESDC&apos;s operations &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; activities.4. To build the capacities of ESDC to be more efficient and effective in management &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; supervision.Target Beneficiaries: CBOs , small scale farmers , vulnerable groups(youth, women) and vulnerable areas that are affected from displacement, the wall and settlers violence, communities who are vulnerable to food insecurity. ESDC#s geographical focus is in all of the West Bank and Gaza Strip with a main focus in rural areas and vulnerable communities (for Vulnerability definition ESDC uses definitions from national publications,UN OCHA, and other related organizations).ESDC#s understanding of partnership: As a local NGO, they share a common objective with internationalNGOs and donors to meet and work with each other to achieve agreed objectives. The local partner brings technical expertise and relationships with local communities, where the international and donor partners contribute financially and in developing thecapacities of the local partner. They also the international skills and capabilities particularly in terms of advocacy and lobbying. Therefore, the agreed objectives are achieved through collective action from both partners , each of them participate within the scope of their capacity.ESDC has a mechanism to identify beneficiaries in their work and are accountable to them through a well defined, organized system for beneficiary selection. ESDC ensures participation of all community members in the developmentof selectioncriteria and the selection process. ESDC presents the list of beneficiaries to the local community, receives feedback on it, and ifthere is a complaint, feedback, or a contradiction, they are open to discuss.They have a system for selectingtarget groups with communities and involving local communities in all project stages: announcing the project in communities, setting criteria with communities, involving communities in needs assessments, designing the interventions, promoting the project, selecting beneficiaries, involving local communities in the selection of beneficiaries, monitoring the progress of projects. ESDC also publishes projects details on their website.ESDC is also accountable to its target group through a feedback system, in which complaints and any notes in regard to activities and other issues related to implementation and activities, can be sent and addressed.ESDC also has forms to measure beneficiary satisfaction. However, this system should be more organized. ESDCrequires more capacity building in this area including mechanism to ensure regular reporting.Level of accountability and transparency is good in general but needs a stronger documentation system that is integrated into their operational manual and M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E system.ESDC works very closely with farmers and CBOs especially cooperatives, and support them in term of capacity building, marketing legislation issues, and with line ministries on the Cooperative Law.  Therefore, ESDC is strategically focusedonthe rights of farmers, policy and legislation that influences them and lobbying with other organization to improve farmers&apos; situation.ESDC defines Vulnerability according to the country context, clusters&apos; definitions and UN agencies especially UNOCHA. They need to systemize their work according to this criteria, and not change on a project by project basis.ESDC has its own gender strategy and give preference to female headed households as target groups, as wellas female producers and women#s cooperatives.ESDC has both internal and external evaluations for its projects to measure impact and outcomes.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-10" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territories</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-17">19806</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">9975</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">9975</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic and Social Development Cen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">9831</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-10-01">9831</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic and Social Development Cen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06463-02:PS">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007018"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="OPT/I MENA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06463"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Risk Communications Dissemination"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002153"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-10"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-10"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-10"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-10"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
