<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="cordaid-41160054-01" dstore:index="283" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-02T06:15:22.2977538Z" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-02T06:24:34.030631Z" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-200913</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saving lives in Jonglei</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei is one of the severely affected states in South Sudan with 404,000 people in need of humanitarian assistance and another 125,000 are affected in the Greater Pibor area. Nine Counties in Jonglei (Twic East, Pibor, Pochalla, Ayod, Uror, Nyirol, Bor South, Duk and Pigi Canal) are the most affected by the floods resulting into displacement of 368,000 people into highland areas, 26,892 Ha of cereals farms destroyed and 11,915 Tons of estimated cereal loss. In addition, an estimated 711,400 animals (Cattles, Goats, Sheep) disappeared or displaced with no access to pastures as grasslands and shrublands are submerged under water with an increased risk of starvation deaths which has resulted into 47,555 reported animal deaths. Compounding shocks from sub-national violence, covid-19 and flooding have severely affected a state that was still recovering from previous flooding in 2019. Following the floods, the majority of Jonglei is declared in IPC 4 with pockets of catastrophe IPC5 in the January 2020 IPC analysis as people will miss the planting seasons since the water is not going down in time for the planting season.
Bor South and Canal/ Pigi county are two of the nine most affected counties in Jonglei state. In Bor South (Bor) 150,000 people have been affected and displaced by the floods and in Canal/ Pigi County, 78,000 people have been displaced. 191 tons of cereal production lost (32% of total county production) and 5,286 reported total number of animals that died amongst 72,366 affected animals. The impact of the flood exacerbates on the IPC 4 July-September projections of Bor and Canal/Pigi County. In addition, the flood has displaced thousands of people with women and children the most affected, houses are destroyed, properties lost, and water infrastructures are made unsafe for drinking. The lack of shelter and safe and sufficient drinking water is a major public health risk, as people cannot protect themselves against the weather and waterborne diseases are on the rise. There is also a spike in malarial cases. Women, children, elderly and disabled are disproportionately affected by the floods, violence, and displacement, making them extremely vulnerable for (S)GBV increasing their protection needs.

Despite efforts to assist the people from some of the affected counties, in Bor some 10,000 HH (60,000 people) have not received any aid and no assistance has reached people of Canal/ Pigi County to date. As such, 138,000 people are in immediate need of food assistance as well as seeds and fishing gears to allow them to rebuild their livelihoods. Household water treatment products including WASH NFIs are needed as well, to ensure immediate access to safe drinking water as water infrastructures are being restored. People also need Shelter and non-food items to ensure proper shelter and protection against weather, reducing protection risks of women, girls, boys and the elderly who are disproportionately affected. Lack of proper shelter and non-food items have seen rise in many cases of pneumonia, Rheumatoid and Malaria among the elderly and children. Furthermore, 96% of the people are using unprotected water sources as their main sources of drinking water has been contaminated or destroyed by the raging floods and in assessed areas no latrines were available (REACH June 2020). The lack of safe drinking water and sanitation facilities is a major public health risk with a looming outbreak of cholera or other waterborne diseases. 


In summary people are in urgent need of humanitarian assistance for their survival including emergency shelter and NFIs (tarpaulins, ropes), food and emergency livelihood support and safe drinking water and sanitation. This project will therefore, aim to reach 64,800 most vulnerable people affected by the multiple shocks in Bor South County and Canal/Pigi County with emergency life-saving assistance as other sources of funding through coordination with different clusters is sought to address the needs in these locations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	people have access to immediate food assistance and their livelihoods are restored:
2.	people have access to safe and sufficient drinking water and improved hygiene

3.	people have access to basic Shelter and Non-Food items
4.	Accountability mechanisms and PSN referrals and support established</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In consultation and coordination with UNOCHA, RRC, and all the clusters, Cordaid will target the most vulnerable households. For beneficiary targeting the cluster standards will be used. Criteria for beneficiary selection include: 
&#x2022;	Children

&#x2022;	Women headed households.
&#x2022;	Child headed households.

&#x2022;	Elderly headed households and persons with specific needs (PSN) such as HH with chronically ill, PWD, PLW.
&#x2022;	Type of shelter and condition the beneficiaries are being accommodate in now.
Households with no basic items /or those who have lost most of their properties during the flooding.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Memisa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="FL-2020-000193-SSD" type="1" vocabulary="1-2"></humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
