<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2059" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-11T23:40:25" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-11T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06465-03:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HIJRA COVID Response Kyangwali</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Initiative Just Relief Aid (HIJRA) will work with community structures and district on community engagement and protection activities and leading risk communication interventions. HIJRA will in this project consolidate their  hygiene promotional and sanitation activities by making them COVID 19 sensitive. Together with Oxfam, HIJRA will work with COVID-19 task Force under the Risk Communication, Social Mobilization and Community Engagement Pillar to ensure hygiene promotional strategies and approached are well aligned to the current priorities and harmonized across response areas. The partner will support the Village Health Team (VHT) approach promoted by the MoH to ensure sustainability of interventions.
Specific activities will include;
&#xF02D; Community awareness creation and sensitization on COVID-19 and its prevention (observing physical/social distancing, good respiratory and hand hygiene etc), nonviolent conflict resolution, and available GBV services and referrals pathways. Community awareness will be through digital and other social media platforms, including two-way communication channels that goes beyond just sharing messages and into actual dialogueand engagement radio talk shows where listeners call in and ask questions to enhance community engagement).&#xF02D; Conduct trainings on hygiene and sanitation practices, and solid waste management to market committees, RWC and market vendors in line with COVID 19 prevention and control.&#xF02D; Production and installation of the translated COVID 19 IEC materials (posters and visibility boards) at markets, religious/ cultural gathering locations and trading centres.&#xF02D; Support to personal health safety of VHTs and water point caretakers through provision of PPEs (re-usable facemasks and pocket size sanitizers).&#xF02D; Skilling and equipping selected community-based groups on soap production to enhance hand washing and boost their livelihood in the post-pandemic era. (immediate soap distributions being carried out already by UNHCR and partners)&#xF02D; Dissemination of translated hygiene and risk-awareness audio messaging on COVID-19 and countering misinformation to communities through Boda Boda Talk Talk, radio talk shows/forums &#x2013; addressing also the different levels of education of communities and the different ways in which man and women access information.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HUMANITARIAN INITIATIVE RELIEF AID</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. HISTORY
         Humanitarian Initiative Just Relief Aid (HIJRA) is an international African humanitarian and development organization that aims to positively contribute towards improving the living standards and conditions of those adversely affected by disasters and conflict in the Horn and East Africa. The organization roots are in Somalia, where a devastating humanitarian crisis emerged after the collapse of the Somali state in 1991. This prompted a group of like-minded professionals to come together to form the organization in response to the glaring humanitarian needs.
          HIJRA works to empower poor people to lift themselves out of poverty and to improve their lives through health, education, agricultural extension and legal services, access to safe drinking water and sanitary latrines, livelihood training, support for safe migration and assistance during natural disasters.            While keeping the focus on our core work at the grassroots, we have taken steps towards transforming HIJRA into a Knowledge Organization by promoting a culture of learning within the organization. This in essence meant re-aligning ourselves to be more thoughtful and methodical about our work, and constantly evaluate ourselves to improve the work we are doing. Closely linked to our ambition of becominga Knowledge Organization is our continuous effort to improve programming capacities so that we are able to make lasting impact in the lives of the poorest and most vulnerable communities. Through innovativeapproaches and hard work, we have been able to reach close to half a million people across our programmes and projects in Kenya, Uganda and Somalia.            HIJRA is a first responder working to provide impartial assistance to those in need. We workto ensure the safety of our beneficiaries and staff by adhering to astrict policy of transparency, neutrality and accountability.2. ACHIEVEMENTSWhat have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?# Beneficiaries of hygiene promotion trained in Somalia and Uganda# Provided healthcare services to vulnerable men and women with impaired access.# Households trained in business, skills entrepreneurship development and market assessment analysis# Provided water supply in Somalia and Uganda, with 115,618 reached altogether in 2018.# Vulnerable pregnant and lactating mothers provided with multiple micro-Nutrient (MMN) supplementations# Provided antenatal, postnatal and emergency obstetric care services to pregnant and lactating mothers.# Training lactating mothers, fathers and other caregivers in the communities about basic infant and young child feeding (IYCF).# Provided legal aid to refugee communities in Uganda3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE            Vision: The end of human suffering in East and the Horn of Africa and the creation of an environment where people live in self-reliance, prosperity, and assured sustainable livelihood pursuits.          Mission: Rapid response to humanitarian crises through the provision of safe and clean water, the creation of healthy living conditions, earning opportunities and the bolstering of food security for the benefit of the poor and vulnerable.Core values1. Accountability            We shall be known for our quality and willingness to take responsibilities and account for what we do for our stakeholders who include our beneficiaries and donors.  We shall conduct our activities in a transparent, impartial and be proven to be reliable and committed to what we do.2. Professionalism            We shall be known as competent humanitarian; expertsatwhat we do; and guided by humanitarian principles; professional ethics and industry best standards.3. Impartial and neutral             Our humanitarian and development work shall be guided by the principles of impartiality and neutrality in delivering services to the people we serve.  We provide assistance to vulnerable populations in need, aimed at saving lives, easing suffering, and promoting dignity and self-reliance.  These longstanding HIJRA principles are the cornerstone of our humanitarian operation.4. Respectful of the dignity of human life              We shall carry our work in a dignified way and deliver assistance and services in accordance with the humanitarianprinciples.5. Collaborative            In team effort we work together with our like-minded partners, communities and other stakeholders for the overall achievement of HIJRA#s vision.1.1. Principle objectives      i. Improve community resilience through livelihood diversification Programmes      ii. Promote basic health services and prevention of public health risks      iii. Improve levels of access to quality basic education;      iv. Build the capacity of our beneficiaries to enhance their physical and psychosocial well-being so that they are less vulnerable and more self-reliantField(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?  Thematic areas of our work:     1. Water SanitationandHygiene               BUILDING CAPACITY TO MANAGE WASH INTERVENTIONS AT THE LOCAL LEVEL             HIJRA&apos;s programmes in Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH) focus on increasing access to water, sanitation and hygiene services, while building the capacity to manage WASH interventions at the local level.             Our programmes in Somalia and Uganda directlybenefits over 400,000 community members comprised of refugees, Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) and other vulnerable host community.  Water and sanitation-related diseases, such as diarrhoea and malaria, remain the leading cause of death among children under age five. This is primarily due to a high proportion of non-functioning water supply facilities, poor access to sanitation and low adoption rates of positive hygiene practices.The overall goal of our programmes achieve reductions in water and sanitation-related illnesses within the communities we serve in Somalia and Uganda by:         # Increasing access to safe water       # Improving sanitation         # Improving hygiene behaviour         # Training and mobilizing community water and sanitation (WASH) committees         2.  Livelihoods                 IMPROVED RESILIENCE AND INCREASED ADAPTIVE CAPACITIES                HIJRA&apos;s livelihoodprogramming in Somalia and Uganda largely aims to contribute to improved resilience and increased adaptive capacities of communities and households to protect their livelihoods over continuing shocks.Programme Outcomes:           - Improved access to productive livelihood for enhanced food access;          - Protection of livelihood assets through the establishment of social safety nets;         - Improved capacities of communities to respond to and copewith recurrent shocks stressors.Programme Activities:  - Conducting participatory, in-depth, vulnerability assessments and systems analysis at community level.         - Promote sustainable production and diversification of incomethroughbeneficiary training and enhancing household community assets.          3. Health               A HOLISTIC APPROACH HAS BEEN INTEGRAL TO HIJRA#S HEALTH STRATEGY               HIJRA&apos;s programmes address the health needs of the poor and marginalized communities in South Central Somalia.          Some of the key focus areas are reductionin maternal and infant mortality, reducing malnutrition, construction of new and rehabilitation of existing health infrastructure, training of communityhealth-care workers, provision of medical equipment essential drugs and immunization.Besides this, HIJRA is also involved in disease surveillance and response.An innovative and holistic approach has been integral to HIJRA&apos;s health strategy.     The cornerstone has been building interlinkages amongst the various stakeholders. HIJRA&apos;s training of and sensitization of community health workers has improved access, as well as quality of health within the communities we serve.             HIJRA services for the poor and marginalized, especially new-borns, children, adolescent girls and mothers. Long-term behaviour changes including inculcating positive health practices are increasingly evident within the communities.           4. Protection   A COMMUNITYTHAT IS SELF-RELIANT IN THE PROVISION OF PROTECTION                   HIJRA&apos;s protection programming targeting refugees in western Uganda, envisages a community that is able to be self-reliant in the provision of protection forthe vulnerable including unaccompanied,separated children and those at risk of abuse, exploitation and neglect as well as a continued reduction of the SGBV incidences.            HIJRA has been able to improve the access of Persons-of-Concern to legal assistance through theprovision of probono legal services such as legal representation, facilitating of witnesses and interpreters to court in addition to other legal services.                The programme has also played a role in reducing crimeby conducting community policing sessions within and around the Settlement and sensitizing the communities on the laws of Uganda.                 The programme has facilitated the establishment of well-organized community with security structures that are able to prevent, detectand report crime to relevant authorities; by mean of strengthening of community based structures along with capacity building of the several authorities such as police and the Refugee Welfare Committee members in charge of defense. Dialogue meetings and community policing were emphasized to ensure peaceful coexistence between host community and refugees.Areas of operation:             Uganda: HIJRA has been responding to the refugee situation in Uganda#s South Western region since 2012 and recentlyextended operations to the mid-west in response to the 2018 influx from the      Democratic Republic of Congo.                 Initial interventions were in the WASH sector at Matanda Transit Centerin 2012; and in2013, HIJRAexpanded to managing Nyakabande and Bubukwanga Transit Center. In the same year, HIJRA started operation as the lead protection partner in Oruchinga Refugee Settlement. In 2014, HIJRA supported the Spontaneous Return of Congolese refugees by provision ofWASH servicesand hot meals in Kinyaara, Muhokya and Ishasha way stations.                 HIJRA has implemented Protection as a partner for UNHCR in Nyakabande Transit Center, as well as Oruchinga, Nakivale and Kyangwali Refugee Settlements. HIJRA&apos;s scope as a protection actor widened over the years to include Nyakabande Transit Center, Oruchinga and later, Nakivale and Kyangwali Refugee Settlements. In Kyangwali, HIJRA also undertook road construction works as the settlement grappled withan influx ofrefugees form the DRC.            Kenya: HIJRA has been operating in Kenya since 2009; in 2010 Nairobi, Kenya became the internationalheadquarters of the organization.                       Since 2010, HIJRA has been providing direct material assistance to refugee children in the form of school uniforms, writing materials, tuition fees and feeding programme contributions.Indirect assistance has also been provided in the form of desk donations to select schools. HIJRA has also integrated a psychosocial component into its current programming in order to address identified gaps in psychosocial support opportunities for urban refugee children.Somalia: HIJRA is a neutral, non-partisan organization. Our mandate as a humanitarian actor is to alleviate human suffering. Our founding roots are in Somalia and as such we have in depth knowledge of the dynamics of the Somali social, cultural and political situation. Many of our field staff are drawn from IDP and host communities and they possess a profound understanding of the problems being faced in the targeted communities and a deep commitment to the achievement of our programme goals and objectives.HIJRA continues to partner and collaborate with targeted communities through their leadership structures with the aim of facilitating their ownership of projects. The close ties with the community coupled with the implementation of internal HIJRA security plans and procedures will not only ensure the safety and security of staff and community members but also of Projects in Somalia as a whole.4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGAnalyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business,and what roles do they play? In this context, whatis unique aboutthe position of the organisation?As HIJRA moves to the next stageof global growth, we are working to ensure that we continue to have a strong culture driven by our values. We are also focusing on issues critical to longer-term organizational development and sustainability, namely leadership, development and succession planning, strategic HR, capacity building of midlevel managers and better internal communication.ProtectionWorking to support the state to ensure that vulnerable populations accessfundamental humanrights. It encompasses child protection, Sexual and Gender Based Violence, legal and community based protection projects.Water Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH)Working to increase access to water, sanitation and hygiene services, while building the capacity to manage WASH interventions at community level.Shelter and InfrastructureWorking to improve access to services mainly through road construction and ensuring access to shelter for vulnerable persons.LivelihoodsWorking to ensure that each person has the tools and choice to live in a secure and dignified manner.EducationWork to improve the levels of access to quality primary education for urban refugee children residing in Nairobi, Kenya.HealthWorking to deliver quality health care services to vulnerable communities in Somalia and ensure their overall well-being.NutritionWorking to improve access and utilization of basic nutrition services (prevention and treatment) to vulnerable and affected populations, targetingchildren and pregnant lactating women to reduce risk of morbidity and mortality linked with acute malnutrition.5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)How are authority and responsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number of people in each position, and if they are men or women.The Board of Directors is the overallpolicy and decision making organ of the organisation. The Board makes decisions and directives, which are implemented by the management team headed by the Executive Director (ED) who is the chief accounting officer for the organization.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.22621 30.81875</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-11">44172</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-01">4172</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">40000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">40000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Fund II</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HUMANITARIAN INITIATIVE RELIEF AID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06465-03:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06465"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="COVID-19 Response in Ug, SW operations"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="7020"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="6480"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="7020"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="6480"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
