<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="1468" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-19T23:40:45" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-19T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-15:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PICOT COVID-19 Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PICOT Consortium together with Koboko radio FM will enhance community vigilance, Response and strengthen livelihoods of vulnerable refugees and host communities to effectively respond and prevent COVID-19 pandemic in Koboko District through the followingactivities:

ACTIVITIESObjective: 1 To increase community risk communication and engagement against COVID-19 pandemic among refugees and host communities in Koboko districtA 1:1 Creation of a community perception tracking tool (CPT) through whichcommunity rumors, beliefs, ideas, concerns etc. are collected, presented and analyzed for discussion in coordination meetings.Community perception trackingtool will be developed by PICOT MEAL officer in consultation with Oxfam. The tool will be used to track the ongoing rumors, ideas, beliefs, associated myths and concerns relating to COVID-19 and the ongoing response by government. It will be administered by PICOTvolunteers in the most suitable method without risking the available guidelines issued byMinistry of Health. Emphasis will be put to ensure volunteers observe maximum infection prevention control measures. It#s anticipated that this activity will give an opportunity to engage local communities (with focus to vulnerable) to share their views on the current response by government, communities as well as their coping mechanisms. Through this activity valid data is obtained to inform response messaging as regards myths and beliefs, redesign strategies and respond to urgent issues affecting thecommunities.A 1:2 Run spot messages, drama and adverts in local languages on local radios guided by WHO and MoH guidelines.PICOT together with the partner (Spirit Fm) will run radio spot messages, Deejay Mentions and adverts in selected local languagesin line with ministry of health guidelines. These messages will serve the dual purpose of addressing incorrect perceptions, believes and myths on one hand while giving new emerging messages regarding COVID-19 albeit re-enforcing the existing messageson prevention and response to COVID-19 pandemic.A 1:3 Translate key COVID-19 messagesinto local languages and sharing them on local radios and social media.PICOT will work with local language experts to translate available messages on COVID-19 prevention and safety practices to ensure a large section of the community who cannot speak and read in English are fully informed on the COVID-19 prevention methods. PICOT will share these messages with its social media influencers to further educate onlinecommunity on COVID-19.A 1:4 Organize radio talk shows to address hygiene, community rumors, beliefs, ideas and concerns relating to COVID-19 pandemicSpecific radio talk shows will be conducted for key leaders (within the task force) to address specific concerns generated from community perception tools relating to ongoing government enforcement of the lack down and other guidelines but also respond to real and perceived community responses and behaviors regarding COVID-19 pandemic prevention guidelines. Theobjective will be to ensure balance in adherence while giving addressing likely excesses from the authority. Attention will be paid to women concerns and other vulnerable members in society in relation to access to public services such as health and legalservices. This talk shows will also serve to address hygiene issues communities experience.Objective 2: To strengthen livelihoodsof vulnerable refugees in waju (lobule) settlements and self-settle Refugees through cash transfer modalities inordertosustain livelihood in the face COVID-19 Pandemic.A 2.1 Conduct a needs assessment to map and assess the most vulnerable people to benefit from the intervention.PICOT work within the exiting guidelines to conduct a rapid needs assessment to ascertaintherightful beneficiariesin the settlement, self-settled urban refugees and host communities.A 2:1 Provide cash transfer for FI and NFI for vulnerable refugees who are at risk of COVID 19 for social protection (safety nets) and improving soapavailabilityPICOT will work with the OPM inWaju (Lobule) settlement and assess to assess the basic needs in the face of COVID-19 lock down. These households will be provided with NFI &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; FI through a cash transfer modality to avail these essential basics to sustain their livelihood in the short run.A2:2 Support and promote kitchen gardens for vulnerable households among refugees and host communities.As COIVD-19 lock down is taking its toll on the local economy, there is already a challenge in availabilityand access to food items in Koboko district where refugees and the host population do not have enough food stuffs in the market due to shortage in supply but also limitation in transportation. Therefore PICOT will support Kitchen gardens for refugees andselected vulnerable households among the host communities by providing short term vegetable seeds to grow that both eaten by the families and sale to acquire other basic needs.A 2:3 Procure and install Bulk/Mass Handwashing Facilities at market places,isolation/quarantine centers, health facilities and communal meeting places including Food Distribution PointsPICOT will procure and install hand washing facilities in selected risky prone areas such as the markets, quarantine centers, health facilities andmajor communal places. In instances where such facilities are available PICOT will provide sanitizers to ensure communities are properly embracing the safety precautions.A 2.4 Post Distribution Monitoring.PICOTwill conduct post distribution monitoring todetermine beneficiary certification, get feedback on the activities, document success and address immediate challenges.Objective 3: To support frontline health service providers and Koboko District COVID-19 coordination task force toeffectively play their roles in preventing and responding to COVID-19 pandemic.A 1:3 Procurement of IPC supplies necessary for enhanced preparedness (such as PPEs, backpack sprayers, chlorine for disinfection etc)PICOT will work with District coordination taskforceto procure IPC supplies to enhance preparedness and protect the frontline service providers in the district as they continue to respond to following suspected cases, conduct screening at the health facility and enforcing the preventive guidelines.A 2:3Support virtual conferences for District Health Coordination Meetings maintaining the physical distance recommendations.In collaboration with district task force and other local structures PICOT will establish appropriate modalities of supportingcoordination of task force work. Emphasis will be in providing timely communications and feedback to community concerns. Support convention ofvirtual meetings and disseminate action points to the relevant stakeholders.A 3:3 Support risk mapping and communitylevelsurveillance and design of appropriate response strategies in line with MOH guidelinesPICOT will work with consortium partner and district task force to ensure effective surveillance of porous border points by providing frontlinehealth workers and other law enforcement officers with appropriate equipment.A 4:3 Strengthen capacity of VHTs on COVID-19 preparedness and response actions in line with MOH SOPs and Protocols)PICOT will work in close collaboration with Oxfam and district task force to providehands on training for VHTs on COVID-19 preparedness and response. The mode of providing this training will be discussed and agreed upon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners in Community Transformatio PICOT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners In Community Transformation (PICOT) is non-profit making Organization founded in 2005 by a group of progressive youth graduates as a CBO in the names of Koboko Youth In Development (KOYID).  The overall goal then was to address development challenges in health (HIV/AIDS) education and lack of skills among youths, women and other vulnerable communities in Koboko District specifically.Due to growth in capacity and programming, in 2013, the organization was registered with National NGO board as PICOT and licensed to work in west nile region. At this point strategic decisions were made to review the vision, mission and strategic objective, expand geographical coverage and thematic focus to include humanitarian response given PICOT#s geographical location along the border of three countries (Uganda, DR Congo and South Sudan). This strategic transformation witnessed changes in organizations# policies. PICOT embarked on a rigorous process of policy review and development. Most notably is the gender policy, work place HIV policy, safe guarding policy and the minimum humanitarian standards guidelines. It was also at this point that PICOT got its first female executivedirector. PICOT continues to pay special attention to gender integration in its institutional growth and program design and implementation to realize its overall vision of holistically transformed communities.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?Over last three years, PICOT has registered tremendous success in its major thematic areas. This can be summarized as follows1. Health programming0ver 6,367 people have been reached through our community programs, stakeholder meetings and digital media platforms in West Nile region. 2,830 of total population reached are females of different social characteristics.  This has increased youth access to SRHR services and information at community, school and facility levels. The graph below gives more details of the number people reached by category excluding social and electronic media.Successfully advocated for local governments, schools and health units to allocate budget for youth friendly services, as result schools recruited senior teachers, budget for girl child was improved, special capacity building for senior women and men teachers on managing adolescent were conducted, youth friendly corners were established in two health units to provide reproductive healthservices to youths.PICOT engaged over 2,526 youths of which 1,421 were females in and out of school in direct conversations on sexual reproductive health risks and prevention through forum theatre plays, Twogere (let&apos;s talk)## game, games and sports and outreaches to increase awareness on SRHR risks among young people, increase demand for reproductive health services and encourage parental involvement in SRH discussion with children at household levels. This has improved responsiveness, changed perceptions and assumptions regarding SRH information among youths, parents and community gate keepers.HIV Programming159 clients with suppressed viral load189 clients resumed care from the lost to follow list of21 TB contacts traced were found positive and are started on treatment.A total of 3290 people were referred for services from communities to different service points.Index testing services generated 18 positives tests of which were 7 females and 11 males.Governance and accountabilityWithin our project of social accountability implemented in Koboko and Maracha districts, PICOT engaged communities to donate land for putting up twin staff house for dranya health center staffs. In Wadra health center III maracha district, communities were mobilized to construct kitchen for the inpatient department. The coolest about this is how each community donated resources to have the kitchen constructed with now helping mothers in theward. A total 704 people reached of which 409 males and 295 femalesYouth Skilling ProjectPICOT skilled 1,500 youths of which 749 females and 751males in different non formal skills areas such as tailoring, carpentry and joinery, metal fabrications, netting, saloon and hair dressing, motorcycle mechanics among others  to empower the youths and boost their livelihood opportunities.3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSEMission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?Working with communities and development partners to identify, mobilise and utilize available resources for sustainable development.Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?1. To improve access to health services among 30,000 target vulnerable people in West Nile by 2022.2. To increase access to quality education and skills training for 7500 children and youths and capacity of6,000 SMCs, PTAs and teachers in primary and secondary schools in the target districts improved by 2022.3. To develop efficient relationships among 43,200 farmers in Farmer Groups so as to enhance their knowledge on: GAPS, post-harvest handling, create linkages with traders and processors that are engaged in commodity warehousing, processing and sales; and increase awareness about environmental protection through community dialogues, afforestation campaigns in West Nile.4. To contribute to improved living conditions of approximately 1,000,000 South Sudan and Congolese refugees by providing timely and adequate humanitarian interventions and response to emergency situations in West Nile.5. To enhance the institutional effectiveness, efficiency, responsiveness and sustainability in the provision of quality services in the communities we serve.Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?1. Holistic health promotion2. Education and Skills Development3. Livelihood and Environment4. Humanitarian Response5. Organizational capacity BuildingGeographical areas:By mandate PICOT is licensed to work in West Nile region however currently PICOT operates in four districts of Maracha, Koboko Yumbe and Arua.4. STRATEGIC POSITIONINGAnalyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? &apos;In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?PICOT as an organization emerged from the very social, political and economic challenges vulnerable communities face on daily basis however these challenges have continued to affect lives of vulnerable people at different lengths and period often caused by social, economic and political factors and because of community#s vulnerabilities, they have not responded well to the shocks brought about by such eventualities hence their livelihood and social wellbeing is ever threatened.PICOT positions its self to mobilize local communities, empower and support them as chage agents to spear head and address their own challenges in the 9 districts (Koboko, Arua, Yumbe, Adjumani, Zombo, Pakwach, Moyo, Nebbi and Maracha) of West Nile sub region, with the aim of not just providing services, but more importantly setting out to influence the sector of health, WASH, agriculture and education to be responsive tothe local needs.Our five year strategic themes attest to our commitment to effectively deliver through our core functions of improved health services, education and skills development, improving Livelihood and environment and responding to humanitarian needs of the refugees and host communities.Together with its partners PICOT will respond to the West Nile regions# sector challenges in Health, Education, Humanitarian response, Livelihoods and environment, by addressing issues of inequality in access, weak sustainabilitymechanisms, low investment in the selected sectors and governance concerns by strengthening transparency and accountability. As such, in the next five years PICOT will position itself as an advocate and direct service provider to work with the most vulnerable of communities which include Children in and out of school,Women, Persons with Disability, People Living with HIV/Aids, Internally Displaced People and refugees, and the elderly. Specifically, PICOT will focus on pathways that lead to improved interventions, give equal opportunities for women and men and ensurecommunities have equal access to service provision in West Nile region.PICOT will continue working with meaningful partners with common values and principles at various levels among which include local NGOs, networks, governments, donors, private sector,academic and research institutions in a bid to achieve its vision. As an indigenous organization, PICOT has the potential and comparative advantage of mobilizing the communities to participate in their development process. The organization has the community trust and support with existing structures and a network volunteers who share the organizations# vision.5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)How are authority and responsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number of people in each position, and if they are men or women.PICOT has a written comprehensive organizational structure even though it has not been implemented fully due to resources. At the helm of it all is the general assembly (board of trustees) that comprises of 24 members. The major duty is to approve audited reports, annual work plans and annual reports and elect new board members once their term of office elapses. PICOT has 9 board members composed of 2 femalesand 6 males. The board members work through committees of human resource, finance and program. Two of these committees are headed by females. The board provide oversight role, fundraise, monitor and supervise the work of management. PICOT has management led by the executive director. The director works through the management team of four staff, a team of field staff, volunteers and interns that are taken in periodically.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.41362 30.95998</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-19">27143</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">27143</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-01">27143</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners in Community Transformatio PICOT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-15:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="184"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="155"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3525"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="900"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2350"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="820"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
