<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2018" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-07T23:30:47" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-07T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-21:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEFORD WN Platform Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEFORD Arua in this ELNHA  PHASE II project will be coordinating the implementation of the joint action plans in West Nile (for Arua,  Koboko and Yumbe districts); on behalf of the West Nile  Humanitarian platform.  The platform  has a steering committeecomprising of 12 members who hold the responsibilities of making decisions on how the Humanitarian Action Fund (HAF) will be implemented witha working group of 07 sector members.  In this last year of the project the platform together with support partner agree to implement the following activities:

Functional district local government structures (DDMC, Municipal council, Sub county, Villages):- Support  DDMCs to follow up on functionality of lower level disaster management  and communities on their roles and responsibilities( Arua &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Koboko)- Raise community awareness on DRR using radio talk shows, etc.disasters in the community &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; action plans-Support DDMC to finalise  Updating contigency plan of Koboko district and share with it stakeholdersfor implementation - Dissemination  and  Translation into local languages of Early warning information through community engagements and radio talk showsSustained capacity, quality and accountability of LNHAs:Organise  2 Joint monitoring visitswith DDMCs and INGOs on the quality humanitarian operations for local actorsOrganise 2 Symposiums for   women and refugee led Organisations to raise awareness  on  the importance  of their leadership  in humanitarian response ( Rhino and Bidibidi settlements) Support at least 20 LNHAs enroll  into various trainings both online and face to face by March 2021 to strengthen their capacitiesOrganize one training for board members to ensurethey have capacity to run and  the organizations and support governance processes Upload the QUAM process on the website so that local actors can self monitor themselvesSupport 40 LNHAs to develop gender and safe guarding policies to ensure delivery of safe humanitarian programsOrganise 2 trainings   for the steering committee and sector leads on governance to enable them play their role effectivelyCoordinated alert and action to humanitarian issues in affected communities:Facilitate monthly information sharing on disaster for quick action.(situation reportson disasters, ) using different media( website, social media pages)Facilitate 3 quarterly coordination meetings of platform membersFacilitate 3 quarterly steering committee meetingsShare the disaster mapping and risk assessments report online and among local actorsPublish quarterly situation reports and upload them on the website and share with all humanitarian actors in the regionUpdate the list of platform members online on a quarterly basis to ensure it inclusiveness of new membersSupport DDMCs Annually update hazard maps and risk assessments to inform humanitarian responseDisseminate information to communities on disaster risks, updated hazard maps (through community voices on radios, etc.)Visibility and recognition of platform :Documentation and sharing of best practices from LNHA&apos;s work (newsletter, website, content, LNHAS interventions on covid-19Develop a joint open feedback mechanism to improve on accountability and feedback between crisis affected people and the LNHAsquaterly Update the online directory of platform members, organized into sectors for easy search and follow upProduction of the report from Rapid accountability review  Exercise (participation, information, feedback &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; decision making) and  disseminate to LNHAs and other stakeholders support Social mobilisation towards crisis (T-shirts, cap, notebook, jacket, umbrella, etc.) support Participation in national  and regional events (platform members) for improved visibilty such as C4C meetings, Nationalcashworking groupsDevelopment of content from partners on interventions on Covid-19Support  for hosting  virtual meetings and webnars on humanitarian issues, information sharing and learning  with other networks.Partnership models established:Facilitate  the steering Committee and sector leads of the platform to establish  consotias among LNHAs ready for resource mobilisationEstablish a C4C regional working group directly linked to the C4C working group at the national level to ensure views fromthe regions are part of C4C conversationsDocumentation of 8 success stories on  consotiums and partneships among LNHAs and INGOs  and  share with LNHAs  for learningAdvocacy and lobbying around humanitarian agenda:Joint  advocacy and influencing forFavorable policies  around localisation Generate alliances with women and women organisations, refugee led organisations working in West Nile to promote the humaninatarian agenda by March 2021Organize two meetings with the districts to discusscontingency budget and guidelines for access Hold two dialogues with INGOs and NNGOs on the issues of CTP standardization Support local actors to be part of the national CTP working group.Write at least 2 concepts to enable the platform implement the influencing strategy as developed by the platform.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT FOR RURAL DEV CEFORD</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The history of Community Empowerment for Rural Development (CEFORD) dates back to 1993 when the Uganda government, with the financial and technical support of the Dutch government, implemented the Community Action Program (CAP) and later the Women Empowerment Program (WEP) in the West Nile region. Both programs were considered successes by the communities and district local governments of West Nile, and external evaluators and the Dutch embassy in Uganda. The focus was on community mobilisation and capacity building through service delivery and the implementation of micro-projects. CAP concentrated on the supply of social infrastructure services and the implementation of agricultural projects, while WEP concentrated on the empowerment of women and the strengthening of their capacities to participate in the development process.
Thus CEFORD was founded, to fill the gap created by the closure of these successful programs that were phased out in June 2000. CEFORD operates in parts of all the five districts of Adjumani, Arua, Moyo, Nebbi and Yumbe.
It was founded in July 2000 but the process of its formation dates back to 1998, to an internal reflection workshop of CAP staff that identified possible scenarios for the future. One scenario suggested a merger of CAP and WEP into a local NGO.The decentralisation of government to districts in Uganda also demanded strong civil society organisations that could support local governments indelivering services.CEFORD&apos;s major achievements in the last three years include a participatory poverty assessment in the districts of Arua and Nebbi. Through these assessments CEFORD gave objective feedback from poor women and men to the district and central governments, and to some donor.It was also successful in supporting the Adjumani district local government in facilitating the formulation of all its sub-county development plans. This enhanced its chance of accessing funds from the central government, from which the communities would benefit.And CEFORD strengthened the capacities of four local organisations through organisational self-assessment and the facilitation of strategic planning. The performance of these organisations has since improved. It also mobilised and linked ten community-based organisations to funding for agricultural activities; over 30 million Ugandan shillings from the German Development Services.CEFORD&apos;s Mission is to improve the capacity of women, men, children and their organisations in the more disadvantaged communities of West Nile effectively to articulate their demands and interests, to increase their production and income in a sustainable way and to secure better access to services.The institutional objectives of CEFORD are to contribute to the following policy and practice changes in West Nile: food and income security is guaranteed, communities have positive attitude to the enrolment and retention of girls in schools, there is active participation of the population in district and sub-county planning and policy formulation (especially around issues of natural resources, peace and security),  peace and security in the region are consolidated especially at the household level, and women are empowered to participate as equal partners to men in decision-making and control over resources at the household and community levels.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.01909 30.91213</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-07">55000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">41250</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">41250</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT FOR RURAL DEV CEFORD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">13750</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">13750</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT FOR RURAL DEV CEFORD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-21:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasing that participate or initiate influencing for space in humanitarian work and that are capable of effective humanitarian response according to humanitarian standards.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5320-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasing that participate or initiate influencing for space in humanitarian work and that are capable of effective humanitarian response according to humanitarian standards.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5320-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasing that participate or initiate influencing for space in humanitarian work and that are capable of effective humanitarian response according to humanitarian standards.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5320-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="30"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
