<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-zm" dstore:index="120" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11623A0103-ZMB-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Aid Zambia: CSO Support</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Action Aid Zambia: CSO Support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
AAZ has applied for a grant from the Embassy of Sweden amounting SEK 46,800,00.00 to support civil society in Zambia for a period of four years, 2018 to 2021. The objective of this initiative is to promote democratic accountability and transparency, and increase awareness and demand for human rights in Zambia through civil society organisations. The Embassy shall enter into an agreement with Action Aid Zambia which shall act as an intermediary organisation to sub-grant to other CSOs as well as provide thematic and institutional capacity buildling. AAZ shall work with different types of CSOs including national, provincial and small grassroots organisations and movements especially women and youth led. This project is expected to contribute to strengthened democratic accountability and transparency and increased awareness and demand for human rights in Zambia with a  focus on anti-corruption; health rights and accountability; environment and climate change governance; and gender equality as a cross cutting theme. Eastern, Southern, Muchinga, Luapula, North-Western and Western Provinces will be AAZ&#x2019;s primary coverage areas  while Lusaka and the Copperbelt provinces will be targeted to compliment already existing interventions.  


The following are the expected outcomes of the project:

Outcome 1: Strengthened CSOs capacity to enhance citizens&#x2019; civic participation and state accountability for improved governance and public service delivery in Zambia.
Outcome 2: Strengthened CSOs and citizen&#x2019;s role in promoting transparency and accountability in public finance management and institutional governance systems.
Outcome 3: CSOs &amp; citizens have strengthened capacity in holding government accountable in the enforcement of policies and regulations for sustainable natural resource management and climate justice.
Outcome 4: Access to better health is promoted through strengthened capacity of CSOs and citizens to demand for accountability in the provision of quality health care.
Outcome 5: Increased CSOs institutional capacity, compliance and accountability among partner Civil Society Organizations (CSOs) in Zambia.

The modality is project support with additional support to their Country Strategy. The Embassy shall contribute SEK44,000,000.00 towards the project and set aside SEK1,000 000.00 for a mid term evalaution aimed at learning in 2020; while AAZ will contribute SEK2,800,000.00.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
AAZ har ans&#xF6;kt om st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n svenska Ambassaden i Lusaka till ett v&#xE4;rde av SEK 46 800 00, f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja zambiska civilsamh&#xE4;llet under perioden 2018 &#x2013; 2022. Syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r att fr&#xE4;mja demokratiskt ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande och transparens, samt att &#xF6;ka kunskap om och m&#xF6;jligheter att kr&#xE4;va m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter. Fokuset ligger p&#xE5; anti-korruption; h&#xE4;lsor&#xE4;ttigheter, milj&#xF6; och klimat; god samh&#xE4;llsstyrning; och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet (som genomsk&#xE4;r och integreras i hela programmet). AAZ kommer att arbeta genom ett antal olika civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer (CSOs). Svenska Ambassaden ska f&#xF6;ljaktligen ing&#xE5; avtal med AAZ, som sedan i sin tur kommer att vidaref&#xF6;rmedla st&#xF6;det till andra CSOs. &#xD6;stra, S&#xF6;dra, Muchinga, Luapula, Nordv&#xE4;stra, och v&#xE4;stra provinserna &#xE4;r AAZs huvudsakliga fokusomr&#xE5;den. AAZ kommer ocks&#xE5; implementera programmet i Lusaka och Copperbelt provinserna f&#xF6;r att komplimentera redan existerande insatser d&#xE4;r. 

Programmets m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r f&#xF6;ljande; 

M&#xE5;l 1: St&#xE4;rka CSOs kapasitet att &#xF6;ka medborgares m&#xF6;jligheter att delta i beslutsfattande, och att kr&#xE4;va ansvarstagande, transparens och god samh&#xE4;llsstyrning.

M&#xE5;l 2: St&#xE4;rka CSOs och medborgares roll I att fr&#xE4;mja ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande och transparens i offentlig finansiell styrning och statens institutionella styrning. 

M&#xE5;l 3: St&#xE4;rka CSOs och medborgare kapacitet att h&#xE5;lla staten ansvarig f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar anv&#xE4;ndning av naturresurser. 

M&#xE5;l 4: &#xD6;ka tillg&#xE5;ng till kvalitativa h&#xE4;lsotj&#xE4;nster genom att st&#xE4;rka CSOs och medborgares kapacitet att kr&#xE4;va kvalitativ sjukv&#xE5;rd

M&#xE5;l 5: St&#xE4;rka CSOs egna kapacitet att sj&#xE4;lva efterleva principer om ansvarstagande och transparens. 

Sidas st&#xF6;d kommer att utg&#xF6;ra prjoketst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja AAZs landsstrategi. Ambassaden ska bidra med SEK 44 000 000 f&#xF6;r detta &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;l. 
SEK 1 000 000 ska avs&#xE4;ttas f&#xF6;r en halvtidsutv&#xE4;rdering under 2020. AAZ kommer att bidra med SEK 2 800 000 ur egna medel.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is intended to contribute to strengthened democratic accountability and transparency, and increased awareness and demand for human rights in Zambia with a particular focus on civic and political participation, anti-corruption; environment and climate change governance and health rights and accountability. The following are the outcomes of the project: Outcome 1: Strengthened CSOs capacity to enhance citizens&#x2019; civic participation and state accountability for improved governance and public service delivery in Zambia.Outcome 2: Strengthened CSOs and citizen&#x2019;s role in promoting transparency and accountability in public finance management and institutional governance systems. Outcome 3: CSOs and citizens have strengthened capacity in holding government accountable in the enforcement of policies and regulations for sustainable natural resource management and climate justice. Outcome 4: Access to better health is promoted through strengthened capacity of CSOs and citizens to demand for accountability in the provision of quality health care. Outcome 5: Increased CSOs institutional capacity, compliance and accountability among partner Civil Society Organization (CSOs) in Zambia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ActionAid, Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1480557.1124906144</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1533434.152222422</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1374803.033026999</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1374803.033026999</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1480557.1124906144</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1533434.152222422</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">4775384.3321366105</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">1480557.1124906144</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">1533434.152222422</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/11623-decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Aid Zambia: CSO Support</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/11623-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Aid Zambia: CSO Support</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018 marked the first year (out of three) of the project supported by the Embassy, aimed at supporting CSOs and social movements to implement projects that are aimed at promoting good governance and increasing citizen&#x2019;s awareness and demand for human rights in Zambia. During year one (August &#x2013; December 2018), several achievements were made relating to setting up partnerships and the operating structures for the projects implementation. Particularly, AAZ developed and sent out the call for proposals; established a Technical Evaluation Committee (TEC) with the role to assess applications received in line with AAZ&#xB4;s existing policies and tools; set up a Project Accountability Team (PAT) with the function to review and award grants recommended by the TEC; Shortlisting applications received and segmenting them against thematic priorities and grants type; and AAZ conducted proposal review workshops targeting the organizations selected after the field assessment. Although the inception phase of the program was successful, AAZ experienced some challenges. Some of these were linked to much higher turnout of proposals than expected, planned and budgeted for; low quality of applications from rural CSOs; and that the manual proposal submission process led to higher workload than anticipated. Learning from these will be key as the project grows. These issues have been discussed with AAZ, and the following mitigation measures have been set up/planned: AAZ received 249 proposals in the first call for proposals, against the overall project expected target of 41. As this turn out needed adequate staff time and resources to review and provide feedback to all the applicants, AAZ could for example only issue a public announcement on applicants who made it to the next stage and only deal with those who sent specific queries/request for comments on their proposals.  Lesson learnt: calling for full proposals is not the best strategy. Rather, the introduction of expression of interest in the next call will lessen the work overload and only filter relevant concept notes to a full application stage. So, to ensure that AAZ are able to adequately manage and review all proposals, they will introduce a concept note stage for the next call. AAZ also noted that staff who are not specifically recruited for the project, spent a lot of their time on its implementation. Thus, during the Annual Review AAZ indicated that they may need to adjust how much of the budget is going to admin costs. AAZ noted a low quality of applications from rural CSOs, making it difficult for them to compete for the funding. As civic participation&#xA0;in rural Zambia is already particularly low, a special focus is needed for this target group. Accordingly, AAZ plans to provide additional support to rural CSOs. Overall, social movements, community groups and other CBOs faced big challenges in competing for the grants. AAZ will need to develop the mechanisms to effectively support this form of partnership. One idea discussed during the Annual Review Meeting is to develop a separate criterion for CSOs run by key populations (e.g. by youths, disabled, LGBTIQ, etc) and for CBOs. Another example is that AAZ had met very rural women-groups, who do a lot of good work around e.g. empowerment and participation, but consist of members who are illiterate. Therefore, there is no way for them to write a proposal that meets the projects current minimum requirements, despite having good projects. Can there be a way to include such groups in the grant? Perhaps it would be possible to accept certain recorded proposals? Can the project establish and make better use of other fiscal agents in the districts, to assist these very small organisations with managing grants? During May 2019, the Embassy travelled with AAZ to see projects supported under the Sida grant. A number of observations were made: Many small grants for short time periods are being awarded; What impact can realistically be achieved under these premises?&#xA0;Going forward, the Embassy will need to consider if we are satisfied with the goal to contribute to a vibrant civil society, or if we have a higher ambition level for the impact we want the Swedish grant to have on governance, gender equality, youth empowerment, etc. I.e. do we want to direct more money to fewer organizations but that are more likely to attain results, or do we want to make sure to reach as many CSOs (particularly in rural areas where civic participation is very low) as possible? On the other hand, the Community Action grant and the Innovation Grant can be seen as a first step on a ladder, where organizations can progress towards qualifying for the Standard Grant (longer term, bigger volumes). In other words, although a three-month grant to a small CBO may be unlikely to achieve the shorter-term results, it can be seen as a longer-term investment, training e.g. youths in advocacy work and civic engagement, and perhaps setting the grounds for a stronger CBO in the future. AAZ training and capacity building will be important here &#x2013; simply providing funding does not appear to be effective, so the tailored trainings will fill a key role. We will need to follow-up with AAZ what type of support they will be providing to these smaller community based CSOs/CBOs. The question also arises if the organizations are able to absorb the funds, as they are not able to use funds after the activity period expires. For example, Mpulungu Youth Vision, which the Embassy visited, are receiving ZMW 100,000 over three months. This seems to be a lot of money to absorb for a very small organization given the time-frame.&#xA0; The Embassy also sampled some agreements signed between AAZ and sub-grantees. The Embassy noted that there is need for AAZ to review their agreement templates to ensure that they make sense for each individual partnership (see details in travel report). For example, it does not make sense to request for quarterly, annual and an end report for a 3-month project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11623" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01" strategy-total-amount="2250000000.0">
    <title>Zambia 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
