<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998e" dstore:index="2520" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105036001-GGG-16020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank&apos;s Umbrella Trust Fund on Jobs, phase 2 (2020-2024)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">World Bank&apos;s Umbrella Trust Fund on Jobs, phase 2 (2020-2024)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution constitutes a continued support to the second phase of the World Bank&apos;s Multi Donor Trust Fund (MDTF) for Jobs (2020-2024) of 80 MSEK. This is a continuation of the support to the fist phase (2015-2020) which was 54 MSEK. 

The objectives of the Fund are:

a) To support the design and implementation of comprehensive, integrated and high-impact jobs strategies for WBG client countries

b) To advance global knowledge on the most effective policies and activities for sustainable jobs, especially for the most vulnerable groups

The work is organised through three windows: 

Window 1 - Supporting Jobs Lending at Scale

Window 2 - Measurement Agenda&#xA0;

Window 3 - Global knowledge production through External Partnerships and Innovation

The aim for the second phase is to raise a total of equivalent to 469,3 MSEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen inneb&#xE4;r ett fortsatt st&#xF6;d till V&#xE4;rldsbankens paraplyfond f&#xF6;r jobb om 80 MSEK, f&#xF6;r fas 2 (2020-2024). Detta &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; st&#xF6;det till fas 1 (2015-2020) som uppgick till 54 MSEK.

Fondens &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att:

a) st&#xF6;tta utformning och implementering av omfattande, integrerade och h&#xF6;geffektiva jobbstrategier p&#xE5; landniv&#xE5;

b) fr&#xE4;mja global kunskap om effektiva policyer och interventioner f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbart jobbskapande, s&#xE4;rskilt f&#xF6;r de mest utsatta grupperna

Detta uppn&#xE5;s genom tre f&#xF6;nster med fokus p&#xE5;: 

1) Skala upp syssels&#xE4;ttnings-ansatsen i Bankens operativa verksamhet p&#xE5; landniv&#xE5;

2) F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrade uppf&#xF6;ljnings- och resultatm&#xE4;tningsmetoder

3) Globalt kunskapande genom partnerskap och innovation

Bankens m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning &#xE4;r att samla totalt motsvarande ca 469,3 MSEK f&#xF6;r fondens andra fas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank Multi Donor Trust Fund (MDTF) for Jobs was established in 2014 as one of the first Umbrella Trust Funds within the World Bank Group, and the second phase is proposed for 2020-204.&#xA0; The second phase of the MDFT Jobs maintains the original objectives of the Fund: a) To support the design and implementation of comprehensive, integrated and high-impact jobs strategies for WBG client countries b) To advance global knowledge on the most effective policies and activities for sustainable jobs, especially for the most vulnerable groups Further, for the second phase, the Jobs Group proposes to re-organise the MDTF Jobs into 3 windows (compared to the previous five windows): Window 1 - Supporting Jobs Lending at Scale: This window will provide techical expertise resources to task teams in other GPs and IFC to help scale up the WBG&#x2019;s jobs lending portfolio across sectors and regions, in order to improve technical quality of operations for improved targeting jobs outcomes and scale up operational approaches especially in low-income and fragile settings. (Note that allocations from the MDTF Jobs will not be used for lending, but the MDTF Jobs will finance technical support to lending operations in other areas in order to strengthen the jobs perspective). Window 2 - Measurement Agenda: This window will advance the technical capacity for measurement of jobs outcome, and upgrade country level data and diagnostics on jobs outcomes, to enable evidence based jobs initiativs and provide policymakers with improved information on expected impact of interventions.&#xA0; Window 3 - Influence through External Partnerships and Innovation: Under this window, the Jobs Group will continue to support a strong engagement and dissemination and outreach between the World Bank Jobs Group and other key stakeholders, to identidfy and accelerate cutting edge soultions to emerging jobs challenges. The goal for the second phase is to ramp up the emphasis specifically on county level operationalisation, as well as the measurement of outcomes, and the work with governments, private sector actors and development partners to reinforce the agenda of private sector-led jobs growth. The overall theory of change is that the MDTF provides direct technical support to country level operations with job-centric designs to enhance jobs outcomes in programmes, provide measurement methodologies, and engage with private and public partners for effective solutions, to increase capacity for implementation of effective programmes and policies in countries and across sectors supported by evidence and data, to ultimately contribute to the accelerated creation of better jobs through scaled up public sector reforms and private sector investments. The onset of the COVID-19 pandemic has not changed the Funds overall objectives, theory of change, or proposed structure for the second phase. Rather it has enhanced the relevance and urgency of both. It has, however, changed the context(s) in which the Fund operates given the pandemics severe disruption on economies and employment. The impact of COVID-19 varies by region and countries, it affects all categories of workers although some have been hit particularly hard, and it has caused new groups to be pushed into poverty. The Fund has therefore already initiated analytical work to track the COVID-19 impact on the labour market globally, to identify which types of firms, workers and households have been most heavily affected by the crisis, and how policy responses correlates with the magnitude of the labour market impact. Special attention will be payed to the medium and long term effects on jobs and labour markets, which is crucial to inform the proposed work of the Fund in the second phase. In relation to the measurement agenda, the speed with which the crisis has unfolded has created new challenges for measurement revealing that the methods and sources normally used to track labour market outcomes may have significant shortcomings and that social distancing and other transmission prevention measures have affected several data-related activities around the world with potential impacts on data availability, quality and reliability. This will all have an effect on the work that will take place during the second phase, but at the moment the proposed objectives and structure is assessed as highly relevant also in light of the pandemic.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.3 - Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja utvecklingsinriktad politik som st&#xF6;der produktiv verksamhet, skapande av anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, f&#xF6;retagande, kreativitet och innovation samt uppmuntra att mikrof&#xF6;retag liksom sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag v&#xE4;xer och blir en del av den formella ekonomin, bland annat genom tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.5 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; full och produktiv syssels&#xE4;ttning med anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetsvillkor f&#xF6;r alla kvinnor och m&#xE4;n, inklusive ungdomar och personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, samt lika l&#xF6;n f&#xF6;r likv&#xE4;rdigt arbete.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.5 - By 2030, achieve full and productive employment and decent work for all women and men, including for young people and persons with disabilities, and equal pay for work of equal value.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">5816474.370498843</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">5816474.3704988435</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">5e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">8460326.357089225</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">5816474.370498843</value>
  </transaction>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61050360" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1180202" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01" strategy-total-amount="4000000000.0">
    <title>Swedish Strategy for global development cooperation on sustainable economic development 2018 &#x2013; 2022</title>
    <titleSV>Sveriges globala utvecklingssamarbete inom h&#xE5;llbar ekonomisk utveckling 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
