<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998e" dstore:index="1818" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5410017102-GGG-12182</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 WHO Research support 2020-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 WHO Forskningsst&#xF6;d 2020-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The following three WHO-based research programmes have applied for continued support from Sida:
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases (TDR); 
ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, HRP; 
iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research (AHPSR). 

The proposed support is a continuation of the previous agreement 2016-2019. The total amount is SEK 307,8 million for the period 2020 - 2022, of which SEK 138,8 million to TDR, SEK 99 million to HRP and SEK 70 million to AHPSR. The contribution support is essentially unearmarked

During the agreement period, TDR&apos;s activities will focus on research on barriers to effective implementation of existing control programs for infectious diseases disproportionally affecting people living in poverty. HRP&apos;s focus includes, amongst many areas related to sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR), research on migrants&apos; needs for SRHR, on adolescents&#x2019; need for SRHR, and women&apos;s enhanced opportunities for safe abortion. AHPSR will focus further on researching health systems and policies together with policy makers to help low- and lower middle-income countries use their resources for the health sector as efficiently as possible.

In addition to undesignated support, there are four components with so-called &quot;soft earmarking&quot;: A Global Health Research Conference (through AHPSR), the ESSENCE Network, the Social Health Innovation Initiative, and enhanced WASH integration within the TDR (the three latter through TDR). In total, this soft earmarking amounts to 8% of the total support.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
De tre f&#xF6;ljande WHO-baserade forskningsprogrammen har ans&#xF6;kt om fortsatt st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sida: 
i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases (TDR);  
ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, (HRP); 
iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research (AHPSR). 

Det f&#xF6;reslagna st&#xF6;det &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; tidigare avtal 2016-2019. Det totala beloppet &#xE4;r 307,8 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2020 &#x2013; 2022, varav 138,8 MSEK till TDR, 99 MSEK till HRP och 70 MSEK till AHPSR. St&#xF6;det &#xE4;r i huvudsak icke &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt. 

TDR:s aktiviteter kommer under avtalsperioden att ha tyngdpunkten p&#xE5; forskning om hinder f&#xF6;r effektivt genomf&#xF6;rande av befintliga kontrollprogram f&#xF6;r fattigdomsrelaterade infektionssjukdomar. HRP:s inriktning innefattar forskning om en bredd av fr&#xE5;gor relaterade till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter (SRHR), bland annat migranters behov av SRHR, ungdomars behov av SRHR och kvinnors st&#xE4;rkta m&#xF6;jligheter till s&#xE4;ker abort. AHPSR kommer att fokusera ytterligare p&#xE5; att genom forskning om h&#xE4;lsosystem och policies tillsammans med beslutsfattare bidra till att fattiga l&#xE4;nder kan nyttja sina resurser f&#xF6;r h&#xE4;lsosektorn p&#xE5; ett s&#xE5; effektivt s&#xE4;tt som m&#xF6;jligt.

Ut&#xF6;ver icke &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt st&#xF6;d ing&#xE5;r fyra komponenter med s&#xE5; kallad &quot;mjuk &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkning&quot;: en global h&#xE4;lsoforskningskonferens (genom AHPSR), n&#xE4;tverket ESSENCE, initiativet f&#xF6;r social h&#xE4;lsoinnovation, och st&#xE4;rkt WASH-integrering (de tre senare genom TDR). Totalt uppg&#xE5;r denna mjuka &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkning till 8% av insatsens budget.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three WHO-based research programmes are proposed for continued support: i) The UNICEF-UNDP-World Bank-WHO Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases, TDR; ii) The UNDP-UNFPA-UNICEF-WHO-World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, HRP; and iii) Alliance for Health Policy and Systems Research, AHPSR, or &quot;the Alliance&quot;. Sida/Sweden is a long-standing supporter of TDR since its creation in 1974. TDR is one of the earliest examples of a Global Health Partnership and has repeatedly received good reviews by external evaluators because of its relevance to both health and development. TDR is the 2011 recipient of the Gates Award for Global Health. With its long history of support, Sida is well familiar with the achievements of the programme. TDR helps facilitate, support and influence efforts to combat diseases of poverty, with the mission to &quot;support effective and innovative global health research, through strengthening the research capacity of disease-affected countries, and promoting the translation of evidence into interventions that reduce the burden of infectious diseases and build resilience in the most vulnerable populations&quot;. TDR main areas are i) Research for policy; ii) Research for implementation; iii) Research for innovation; and iv) Research for integrated approaches. Sida/Sweden is an as long-standing supporter of HRP, even since a couple of years before its creation in 1972. As such, Sida is equally familiar with the HRP&apos;s achievements. HRP is the main instrument within the United Nations system for research in human reproduction, bringing together policy-makers, scientists, health care providers, clinicians, consumers and community representatives to identify and address priorities for research to improve sexual and reproductive health. The mission of HRP is &quot;the attainment of all people of the highest possible level of sexual and reproductive health. HRP strives for a world where all women&#x2019;s and men&#x2019;s rights to enjoy sexual and reproductive health are promoted and protected, and all women and men, including adolescents and those who are underserved and marginalized, have access to sexual and reproductive health information and services&quot;. AHPSR is a younger programme than TDR and HRP and recently celebrated its 20th anniversary. Sweden was one of the drivers of the creation of AHPSR and has been actively involved since then, leading to good insights into their activities. AHPSR work to improve the health of those in low- and middle-income countries by supporting the generation and use of evidence that strengthens health systems. Together with organizations around the world, the AHPSR aims to i) provide a unique forum for the health policy and systems research community; ii) support institutional capacity for the conduct and uptake of health policy and systems research; iii) stimulate the generation of knowledge and innovations to nurture learning and resilience in health systems; and iv) increase the demand for and use of knowledge for strengthening health systems. &#xA0; HRP and TDR are &#x201C;special programmes&#x201D; of WHO which gives them an independent status in relation to WHO. They are co-sponsored by a number of UN-agencies (UNICEF, UNDP, World Bank and WHO are co-sponsors of both TDR and HRP, and additionally, UNFPA is co-sponsor of HRP). As a WHO-hosted partnership, AHPSR is also guaranteed its independence. The difference between the two set-ups used to be the co-sponsorship of the special programmes, although today the definitions are being discussed at WHO. The future format of AHPSR is described later in this appraisal. When the special programmes were created in the early 1970&#x2019;s WHO did not actively engage in research, but as a number of member states could see the importance of producing research of relevance (in this case tropical diseases and human reproduction), TDR and HRP were created. Over the years, the importance of producing evidence to feed into policies and guidelines was increasingly recognized and other UN agencies joined the effort as co-sponsors. Similarly, the areas of health policy and systems research were neglected and in the late 1990&#x2019;s a group of global health leaders, including senior scientists, policy makers and representatives of various agencies and programs with a stake in health policy and systems research agreed on the need to create a body that would address these areas, and AHPSR was created as a hosted partnership at WHO. Being based at WHO and having a close interaction with the co-sponsors provides the research programmes with a unique opportunity to accelerate translation of research results into policies and guidelines. Through country and regional offices and their close relation to a county&#x2019;s Ministry of Health, the possibility for implementation at this level is also improved. As WHO is now putting more emphasis into the country and regional offices, this is expected to play an even more important role in the coming years. The importance of research and evidence is even more clear now that WHO has assigned a first Chief Scientist and a Science Division, and one can foresee a closer interaction between the research programmes and WHO at all levels. Over the years, as the world changes, the areas of research addressed as well as the ways to address the need of evidence and implementation have changed in the three programmes. The research programmes show an embedded ability to adapt their activities to changes in global health and to take leading roles in the global research agenda. There are still pertinent questions to be addressed in the programmes&#x2019; respective areas. For example, there is presently a strong focus on implementation research and interaction with decision-makers, as well as strengthening research capacity in LMICs and ensuring that high quality research is done in countries. This will be further described in the next section. As the bulk of Sida&apos;s support to the programmes is given as undesignated funding, the results of the upcoming phase are expected to contribute to the attainment of the respective missions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO/World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41143" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organisation - core voluntary contributions account</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="12182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="121" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health, General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.b - Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public healt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.b - St&#xF6;dja forskning om och utveckling av vaccin och l&#xE4;kemedel mot de smittsamma och icke-smittsamma sjukdomar som i f&#xF6;rsta hand drabbar utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder. S&#xF6;rja f&#xF6;r tillg&#xE5;ng till ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomliga grundl&#xE4;ggande l&#xE4;kemedel och vaccin, i enlighet med Doha-deklarationen om TRIPS-avtalet och folkh&#xE4;lsa, i vilken det bekr&#xE4;ftas att utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna har r&#xE4;tt att fullt ut utnyttja den flexibilitet som avtalet om handelsrelaterade aspekter av immaterialr&#xE4;tter erbjuder f&#xF6;r att skydda folkh&#xE4;lsan och, framf&#xF6;r</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">3489884.622299305</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">3489884.622299305</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3489884.622299305</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">3489884.622299305</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3489884.622299305</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">3489884.622299305</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">10469653.866897915</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">3489884.622299305</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A report on TDR&apos;s results from 2019 and ongoing activities 2020 was presented at the annual Joint Coordinating Board (JCB), where Sida is a member. Many interesting results have been achieved in accordance with the Strategic plan and biennial plans, and in addition, their work contribute to the ongoing covid-19 pandemic. Through the WHO Science Division, research at different departments across WHO as well as between the three Sida-funded research programmes is more connected and synergies can be explored. A joint Theory of Change for research capacity strengthening has been developed for the three programmes. The TDR Secretariat is involved in more WHO activities now, especially thanks to the dual roles of TDR&#x2019;s director (also being director of the newly established Research for Health department of the Science Division). TDR Director is also invited to more external meetings, such as the Global Fund, in his role as Director of Research for Health. TDR has a successful model for budgeting, with two budget scenarios which are approved at JCB. This way, they can smoothly and efficiently shift to the evolving final budget. This model was presented to WHO departments at the &#x201C;WHO Value for Money&#x201D; initiative last year. Selected results 2019: - TDR and WHO&#x2019;s Department of Control of Neglected Tropical Diseases have collaborated with the International Atomic Energy Agency and its joint division with the Food and Agriculture Organization to develop guidance on testing the Sterile Insect Technique (SIT) to control diseases carried by Aedes mosquitoes such as dengue, Zika and chikunguna. - TDR, in collaboration with the WHO Global Tuberculosis Programme and technical partners, has developed an implementation/operational research package (ShORRT) to support the use of all-oral shorter drug regimens for patients with drug-resistant TB. Detecting tuberculosis cases in West and Central Africa is a persistent challenge, especially in children. It is estimated that 70% of TB cases in children under five are neither detected nor treated. In Senegal, to address these missed cases, the National TB Control Programme is studying a new active case finding strategy, where TB screening is integrated into malnutrition screening campaigns. If successful, the approach will be scaled up across other regions in Senegal. The pilot study was conducted during a one-week malnutrition screening campaign in Thi&#xE8;s and Tivaouane districts that gathered up more than 70000 children under five years old. Parents were also asked to bring their children ages 5 to 14 for TB screening. Community engagement was essential to ensure broad participation. - In June 2019, TDR and WHO launched a new training course on ethics in implementation research to ensure appropriate engagement with research subjects and relevant communities and to safeguard against any potential harm.&#xA0; &#x201C;Implementation research is key to improving programmes for children in &#x2018;real world&#x2019; settings, but must be done while protecting communities and children. As a TDR co-sponsor, UNICEF therefore welcomes this new training course on ethics in implementation research&#x201D;, says Stefan Peterson Chief of Health, UNICEF, which alos shows increased collaboration with one of TDR&#x2019;s so-sponsors. - In 2019, 744 scientists (72% women) were trained in good health research practices and 2999 (55% women) in implementation research. Short training courses in good health practices were institutionalized in five regions: - Africa: Kenya, Nigeria, Mozambique; - Americas: Bolivia, Ecuador, Guatemala, Honduras, Jamaica, Peru; - Eastern Mediterranean: Lebanon; - Europe: Armenia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Georgia, Kazan State of Russia, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Ukraine, Uzbekistan; - South-East Asia: India, Myanmar, Nepal - More than 5000 researchers from more than 200 countries participated in TDR&#x2019;s Massive Open Online Course on Implementation Research conducted in English, French and Spanish. - Complementing the training programmes on research for implementation, TDR also supports the Clinical Research and Development Fellowship scheme, which allows early- to mid-career researchers in low- and middle-income countries to learn how to conduct clinical trials. Participants are placed for 12 months in pharmaceutical companies, product development partnerships, or research organizations and receive a grant to reintegrate with their home institution. The fellowship is jointly implemented by TDR and the European &amp;amp; Developing Countries Clinical Trials Partnership (EDCTP). One of the fellowships is a researcher from Nigeria who is placed at the Sida-funded International Vaccine Institute, IVI, in South Korea. - TDR is at the interface between research and healthcare delivery. Embedded within the UN family through its co-sponsors (UNICEF, UNDP, the World Bank, and WHO), this unique position allows TDR to create a bridge from local communities to the World Health Assembly to enable the broadest possible scope of dialogue and debate across the spectrum of health research &#x2013; from priority setting to evidence-based policy-making at local, national, regional and global levels. This global engagement includes collaboration with WHO regional offices on research grants, shaping the global health research agenda, leading a collaborative network on research funding, creating an enabling environment and providing evidence for community-engaged social innovations to transform health care delivery, and leveraging a global network of 7500 scientists and experts who have been associated with TDR. - 6 country hubs of the Social Innovation in Health Initiative are playing a leadership role in advancing social innovations through research. In 2019, one of the SIHI supported innovations in Uganda was presented to UNICEF and UNDP&#x2019;s &#x201C;Big Think Challenge&#x201D;, and was awarded second prize. This initiative is run by a previous Sida-sandwich PhD student from Makerere university. TDR, UNDP and UNICEF now join forces to support the scale-up of this initiative on private health sector management for childhood illness. - In May 2019, TDR launched an online resource to guide the development of new drugs, vaccines and diagnostics for which there are limited markets or incentives for research and development. An essential tool for realizing universal health coverage, the Health Product Profile Directory aims to promote research and development for products to combat neglected diseases and threats to global health, including antimicrobial resistance and diseases with pandemic potential. The Health Product Profile Directory is a free-to use online resource created and developed by TDR on behalf of WHO as a global public good. It provides a searchable database of profiles for health products needed to tackle pressing health issues in global health, including those prioritized by WHO. The summary of the published profiles outlines 8-10 key characteristics (such as target population, measures of efficacy and dosage) for the development of health products, including medicines, vaccines and diagnostics. Building in these characteristics at an early stage of the development process is essential to ensure that the final products will be accessible to the populations that need them. Currently, the Directory contains 233 product profiles, with the majority describing the needs for three infectious diseases: HIV, TB and malaria. 2020 results until June: - TDR has built the capacity of scientists to investigate gender dimensions of health, which are often overlooked. There is a growing recognition that gender norms, roles, power relations, socioeconomic factors, and other drivers of inequality intersect with each other and influence access to health services and health outcomes. This must be considered when designing and implementing health interventions and monitoring universal health coverage. In response, TDR has developed tools to strengthen such research capacities, including an intersectional gender research toolkit and an online course on gender-based analysis. In June 2020 TDR launched its new strategy for intersectional gender research. Developed over a number of years with expert input, this strategy expects to lead to a more inclusive, effective response to infectious diseases. The strategy will shape how TDR works over the coming years. Sida Research Cooperation Unit was involved in the process, especially invited as Sida is considered leaders on gender issues in global development. - The establishment of a new Secretariat for the growing Social Innovation in Health Initiative (SIHI) network took place earlier this year. Based in the Philippines, the team will coordinate the work of SIHI and raise the profile of social innovation in health through effective communications, supporting social innovation through research capacity and advocacy. - There is a TDR paper in The Lancet Global Health focused on social innovation in health, making the case that rigorous research, engaging all actors, is needed to test, optimize, and scale up innovations. It calls for researchers, governments, and health professionals to adapt in order to reap the full benefits of social innovation in health. Sida Research Cooperation Unit contributes with an article as well. Covid-19 response: Although TDR&#xA0;are not reactive to emergencies, their work directly contributes to emergencies which appear. For example, TDR has long supported capacity building for research on infectious diseases of poverty through various training programmes. A recent TDR survey showed that 60% of the former trainees that replied were now responding to COVID-19, and almost 80% of these were able to do so thanks to the skills acquired in TDR training. TDR continues to work in many ways to contribute to the COVID-19 situation, including follow-up work of the COVID-19 Clinical Research Coalition, reviewing daily research publications included in the WHO database of publications on COVID-19, working with our co-sponsors on joint activities, and developing a customized training course on good clinical practices for research teams in hospitals participating in the WHO &#x201C;Solidarity&#x201D; clinical trial for COVID-19 treatments.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="54100171" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
