<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-ke" dstore:index="1045" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-06T13:45:33" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-06T13:45:34" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5111012603-KEN-16011</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Social Protection Support - UNICEF &amp; WFP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kenya Social Protection Support - UNICEF &amp; WFP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to UNICEF/WFP Social Protection in Kenya

UN WFP and UNICEF have submitted a joint programme proposal to Sweden for support to the Government of Kenya to provide assistance towards equitable access to social and child protection for a total of 78 MSEK.   

The long-term vision for change is an integrated, child-sensitive and shock-responsive social protection system that links beneficiaries to basic social services, so as to benefit an increased number of men, women, boys and girls; from the poorest and most vulnerable households.   

The proposal aims at 
i) Support Technical Assistance to review, develop and implement legislation, processes and strategies on Social Protection(SP) and Child Protection (CP), systems    strengthening, 
ii) Enhanced capacity and increased efficiencies in the delivery of social protection programmes and to
iii)  strengthen intersectoral coordination linkages at the national and county level. 

The proposed programme will use already existing models and focus on linking cash transfers beneficiaries to child protection services through integrated case management.   

There will be one contribution with two agreements (one with WFP and another with UNICEF).  It is expected that the appraisal, reviews, field missions and evaluations will be conducted jointly.  SE in Kenya has worked previously with support to social protection via both WFP over the last 3 years and UNICEF to both social and child protection over the last 14 years in the development and implementation of different aspects of social protection.  

The current  assessment is for 78MSEK for 3 years distributed as follows - UNICEF 66MSEK and WFP 34MSEK.  However, due to the fact that currently there is no government formed in Sweden and the aid budget for 2019 is not yet decided, the Embassy will sign with both UNICEF and WFP a one year agreement in 2018 for a total of 40 MSEK - 30MSEK for UNICEF and 10MSEK for WFP.  However, should funds be available after the government appropriation, Sweden can then take a decision to avail more funds and prolong the activity period.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FN:s WFP och UNICEF har l&#xE4;mnat ett gemensamt programf&#xF6;rslag till Sverige g&#xE4;llande ett st&#xF6;d p&#xE5; totalt 78 MSEK till den kenyanska staten. Syftet &#xE4;r att bygga upp ett system som ger r&#xE4;ttvis tillg&#xE5;ng till sociala skyddssystem och barnskyddssystem.   

Den l&#xE5;ngsiktiga visionen &#xE4;r ett socialt skyddssystem som &#xE4;r integrerat, tar h&#xE4;nsyn till barn och fungerar i n&#xF6;dsituationer, som ger f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;nstagarna tillg&#xE5;ng till ett grundl&#xE4;ggande socialt skydd samt att ett &#xF6;kat antal m&#xE4;n, kvinnor, pojkar och flickor fr&#xE5;n de fattigaste och mest s&#xE5;rbara hush&#xE5;llen f&#xE5;r tillg&#xE5;ng till detta.

F&#xF6;rslaget g&#xE5;r ut p&#xE5; att ge teknisk assistans vid revidering, utveckling och inf&#xF6;rande av lagar, rutiner och strategier g&#xE4;llande socialt skydd och barnskydd, att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka system, &#xF6;ka kapaciteten och effektiviteten i de sociala skyddsprogrammen samt st&#xE4;rka koordinationen mellan olika sektioner p&#xE5; nationell och regional niv&#xE5;. Det f&#xF6;reslagna programmet kommer att utg&#xE5; fr&#xE5;n befintliga modeller och fokusera p&#xE5; att koppla kontant&#xF6;verf&#xF6;ringsmottagare till barnskyddstj&#xE4;nster med hj&#xE4;lp av integrerad &#xE4;rendehantering. 
  
Det kommer att vara en insats med tv&#xE5; avtal (ett med WFP och ett med UNICEF). Planen &#xE4;r att bed&#xF6;mningar, revisioner, f&#xE4;ltuppdrag och utv&#xE4;rderingar ska utf&#xF6;ras gemensamt. Sverige har de senaste tre &#xE5;ren arbetat med att st&#xF6;dja sociala skyddssystem i Kenya tillsammans med WFP samt under de 14 senaste &#xE5;ren tillsammans med UNICEF arbetat med socialt skydd, barnskydd och utveckling och genomf&#xF6;rande av olika sorters sociala skyddsmekanismer.  

Det nuvarande f&#xF6;rslaget &#xE4;r 78 MSEK under tre &#xE5;r, f&#xF6;rdelade enligt f&#xF6;ljande &#x2013; UNICEF 66 MSEK och WFP 34 MSEK.  Eftersom det inte bildats n&#xE5;gon ny regering i Sverige efter valet och bist&#xE5;ndsbudgeten f&#xF6;r 2019 &#xE4;nnu inte &#xE4;r beslutad kommer ambassaden att teckna ett&#xE5;riga avtal p&#xE5; totalt 40 MSEK med UNICEF (30 MSEK) och WFP (10 MSEK) f&#xF6;r 2018.  Om den nya regeringen ansl&#xE5;r mer medel kan Sverige besluta att avs&#xE4;tta mer medel och f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;nga aktivitetsperioden.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed programme has an overall goal to ensure that people in Kenya, especially the most vulnerable groups, live in dignity, are free from poverty, hunger, violence, abuse and exploitation, to be able to exploit their full human capabilities and contribute to the national development.
The original assessment of the objectives and contribution&apos;s theory of change still stands&#xA0;save for the current Covid-19 pandemic which has brought in positive aspects of testing the shock-responsiveness of the Social Protection system in Kenya and how to enhance the system to&#xA0;address varying types of shocks which will affect Kenya&#xA0;in future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFP/World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41140" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="16011" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social protection and welfare services policy, planning and administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1414986.3730631834</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1414986.3730631834</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1499539.7219920831</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/agreement-51110126-wfp-strengthening-child-and-social-protection-systems.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement 51110126 Kenya Social Protection UNICEF &amp; WFP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/decision-51110126-kenya-social-protection-unicef---wfp.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision 51110126 Kenya Social Protection UNICEF &amp; WFP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/51110126-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This report is the a comprehensive final report for 2019. This is the first comprehensive annual report for a joint programme on the Joint Programme on Strengthening Child and Social Protection Systems in Kenya implemented by both UNICEF and WFP. The report was delivered on time and comments given on the first draft. The following are highlights of the achievements:- 1. Development of Social Protection Framework at County LevelAt the county level, UNICEF and WFP continued its support to social protection legal and policy frameworks will leverage county resources and assure sustainability of county led programmers. The development of the policies lays a solid foundation for establishment of county-specific social protection interventions financed by the respective county governments and addresses context-specific needs identified by the county and complements and enhances coverage of the overall social protection system in Kenya. This inlude Maternal, Newborn and Child Health/ Family Planning (MNCH/FP) in both Kakamega and Vihiga, development of a Social Protection Strategy in Mombasa, a disability bill in Wajir. In Makueni, Baringo, Marsabit and Wajir counties; social protection capacity needs assessment to deliver food and nutrition security conducted. 2. Establishment of the Social Assistance FundThe Government of Kenya supported to develop regulations for establishment of the Social Assistance Fund within the Public Finance Management Act (2012). This is pending before Parliament but it is envisaged to result in enhanced coverage for social protection, provision of timely, regular and adequate benefits to all targeted persons with clear complaints and grievances mechanisms. 3. Existence of a Social Protection PolicyThe GoK was supported to update the National Social Protection Policy leading to a more inclusive, child-sensitive, and shock-responsive national social protection policy.4. Adoption of the National Social Protection Investment Plan (NSPIP) GoK supported to develop a 10-year National Social Protection Investment Plan (NSPIP) which outlines proposals for expanding the national social protection sector up to 2030 to maximize the economic, social and political benefits of sector investments. The Plan proposes the progressive introduction of a Universal Child Benefit (UCB) which will expand coverage of the National Safety Net Programme (NSNP) and significantly increase the number of children reached by Social Protection measures, addressing existing equity issues within the NSNP. 5. Evidence generation for policy and programme developmentBaseline for the universal pension for the Inuajamii70+ developed. The report is a vital step towards evidence-based policy decision making.6. Existence of a comprehensive child protection legislationThe draft Children&apos;s Bill is still pending before Parliament. The Process is hindered by the lack of consensus on administration of various components and functions of the child protection system.7. Finalize and implement recommendations of the investment case study to enhance policy decisions necessary for appropriate programme complementarity including appropriate gender considerations.The GoK commissioned a study on the above. The evidence indicates Cash-Plus models are capable of facilitating long-term productive impacts of cash transfers. It demonstrated how raising household income and thus purchasing power, cash transfers enable households to make productive investments. However, design and implementation barriers of cash transfer schemes may fail to raise household income enough to make productive investments. The Government commits to increasingly focus on all identified barriers and gradually remove them. In designing new interventions, the government and partners will consider the barriers that hinder gains related to cash transfers. 8.Existence and utilization of a national single registry that is linked to county and/or sector-specific MISs.WFP and UNICEF supported the continued development and enhancement of existing MISs, e.g. to accommodate cash plus and shock-responsive models within the framework of the NSNP. To facilitate effective linkages between the social assistance, social security and health insurances databases in turn promote effectiveness, efficiency and maximize on results for integrated programming. A high-level result for this system will be the development of a social registry to significantly bridge and facilitate seamless delivery of humanitarian and development assistance including timely response to emergencies using the social protection system.10. Existence and utilization of a shock-responsive social protection system that is supported by the Single Registry, the Harmonized Household Registration System and the referral mechanism.11. An assessment done on Shock-responsive Social Protection to explore potential of integrating shock-responsive pillars into the ongoing interventions including the single registry. GoK launched a dialogue to explore potential efficiency benefits of linking humanitarian and social protection interventions.12. Existence and application of a comprehensive monitoring and evaluation framework for the social protection sectorGoK supported to develop an evaluation plan and monitoring tools for monthly, quarterly and annual reporting on the Social Protection sector.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="51110126" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
