<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-jo" dstore:index="71" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11651A0102-JOR-15180</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC Jordan &amp; Lebanon resilience project 2017-2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IRC Jordanien -Libanon resiliens projekt 2017-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
IRC-UK will promote gender equality by supporting displaced and local communities, with a focus on vulnerable women and girls, in Jordan and Lebanon in 2017-2020, to increase social and economic resilience. The project in total is budgeted 54.7 MSEK.
The project is extended to November 2020 with an additional contribution of 51.8 MSEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
IRC-UK kommer att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet genom att st&#xF6;dja f&#xF6;rdrivna och lokala samh&#xE4;llen, med fokus p&#xE5; utsatta kvinnor och flickor, i Jordanien och Libanon 2017-2020, f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka den sociala och ekonomiska &#xE5;terh&#xE4;mtningsf&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan. Projektet omfattar 54,7 MSEK totalt.
Projektet f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngs till nov 2020 med 51,8 MSEK till&#xE4;gg.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SECuRE II Sida considers the renewed partnership highly relevant given that exposure to GBV, although partly mitigated by the initial phase of this project and other partners&#x2019; complementary interventions, remains however significant in the refugee crisis settings, as a result of socioeconomic vulnerability, of negative copying mechanisms and of inequitable cultural practices. It requires a scaling up of tested and efficient redressment interventions, like those utilized by IRC during the phase I of SECuRE. IRC proposed intially to plan for a phase II of SECuRE over a three year timeline (2020-2022). It would have make much sense as it takes time to change societal norms and to build resilience in a sustainable way. The Syrian refugees, over one million persons in Lebanon and over 600,000 persons in Jordan, will be still most probably in large numbers in both countries in the coming years, necessitating a robust response and self-reliance solutions like the ones offered by IRC and others.&#xA0; However, Sida does not have yet a visibility on the continuation of the Syria Crisis strategy after the cycle for 2016-2020 comes to an end. Despite it is likely that it is renewed and will be catering as well a response to refugee situations in host-countries, it was not possible to plan for extension beyond 2020. Therefore, the extension cycle is so far limited to one year. It is considered, based on the findings of field visits conducted by the embassy, annual review meetings and assessments of reports, that IRC has been delivering so far a high standard GBV and gender equality intervention that needs to be consolidated and further supported. Sida has drawn conclusions on performances that are positive for the first year of the previous partnership (2018). Lessons learnt were shared, identifying the limits of capacities of the potential local partners and the scarce economic opportunities in Northern Lebanon as obstacles to the sustainability of the programme, while in Jordan IRC has been challenged and delayed by excessive administrative complications from the authorities in the registration of the projects of sub-grantees. The restrictive policies of host countries on refugee labour are a significant impediment to their access to jobs and vocational training, especially in Lebanon where a campaign on cracking down illegal foreign labour by the Ministry of Labour in August-October 2019 has put additional threats to the refugees&apos; livelihoods. Violence, abuse and exploitation are particular risks that women and girls face as a consequence of the protracted Syrian refugee crisis. The economic challenges facing host-countries (for example, depreciating wage levels, higher cost of living and exclusion to access decent jobs), keep refugees struggle to earn a living and to get adequate food and health care. Women and youths face economic exclusion and additional barriers at the labour market due to inequitable host countries&#x2019; policies and patriarchal social norms that restrict women&#x2019;s role and makes it more difficult for them to access the labour market in a safe way. It is our assessment that IRC&#x2019;s project, by addressing these conditions, meets particularly well Sweden&#x2019;s own priorities in regard of gender equality, women empowerment and human rights. Lack of childcare and safe transportations are reported to be the two main barriers women face to accessing livelihood services. IRC addresses these obstacles by providing adapted services. Gender-based violence is highlighted as continuous challenges facing women and girls on a daily basis, generated by the hardship of protracted displacement and social exclusion. Refugee settlements increase the safety risk of women where social norms and power dynamics in this environment place a major pressure on women and girls. The areas targeted in the project are hosting the highest number of refugees in Lebanon and Jordan and show little prospect of economic growth. The locations are marginalized and hard-to-reach areas. Sida recognises that IRC may be particularly challenged in these areas, but it is a calculated risk as IRC is considered able to overcome difficulties. The absence of IRC&apos;s intervention would definitely create a deeper socioeconomic gap and would leave gender inequities un-addressed. The project design is primarily planned to target female adults, youth and adolescents, but also to be gender-transformative and involve male youth and men who can support women and girls&#x2019; empowerment and prevent violence against them. Women&#x2019;s protection and empowerment programming is designed to be linked with livelihood opportunities that seek to promote and generate a safe income for women. Only a long term programming can allow to meet such objectives, according to Sida. A one year timeline for this project can be considered short in that aspect. However, IRC&#x2019;s programme extension builds on a 24 month experience that will be continued. Therefore, the programme can be considered a three year long intervention, which is a significant timeline for consolidating outcomes. The project design is aligned on the 2019 Regional Refugee and Resilience Plan (3RPs: LCRP for Lebanon and JRP for Jordan). For addressing durable solutions, protection and resilience needs of impacted and vulnerable communities, IRC has objectives that are included in the interagency response plans. Sida has observed that IRC is a strong member of different humanitarian coordination forums and working groups, both in Lebanon and Jordan, articulating relevant advocacy at different levels regarding gender-based violence, protection issues more broadly, access to livelihoods and the right to a voluntary and safe return. IRC&#x2019;s programmes are implemented in a coordinated manner with partners, with the intention to avoid duplications and gaps and to contribute to a comprehensive and coherent response. IRC&#x2019;s cross-border humanitarian programmes in Syria (North West and North East Syria currently) provides experience and opportunities to learn from for other branches of IRC in neighbouring countries and to align the programmes in an informed manner. The number of targeted direct beneficiaries is 13,696 persons (10,970 individuals). while the total number of indirect beneficiaries are 67,250 persons (53,950 persons individuals). In the description of the objectives and the logical framework, IRC is able to provide Sida with an approximate breakdown of these figures by sex and age, which is satisfactory. For Lebanon, IRC will support 3,335 direct and 15,475 indirect beneficiaries. For Jordan, 10,361 direct beneficiaries will be supported, while 51,775 persons will benefit indirectly from the project. The ratio between Lebanon and Jordan is 30/70, grossly, while the budget ratio between the 2 countries is 50/50. The difference is justified by higher operational costs in Lebanon due to the multiple locations, while in Jordan sub-grantees are fewer and concentrated in two urban locations, including the capital city. The project locations are the same, plus Arsal in the Bekaa valley in Lebanon, and Eastern Amman area for Jordan. SECuRE I (initial assessment done in Nov. 2017) Through this application to Sida&apos;s development funding, in the frame of Sweden&apos;s Regional Strategy for the Syria Crisis, IRC is intending to &quot;promote gender equality by supporting displaced and local communities, with a focus on vulnerable women and adolescent girls, in Jordan and Lebanon to promote economic and social resilience. The IRC will support Syrian refugees, and vulnerable host communities with the skills and resources to generate income and assets (objective 1), will empower women and girls to contribute to their communities and homes (objective 2), and will ensure the provision of specialized life-saving, targeted, age-appropriate gender-based violence (GBV) and psychosocial support (PSS) for women and girls (objective 3). The programme design is based on interdependent and tailored services to address violence response and prevention as well as livelihood access, and takes into account the specific needs, preferences, capabilities and gaps in skills and knowledge of beneficiaries.&quot;  IRC-UK&apos;s project to be funded by Sida, called SECuRE, aims to reach 20,611 beneficiaries overall (18,356 in Jordan, 80% female and 2,255 in Lebanon, 91% female). Given that the total budget is 54.6 MSEK, the project requires 2,653 SEK per beneficiary.  Sida notices that the project has 88% of its beneficiaries in Jordan, while activities in Lebanon will absorb 35% of the total budget.This costing issue is included in the dialogue of Sida and IRC about the budget and resource allocations in support to IRC&apos;s office and interventions in Lebanon, taking into account as well that Sida&apos;s Humanitarian Unit is planning to provide IRC with 5 MSEK in 2018 for protection interventions focusing on gender-based violence, in continuation to a contribution of 7 MSEK provided to IRC for the same purpose in 2017. It is suggested here that the humanitarian contribution is phased out in 2018 and that the contribution for IRC from Syria crisis strategy budget line is increased in 2019, subject to a amendment and cost extension, if decided so.  The targeted project locations in Lebanon are Mount Lebanon, Deir Dalloum and Wadi Khaled, which are in the northern part of the country, for the two later ones close to the Syrian border. There are different locations from the Sida/HUM-supported GBV project (in the Akkar governorate and Bekaa valley).  The targeted project locations in Jordan are Irbid, Ramtha, Mafraq and Zarqa, north of Amman, close to the Israeli and Syrian borders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC/International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21506" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3172622.3839084595</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2305438.932306814</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2749606.066053998</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3172622.3839084595</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2305438.9323068135</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2749606.066053998</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">9102609.102609102</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">3172622.3839084595</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">2305438.932306814</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC reported the following results, according to agreed objectives:1) Women generate income and assets, and are able to use and control resources,2) Women and girls shape and contribute to their communities and homesand 3) Women and girls are protected from and supported to recover from the consequences of GBV. Achieved progress and challenges of the programme implementation were captured in IRC&apos;s reports, including mitigations of the effects of the social unrest in Lebanon and of the Corona pandemic on the programme through adaptation of the activities and resources. Some undermet objectives were identified by IRC, admitting when a planned target may have been over-ambitious in the initial planning, like the potential profit that was expected to be sustained from creating and supporting micro-businesses in Jordan. The economic situation in Jordan does not leave much room for running businesses successfully. IRC recognizes as well that, in the case of North Lebanon (Wadi Khaled), the planned expected economic opportunities were not matching the reality of this excluded area. In this marginalized territory whose population doubled with the Syrian refugee influx in 2013, IRC has been confronted to the limited capacities of the local civil society, of the markets and existing businesses, to the lack of socioeconomic opportunities and at the same time to a very conservative culture. However, despite limitations of their economic dividends, beneficiaries are acquiring new skills and self-confidence that bring a significant difference to their lives.&#xA0; Our assessment is that IRC provides challenged persons, households and communities with both recovery opportunities and resilience through high quality and &apos;client&apos;-tailored services that are relevant and on high demand, especially in this time of economic crisis. The ongoing crisis in Lebanon (closure of businesses, depressed markets, job destructions, inflation) and the lockdown situations in both countries since March 2020 are however significant obstacles to the empowerment objectives of IRC&apos;s programme. IRC shared with us data on decreasing job opportunities being offered by the market. IRC learnt a lot about factors that were unidentified in the planning phase throughout the implementation phase. IRC could however adapt the programme by recognizing the programme challenges and making possible adjustments at an early stage. IRC is an organization able to reflect on itsself and to adapt with agility. It is noticeable that IRC is generally meetings its result targets, with few exceptions, and that during year 2, it accelerated achievements in order to catch up with delayed results. Results under the target for combined year 1 and 2 may be slightly below expectation due to lower implementation during year 1 and despite reinforced implementation during year 2. In many cases, results are above targets. Interesting and unexpected cooperation experiences with local actors that the programme has generated, were shared by IRC, like the ad hoc training requested by the Jordanian police school from IRC for GBV case management and psychosocial counselling techniques, and like the facilitating role of the municipality of Wadi Khaled in Lebanon in promoting the programme among the population. IRC played there the role of a development actor of proximity, funding with another donor&apos;s resources repairs to the municipal sewage system that made cooperation even more easier afterwards for other interventions. The feedback of beneficiaries about the programme gives indications of positive transformations it brought into their lives: men learning to share decision-making with their spouse, women getting conflict resolution or anger management skills, women and girls acquiring technical skills and increasing their employability, girls negotiating successfully the delay of their too early marriage, etc. A particular character of the programme that defines its success is the way all services and activities are integrated with one another and complementary so that maximum benefit is achieved. Committed trainees may be recruited as volunteers and benefit from a per diem allowance. Mothers may leave their infants at the kindergarten while attending training or counselling sessions. GBV services and empowerment services are integrated, removing the potential stigma of attending a center for case management of GBV. Persons seeking such services are offered as well, like other people and without being identified as GBV survivors, training and socioeconomic opportunities that make the visit to the center casual and unnoticed. The programme benefits to other family members as well who may attend lifeskills sessions, focus group discussions on gender roles, and improve ability to sustain livelihoods and employability. Another particularity of IRC programme is that it is tailored on the beneficiary herself/himself who is more perceived as an agent of the implementation whose opinion is listened to than a recipient. The experience of visiting IRC-run centres, as the embassy has done at several occasions, brings a sense of high spirit and dynamism among both personal and clients, opposite of victimization, and the impression that things have already started to get better for them despite their life situation as refugees. An obstacle for which IRC has found mitigation measures during year 3 is the cost of transport barriers from the community to the centres. IRC has introduced the distribution of taxi vouchers for women and girls living at a too long distance for sustaining their attendance. IRC has also reorganized the services and the curricula in more compact schedules at convenient time of the day so that beneficiaries optimize their time spent at the centre. The overall impression of the programme confirms Sida&apos;s positive assessment of this partnership. It is meeting a priority need in areas of socioeconomic exclusion. It delivers demand-driven and a wide offer of concrete services to the beneficiaries, based on a continuous dialogue with them and reassessement of the progress and relevance of the programme. It addresses GBV and socioeconomic hardship, which are interrelated, in a holistic manner.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11651" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1110401" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2023-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01" strategy-total-amount="3210000000.0">
    <title>Syria Crisis 2016-2023</title>
    <titleSV>Syrienkrisstrategin 2016-2023</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
