<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998d" dstore:index="1716" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:22" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:23" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12487A0101-GGG-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 MADRE, Women peace &amp; security 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 MADRE, Kvinnor fred och s&#xE4;kerhet 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
MADRE is an international civil society organization based in the United States. 
MADRE works in solidarity with local women-led organization in areas and countries affected by conflict and war to promote social justice and women&apos;s full participation in conflict resolution and peace building. Currently, MADRE is working in Iraq, Syria, Palestine, Kenya, Sudan, Nicaragua, Guatemala, Haiti, DRC and Colombia. MADRE uses a variety of strategies, such as legal advocacy work, forwarding of funds to local partners, humanitarian support, capacity building and mobilization of women&apos;s organizations and activists. MADRE is also a strong voice in the design of the international dialogue and normative framework for Women&apos;s Peace and Security in close cooperation with both international and national partners as well as by supporting the practical implementation of the central parts of the agenda at national level.

MADRE plans to expand its operations during the next strategic period and budget projection for 2018/19, 2019/20, 2020/21 is a total of approximately SEK 200,000,000, of which about 28% is planned to be forwarded to local partners. Other donors mainly consist of US private foundations and individual donors.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
MADRE &#xE4;r en internationell civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisation baserad i USA. MADRE arbetar i solidaritet med lokala kvinnoledda organisation i konflikt- och krigsomr&#xE5;den  f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja social r&#xE4;ttvisa och kvinnors fulla deltagande i konfliktl&#xF6;sning och fredsbyggande. F&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande arbetar MADRE i Iraq, Syrien, Palestina, Kenya, Sudan, Nicaragua, Guatemala, Haiti, DRK och Colombia. MADRE anv&#xE4;nder en rad olika strategier, exempelvis juridiskt p&#xE5;verkansarbete, vidaref&#xF6;rmedling av medel till lokala partners, humanit&#xE4;rt st&#xF6;d, kapacitetsuppbyggnad och mobilisering av kvinnoorganisationer och aktivister. MADRE &#xE4;r dessutom en stark r&#xF6;st i utformningen av den internationella dialogen och normativ ram kring Kvinnor fred och s&#xE4;kerhet i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med b&#xE5;de internationella och nationella partner samt genom att st&#xF6;dja det praktiska genomf&#xF6;randet av de centrala delarna i dagordningen p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;. 

MADRE planerar att expandera sin verksamhet under n&#xE4;sta strategiperiod och budgetprojiceringen f&#xF6;r &#xE5;ren 2018/19, 2019/20, 2020/21 &#xE4;r totalt motsvarande ca 200 000 000 kronor, varav ca 28% &#xE4;r ber&#xE4;knat till vidaref&#xF6;rmedling till lokala partners. Andra givare best&#xE5;r fr&#xE4;mst av amerikanska privata stiftelser och individuella givare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MADRE Strategy for 2018-22 presents 3 interlinked goals; 1) Women at the margin leads, meaning women and girls who are excluded from power and representation in their societies will gain capacities, resources and access to policy making and other centers of power; 2) Policies and attitudes change, meaning new policies at local, national and global level to uphold women&#x2019;s rights and change of attitudes and social norms to reflect priorities of women at the margin; 3) Progressive movements gain power, meaning movements that are critical to advancing social change for social justice and gender equality are strengthened and play leadership roles in global movements.
MADRE seeks to assist community based and women led grassroots organisations to address gendered root causes of conflict, the effect of disasters and their aftermath by advancing human rights and social justice and to meet critical needs in the communities. MADRE furthermore recognizes the disproportionate impact of conflict on women and girls, and the need to ensure their active participation in conflict resolution and peace building to ensure both inclusive society and sustainable peace. MADRE specifically seeks to prioritize marginalized groups, such as young women and girls of indigenous or Afro-descendant origin or with disablities and LGBTIQ people. MADRE also directly link conflict and fragility to climate change and environmental deterioration, and the potential gendered consequences in the communities.
MADRE argues that human rights obligations and social justice can be strengthened in conflict and fragile contexts by meeting the urgent community needs through programs that asserts women&#x2019;s rights and leadership, including sustaining the environment; support the participation, agency and voice of grassroots women in a rage of social movement and policy making spaces; strengthen the exchange of ideas and strategies within and across social movements and diverse communities of activists; improve policies at all levels of governance by using the human rights framework to institutionalize social movement demands; and change and challenge social norms and attitudes using legal advocacy combined with community mobilization and organizing.
MADRE builds on more than 35 years of institutional expertise and practical experience from 25 countries. MADRE is a leading international women&#x2019;s rights organisation, and distinguishes itself by standing at the intersection of the movements for global peace, economic, environmental and climate justice, women&#x2019;s and LGBTIQ rights, sexual rights and Indigenous and Afro-descendant rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Madre Inc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">575347.5098959771</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">575347.5098959772</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">575347.5098959771</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">575347.5098959771</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Conclusions on Performance of core support to MADRE is based on the&#xA0;annual narrative (Dox 000795/20) and financial reporting (Dox 037480/19), the following correspondence (Dox 001439/20) and Sida&#xB4;s assessment (Dox 001449/20). It is also based on the&#xA0;audit report (Dox 011127/20), the Management&#xA0;response (Dox 013469/20) and correspondence regarding&#xA0;the audit (Dox 015030/20), including Sida&#xB4;s Statement on the Audit (Dox 016409/20) which was done in collaboration with the Unit&apos;s&#xA0;Controller. The Annual Review and Learning meeting&#xA0;was held 12th of June 2020, and Minutes are documented (Dox 027318/20) and a meeting on the work plan and budget was held in October 2019 (Dox&#xA0;032520/19) and Statement of the same (Dox&#xA0;033823/19). A field trip to one of MADREs partners in Iraq (OWFI) was planned for March 2020 but had to be cancelled due to a raid against the organisation and a subsequent lawsuit. Unfortunate for Sida&#xB4;s continued assessment of the intervention during the last period, no field trip could later be arranged due to the covid-19 outbreak. The possible consequences&#xA0;for OWFI&#xA0;is not seen under the present reporting.&#xA0; MADRE has over the period&#xA0;disbursed 2,4 MUSD in grants and 924 000 US in in-kind support&#xA0;- disbursed through 73 grants to 55 organisations in 23 countries - showcasing an increase of 23 organisations and 8 more countries than 2018. 290 000 USD of the grants were&#xA0;disbursed for&#xA0;disability justice for the first time. MADRE has over the year piloted and strengthened three types of grant making: partners a local grant-makers; seed grants for potential&#xA0;partners; and a two-pronged emergency response.&#xA0; Below is a selection of processes and achieved&#xA0;results.&#xA0; Goal 1: Ending Sexual and Gender-based violence in conflict and disaster Objective 1: Build the capacity of grassroots women&apos;s&#xA0;organisations to meet the immediate&#xA0;needs of sexual and gender based violence survivors and help them become leaders and long-term agents of change - In Iraq MADRE has supported OWFI&#xA0;to operate shelters and safe houses, including&#xA0;psychosocial support,&#xA0;for survivors of S/GBV, rape, honor killings, violence and early/forces marriages, including for nearly 100 women and six LGBTIQ&#xA0;persons. 186 Yezidi&#xA0;women surviving sexual slavery and genocide from ISIS have received&#xA0;support and protection at the Women&apos;s&#xA0;center i Dohuk.&#xA0;The holistic model is supporting the women to transform from victims to activists. The newly&#xA0;established feminist school reaches broader than the shelters and are open to more participants and helps create a network of trained feminist activists.&#xA0;Focus has also been to build the capacity of the organisation, for example resulting in&#xA0;strengthened measures and awareness of&#xA0;security and risks for staff.&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; - The Viva Girls&#xA0;initiative was launch last year to promote the leadership of the most marginalized girls. The idea is to fill the gaps and prioritize hard to reach groups in remote places and to use MADREs&#xA0;existing network of partners in identifying needs and communities for this initiative. Work is still in early stages and will be in a better position to deliver&#xA0;results next period. Objective 2: Increase&#xA0;prioritization by national, regional and international policymakers to address sexual and gender-based violence - In Colombia MADRE&#xB4;s&#xA0;partner (Proceso&#xA0;de Communidades&#xA0;Negras, PCN) work with documenting afro-colombian&#xA0;and indigenous women&#xA0;and girls&#xA0;voices for transitional justice to continue to build&#xA0;a platform&#xA0;to seek justice and accountability for&#xA0;CRSV and SGBV&#xA0;committed against women in these communities. MADRE has provided training to collect and structure testimonies which now form part of the first ever Observatory on sexual and gender&#xA0;based violence against afro-colombians&#xA0;(VigiaAfro). Because of this, cases&#xA0;are now being presented to the Special jurisdiction for peace (transitional justice body for implementation of the Peace Accord between the government&#xA0;and FARC). Another partner (Taller de Vida) is doing the same work but with a different approach that includes psychosocial support&#xA0;and is addressing the Truth Commission with testimonies. Both approaches&#xA0;have&#xA0;also benefited&#xA0;the survivor&apos;s&#xA0;healing process. - In Iraq, MADRE has worked with its approach&#xA0;&quot;documentation-for-advocacy&quot; in collaboration with&#xA0;OWFI&#xA0;and OutRight&#xA0;Action&#xA0;International to collect and document crimes based on gender (outside sexual violence), committed against&#xA0;girls,&#xA0;women and&#xA0;LGBTI&#xA0;persons alike, by ISIS. This is a first time effort globally to broaden the gender definition as part of the umbrella of crimes against humanity (to include LGBTI). So far, MADRE and&#xA0;its partners have collected evidence of gender based crimes, encompassing almost 4 400 victims and the identification of nearly 2 000 ISIS fighters. UN&#xA0;Investigative Team to Promote Accountability for Crimes committed&#xA0;by Daesh/ISIL&#xA0;(UNITAD) has asked to be allowed&#xA0;to use detailed information about cases which formed part of MADRE&#xB4;s&#xA0;2017 ICC&#xA0;Petition (https://www.madre.org/sites/default/files/PDFs/ICC%20Petition%20with%20Sept%2010%20Addendum.pdf) to advance protection of the rights of women and LGBTIQ people on the international stage. A&#xA0;similar agreement with the International, Impartial&#xA0;and Independent Mechanism for Syria is being negotiated.&#xA0; Objective 3: Law and Policy change and its implementation - MADRE and OWFI&#xA0;has advocated for the legalisation of NGO&#xA0;run shelters (for ISIS victims amongst other) and the illegalisation of domestic&#xA0;violence - both with considerable&#xA0;success as laws are drafted but decisions in parliament are still pending. The question of shelters has even reached the international scene through the local-global collaboration - the&#xA0;OWFI&#xA0;CEO&#xA0;could for example&#xA0;address the shelter issue on CEDAW&#xA0;Committee in November 2019. This approach has been paired with local capacities to negotiate local permissions to run shelters, which has also&#xA0;materialized in in Samarra, Mosul and Sharqat. These&#xA0;result can be overtaken by events in Iraq during 2020. As mentioned previously, the organisation was raided in 2020 by&#xA0;national authorities&#xA0;(which&#xA0;is not part of the 2019 reporting) and is facing legal suit, which is closely followed by Sida and the Embassy in Iraq. - In 2019 MADRE entered a new partnership with SOFEPADI&#xA0;(Female Solidarity for Integrated Peace and Development) in DRC&#xA0;to raise awareness of woman&apos;s&#xA0;rights under&#xA0;DRC legislation. A broad consultation of 152 women led organisations in 14 localities kicked off the collaboration in order to get inputs for MADREs shadow report to CEDAW, resulting in 16 out of 17 recommendations adopted by&#xA0;the CEDAW&#xA0;Committee. It was furthermore determined that the continued focus will be on the development and passage of a domestic violence law that&#xA0;recognised marital rape, to support the shift from&#xA0;the usage of medical certificates of physical&#xA0;injuries in relation to sexual violence&#xA0;and instead&#xA0;put emphasis on psychosocial&#xA0;trauma and on a reparations law for survivors of sexual and gender-based violence.&#xA0; - MADRE support a partner (Wangki&#xA0;Tangni) in Nicaragua to implement national legislation which criminalizes domestic violence, with a focus on 63 indigenous Miskoto communities and to find community based programming and action plans. The work has resulted in a higher sense of security among women, going up from 38% in 2016 to 86% in 2019 (according to the Wangki&#xA0;Tangni&#xB4;s&#xA0;survey). Key concepts have&#xA0;been to work work with men to promote &quot;new masculinities&quot; and through a women-led radio station to change perceptions and behaviours around violence and women&apos;s&#xA0;and girls rights. The collaboration has also contributed to women-led regional level exchange between indigenous communities&#xA0;and policy makers. Goal 2:Building a just peace Objective 1: Capacity building - MADRE and its partners PCN&#xA0;have worked to develop&#xA0;community security for women and human rights defenders in Colombia in four regions (Buenaventura, Tumaco, Norte de Cauca and El Caribe), which is assessed as particularly&#xA0;important given the raise in attacks against afro-colombian&#xA0;female leaders. All regions now have draft security protocols and increased awareness on how to prevent and protect themselves from a holistic perspective but also in increased documentation&#xA0;and usage of alerts.&#xA0; MADRE is developing a feminist approach to emergency relief&#xA0;response as part of its programming. A Emergency and Disaster Relief Fund is established in order to create an alternative method of merging immediate needs with long-term solutions and transformation of root caused of crisis.&#xA0;In 2019 MADRE joined Feminist Humanitarian network. The idea is to put women leaders and local organisations in the forefront of the response but also to use humanitarian funds to broker local peace and ceasefire. Work have been spearheaded in Gaza (via NAWA, Dalia, RAWA and Palestinian Medical Relief Society) and&#xA0;Yemen (Food4Humanity, Yemen Act, Peace track Initiative, Women Solidarity Network). The latter combining relief work with&#xA0;peace building and protection (WHRD) components, including documentation of gender-based violence against these women. 30 cases have been referred&#xA0;for investigation. MADRE and WILPF also supported PTI to host the Group of Eminent Experts on Yemen - investigating human rights abuses - to allow for local activists to meet and feed into the international expertise, including the UN Special&#xA0;Envoy for Yemen. Also Nicaraguan-Guatemalan exchanges has strengthened regional collaboration between indigenous&#xA0;women and Palestinian mid-wives are providing small-scale SRHR councelling&#xA0;and a Syrian&#xA0;center for psychosocial&#xA0;healing has been set-up.&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; Objective 2: Movement building and strategies for change between women&apos;s&#xA0;rights activists.&#xA0; - For several years MADRE has convened partnerships between women&apos;s&#xA0;organisations in Iraq to put forward joint strategies for change which is now showing some results in terms of increased group cohesion and cooperation. OWFI has rendered a growing reputation as leader among the NGO&#xB4;s, which makes the raid against them both more &quot;understandable&quot; but also more alarming and put gained results at high risk. Notable is that a broader group of women activists have convened, like&#xA0;afro-Iraqi women, women with disabilities and LGBTI&#xA0;persons.&#xA0; - The creating of the feminist FIRE consortium (with WILPF, Kvinna till kvinna, Nobel Womens Initiative and medica mondiale) is to create a global platform for feminist peace and ending gender-based violence.&#xA0; Objective 3: Strengthening women&apos;s&#xA0;participation in peace processes and securing redress for conflict-related gender-based crimes - MADRE&#xB4;s&#xA0;international advocacy on Crimes Against Humanity Treaty came about as a universally applied gender definition has been missing, allowing for gender to be defined narrowly and as a social construct (including&#xA0;LGBTI) - thus making it difficult to prosecute a broad range of gender based crimes and discrimination (based on victims sexual orientation, sex characteristics, gender identity). MADRE has taken a lead, gathered other civil society organisations and lobbied&#xA0;the International Law Commission (ILC) which&#xA0;has finally recommended that the outdated definition is replaced, using the&#xA0;arguments put forward by MADRE, if ratified leading to a broader protection for women and LGBTI persons in international criminal&#xA0;law.&#xA0;&#xA0; - Promoting accountability for gender-based crimes committed by ISIS in Iraq has direct bearing on the above advocacy work, but is applying a local approach with the focus on community hearings for these crimes to complement other accountability&#xA0;measures for transitional justice. Steps have been taken to advocate locally.&#xA0;&#xA0; Goal 3: Advancing Climate justice Objective 1: Capacity building Women-led climate adaptation and mitigation in Kenya is supported through Indigenous Information Network (IIN), with a focus on community-led water management and reforestation, while in Nepal the partner National Indigenous Women Forum (NIWF) main focus is on capacities for sustainable farming. In eastern Sudan MADRE supports Zenab for Women in Development for women farmers to mitigate negative impacts of climate change on their livelihoods. Targeted groups for all the climate justice&#xA0;work is on indigenous communities and to create and support locally anchored projects which builds capacity for future livelihoods and survival.&#xA0; Objective 2: Movement building - INN in Kenya is providing a local shelter network for girls fleeing FGM and early marriage. MADRE is providing support for empowerment work to grow movement for indigenous girls rights and build community oriented youth leadership. INN is also using its platform as african leaders for indigenous women to leverage adolescent&#xA0;power and have launched&#xA0;partnership in Tanzania and Cameroon for the same.&#xA0; - MADRE is using policy gains in Nepal to push for a broader protection agenda for indigenous women world wide. CEDAW is seen as not protecting indigenous rights&#xA0;enough and MADRE is working&#xA0;in coalition with others&#xA0;to for the preparations and consultations for the submission of a new recommendation in February 2021.&#xA0; Objective 3: Advancing law and policy change&#xA0;and implementation MADRE&#xB4;s&#xA0;strategic&#xA0;approach is to both support local level projects and global-level policy proposals to elevate indigenous women&apos;s&#xA0;voices.&#xA0; - In Nepal its partner NIWF&#xA0;has&#xA0;been supported to advance national and international&#xA0;policy work, including women with disabilities, resulting in a shadow&#xA0;report to CEDAW&#xA0;(15 out of 32 recommendations being adopted bu the committee) and access to key government officials, the National human rights commission in Nepal and UN&#xB4;s&#xA0;Special Rapporteur&#xA0;on violence against women. The increased&#xA0;visibility in media has increased awareness and the CEDAW&#xA0;recommendations has been used to influence laws and practise as well as to educate&#xA0;indigenous women on their rights.&#xA0; - MADRE has provided on-going training to their partners on the provision of UN Declaration of the Rights of Indigenous Peoples, including their rights&#xA0;to free, prior&#xA0;and informed&#xA0;consent on their land and territories. An evaluation of the work shows that the level of understanding of these legislation are raised considerably as has the knowledge of how to use these tools at local and national levels. These insights have been put into practise and furthermore given the participants&#xA0;new leadership roles in their communities (for example being selected to give speeches or&#xA0;nominated to lead engagements&#xA0;with policy bodies, advocacy campaigns and human rights reports submissions).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="12487" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1120103" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01" strategy-total-amount="0.0">
    <title>Sustainable peace 2017-2022</title>
    <titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar fred 2017-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
