<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-298" dstore:index="198" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12780A0102-AFR-12182</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Belmont Forum call on Ocean Sustainability</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Belmont Forum utlysningen Ocean Sustainability</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to address COVID-19
The National Research Foundation (NRF) of South Africa has applied to Sida for funding of 15.1 million SEK to provide grant management services plus additional capacity building and networking activties for African grantees funded in the frame of the 2018 Belmont Forum Collaborative Research Action (CRA) call  &quot;Transdiciplinary Research for Ocean Sustainablity&quot; during the period 2020-02-01 until 2023-06-30. Of the 15.1 million SEK, approx. 11.6 million SEK will be forwarded to six African researchers participating in four transnational research consortia that have applied for Sida funding and were granted funding after expert review.

The purpose of the proposed partnership between Sida, the NRF and Belmont Forum is to facilitate participation of researchers from low-income countries in sub-Saharan Africa and other sub-Saharan countries where Sweden has bilateral development cooperation in transnational research projects addressing challenges related to understanding, mitigating, and adapting to global environmental change. Belmont Forum is a partnership of funding organizations, research councils and regional consortia working with open CRA calls. Sida will partner with the NRF for administration and management of funding to African research partners selected through Belmont Forum CRA calls. 

In 2018, Belmont Forum, in collaboration with Future Earth and the Joint Programming Initiative Healthy and Productive Seas and Oceans (JPI Oceans), launched the CRA call for proposals on &quot;Transdisciplinary Research for Ocean Sustainability&quot; with the aim to bring together researchers and other expertise across the globe to find innovative solutions in order to accelerate sustainable use of oceans and minimize the effects from global change. In this call, 16 funding organizations from 14 countries went together to fund transnational research projects. Funding was allocated to 13 projects with a total sum of 14.3 million Euro (approx. 149.4 million SEK) with Sida&apos;s contribution of 1.1 millio Euro (approx. 11.4 million SEK) representing approx. 7.4% of the total funding.

Previous experience from supporting research through the Belmont Forum framework shows that Belmont Forum CRAs follow a well-established robust call and review process, research themes are highly relevant to sustainable development and funded projects have a great potential for impact.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
National Research Foundation (NRF) Sydafrika har hos Sida ans&#xF6;kt om 15,1 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r att administrera finansiering av och tillhandah&#xE5;lla kapacitetsst&#xE4;rkande och n&#xE4;tverksbildande aktiviteter f&#xF6;r afrikanska forskare som beviljats anslag inom ramen f&#xF6;r 2018 &#xE5;rs Belmont Forum Collaborative Research Action (CRA) utlysning &quot;Transdiciplinary Research for Ocean Sustainablity&quot; under perioden 2020-02-01 till 2023-06-30. Av ovann&#xE4;mnda beloppet kommer ca. 11,6 miljoner SEK att vidarebefordras till sex afrikanska forskare som deltar i fyra transnationella forskningskonsortier som har ans&#xF6;kt om Sidafinansiering och beviljades anslag i utlysningen efter expertgranskning.

Syftet med partnerskapet mellan Sida, NRF och Belmont Forum &#xE4;r att st&#xF6;dja och &#xF6;ka deltagandet av forskare i l&#xE5;ginkomstl&#xE4;nder i Afrika s&#xF6;der om Sahara och andra l&#xE4;nder i omr&#xE5;det d&#xE4;r Sverige har bilateralt utvecklingssamarbete i transnationella forskningsprojekt som ska generara kunskap f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;, f&#xF6;rebygga och begr&#xE4;nsa globala milj&#xF6;- och klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar och anpassa samh&#xE4;llen till s&#xE5;dana f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar. Belmont Forum &#xE4;r ett partnerskap mellan ett antal internationella forskningsfinansi&#xE4;rer, forskningsr&#xE5;d och regionala konsortium som har utvecklat CRA instrumentet f&#xF6;r &#xF6;ppna utlysningar. Sida kommer att samarbeta med NRF f&#xF6;r att administrera finansieringen av partners fr&#xE5;n ovann&#xE4;mnda afrikanska l&#xE4;nder som har f&#xE5;tt forskningsanslag beviljade i Belmont Forum CRA utlysningar.

2018 lanserade Belmont Forum, i samarbete med Future Earth och Joint Programming Initiative Healthy and Productive Seas and Oceans (JPI Oceans), CRA utlysningen &quot;Transdisciplinary Research for Ocean Sustainability&quot; med syftet att f&#xF6;ra samman forskare och annan expertis fr&#xE5;n hela v&#xE4;rlden f&#xF6;r att hitta innovativa l&#xF6;sningar f&#xF6;r ett uth&#xE5;lligt anv&#xE4;ndande av havsresurser och anpassning till havsrelaterade klimat- och milj&#xF6;f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar. I utlysningen samlades 16 forskningsfinansi&#xE4;rer fr&#xE5;n 14 l&#xE4;nder f&#xF6;r att finansiera transnationella forskningsprojekt. Finansiering tilldelades 13 projekt med totalt 14,3 miljoner Euro (ca. 149,4 miljoner SEK); Sidas bidrag p&#xE5; 1,1 miljoner euro (ca. 11,4 miljoner SEK) motsvarar 7,4% av den totala finansieringen.

Tidigare erfarenheter fr&#xE5;n att st&#xF6;dja forskning genom Belmont Forum visar att CRA utlysnignar &#xE4;r baserade p&#xE5; etablerade och tillf&#xF6;rlitliga utlysnings- och granskningsf&#xF6;rfaranden, att utlysningarnas inneh&#xE5;ll &#xE4;r mycket relevant f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling och att finansierade projekt har en stor p&#xE5;verkanspotential.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objectives of the intervention&#xA0;are to generate new&#xA0;knowledge,&#xA0; strengthen research capacity and promote transdisciplinary research to&#xA0;find solutions&#xA0;for ocean sustainability on the African Continent. The specific objectives of this program are: to administer CRA grants in Somalia, Kenya, Mozambique and Madagascar; to provide technical assistance to selected institutions to support the design, implementation and monitoring of innovative approaches and interventions for the CRA project; to manage capacity building or networking activities to support effective delivery of the CRA programs; to follow up on projects and reporting; to document, process and develop a learning model capable of facilitating continuous learning, increased impact and sustainability of the funded CRA projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NRF/National Research Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12004" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other public entities in recipient country</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="12182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="121" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health, General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">504277.7525143033</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">571241.2356306645</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">504277.7525143031</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">571241.2356306645</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1075518.9881449677</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">504277.7525143033</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2018, Sida signed a Memorandum of Understanding to participate in the Collaborative Research Action (CRA) on Transdisciplinary Research for Ocean Sustainability with the purpose to facilitate participation of researchers from low-income countries in sub-Saharan Africa and other sub-Saharan countries where Sweden has bilateral development cooperation in transnational research projects. Sida initially indicated a tentative budget of a total maximum of 8 MSEK towards grants for applicants from Comoros, Kenya, Madagascar, Mozambique, Somalia and Tanzania. However, to maximize the number of funded projects highly ranked in the scientific assessment (see outcome of decision meeting, Dox document 003535/20), Sida raised its funding commitment for research projects to 11.35 MSEK. This made is possible to allocate funding to four projects with six African project partners in Kenya, Madagascar, Mozambique and Somalia: Project 1408 Salt-Mine: Dr Joseph Kamau, Kenya Marine and Fisheries Research Institute (KMFRI), Mombasa, Kenya; John Livingstone, Pastoral and Environmental Network in the Horn of Africa Somaliland (PENHA Somaliland), Hargeisa, Somalia; Dr R. Mbithi Mulwa, The Environment for Development (EfD) Initiative, University of Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya Project 1414 ARMSRestor: Dr Glidas Todinanahary, University of Tolaria Fishery and Marine Science Institute (IHSM), Toliara, Madagascar Project 1485 MULTI-FRAME: Almeida Tom&#xE1;s Guissamulo, Eduardo Mondlane University-Museum of Natural History, Maputo, Mozambique Project 1490 OceanFrontCHANGE: Dr David Obura, Coastal Oceans Research and Development in the Indian Ocean (CORDIO) EastAfrica, Mombasa, Kenya Contact details for the African partners can be found in Dox document 004832/20; full proposal with project details are included in the handover material. The role of the NRF in this cooperation is to provide grant management services including due diligence of institutions receiving Sida funding, forwarding of funds and follow-up. In addition, the NRF will provide capacity building and networking activities for the projects. The NRF is also partner in the CRA Ocean Sustainability providing support to South African researchers and providing common activities to the Sida and NRF cohorts of researchers is expected to generate additional opportunities for collaboration and other synergies. Further information on the background and details of this intervention can be found in the appraisal document and updated handover notes from Emilia Molnar (Dox document&#xA0;035532/19).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="12780" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
