<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-xk" dstore:index="112" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10898A0105-KOS-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Continued support to the minority RAE communities 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Continued support to the minority RAE communities 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Danish Refugee Council  has presented a proposal to Sida for implementing a project &quot;Support for social entrepreneurship and socio-economic empowerment of minority communities in  Kosovo 2018-2021&quot;.  The proposal corresponds well with Multi Dimensional Poverty Analysis that Sida in Kosovo conducted in 2017. Compared to the previous cooperation phase, the proposal focuses more on the empowerment of the most marginalized and underrepresented groups, notably RAE communities not limited only to Roma Mahalla in Mitrovica. The proposal is highly relevant and  corresponds with  current Result Strategy for Sweden&apos;s Reform Cooperation with Eastern Europe, Western Balkans and Turkey 2014&#x2013;2020.The budget for the project is 26 000 000 SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
DRC har presenterat ett f&#xF6;rslag till SIDA om st&#xF6;d till minoritetssamh&#xE4;llen i Kosovo som g&#xE4;ller entrepren&#xF6;rskap och socio-ekonomiskt egenmakt under perioden 2018-2021. F&#xF6;rslaget ligger v&#xE4;l i linje med den multidimensionella fattigdomsanalysen som SIDA i Kosovo genomf&#xF6;rde 2017. Projektet &#xE4;r utformat f&#xF6;r att aktivt engagera de lokala och centrala myndigheterna i Kosovo och st&#xF6;dja dem i genomf&#xF6;randet av regeringens strategi med namnet Strategy for Communities and Return [1] samt Strategy for Inclusion of Roma and Ashkali Communities in the Kosovo Society 2017-2021. Projektet bidrar ocks&#xE5; till strategin Small and Medium Enterprise Development Strategy of Kosovo 2012-2016 - med en vision mot 2020, som kr&#xE4;ver en &quot;f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad st&#xE4;llning f&#xF6;r kvinnliga entrepren&#xF6;rer, ungdomar, minoriteter, s&#xE4;rskilda grupper och st&#xF6;d till entrepren&#xF6;rer i missgynnade zoner&quot; ( Strategiskt m&#xE5;l 7). I j&#xE4;mf&#xF6;relse med den tidigare samarbetsperioden, fokuserar detta f&#xF6;rslag mer p&#xE5; egenmakt hos de mest marginaliserade och underrepresenterade grupperna, i synnerlighet RAE, och inte endast Roma Mahalla i Mitrovitca. Vidare &#xE4;r f&#xF6;rslaget h&#xF6;gst relevant och korresponderar med den nuvarande Result Strategy for Sweden&apos;s Reform Cooperation with Eastern Europe, Western Balkans and Turkey 2014&#x2013;2020. Budgeten f&#xF6;r projektet &#xE4;r 26 000 000 SEK. Denna f&#xF6;reslagna intervention &#xE5;terspeglar f&#xF6;ljande policymark&#xF6;rer:
J&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet 1 &#x2013; Viktigt m&#xE5;l;
Demokrati och m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter 1 - Viktigt m&#xE5;l;
St&#xF6;d till milj&#xF6;arbetet 1 - Viktigt m&#xE5;l
Andra mark&#xF6;rer &#xE4;r:
Konfliktf&#xF6;rebyggande &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder, fred och s&#xE4;kerhet  2 - Huvudm&#xE5;l
Syssels&#xE4;ttning 1 - Viktigt m&#xE5;l

Danish Refugee Council has presented a proposal to Sida &quot;Support for social entrepreneurship and socio-economic empowerment of minority communities in  Kosovo during the period 2018-2021&quot;.  The proposal corresponds well with Multi Dimensional Poverty Analysis that Sida in Kosovo conducted in 2017. The project is designed to actively engage Kosovo local and central authorities and support them in implementing the Kosovo Government policies for Communities and Return  as well as Strategy for Inclusion of Roma and Ashkali Communities in the Kosovo Society 2017-2021.  The project also contributes to the Small and Medium Enterprise Development Strategy of Kosovo 2012-2016 with a vision towards 2020, which calls for &#x201C;Improving the position of female entrepreneurs, youngsters, minorities, specific group and support to entrepreneurs in disadvantaged zones&#x201D; (Strategic goal 7). Compared to the previous cooperation phase, the proposal focuses more on the empowerment of the most marginalized and underrepresented groups, notably RAE communities not limited only to Roma Mahalla in Mitrovica. The proposal is highly relevant and  corresponds with  current Result Strategy for Sweden&apos;s Reform Cooperation with Eastern Europe, Western Balkans and Turkey 2014&#x2013;2020.The budget for the project is 26 000 000 SEK. This proposed intervention reflects the following policy markers: Gender equality 1 - Significant objective; Democracy and Human Rights 1 - Significant objective; Aid to environment 1 - Significant objective 
Other markers are: Conflict prevention, peace and security 2 - Principal objective 
Employment 1 - Significant objective</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRC proposal &quot;Strengthening Community Resilience to Conflict&quot; is motivated by their assessment on continuous inter-ethnic division and alienation as factors of potential inter-ethnic conflict in Kosovo. To address this, DRC proposes a set of activities grouped under an additional component of Grant Agreement 10898 (Specific Objective and Activity Area 4), conceived as an 18-month pilot that will focus on creating or strengthening linkages based on in-depth understanding of the dynamics at the community level, which may vary from a location to the other. The pilot is conceived in line with several points listed under Expected Result 2 of the Results Strategy for Sweden&#x2019;s Reform Cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014&#x2014;2020, which refers to achieving &#x201C;strengthened democracy, greater respect for human rights and a more fully developed state under the rule of law&#x201D;. Namely, in direct reference to the above-mentioned Expected Result, the proposed activities will &#x201C;target increasing trust within and among the parties [&#x2026;] and contribute to reconciliation, so as to counter the emergence of new conflicts&#x201D;. They will aim to promote &#x201C;increased trust and reconciliation between parties&#x201D;, to &#x201C;strengthen the rights of the Roma [&#x2026;], ethnic and religious minorities&#x201D;, and to &#x201C;increase recognition and respect for such groups&#x201D;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dansk Flygtningehj&#xE4;lp/Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.D" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.d - St&#xE4;rka alla l&#xE4;nders, i synnerhet utvecklingsl&#xE4;ndernas, kapacitet n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller tidig varning, riskreducering och hantering av nationella och globala h&#xE4;lsorisker.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.d - Strengthen the capacity of all countries, in particular developing countries, for early warning, risk reduction and management of national and global health risks.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">211508.1589272306</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">211508.1589272306</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">230139.0039583909</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">211508.1589272306</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kosovo/drc-2018-2021-avtal.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement Sida DRC</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kosovo/drc-2018-2021-beslut-insats.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beslut om insats DRC 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project activities implemented in Roma Mahalla/Mahala and Dy Korriku/Sitnicko Naselje have proven to be successful in the short-to-medium term. They have resulted in enhanced access to income generation opportunities and skills development, especially for youth and women. The long-term sustainability of the project faces some challenges, namely in terms of the lack of commitment by central and local institutions to assume full responsibility towards RAE communities inclusion and protection. &#xA0; DRC has been instrumental in facilitating interaction and access to services, such as unemployment benefits for RAE communities.&#xA0; It should be noted that some reluctance still exists within RAE communities to participate in the vocational-educational training programmes offered by the Kosovo system. The NGO grant schemes have yielded positive results, but some gaps remain open particularly in the area of education. DRC plans to support a local NGO RADC to set up and manage a fully-fledged Learning Centre in Roma Mahalla/Mahala in line with the provisions of the relevant Administrative Instructions of the Ministry of Education and Technology. Activities that focuses on promoting inclusive resilience through livelihoods as a means to bring communities together has started to show positive results. The geographical scope of support has included the municipality of Zvecan/Zve&#xE7;an and the area North to the Ibar river. The interaction with municipal authorities has been positive, despite some challenges due to the political situation. These challenges, although resulting is slight delays, have not significantly affected the work plan - DRC and its local implementing partners showed flexibility to adjust to a new socio-political dynamics and circumstances. The situation in which the residents of North Kosovo live is always particularly problematic &#x2013; for instance, during CoVID-19 they had to comply with double restrictions of movement (one from the Kosovo Government and one from Serbia&apos;s Government). DRC will explore the possibilities to continue supporting rural development by expanding it to all four North municipalities. This would contribute to strengthen individual and community resilience. The impact of CoVID-19 was felt particularly in relation to conflict perspective. Planned activities with youth groups had to be postponed and revised. Consultations with a local NGO partner are still ongoing. Discussions on the psychological effects on CoVID-19 are held, correct information are disseminated&#xA0; and the most vulnerable families and individuals&#xA0; are identified, registered and supported with food, hygienic and sanitary material.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="10898" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
