<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-ua" dstore:index="306" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11564A0101-UKR-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine (HRMMU)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till FN:s Human Rights Monitoring Mission i Ukraina</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The aim of the intervention is to improve monitoring of human rights in Ukraine, in particular monitoring and documentation of violence and violations taking place as a consequence of the armed conflict in the Eastern parts of the country. The intervention aims at increase awareness of human rights violations among relevant Ukrainian and international actors and strenghten their capacity to identify and react to human rights violations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra tillsynen p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;det m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter (MR) i Ukraina, och d&#xE5; s&#xE4;rskilt &#xF6;vervakning och dokumentering av v&#xE5;ld och &#xF6;vergrepp som sker som konsekvens av konflikten i de &#xF6;stra delarna av landet. Insatsen syftar till att &#xF6;ka medvetenheten kring m&#xE4;nniskor&#xE4;ttsbrott bland relevanta ukrainska och internationella akt&#xF6;rer samt st&#xE4;rka deras kapacitet att identifiera och reagera p&#xE5; kr&#xE4;nkningar av de m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheterna.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the programme is to improve the observance of human rights in Ukraine, particularly in respect of violations and abuses stemming from the Russian aggression. The programme will aim at raising awareness of human rights violations among Ukrainian stakeholders, the UN system and the broader international community and at developing the capacity of local stakeholders to identify and address human rights violations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OHCHR/Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41313" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (extrabudgetary contributions only)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">468000.468000468</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">920556.0158335634</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">846032.6357089225</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">423016.3178544613</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">920556.0158335634</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">846032.6357089225</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">423016.3178544613</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">468000.468000468</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2808002.808002808</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">468000.468000468</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">920556.0158335634</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">846032.6357089225</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine (HRMMU) continued to remain the major reference point on the human rights situation and violations of humanitarian law in Ukraine. HRMMU continued to monitor, report and advocate on the human rights situation through its office in Kyiv, as well as field offices in Donetsk and Luhansk (in armed group-controlled territory); and in Kharkiv, Kramatorsk, Mariupol and Odesa (in Government-controlled territory). In accordance with General Assembly (GA) resolution 68/262, HRMMU also monitored remotely, produced reports and advocated on the human rights situation in the Autonomous Republic of Crimea and the city of Sevastopol, Ukraine, temporarily occupied by the Russian Federation. Information, findings, analysis and recommendations were shared with national stakeholders and the international community, serving as a basis to inform and shape responses in addressing human rights violations. HRMMU&#x2019;s findings and analysis have been used at a high level in the peace processes (Trilateral Contact Group in Minsk and Normandy Four), in the OSCE Permanent Council in Vienna, at the Security Council, and the Human Rights Council. HRMMU&#x2019;s work has been instrumental in shaping strategic response mechanisms, including as foreseen in the Partnership Framework between the Government of Ukraine and the United Nations for 2018-2022, where HRMMU drafted its human rights component. In 2019, HRMMU delivered and reached its programmatic targets as planned, despite a changing political environment. Compared to the initial 2019 results framework, there were only two noteworthy changes during the reporting period, with one related to the inclusion of additional activities aimed at raising awareness, countering misconceptions and hate narratives and encourage acceptance and inclusion of the LGBTQI community, including among police officers of the National Police of Ukraine. The second was to assess the human rights impact of the conflict in the east of Ukraine on the enjoyment of economic and social rights of Ukrainians, especially in conflict-affected areas. All other activities and interventions were in line with programmatic and operational plans. MAJOR RESULTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS Protection, monitoring, documentation, and selected follow-up  337 new cases of human rights violations, including violations of international human rights and international humanitarian law were registered in OHCHR&#x2019;s Human Rights Database in 2019 for future accountability, based on more than 595 interviews (of which over 39 per cent were with women). HRMMU monitored 469 trials, visited 69 places of detention and took 1,411 follow-up actions, reflecting the efforts, in particular of field teams, to gather additional information to corroborate allegations of human rights violations from interviews, and to engage in advocacy interventions for the protection of victims. 140 people (138 men and 2 women) detained arbitrarily were released following HRMMU advocacy. HRMMU completed 112 monitoring missions throughout Ukraine in 2019, including 18 missions to the administrative boundary line with Crimea. HRMMU recorded and corroborated 167 civilian casualties (27 killed and 140 injured) that occurred in 2019. Furthermore, HRMMU corroborated an additional 234 civilian casualties that occurred in 2014-2017. In 2019, conflict-related civilian casualties decreased by 40 percent compared with 2018 and reached their lowest levels for the entire conflict period  HRMMU civilian casualty recording, reporting and advocacy &#x2013; in coordination with national and international partners &#x2013; contributed to the continued decrease of civilian casualties. The Mission&#x2019;s focus on life-saving activities in eastern Ukraine, including a wider &#x2018;protection by presence&#x2019; effort, was a contributing factor. HRMMU was able to reach victims and witnesses of violations; remote sites, shelled areas, grey zones, hotspots, checkpoints and vital civilian infrastructure; and interact with duty bearers, in a timely manner. The life-saving component of HRMMU&#x2019;s work benefitted an estimated 10,000 civilians residing in the conflict zone. For the first time since the outbreak of the conflict, a State policy for remedy and reparations to civilian victims of the conflict was discussed in Parliament  Following OHCHR/HRMMU advocacy coordinated with, and amplified by, national and international partners, the Parliament developed legislation to provide remedy and reparation for deaths and injuries of civilians, and for the loss of property, including housing, which could lead to a comprehensive State policy of remedy and reparations to civilian victims of the conflict. This is a long-standing HRMMU recommendation. Enhanced freedom of movement across the contact line (both for persons and goods)  HRMMU&apos;s advocacy, combined with awareness-raising through its monitoring and reporting, contributed to the Government of Ukraine&#x2019;s adoption in August 2019 of a resolution regulating the movement of individuals and transfer of goods across the contact line, with consideration of comments and suggestions that HRMMU and partners had provided. The resolution prescribes the establishment of a list of goods prohibited for transfer, to replace the list of goods allowed for transfer; and that children below 14 would be able to cross the contact line without passports. Registration of births and deaths of Ukrainians residing in armed group-controlled territory  Following OHCHR/HRMMU&#x2019;s advocacy, in coordination with other UN agencies, on 23 October 2019, the Cabinet of Ministers approved regulations introducing an administrative procedure for the registration of births and deaths occurring in territory controlled by self-proclaimed &#x2018;republics&#x2019;. This was a longstanding HRMMU recommendation supported by UN agencies working in Ukraine, as the UN worked as one to advocate on the issue of the registration of births and deaths of Ukrainians residing in armed group-controlled territory. Reduced quasi-automatic pre-trial detention in conflict-related cases in Ukraine  Regarding the administration of justice, HRMMU&#x2019;s advocacy succeeded in reducing the quasi-automatic use of pre-trial detention in conflict-related cases. This success was possible due to long-term (years-long) advocacy, by repeating recommendations disseminated through different channels and to various audiences, notably to legal professionals through two widely used online legal databases and a periodical for lawyers. Increased proper classification of hate crime incidents in Ukraine  HRMMU continued its advocacy for the proper classification of hate crimes under article 161 of the Criminal Code throughout the implementation period. During the 20 June 2019 meeting between HRMMU and the Head of the National Police, the latter informed HRMMU that the police had changed its approach to the investigation of hate crimes. In response to UN Human Rights recommendations, the police have started gathering statistics, which indicate that cases of hate crimes had increasingly been classified as such compared with 2018. It is worth noting that in parallel, the overall number of the incidents decreased. &#xA0; Legal gaps in the definition of rape and sexual violence identified in the OHCHR/ HRMMU report addressed through amendments to the Criminal Code of Ukraine  HRMMU advocacy, coupled with technical assistance, allowed HRMMU, together with UN Women, to address some of the gaps in the legal definition of rape and sexual violence identified in the 2017 OHCHR/HRMMU report on conflict-related sexual violence, through amendments to the Criminal Code of Ukraine, which entered into force in 2019. Protection from conflict-related human rights violations such as torture and ill-treatment, SGBV, incommunicado detention and assistance to 650 individuals  650 individuals &#x2013; victims, family members and other persons affected by grave conflict-related human rights violations such as torture and ill-treatment, sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV), incommunicado detention and more, received legal assistance from civil society organisations (CSOs) supported by UN Human Rights. Renewal of the Social Cohesion Campaign  HRMMU contributed to the renewal of the UN in Ukraine&#x2019;s social cohesion campaign, updating two out of four briefing notes (on the need for the Government of Ukraine to ensure payment of pensions and the registration of births and deaths for people living in armed group-controlled territory) and providing comments to the other two (on freedom of movement and IDP inclusion). Furthermore, as part of the UN&#x2019;s humanitarian work, HRMMU analysis supported the development of joint rapid response to address the disruption of basic services in the conflict-affected areas, together with OCHA, IOM, UNHCR, UNICEF and WHO. Addressing and preventing conflict-related sexual violence included in the national action plan on Security Council Resolution 1325 on Women, Peace and Security  HRMMU&#x2019;s follow-up advocacy jointly with UN Women contributed to the inclusion of measures to address and prevent conflict-related sexual violence in the overall national action plan on the realization of UN Security Council Resolution 1325 on Women, Peace and Security. &#xA0; Reports/briefing notes produced in 2019&#xA0; Briefing note on accountability for killings and violent deaths during Maidan protests, including discussion of main impediments to bringing perpetrators to account and ensuring justice for all victims (19 February 2019). Thematic report on civic space and fundamental freedoms ahead of the presidential, parliamentary and local elections in Ukraine in 2019-2020 (12 March 2019). The report and advocacy based on HRMMU&#x2019;s report, e.g. a G7 statement before elections calling for effective investigations of attacks by extreme right-wing groups, contributed to the fact that the Presidential elections were held in a peaceful, competitive and largely inclusive manner. 25th report on the human rights situation in Ukraine, covering 16 November 2018 to 15 February 2019, marking the five-year anniversary since the Government invited UN Human Rights to Ukraine. Key issues highlighted included arbitrary and prolonged detention, systemic use of torture and ill-treatment, and lack of access to justice, as well as impunity. Civilian casualties were down during the reporting period, but civilians living on both sides of the contact line continued to suffer. The report also welcomed the transfers of pre-conflict prisoners from territory controlled by self-proclaimed &#x2018;Donetsk people&#x2019;s republic&#x2019; and by self-proclaimed &#x2018;Luhansk people&#x2019;s republic&#x2019;. In Crimea, HRMMU continued to document violations of international human rights and international humanitarian law. Early warning note on human rights concerns ahead of the first round of the presidential elections in Ukraine, which took place on 31 March 2019. The note was shared with UN Human Rights&#x2019; headquarters in Geneva, as well as the Resident Coordinator, who channelled it to the UN&#x2019;s headquarters in New York, as early warning. Briefing note on accountability for killings and violent deaths on 2 May 2014 in Odesa (published on 2 May 2019). HRMMU held a press event presenting its views on the key impediments to bringing perpetrators to account and ensuring justice for victims. 26th report on the human rights situation in Ukraine (published on 13 June), covering the period of 16 March to 15 May 2019. Key issues highlighted included the effect of the conflict in eastern Ukraine on the civilian population, as well as torture and ill-treatment, issues with the administration of justice and impunity, notably for attacks on prior peaceful assemblies and minorities. The report also highlighted concerns relating to the lack of regular, unimpeded confidential access to all places of detention for international monitors in territory controlled by self-proclaimed &#x2018;republics&#x2019;. In Crimea, HRMMU continued to document violations of international human rights and international humanitarian law. HRMMU launched the report with a live-streamed press statement by the Head of the Mission, simultaneously translated into Ukrainian and sign language, followed by a launch event for civil society and representatives of embassies and international organizations. 27th report on the human rights situation in Ukraine (published on 17 September 2019), covering the period of 16 May to 15 August 2019. Key issues highlighted included the effect of the conflict in eastern Ukraine on the civilian population, as well as torture and ill-treatment, and issues with the administration of justice and impunity. The report also highlighted concerns relating to the lack of regular, unimpeded confidential access to all places of detention for international monitors in territory controlled by self-proclaimed &#x2018;Donetsk people&#x2019;s republic&#x2019; and self-proclaimed &#x2018;Luhansk people&#x2019;s republic&#x2019;. In Crimea, HRMMU documented violations of international human rights and international humanitarian law. The press launch by the Head of the Mission was live-streamed and simultaneously translated into Ukrainian and sign language. It was followed by a launch event for civil society and representatives of embassies and international organisations. HRMMU prepared the first report of the Secretary General on the human rights situation in Crimea, pursuant to resolution 73/263 &#x2013; published in August 2019 and presented to the General Assembly in October 2019. The 28th report on the human rights situation in Ukraine, covering the period from 16 August to 15 November 2019 (published on 12 December 2019), highlighted that while political efforts to end the conflict continued, the civilian population residing close to the contact line experienced daily hardship due to ongoing hostilities, resulting in the continued degradation of their socio-economic rights. People living in remote communities close to the contact line that are considered &#x201C;isolated&#x201D;, due to the disruption of road infrastructure, internal checkpoints, the contact line, and insecurity, continued to experience difficulties accessing social benefits and essential public services, such as healthcare, medicines, and education. HRMMU circulated eight updates (non-papers) on conflict-related civilian casualties (civcas) among key national and international stakeholders in 2019. HRMMU also provided over 20 ad hoc briefs (oral and written) on civilian casualties at the request of various UN agencies and national and international partners.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="11564" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
