<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-mk" dstore:index="73" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12372A0101-MKD-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender budgeting (UNW)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Gender budgeting (UNW)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Makedonien har &#xE5;tagit sig att arbeta f&#xF6;r en st&#xE4;rkt j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet genom dels internationella &#xE5;taganden och dels nationella policies och planer. 
I Makedonien har en reform av den offentliga finansiella styrningen inletts d&#xE4;r man bl.a vill inf&#xF6;ra programbaserad budgetering. Man &#xF6;nskar &#xE4;ven inf&#xF6;rliva en j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsintegrerad budgetprocess. Det betyder att nationella och lokala budgetar formuleras, planeras, genomf&#xF6;rs och utv&#xE4;rderas med h&#xE4;nsyn till de olika behov m&#xE4;n, kvinnor, pojkar och flickor har samt vilka effekter som budgeten ger f&#xF6;r dessa olika grupper. Reformen ber&#xF6;r b&#xE5;de central och kommunal niv&#xE5;. UN Women har sedan tidigare arbetat med j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsintegrering i budgetprocesser, i Makedonien och i ett 70-tal andra l&#xE4;nder. I f&#xF6;religgande programf&#xF6;rslag i Makedonien medverkar, f&#xF6;rutom ber&#xF6;rda stats- och kommuntj&#xE4;nstem&#xE4;n, &#xE4;ven parlamentariker och kommunpolitiker samt civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer. Sida, tillsammans med schweiziska SDC, st&#xF6;djer detta arbete under perioden 2018-2021 med ett belopp om totalt 11,7 miljoner SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Macedonia has made commitments to work for improved gender equality by signing international conventions and enacting national laws and policies. An ongoing reform of the public financial management system includes an initative to introduce and institutionalise gender responsive budgeting (GRB). This means that national and local budgets are formulated, planned, executed and evaluated with consideration to the needs of men, women, boys and girls, and that the effects budgets bring are analysed with reference ot these groups. The reform concerns both central and municipal level. UN Women has been involved in GRB work both in Macedonia and in around 70 other countries in the world. The programme in Macedonia involves civil servants both at central and local level, parliamentarians, local politicians and civil society organisations. Sida, together with Swiss SDC, supports the implementation of the programme with 11.7 million SEK during the period 2018-2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project Promoting Gender Responsive Policies and Budgets: Towards Transparent, Inclusive and Accountable Governance in FYR of Macedonia has an overall objective &#x201C;To improve women&#x2019;s lives and support the inclusion of the most vulnerable groups through systematic and sustainable integration of gender perspective at all stages of national and local policy-making and budgeting processes.&#x201D;
To contribute to the achievement of the overall goal, the project will work towards achieving the following two &#xA0;outcomes:
- The Government&#x2019;s public finance management and the strategic planning processes are improved to respond to the different needs of women and men as a result of effective application of gender responsive budgeting 
- Civil society organizations, women, including the most vulnerable actively participate in planning and decision-making mechanisms, and their priorities are fully reflected in public policies and budgets.&#xA0; 
The theory of change of the proposed intervention is as follows:&#xA0;IF (1) national and local institutions formulate, implement and monitor evidence-based policies and budgets which fully reflect gender equality commitments; (2)&#xA0; Members of Parliament and gender advocates demand accountability to GEWE commitments; (3) Women, including the most vulnerable, voice their needs and participate in local planning and decision-making; THEN more women, including the most vulnerable, will influence the development of and benefit from gender responsive policies and budgets; BECAUSE the capacities of national and local institutions are increased, accountability mechanisms are strenghtened and women&apos;s needs and concerns are fully taken into consideration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Macedonia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">425987.2963269815</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">391501.6021743039</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">301475.6180983094</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">164989.0875924297</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">425987.2963269815</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">391501.6021743039</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">301475.6180983094</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">164989.0875924298</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1346313.173156</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">425987.2963269815</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-28">391501.6021743039</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-28">301475.6180983094</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/vbtla/12372_AgreementPromotingGenderResponsivePoliciesandBudgets-TowardsTransparentinclusiveandAccountableGovernanceinFYRMacedonia12372.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Promoting Gender Responsive Policies and Budgets - Towards Transparent inclusive and Accountable Governance in FYR Macedonia 12372</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/vbtla/12372_DecisiononContributionPromotingGenderResponsivePoliciesandBudgets-TowardsTransparentinclusiveandAccountableGovernanceinFYRMacedonia12372.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution Promoting Gender Responsive Policies and Budgets - Towards Transparent inclusive and Accountable Governance in FYR Macedonia 12372</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The EC progress report for North Macedonia for 2020 reports on &#x201C;some progress made&#x201D; on equality between women and men. Despite the legal framework which is largely in line with the EU acquis, there is still a need for upgrading following the ratification of the Istanbul Convention. North Macedonia published its first Gender Equality Index in October 2019, which indicated improvements regarding equality in decision making. Nevertheless, the gender gap in this field is assessed to be significant. Gender stereotyping persists, and attacks to women are noted. Women in public life are susceptible to particularly vicious attacks through social media, which was confirmed during the parliamentary elections in 2020. Systematic data gathering on gender-based violence is lacking. The action plan for the Istanbul Convention lacks specific funding for its effective implementation. UN Women maintains its role as strategic partner to the Ministry of Labour and Social Policy, and it provides direct support to the capacity development of the institution. Besides the challenges and restrictions imposed due to Covid 19 pandemics, UN Women reports on important progress achieved under the project Promoting Gender Responsive Policies and Budgets: Towards Transparent, Inclusive and Accountable Governance in North Macedonia. At central level the project is reporting on the following results: - Finalized evaluation of the progress and impact of the National Strategy for Gender Equality (2013- 2020) and the National Action Plan on Gender Equality (2018-2020), and providing important recommendations and baseline data for conceptualizing the strategic goals for advancing gender equality in the upcoming 5 years. Initiation of development of the new National Strategy for Gender Equality (2021-2026) by the means of established Working Group composed of representatives of Government institutions, local government, and civil society. Provided support to the Ministry of Labour and Social Policy in drafting documentation of best practices on GRB in the region, to be used as resource document in guiding and mentoring other line-ministries in adopting and implementing similar practices on GRB in North Macedonia. Organized series of workshops for line-ministries and state agencies for applying gender responsive budgeting in the development of the strategic plans, programmes, and budgets for the upcoming year. Developed sector-specific briefs for each institution and discussed gender responsive interventions in alignment with the gender equality commitments set in the Government Work Plan (2020 &#x2013; 2024). All recommendations for gender responsive measures are reported as shared by the Ministry of Labour and Social Policy to the relevant line-ministries for their integration in the new 3-annual strategic plans. Prepared Guidelines for gender mainstreaming in the strategic plans of line ministries/state institutions in alignment with the gender specific provisions in the Government Strategic Planning Methodology, providing important information and tools for public administration to apply GRB. Provided recommendations to Ministry of finance in introducing gender in several important Articles of the Final draft of the new Organic Budget law (Article 3 &#x2013; Budgetary Principles, Article 8 &#x2013; Fiscal and other implications when proposing acts and regulations, Article 31 &#x2013; Proposed financial plans of budget users, Article 92 &#x2013; Content of the Annual Budget Execution Report of the state or the municipality). On the basis of the recommendations of the Working Group on COVID-19, the Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Water Economy adopted a new Rulebook related to production and sale of food of non-animal origin, with new criteria which are more responsive to the needs of women small scale producers. Provided expert support by UN Women&#xA0;in mainstreaming gender in the new Strategy for Regional Development of the Republic of North Macedonia (2020 &#x2013; 2029) including recommendations for 12 sectoral studies that are incorporated in the Strategy. On mainstreaming gender in the oversight role of the Parliament, the Members of Parliament and representatives from the Parliamentary Institute are introduced to the application of gender-responsive budgeting in the review and oversight of the proposed legislation, policies and budgets. The capacity strengthening of the Parliamentary Institute on gender responsive legislative and policy review resulted with Comparative Analysis from gender perspective on financing of political parties in North Macedonia developed by the Parliamentary Institute. At local level UN Women provided: Mentoring support to the municipalities by a local team of experts - focused on data collection and consultation with Coordinators on equal opportunities for adapting local programmes and budgets to the newly emerged situation caused by COVID-19. Support to municipality of Skopje to finalize its Strategy on Gender Equality for the period 2020-2025, as well as an Action Plan containing measures and activities to be implemented by the end of 2025. Support to municipality of Stip to&#xA0;develop a new Strategy on Gender Equality, which is in a final phase of adoption, Support to municipalities&#xA0;Aerodrom and Bitola, with mentoring support from UN Women, in conducting gender analysis upon which new Strategies on Gender Equality will be developed. On cooperation with associations of local authorities UN Women supported: Implementation of the first e-learning course by the Network of Associations of Local Authorities (NALAS) on Gender Mainstreaming and GRB in Macedonian, Albanian and Turkish language(http://nalas.eu/News/e-Academyautumn) . Compiled through&#xA0;NALAS network of Knowledge Management Assistants and shared best practices on Gender Responsive budgeting at Local Level across the countries of South East Europe. Updated and developed e-platform with new tools for collecting gender disaggregated data from all municipalities by ZELS. Access to the platform is enabled for each municipality in&#xA0; North Macedonia, allowing them to insert and update regular gender disaggregated data and information about their municipality. Regarding the cooperation with the local CSO sector UN women reports on: Selection of Akcija Zdruzenska and the National Council for Gender Equality, in partnership with AGORA as Responsible parties to implement outreach and empowerment initiatives for increased participation of women in local decision-making processes. The CSOs are covering eight administrative planning regions in the country in order to ensure full geographical reach. Activities in response to Covid-19 pandemic The mapping study on the impact of Covid-19 on the socio-economic situation of women at local level was promoted at the online workshop for sharing best practices in the area of innovation of social services. A total of 32 representatives from 26 municipalities participated at the workshop, discussing on how to address the gendered impact of Covid-19 at local level based on the mapping study and sharing gender responsive initiatives that were undertaken during the Covid-19 crisis. The Rapid Gender Assessment (RGA) of Covid-19 was published on both English and Macedonian (https://bit.ly/3lvElOs). The RGA is expected to serve as data source to support policymaking initiatives to address the gendered impact from the pandemic, to identify the key priorities to support the most vulnerable groups and to understand different dimensions of how affected women and men experience and cope with the outbreak. In addition, findings of the RGA serves as a basis in the development of the strategic plans of the line-ministries and for the situational analysis for the new National Strategy for Gender Equality (2021-2026). Rapid assessments were initiated in five municipalities Strumica, Kochani, Veles, Gjorce Petrov and Sveti Nikole &#xA0;in engendering the selected local programmes and budgets to better respond to the post-emergency needs due to Covid-19. The assessments are to be finalized in the first quarter of 2021. Regarding communication of project results: Public awareness raising campaign has been completed under the title &quot;Why Your Money Counts? The goal of the campaign was to improve understanding that public funds influence the lives of women and men differently, and to raise awareness how all citizens, women and men, can demand accountability and transparency of public spending. The related social media posts during the campaign are reported to have a reach-out to over 15,000 people and had over 2,500 organic engagements. Unexpected negative results The imposed Covid-19 protecting measures and restrictions to in-person meetings resulted with cancellation of travels and organizing trainings on-line. This had an underspending effect to the project budget. The underspending of project budget has been discussed by the Embassy with UN Women and an early alert to the possibility of requesting six-months no-cost extension to the project (extending the project end date to 1st April 2023) has been mentioned. Due to Covid-19 pandemic and changing political decision-makers after the elections, the slow processes and decision-making by the Ministry of Labour and Social Policy in finalizing the process of adaptation of the operating space for the Center of Excellence on GRB. It is expected that the premises for the Center of Excellence will be fully functional by the first quarter of 2021 and depending on the Government crisis measures in response to Covid-19 the official launch of the center will be decided.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="12372" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
