<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-so" dstore:index="121" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13455A0101-SOM-43010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Strengthening Somali Institutional Capacity through Diaspora</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Strengthening Somali Institutions Capacity through Diaspora</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen har till syfte att bidra till den p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende stabiliserings- och statsbyggnadsprocessen i Somalia genom att tillvarata den kompetens och kunskap som finns hos den somaliska diasporan. Insatsen skall f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka kapaciteten hos viktiga ministerier och institutioner. Den har fokus p&#xE5; st&#xF6;d till statens k&#xE4;rnfunktioner som &#xE4;r avg&#xF6;rande f&#xF6;r att Somalia skall uppn&#xE5; sina m&#xE5;l som anges i den nationella utvecklingsplanen. Sida har sedan 2013 finansierat program f&#xF6;r sekondering av somalisk diaspora (akademiker) till en rad institutioner i Somalia, genomf&#xF6;rt av International Organization for Migration (IOM). Sekonderingen har skett till institutioner p&#xE5; federal och delstatsniv&#xE5;.

Den andra fasen av programmet &quot;St&#xE4;rka den somaliska institutionella kapaciteten genom diaspora&quot; kommer att implementeras av Nordic International Support Foundation (NIS). NIS &#xE4;r en norska ideell organisation (NGO) med huvudkontor i Oslo, Norge, med landskontor i Somalia, Mali och Myanmar. NIS &#xE4;r en samarbetspart till Sida i Myanmar sedan 2015 och har bl.a. implementerat den givargemensam fonden &#x201D;Peace Support Fund (PSF)&#x201D;. 

Den nya fasen kommer att bygga vidare p&#xE5; fas 1 av det tidigare st&#xF6;det och kommer att forts&#xE4;tta prioritera statliga institutioner i syfte att st&#xE4;rka den institutionella kapaciteten hos prioriterade institutioner som har viktiga funktioner i statsbyggnaden i Somalia, inklusive st&#xE4;rkande val- och konstitutionella processer samt en fungerande federal modell i Somalia.

De sektorer och institutioner som skall prioriteras i den nya fasen av programmet inkluderar; h&#xE4;lsa, r&#xE4;ttvisa, offentlig finansiell styrning, m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet, planering, statistik, utrikes- och internationellt samarbete, konstitutions&#xF6;versynen och val samt president och premi&#xE4;rminister kontoren. Det nya programmet kommer &#xE4;ven fortsatt st&#xF6;dja kapacitetsutveckling f&#xF6;r ministeriet f&#xF6;r humanit&#xE4;ra fr&#xE5;gor och katastrofhantering. Diaspora experterna kommer ocks&#xE5; att sekonderas till institutionerna p&#xE5; delstatsniv&#xE5;.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The intervention is intended to contribute to the ongoing process of stabilization and statebuilding of Somalia by strengthening the capacity of key government institutions to perform core government functions  through the mobilization of Somali diaspora resources. Institutional capacity building intervention targeting the identified key Somali institutions is critical for Somalia to successfully achieve its reconstruction and development objectives stipulated in the National Development Plan. The intended impact of the program is that key government institutions are better able to perform their functions in the stabilisation and statebuilding process in which they play critical roles. 

Sida has been supporting the secondment of high-capacity Somali Diaspora to a range of institutions in Somalia since 2013. This work has sought to support the Federal Government of Somalia (FGS) in the implementation of the Somali National Development Plan (NDP), as well as institutional capacity development more broadly. The second phase of the program &quot;Strengthening Somali Institutional Capacity through Diaspora&quot; will be implemented by the Nordic International Support Foundation (NIS). This will build on phase 1 of the previous support and will continue prioritizing government institutions such as good governance and strengthening the electoral and constitutional processes as well as functioning federal model of Somalia.

The targeted sectors includes but is not limited to :Justice and constitution, Health and Public Financial Management, Gender and Human Right, Planning, Statistics, Foreign Affairs and international Cooperation as well as the office of the President and the office of the Prime Minister. The project will also continue to support the Ministry of Humanitarian Affairs and Disaster Management. The Diaspora experts will also be seconded to the federal and member states institutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention is intended to contribute to the ongoing process of stabilization and statebuilding of Somalia by strengthening the capacity of key government institutions to perform core government functionst through the mobilization of Somali diaspora resources. Institutional capacity building intervention targeting the identified key Somali institutions is critical for Somalia successfully achieve its reconstruction and development objectives stipulated in the National Development Plan.&#xA0;The intended impact of the program is that key government institutions are better able to perform their functions in the stabilisation and statebuilding process in which they play critical roles. The indicator of the intervention&#x2019;s contribution to the ongoing process of stabilisation and state building of Somalia is the number of target institutions effectively implementing&#xA0; policies and procedures. This measures the extent to which the program has strengthened the FGS&#x2019; institutional capacity to engage in the process of stabilisation and statebuilding.
Sida has been supporting the secondment of high-capacity Somali Diaspora to a range of institutions in Somalia since. This work has sought to support the Federal Government of Somalia (FGS) in the implementation of the Somali National Development Plan (NDP), as well as institutional capacity development more broadly. The second phase of the program &quot;Strengthening Somali Institutional Capacity through Diaspora&quot; builds on previous support and will continue prioritizing government institutions such as good governance and strengthening the electoral and constitutional processes as well as functioning federal model of Somalia. The targeted sectors includes but is not limited to : Justice and constitution, Health and Public Financial Management, Gender and Human Right, Planning, Statistics, Foreign Affairs and international Cooperation as well as the office of the President and the office of the Prime Minister. The project will also continue to support the Ministry of Humanitarian Affairs and Disaster Management. The IOM Diaspora experts will also be seconded to the federal and member states institutions.&#xA0;The program will have distinct implementation phases and components.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIS/Nordic International Support Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.a - Ensure significant mobilization of resources from a variety of sources, including through enhanced development cooperation, in order to provide adequate and predictable means for developing countries, in particular least developed countries, to implement programmes and policies to end poverty in all its dimensions.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.a - S&#xE4;kra en betydande resursmobilisering fr&#xE5;n en m&#xE4;ngd olika k&#xE4;llor, inklusive genom &#xF6;kat utvecklingssamarbete, i syfte att ge utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, i synnerhet de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, tillr&#xE4;ckliga och f&#xF6;rutsebara medel f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra program och politik f&#xF6;r att avskaffa all form av fattigdom.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1686124.0072335792</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2850205.5441545327</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4074588.96598152</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1686124.007233579</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2850205.544154531</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4074588.96598152</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">8430620.036167</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">1686124.0072335792</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">2850205.5441545327</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/somalia/13455_13455-Agreement-StrengtheningSomaliInstitutionsCapacitythroughDiaspora.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13455 - Agreement- Strengthening Somali Institutions Capacity through Diaspora - NIS</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/somalia/13455_13455-Decision-StrengtheningSomaliInstitutionsCapacitythroughDiaspora.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13455 - Decision - Strengthening Somali Institutions Capacity through Diaspora - NIS</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="13455" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060903" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Somalia 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Somalia 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
