<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998d" dstore:index="2163" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13842A0101-GGG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Geneva Call core support 2020-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Geneva Call k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2020-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
New/additional funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Geneva Call has applied to Sida for core funding of 30 million SEK for 2020-2022 to implement its Strategic Plan. 

The Strategic Plan outlines Geneva Call&apos;s humanitarian engagement with Armed non-State actors (ANSAs) towards better protection of civilians in situations of conflict. Thematic areas are the ban on antipersonnel mines and cooperation in mine action; the protection of children from the effects of armed conflict; the prohibition of sexual violence in situations of armed conflict and the work towards the elimination of gender discrimination; the protection of cultural heritage in armed conflict; the protection of health care; and the prohibition of forced displacement. The organisation is currently active in 13 contexts and has offices in 12 of them (Yemen, Iraq, Colombia, Syria, the DRC, Mali, Lebanon, the Philippines, Afghanistan, Myanmar, South Sudan and Ukraine).

Geneva Call&apos;s total budget is 410 million SEK. The Sida core support covers roughly 10 percent of the total need per year and about 50 percent of the current core support. Other key donors are Switzerland, ECHO and Norway.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Geneva Call har ans&#xF6;kt till Sida om k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d om 30 miljoner kr f&#xF6;r perioden 2020-2022 f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra organisationens &#xF6;vergripande strategiska plan. 

Den strategiska planen anger Geneva Calls humanit&#xE4;ra engagemang med icke-statliga v&#xE4;pnade akt&#xF6;rer i syfte att st&#xE4;rka skydd av civila i konfliktkontexter. De tematiska omr&#xE5;dena &#xE4;r f&#xF6;rbud mot antipersonella minor och samarbete kring minhantering, skydd av barn fr&#xE5;n effekter av v&#xE4;pnad konflikt, f&#xF6;rbud mot sexuellt v&#xE5;ld i v&#xE4;pnade konflikter and mot elimineringen av k&#xF6;nsdiskriminering, skydd av kulturellt arv i v&#xE4;pnade konflikter, skydd av h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, samt f&#xF6;rbud mot tv&#xE5;ngsf&#xF6;rflyttningar. Organisationen &#xE4;r f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande aktiv i 13 kontexer och har kontor i 12 av dem (Jemen, Irak, Colombia, Syrien, Demokratiska Republiken Kongo, Mali, Libanon, Filippinerna, Afghanistan, Myanmar, Ukraina och Sydsudan). 

Geneva Calls totala budget &#xE4;r 410 miljoner kr. Sidas k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d t&#xE4;cker ungef&#xE4;r 10 procent av det totala behovet per &#xE5;r och cirka 50 procent av k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;det. &#xD6;vriga huvudsakliga givare &#xE4;r Schweiz, ECHO och Norge.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute towards the improved protection of civilians in armed conflicts, through the increased respect for humanitarian norms by Armed non-State actors (ANSAs), for the period 2020-2023, Geneva Call will: - Deepen expertise on the engagement of ANSAs and consolidate its action on the ground; - Strengthen Geneva Call&#x2019;s capacity to implement its operations effectively and sustainably. The Geneva Call Operational Portfolio for 2020 outlines the details for the first year of implementing the new strategy, including geographical and thematical priorities. According to the plan, a key focus for the year is to reinforce the monitoring of the signatories of the Deeds of Commitment, making sure that they are accountable and to support their positive steps in better respecting International Humanitarian Law (IHL) norms and civilians in the current countries of operations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geneva Call</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21050" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geneva Call</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.2 - Till 2030 minst halvera den andel m&#xE4;n, kvinnor och barn i alla &#xE5;ldrar som lever i n&#xE5;gon form av fattigdom enligt nationella definitioner.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2 - By 2030, reduce at least by half the proportion of men, women and children of all ages living in poverty in all its dimensions according to national definitions.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.4 - Strengthen efforts to protect and safeguard the world&#x2019;s cultural and natural heritage.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.4 - St&#xE4;rka insatserna f&#xF6;r att skydda och trygga v&#xE4;rldens kultur- och naturarv.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">1089267.0184752378</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">1089267.0184752378</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1057540.7946361536</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">4261889.402383697</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Geneva Call Annual Report for 2019 shows progress towards the strategy of 2017-2019 and also reflects on results achieved during its 20 years of operations. Since its initiation, Geneva Call&#xA0;has developed a unique methodologyto increase awareness of, and respect for International Humanitarian Law (IHL) and Iinternational Human Rights Law (IHRL) by Armed Non-State Actors.&#xA0;It has managed to engage 158 key ANSAs in 25 countries, many of which have taken active steps and made formal commitments to respect specific humanitarian norms. Geneva Call engages ANSAs on specific thematic IHL and IHRL-related areas such as the ban on anti-personnel mines andcooperation in mine action, the protection of children from the effects of armed conflict, the prohibition of sexual violence insituations of armed conflict and towards the elimination of gender discrimination. Furthermore, it has recently developed its thematic humanitarian engagement efforts on the protection of cultural heritage in armed conflict, the protection of health care, and the prohibition of forced displacement. A total of 65 ANSAs have signed an innovative instrument known as the Deed of Commitment. The Deed is a mechanism developed by Geneva Call to enable ANSAs to pledge to respect IHL and relevant norms of IHRL and to be held publicly accountable for their commitments. Throughout the last period (2017-2019), Geneva Call&#xA0;estimates that overall 80% of the results expected in the strategy were achieved. Geneva Call&#x2019;s operations target ANSAs having the greatest impact on civilians as well as initiating contacts with &#x201C;hard-to-reach&#x201D; ANSAs. Efforts in building trust with the leadership of these groups, has led to the signing of Deeds of Commitment, reviews of internal codes of conduct and the adoption of unilateral declarations. In addition, Geneva Call has strived to share its experience and expertise with the humanitarian community through conferences, research, training and other activities.These are some of the results achieved:&#xA0; -&#xA0;In the Democratic Republic of the Congo, the Alliance des Peuples pour un Congo Libre et Souverain (APCLS) issued a unilateral declaration committing to facilitate humanitarian access to areas under its control. Another ANSA, the Nduma D&#xE9;fense du Congo-Renov&#xE9; (NDC-R) shared its Code of Conduct for revision by Geneva Call&#x2019;s policy and legal unit. Two ANSAs nominated focal points to improve cooperation with humanitarian workers and facilitate humanitarian access to areas under their control. -&#xA0;Geneva Call has been working on the protection of children and education in armed conflict since 2010. To date, 29 ANSAs have signed the Deed of Commitment for the Protection of Children from the Effects of Armed Conflict and have taken measures to implement them, such as the demobilization of child soldiers. Other ANSAs have undertaken similar pledges. - Geneva Call has been working on gender issues since 2012. To date, 25 ANSAs have signed the Deed of Commitment prohibiting sexual violence in armed conflict and towards the elimination of gender discrimination and have taken measures to implement them. Other ANSAs have undertaken similar pledges. In addition to engaging ANSAs specifically on the prohibition of sexual violence and working towards the elimination of gender discrimination, Geneva Call addresses sexual violence and the differentiated impact of armed conflict on women, girls, men and boys as part of its other thematic topics. - Geneva Call started to work on the protection of health care in armed conflict in 2018. To date, 2 ANSAs have signed theDeed of Commitment for the protection of health care in armed conflict and have taken measures to implement them. Other ANSAs have undertaken similar pledges.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="13842" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
