<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998e" dstore:index="2274" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105002302-GGG-16010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 World Bank Rapid Social Response</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 World Bank Rapid Social Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The proposed intervention is relevant to the broader objective of     fighting poverty  and strengthening  of institutions in order to      ensure a better and rapid response  to crisis and emergencies. The    programme  will also assist  in building up  efficient social         protection and labor systems to  help the poor and vulnerable  and to mitigate the harmful effects of crises in a coherent manner.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Denna insats genom V&#xE4;rldsbankens TF syftar till att bidra till att    bygga och st&#xE4;rka socialt skydd och arbetsmarknadssystem i             utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, n&#xE4;mligen i Afrika. Insatsen avser system f&#xF6;r     social trygghet, socialf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kring och arbetsmarknadsprogram. Det      &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra de fattigas motst&#xE5;ndskraft mot    ov&#xE4;ntade katastrofer och kriser.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.4 - Besluta om politik, s&#xE4;rskilt finans-, l&#xF6;ne- och socialskyddspolitik, och successivt uppn&#xE5; &#xF6;kad j&#xE4;mlikhet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.4 - Adopt policies, especially fiscal, wage and social protection policies, and progressively achieve greater equality.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">2954689.831434945</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Rapid Social Response Multi-donor Trust Fund was designed as a response to meet the effects of the financial crises in 2008-2009. Overall it has had extensive effects for promoting expansion of social protection as a tool to reduce poverty. Since its inception the RSR has approved 260 activities in 100 countries with support amounting to 122 million USD. It is estimated that the RSR through strategic interventions has contributed to leverage 10,8 billion USD in financing from the International Devleopment Association (IDA). The systems reviews, studies and development of capacity and technical know-how has formed the basis for designing and implementing large-scale social protection programmes that reaches an estimated 176 million people. The RSR also gathers practioners in partner countries for knowledge exhange and dialogue in South-South learning forums that has gathered over 1600 participants from 100 countries and also has a &quot;community of practice&quot; for countinous exchange with over 570 participants. A specific component of the RSR is also targeted to knowledge generation with policy and methods development which is essential for expansion of the right to social protection. RSR reports on results bi-annually with a delay in reports which means the latest report covering 2017 to December 2018 was received in November 2019. The report was discussed at a donor meeting in Ankara in November 2019, with Sida participating on-line.&#xA0; In the latest reported period 2017-2018 there is a decline in approved applications during 2018 which also reflects the decline in the available budget for the RSR MDTF. In December 2018, 5,3 MUSD remained of the total budget of 112MUSD. An updated budget overview in November 2019 showed that 3,8MUSD remained of the total budget of the RSR Classic. The main donors that have contributed to the RSR are; Russia, United Kingdom (DFID), Norway, Sweden, Australia and Denmark, Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, and GFDRR (Global Facility for Disaster Risk Reduction). During the implementation period, the original RSR MDTF has also been complemented with specific &quot;windows&quot; with ear-marked thematic support. Russia has supported a window on nutrition-sensitive social protection, while Denmark has support a window focused on youth. In late 2018 the RSR MDTF was complemented with a gender window focused on gender-integration in social protection schemes, which was supported by DFID and Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation with in total 12,2 MUSD. In March 2020, Australia agreed to provide additional funds to the original trust fund &quot;RSR Classic&quot; to support governments to rapidly develop strategies to meet the challenge of increased poverty during the Covid-19 pandemic.&#xA0; The wide scope of the RSR has made aggregation of results challenging, while results are clear in the large number of satisfactory interventions that have been financed which has resulted in development of key aspects of social protection systems in 100 countries. The targeted windows have provided a clearer overview of results and has also enabled focus on strategic aspects. The gender-window supported by DFID was a result of low priority of gender integration in the initiatives that applied for support from the RSR.&#xA0; A few highlights can be mentioned to provide examples of results achieved from the 300 initiatives that were supported during 2017-2018 to improve social protection and labour systems components and architecture to which over 22 MUSD were allocated. In Botswana the RSR grant contributed to the preparation of a comprehensive National Social Protection Framework which provides a road-map for a coordinated nutrition-sensitive and schock-responsive social protection system. A division of labour and respsonsibility for different stakeholders was developed as well as a proposal of how to integrate nutrition into social protection programming. The RSR financed acitivites also contributed to development of a single registry of beneficiaires to improve the efficiency of social protection. In addition, a social intermediation strategy was developed with a focus on supporting beneficiaries to &quot;graduate&quot; from social assistance to labour market programs. In Sierra Leone the RSR financed activities that increased the effectiveness of the social protection program. Technical assistance during the Ebola recovery period and during floods and landslide emergencies supported development of the social safety net system and expansion of standardised cash transfers in the country. The grant also facilitated national dialogue about social protection issues for the revision of the social protection policy. The revised social protection poliy was later approved by the Cabinet.&#xA0; The RSR also supports policy development, for example in 2019 publishing the book &quot;Exploring Universal Basic Income - A Guide to Navigating Concepts, Evidence and Practices&quot;. The book has supported learning and discussion on key issues in social protection relating to targeting or universal approaches and on how the term &quot;universal&quot; can be interpreted.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="61050023" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1180202" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01" strategy-total-amount="4000000000.0">
    <title>Swedish Strategy for global development cooperation on sustainable economic development 2018 &#x2013; 2022</title>
    <titleSV>Sveriges globala utvecklingssamarbete inom h&#xE5;llbar ekonomisk utveckling 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
