<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-cd" dstore:index="248" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5125001304-COD-12264</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 DIAKONIA - Strengthening Civil Society Organisations in the DRC 2018 - 2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 DIAKONIA - Strengthening Civil Society Organisations in the DRC 2018 - 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to address COVID-19
New/additional funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Diakonia has applied to Sida for funding of SEK 42 877 799 to carry out the program &quot;Strengthening the civil society for a life in dignity for all 2018-2021&quot; in DR Congo during June 2018- May 2021.

The development objective of the program is to support  - A democratic state building in the DRC where all women, men, girls and boys can enjoy their freedoms, demand their rights and live a life in peace and dignity.

The intervention aims at:
 a. Civil society strengthened and advocates for democracy, accountability, gender equality and greater respect for human rights, in dialogue with duty bearers;
b. The Congolese citizens, in particular women, demand respect for human rights; 
c. Increased number of women present in public decision-making processes promoting non-discriminatory laws and public policies towards women; 
d. The Congolese citizens embrace democracy, elect their local, provincial and national leaders and hold them accountable. Diakonia will implement the intervention together with local civil society organisation.  

A total of 56% of the budget will be forwarded from Diakonia to 8 local organisations. After consultation with Sida, Diakonia will also enter into agreements with other partners for implementation of cultural activities within the program. The program will primarely be implemented in Kongo Central, Kwilu, Maindombe, Kasai Central, Lualaba and Kinshasa.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Diakonia har s&#xF6;kt bist&#xE5;ndsmedel fr&#xE5;n Sida om 42 877 799 SEK f&#xF6;r programmet &quot;Ett starkare civilt samh&#xE4;lle f&#xF6;r ett v&#xE4;rdigt liv&quot; f&#xF6;r perioden juni 2018 - maj 2021. 

Insatsens &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r demokratisk en samh&#xE4;llsbyggnad d&#xE4;r alla kvinnor, m&#xE4;n, flickor och pojkar ska kunna leva i frihet, kr&#xE4;va sina r&#xE4;ttigheter och &#xE5;tnjuta ett liv i fred och v&#xE4;rdighet.

Insatsen syftar till att: 
a. st&#xE4;rka civilsamh&#xE4;llet och demokratin samt f&#xF6;respr&#xE5;ka ansvarighet, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och st&#xF6;rre respekt f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter; 
b. st&#xE4;rka r&#xF6;sten f&#xF6;r kongolesiska medborgare, s&#xE4;rskilt kvinnor, n&#xE4;r det kommer till utkr&#xE4;vandet av m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter; 
c. fler kvinnor ska vara delaktiga i offentliga beslutsfattanden samt att fr&#xE4;mja lagar och policys som inte &#xE4;r diskriminerande mot kvinnor;
d. kongolesiska medborgare anv&#xE4;nder demokratin, v&#xE4;ljer sina lokala, regionala och nationella ledare samt utkr&#xE4;ver ansvar ifr&#xE5;n dessa ledare. 

Diakonia kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet tillsammans med &#xE5;tta organisationer f&#xF6;r det lokala civilsamh&#xE4;llet i DR Kongo. Diakonia avser &#xE4;ven att ing&#xE5; avtal med ytterligare partners vad avser kulturella aktiviteter inom programmet. Innan beslut fattas om dessa ska Diakonia f&#xF6;rst konsultera Sida.  

Totalt kommer Diakonia vidaref&#xF6;rmedla 56% av budgeten till &#xE5;tta lokala organisationer. Insatsen kommer huvudsakligen att genomf&#xF6;ras i Kongo Central, Kwilu, Maindombe, Kasai Central, Lualaba och Kinshasa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme describes how Diakonia intends to strengthen Congolese civil society organization and administrative as well self-management capacity in the DRC. It also describes objectives and proposed results, mainly focused on the better understanding of the democratic process, motoring of human rights violation, capacity of women and youth leaders to engage with public institutions for life indignity as well youth pro-democracy to engage in democratic debate and to improve DRC transparency and accountability, especially during the State management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="122" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12264" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 control</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4 - By 2030, reduce by one third premature mortality from non-communicable diseases through prevention and treatment and promote mental health and well-being.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.4 - Till 2030 genom f&#xF6;rebyggande insatser och behandling minska det antal m&#xE4;nniskor som d&#xF6;r i f&#xF6;rtid av icke smittsamma sjukdomar med en tredjedel samt fr&#xE4;mja psykisk h&#xE4;lsa och v&#xE4;lbefinnande.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.6985352403</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1150695.019791</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/dr-congo/51250013agreementgrant.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/dr-congo/51250013decision.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia-Strengthening Civil Society Organisations in the DRC 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Between 15th June 2019 - May 14th 2020, Diakonia continued to implement &#x201C;Strengthening Civil Society Organisations in the DRC 2018 &#x2013; 2021&#x201D; as planned in year 2. But, when the Covid19 pandemic broke out, the DRC Government applied measures that obliged partners to adjust programmes after consultation with the Embassy. The main achievements were in capacity building of all 8 partner organizations: Administrative and Financial Management; Two curricula for Women, Youth, PLWD Human Resources and Civic Education were designed; sensitization campaigns and monitoring of Human Rights was documented; Establishment of Multi-Actor Dialogue Framework and Women &amp;amp; Girls training in Feminine held in all selected provinces; Transformational Leadership and Gender Justice capacity building and production of Training Module on Gender, Women&#x2019;s Rights; Advocacy by the Demo/HR consortium upon local Electoral training of youth electoral Observation and meaningful vote and participative democracy. Result areas and outcomes during the period include: Outcome 1: Civil society strengthened in order to advocate for democracy, accountability, gender equality and greater respect for Human Rights, in dialogue with duty bearers 33 Dialogue frames established in the 6 provinces (members are now doing joint advocacy activities; The Framework is now considered as the official voice of the CS towards the authorities. They are now asking the frame to provide their input for authorities&#x2019; planning) 3 Consortia established (2 are functional: Human Rights defenders and Democracy) by ACAJ, VSV, CEHAJ1325 for HR chaired by ACAJ; by NSCC, LYREC and CEJP for Democracy chaired by NSCC. Staffs from all 8 partner organisations have had their financial management capacity reinforced, resulting in their financial management practices, as shown by the audit report which showed drastic improvements. Outcome 2: The Congolese citizens, in particular women and youth, demand respect for Human Rights Human Rights Module (being prepared by CEHAJ1325 Specialists): To be integrated into the Basic Education Curriculum. A Civic Education Module on Human Rights (under preparation, by ACAJ Specialists) Human Rights sensitisation campaigns in the 6 provinces (by ACAJ, VSV, LYREC &amp;amp; CEHAJ1325) Workshop on Human Rights Violation Monitoring (Kongo Central, by ACAJ) Monitoring of Human Rights Violation (VSV) Study on Human Rights practices within security services (Ongoing, by CEHAJ1325) Protection of HRD in danger (by HR Protection Mechanism set by Diakonia within the HR Consortium) Outcome 3: Increased number of women present in public decision-making processes promoting non-discriminatory laws and public policies towards women Electoral reforms Advocacy (by Diakonia partners and non partners, led by NSCC; result: preparation of &amp;amp; dissemination of CS-wide Vade-Mecum); initiatives to reinforce DRC Women&#x2019;s political participation (led by FMJC; resulting in an Advocacy Strategy) Girls&#x2019; participation in decision-making organs at the local level: This to be revealed by the evaluation report. Preparation of a training module on gender and Women&#x2019;s Rights (by CONAFED, distributed to Gender &amp;amp; Development Local Committees). Outcome 4: Congolese citizens embrace democracy, elect their provincial and national leaders, and hold them to account Deployment of community mobilisers and dissemination of sensitization materials/cards on decentralization and local elections: Diakonia noticed an improvement in the understanding of their role by the population as rights-holders in terms of democracy and elections (consciousness). Compilation and validation of Multi-Stakeholder Dialogue Frameworks&#x2019; priority list (these have been sent to Provincial Governments for consideration in their planning cycles). Awareness-raising Campaign on &#x2018;Meaningful&#x2019; Voting and Participatory Democracy. (Impact: The Catholic Church confirmed that the population voted according to manifesto, not personalities). Training of Election Observers (Impact: EU, Carter Centre, AU Observation missions all uploaded the vital and important role played by Congolese Electoral Observers. This is expected to continue for local elections, still to be held).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="51250013" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1225000000.0" strategy-end-date="2019-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <title>DR Congo 2015-2019</title>
    <titleSV>DR Kongo 2015-2019</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
