<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-lr" dstore:index="133" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5124004301-LBR-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum Syd Civil Society Strengthening</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Forum Syd Civil Society Strengthening</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The contribution is a support to  Forum Syd for the implementation of the project Sustainable ownership: empwering communities and civil society in Liberia. The project has an objective to build capacity of civil society organizations in Liberia to strengthen local CSOs presence in rural counties in Liberia through increased capacity of rights-holders living under marginalised conditions to claim their rights and participate in locally owned initiatives and local development processes. The project will reach 26 local organizations (14 as receipients of sub-grants and 12 as receipients of seed grants) in seven of Liberia&apos;s 15 counties. The project has three years implementation cycle mid 2018-2021. A simplified environment assessment was done by Forum Syd, in additional an environment and climate review by Sida Helpdesk on environment and climate made recommendations that will informed continuous environment improvement in the project. Resources in budget and project work plan for environment and climate has been made. For gender, resources in the budget and plan has been allocated to integrate the gender perspective and Forum Syd has described in their theory of change an attention to mainstream gender. For this reason both environment and climate and gender marker are significant for the project.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Insatsen &#xE4;r ett st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r implementering av Forums Syds projekt: &#x201D;Sustainable ownership: empowering communities and civil society Liberia&#x201D;. Projektet har som m&#xE5;l att bygga upp det liberianska civilsamh&#xE4;llets kapacitet genom att st&#xE4;rka och &#xF6;ka n&#xE4;rvaron av lokala civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer p&#xE5; den liberianska landsbygden. Civilsamh&#xE4;llet avser att &#xF6;ka kapaciteten f&#xF6;r r&#xE4;ttighetsb&#xE4;rare, som lever under marginaliserade f&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden, att ha anspr&#xE5;k p&#xE5; sina r&#xE4;ttigheter och specifikt r&#xE4;ttigheterna att delta i lokala initiativ och utvecklingsprocesser. Projektet kommer n&#xE5; ut till 26 lokala organisationer (14 som mottagare av bidrag och 12 som motagare av ig&#xE5;ngs&#xE4;ttningsst&#xF6;d &#x201D;seed grants&#x201D;) i 7 av Liberias 15 counties (l&#xE4;n). Projektet har en tre&#xE5;rig implementeringscykel fr&#xE5;n mitten av 2018 till mitten av 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the proposed intervention is &apos;Civil society organizations have developed and strengthened their presence in rural counties in Liberia through increased capacity of rights-holders living under marginalized conditions to claim their rights and participate in locally owned initiatives and local development processes.&apos; Three main outcomes are expected to be achieved by the project: 1. Partner organizations and communities have developed their capacities to participate in decision-making processes; 2. Partner organizations have developed their advocacy and monitoring skills of government institutions, public service providers and/or private sector actors&apos; performance in relations to the three thematic areas of the programme; 3. Partner organizations and existing CSO networks have the capacity and resources to develop, fund-raise and implement projects of their own choice that are clearly linked to the needs and priorities identified by involved rights-holder groups and communities. The proposed intervention will reach a total of 26 local CSOs in rural Liberia in two categories - 14 local CSOs as sub-grants and&#xA0; 12 grassroots organizations will receive seed grants. The overall focus of the project is civil society strengthening within three areas: governance and accountability, gender equality and environment and climate change resilience and sustainable use of natural resources. All partners are expected to actively promote gender equality, and some of the organizations will focus on improving environment through sustainable agriculture methods, sustainable energy alternatives, awareness raising on environment and climate change. All partner organizations are expected to mainstream their work through an environment lens, using environmentally sustainable working methods and increase their awareness and knowledge on environment and climate change, natural resource management and rights. The overall goal of the project is to respond to the limited rights and opportunities in rural communities, and the limited presence of participatory and locally based development initiatives.&#xA0; In addition to support to already existing CSOs in the rural areas, the proposed intervention will support non-registered right-holders strengthen their organizations. This is important and relevant for small scale local initiatives that face disadvantage due to high registration cost&#xA0; and lengthy bureaucratic processes that deny them formal registration. Where formal registration is used as criteria to receive donor assistance, rural based organizations representing people living in poverty are often left out. Forum Syd&apos;s expressed commitment to reach non-registered right-holders to strengthen their organizations is addressing this important gap. Forum Syd in its proposed intervention intends to achieve its goal to strengthen the capacity of CSOs in rural Liberia through four key methods: a) Build capacities of local CSOs to develop their own sustainability plans and project ideas, as well as to deepen their discussions on their mission and vision, and engage in long-term strategic planning; implement and monitor participatory and inclusive local sustainable development initiatives; be better equipped to raise awareness and mobilize rights-holders through a human rights-based approach and support rights-holders to organize themselves and engage in collective action. b) Strengthen a rights-based and gender aware development of local CSO, supporting increased internal accountability, transparency and member-based decision-making processes; c) Build capacity of local authorities/duty bearers, service providers, community structures and traditional authorities, in their understanding of their duties and obligations, the role of civil society, and how to engage in transparent, accountable, participatory, inclusive, gender sensitive and environmentally sustainable processes with rights-holders and communities d) Promote dialogue and inclusive democratic decision-making processes involving rights-holders, local CSOs and government institutions at the county and national level. The partner organizations to be supported by Forum Syd at the end of the project will demonstrate a number of positive change in attitudes, behaviors and relations: they will be better organized for collective actions on issues relating to gender, environment and and climate change and sustainable use of natural resources; they will have better understanding of the role, obligations and responsibilities of the key duty bearers of the State and will possess better skills to advocate, negotiate and undertake joint activities with duty bearers at the local and national levels. Communities in the seven counties of the project (Bomi, Bong, Grand Gedeh, Nimba, Montserrado, Grand Bassa and Grand Cape Mount) are expected to experience increase activities of Forum Syd supported partners in the areas of gender equality, environment and climate change and sustainable use of natural resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ForumCiv (f d Forum Syd)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1795084.2308754486</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1247898.1376706606</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2252286.9319684007</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908456</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1795084.2308754488</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1247898.1376706618</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2252286.9319684007</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">5948794.071619257</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">1795084.2308754488</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">317262.2383908459</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">1247898.1376706606</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/liberia-and-sierra-leone/51240043_forum-syd-civil-society-strengthening_agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum Syd civil society strengthening agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/liberia-and-sierra-leone/51240043_forum-syd-civil-society-strengthening_proposal.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum Syd civil society strengthening application</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/liberia-and-sierra-leone/51240043_forum-syd-civil-society-strengthening_decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum Syd civil society strengthening decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific progress on the three outcomes/result areas are documented below:Outcome 1 (organizations&#x2019; capacity to participate in decision-making processes): Forum Syd approved 11 grants to CSOs in 2019 with the aim to strengthen their capacity as organizations and increase their knowledge in thematic areas and the roles of duty bearers and rights holders. Forum Syd also prepared nine new grants for approval by the grant making committee and supported two community events that contributed to Outcome 1: a celebration of activism and an awareness raising event focused on the rights of girls. Outcome 2 (monitoring and advocacy skills): took the form of, for example, women&#x2019;s leadership empowerment and engaging duty-bearers in dialog on farming and climate change. Under the Land Rights Component, Forum Syd analyzed a mapping Report; devised the grant application focusing on Land Rights; and trained staff and local CSOs in the Forum Syd Right(s) Way Forward (RWF) methodology. Outcome 3 (builds on Outcomes 1 and 2): This is expected to show specific results at a later date but the ground work continues: grant making to CSOs; the land rights component is defined and partners identified and systems, procedures, trained staff and partners are in place.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="51240043" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060503" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01" strategy-total-amount="1320000000.0">
    <title>Liberia 2016-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Liberia 2016-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
