<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-zw" dstore:index="117" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-06T13:45:33" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-06T13:45:34" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12794A0101-ZWE-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Internews media programme Zimbabwe</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Internews mediaprogram Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
Internews Europe has applied for programme support of 22 million SEK for their &quot;Zimbabwe Media Developement&quot; (ZMD) programme during 2019 - 2021. The ZMD programme will primarily focus its work on Southern Zimbabwe (Bulawayo, Matabeleland North, Matabeleland South and Midlands). Some activities will also be in Harare (in cooperation with the media programme by Fojo which will focus on the Northern parts of the country). 

The programme is designed to ensure a resilient, digitally-enabled and sustainable independent media and civil society in Southern Zimbabwe to have the skills, knowledge and tools they need to reach citizens with accurate and impartial information that promotes inclusion and accountability. The target group for the programme are mainly women and youth.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Internews Europe har ans&#xF6;kt om programst&#xF6;d p&#xE5; 22 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r sitt program &quot;Zimbabwe Media Development&quot; under 2019-2021. Programmet kommer fr&#xE4;mst att verka i s&#xF6;dra Zimbabwe, men kommer &#xE4;ven att ha ett antal aktiviteter i Harare (i sammarbete med det medieprogram som drivs av Fojo, vilket fr&#xE4;mst fokuserar p&#xE5; norra delarna av Zimbabwe). 

&quot;Zimbabwe Media Development&quot; &#xE4;r designat f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka och kapacitetsutveckla den oberoende mediesektorn samt civilsamh&#xE4;llet i landet, d&#xE4;r stort fokus ligger p&#xE5; att utveckla anv&#xE4;ndandet av digital media, f&#xF6;r att man ska kunna framst&#xE4;lla och n&#xE5; ut till befolkningen med opartisk information som fr&#xE4;mjar inkludering och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. M&#xE5;lgruppen f&#xF6;r programmet &#xE4;r fr&#xE4;mst kvinnor och unga.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention is expected to increase the quantity and reach of independent, reliable and data-driven information into the public sphere, with a focus on content production and consumption by women, youth and rural communities. Further it is expected to strengthen the capacity of media and civil society to inform and elevate citizen voices as key to holding the government accountable on key project themes i.e. governance, human rights, gender, corruption, health, environment, climate change. Finally, the ZMD programme is expected to improve the business and financial sustainability of independent media.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Internews Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453072</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.0191211441</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">977230.5286817161</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453074</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.0191211443</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">977230.5286817164</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2326589.748199537</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">740278.5562453072</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">651487.0191211441</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-06">217162.339707048</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zimbabwe/agreement---internews.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zimbabwe/decision-on-contribution---internews_23052019150913.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Internews supported many journalists, media, and CSOs to carry out awareness campaign and share accurate information about the pandemic. Internews support to local partners resulted in the production of more than 40 COVID-19 related stories and awareness campaigns in various formats. In April 2020, one of the Internews partner radio station; Skyz Metro FM produced content on COVID &#x2013; 19 programmes that reached approximately half a million listeners. Training and mentoring of Journalists and civic society players gave birth to new media initiatives as well as the revival of several defunct websites. The Community Podium TV; a youth-run vibrant, digitally enabled media organisation is one such example of an entity that was birthed as a direct result of the media entrepreneurship and media upskilling training. With Internews&#x2019; support and mentoring, the organisation produced a wide range of COVID-19 awareness campaigns both in video and print format reaching an estimated 4000 viewers daily. Internews support through the ZMD project also enabled CITE (our leading local partner) to become an authoritative source of Southern region information. Within the period under review, support from Internews enabled CITE to produce and post over 800 stories on its website. The increase in content ultimately resulted in a significant (about 20%) increases in audiences from about 67k to over 80k weekly across on all its platforms. Internews support also helped local partners to amplify and enhance giving voices to communities so that they can hold public officials to account for their actions. For instance, a programme which was flighted by CITE on Facebook and shared on YouTube resulted in the perpetrators of gender-based violence (GBV) in Cowdray Park suburb being brought to book. Moreover, another story on police brutality by CITE led to the Member of Parliament for Bulawayo East, to call upon the Zimbabwe Human Rights Commission (ZHRC) and Zimbabwe Peace and Reconciliation Commission (ZPRC) to investigate the conduct of the police. These initiatives ultimately led to the establishment of an online petition calling for justice for the deceased. Also, the coverage of the full council meetings of the council by CITE provides citizens with information on local governance to promote civic engagement for democracy and accountability. Internews also facilitated the youth and women roundtable events to enhance information dissemination in vulnerable communities. Internews also successfully fostered an online community engagements and social media campaigns for partner organizations CITE, Kubatana, HIFC, Sunshine Cinemas and ZACRAS which ultimately led to content sharing formats and platforms. As an outcome of the editorial meeting, Cite, and Kubatana collaborated positively in the campaign around Constitutional Amendment Number 2, police brutality in Bulawayo during the lockdown. Due to the ban on public gatherings during COVID-19, Sunshine Cinema had to go digital in efforts to reach audiences. They have since developed a free podcast series &#x2013; instead of the screenings. These were also shared across platforms and formats. Internews supported ZACRAS to lobby for more community radio licensing, and four of its members have since applied for licensing. To enhance media sustainability, all the Zimbabwe-based ZMD partners participated in the media market forum where the audience ratings conducted by GeoPoll were shared and discussed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="12794" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061503" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01" strategy-total-amount="1500000000.0">
    <title>Zimbabwe 2017-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Zimbabwe 2017-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
