<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-bd" dstore:index="507" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:22" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:23" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5106006202-BGD-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Media Support Bangladesh</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Mediast&#xF6;d Bangladesh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The development intervention consists of a five-year project in the field of media development and human rights, which will be implemented by the FOJO Media Institute in cooperation with a local partner, the Management and Resources Development Initiative (MRDI). The project is called Improving Investigative Journalism, Bangladesh. Operations comprise a number of components that aim at capacity development of media organizations and individuals active in the media, networking, sectoral strengthening and special efforts in the field of media security.

Special thematic focus within the initiative lies in Sida&apos;s priority issues in good governance, human rights, labor law, gender equality, environment and climate.

It is Sida&apos;s opinion that the FOJO Media Institute has a unique position in Swedish development cooperation in the field of media development, has shown good results in previous projects of similar nature in other countries and has good prospects for achieving results also in this project in Bangladesh.

The initiative in question is fully in line with the Government&apos;s Development Cooperation Strategy with Bangladesh 2014-2020.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Utvecklingsinsatsen utg&#xF6;rs av ett fem&#xE5;rigt projekt inom omr&#xE5;det medieutveckling och m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter vilket skall genomf&#xF6;ras av Fojo Media Institute i samarbete med en lokal partner, Management and Resources Development Initiative (MRDI). Projektet har namnet Improving Investigative Journalism, Bangladesh. Verksamhet omfattar ett flertal komponenter som syftar till kapacitetsutveckling av medieorganisationer och individer verksamma inom media, n&#xE4;tverksbyggande, sektorst&#xE4;rkande och s&#xE4;rskilda insatser p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;det s&#xE4;kerhet f&#xF6;r medieakt&#xF6;rer. 

S&#xE4;rskilt tematiskt fokus inom insatsen ligger p&#xE5; f&#xF6;r Sida prioriterade fr&#xE5;gor inom god samh&#xE4;llsstyrning, m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter,  arbetsr&#xE4;ttsfr&#xE5;gor, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och milj&#xF6; och klimat. 

Det &#xE4;r den Sidas bed&#xF6;mning att FOJO Media Institute har en unik st&#xE4;llning inom svenskt utvecklingssamarbete p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;det medieutveckling, har visat goda resultat i tidigare projekt av liknande natur i andra l&#xE4;nder och har goda f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar att n&#xE5; uppst&#xE4;llda resultat &#xE4;ven i detta projekt i Bangladesh. 

Insatsen i fr&#xE5;ga &#xE4;r helt i linje med regeringens Strategi f&#xF6;r Utvecklingssamarbetet med Bangladesh 2014-2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching development objective for the intervention is to: &quot;Contribute to improving the conditions for people to raise themselves out of poverty, strengthening democracy, respect for human rights and gender equality, and to contribute to sustainable development.&quot;
The specific objective of the intervention is stated as &#x201C;Media in Bangladesh contributes to strengthened democracy and gender equality, greater respect for human rights and freedom from oppression.&#x201D;To this Objective, Fojo links three outcomes &#x2013; two immediate and one intermediate.
1) The first immediate outcome is linked to the strengthening of individual media outlets and journalists in their production of qualitative journalism: &quot;Targeted media houses and news providers identify, research and produce high quality investigative journalism, particularly on gender equality, labour rights, corruption and environmental impact and climate change&quot;.
2) The second immediate outcome is focused on strengthening the media sector as a whole, to enable a conducive environment for this production: &quot;Targeted partners in the media sector collaborate to create a conducive environment for investigative journalism, particularly on gender equality, labour rights, corruption and environmental impact and climate change&quot;.
The theory of change links the outcomes to the overarching and the specific objective through the following logic: &quot;The stories published result in an invigorated debate on issues related to gender equality, labour rights, corruption and environmental impact and climate change as well as other issues vital for the development of democracy, gender equality and respect for human rights. The debate contributes to strengthened democracy and gender equality, greater respect for human rights and freedom from oppression. Strengthened democracy and gender equality, greater respect for human rights and freedom from oppression contributes to improving the conditions for people to raise themselves out of poverty in a better environment.&#x201D;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medieinstitutet Fojo/Linn&#xE9;universitetet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="17.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.9 - &#xD6;ka det internationella st&#xF6;det f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av effektiv och riktad kapacitetsuppbyggnad i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna till st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r nationella planer f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra alla m&#xE5;len f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling, inklusive genom samarbete nord&#x2013;syd och syd&#x2013;syd samt trepartssamarbete.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.9 - Enhance international support for implementing effective and targeted capacity-building in developing countries to support national plans to implement all the Sustainable Development Goals, including through North-South, South-South and triangular cooperation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">617497.3126160462</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">617497.3126160462</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">664636.8258049437</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/decision-on-appraisal--51060062--1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media Support Bangladesh Fojo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/51060062-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/decision-on-contribution-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media Support Bangladesh Fojo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has achieved important results since the start of the project and in the reporting period despite increasing contextual challenges. The gradually worsening situation with regard to freedom of speech and freedom of the press continued in the reporting period. The outbreak of the Covid-19 pandemic in Bangladesh in March 2020 brought additional challenges for media outlets and journalists, as revenues sharply declined and journalists on the frontline were exposed to health and safety related risks. The number of journalists, bloggers, human rights activists and those critisizing the Government increased in the wake of the Covid-19 crisis. The Covid-19 crisis also had direct implications for the implemenation of the project. While the project quickly adapted by eg. adopting digital tools for trainings and capacity building, some activites were not possible to carry out and had to be shifted partly or fully to year 5. Some examples of results achieved and reported in the annual report include: - The project directly benefitted 46% more journalists with access to knowledge, techniques and tools to produce twice as many investigations than in the previous year. - Production of stories supported through the project significantly increased in the reporting period. Targeted media houses and journalists produced a total of 142 stories, which corresonds to a 364 % increase compared to the previous year. Among the stories produced, 47% were on corruption, 43% on environment and climate change, 3% on gender and the remaining on crime. 55 fact check stories were produced, 64 % of these on crime or Covid-19. - In response to Covid-19, the project quickly adapted and organized a series of webinars, a Covid-19 reporting handbook and collaborated with sector-wide media associations to support journalists covering the pandemic, while ensuring their own safety.&#xA0;Each webinar and safety training was aimed at specific target groups such as media leaders, camera men, women journalists, field reporters, etc. - The project reached 880 direct&#xA0;beneficiaries in the reporting period.&#xA0;Out of the total number of beneficiaries, 42% received knowledge on how to stay safe in the pandemic and how to investigate it. - Advocacy programmes organised, reached more than 35 000 through social media, and the knowledge contents created were read by hundreds of thousands, both in Bangladesh and around the world.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="51060062" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
