<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998d" dstore:index="1136" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:22" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:23" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10697A0103-GGG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WILPF core support 2017-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">WILPF k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2017-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The Women&#x2019;s International League for Peace and Freedom is a global women&apos;s rights organisation, which was founded in 1915. WILPF works to advance feminist peace for equality, justice, and demilitarised security by way of two interlinked paths: by addressing
the root causes of violence with a feminist lens and by mobilising for nonviolent action. WILPF is a membership organization with active sections in 42 countries around the world, but also functions as an NGO with programmatic collaborations in for example the MENA region. Sida provides core support to the WILPF International Secretariat in Geneva based on the WILPF International Strategy 2017-19.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
The Women&apos;s International League for Peace and Freedom &#xE4;r en global kvinnor&#xE4;ttsorganisation som grundades 1915. WILPF arbetar f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; feministisk fred f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mlikhet, r&#xE4;ttvisa och en avmilitariserad s&#xE4;kerhet genom en tudelad men sammankopplad ansats: genom att adressera grundorsaker till v&#xE5;ld med en feministik ansats och genom att mobilisera f&#xF6;r ickev&#xE5;ldsam aktion. WILPF &#xE4;r en medlemsbaserad organisation med aktiva sektioner i 42 l&#xE4;nder v&#xE4;rlden runt, men fungerar &#xE4;ven som en icke-statlig organisation med programsamarbeten i till exempel MENA-regionen. Sida f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s ge k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till WILPF:s internationella sekretariat i Geneve baserat p&#xE5; WILPF:s internationella strategi f&#xF6;r 2017-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WILPF/Women&apos;s International League for Peace and Freedom</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.3 - Avskaffa alla skadliga sedv&#xE4;njor, s&#xE5;som barn&#xE4;ktenskap, tidiga &#xE4;ktenskap och tv&#xE5;ngs&#xE4;ktenskap samt kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.3 - Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">863021.2648439658</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">793155.5959771149</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">793155.5959771149</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.6985352403</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">863021.2648439655</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">4095004.0950040948</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">863021.2648439656</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">793155.5959771149</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As this report covers 2019 and the original objective areas for reporting results is being used. The report contains many interesting results and the below only presents some few high-lights in each area as space is limited.&#xA0; 1. Transform gendered power -&#xA0;Understanding of gendered power and meaningful participation for women improves advocacy and actions for peace at global and local levels This component includes both global and local normative changes. At the global level WILPF has influenced policy coherence and coordination in&#xA0;the UN Security Council, the SDGs and the 2030 Agenda to adapt a balanced and integrated approach to women, peace and security. This is notable when it comes to for example inequalities as root cause of sexual violence in conflict, to disarmament and human rights as key in conflict prevention and to move beyond gender parity to reach women&apos;s&#xA0;meaningful participation. This includes better language in the two new UNSCR&#xA0;2467 and 2463 from last year as well as the three female briefers&#xA0;from civil society&#xA0;in the Security Council and the WPS&#xA0;scorecard methodology.&#xA0; Indicator 1.1: Evidence of take-up of gender analysis and women&#x2019;s meaningful participation among stakeholders, policymakers, key debates, and resolutions Evidence: Our country-level analysis and advocacy has an impact in the UN Security Council Independent Experts Group (IEG) Country briefs on Yemen, DRC&#xA0;and Afghanistan were shared with the UN Security Council Independent Experts Group and influenced&#xA0;the outcome letters. The gender blindness of the Stockholm Agreement for Yemen was lifted and the subsequent follow-up of gender inclusion, as was the recommendation of gender cross-cutting of mandate in DRC&#xA0;and the systematic work in&#xA0;UPR-process, National Action Plans,&#xA0;SC and advocacy&#xA0;towards influential&#xA0;UN leaders to push for more and meaningful inclusion of women in political and peace processes.&#xA0; Indicator 1.2: Evidence of take-up of gender analysis and women&#x2019;s meaningful participation in national/local decision-making processes Evidence: Cameroon National Dialogue and Gender Conflict Analysis WILPF engaged in the Major National Dialogue for peace and created a women consultation platform to ensure a broad and geographically diverse female inclusion of the process and peace initiative. The findings and recommendations were taken forward in order to mainstream gender in the various commissions. Nevertheless, challenges with participation remained and numbers were still low. But woman&apos;s&#xA0;perspectives were more taken into account as the engagements were paired with a gender conflict analysis process (involving more than 1500 persons and thorough&#xA0;investigations) to address the underlying causes of conflict. The process involved African and international expertise and can serve as a new way of working to collect better diagnostics which are formed closer to the&#xA0;realities and actual conflicts. &#xA0; 2. Stigmatise war and violence -&#xA0;Militarised thinking, systems and technologies of war are challenged at global and local levels WILPF has pushed the gendered aspects of disarmament for 20 years and the organisation continues to push for the connection between arms control, human rights and WPS. The work also contains lobbying&#xA0;for more raticifications&#xA0;of Treaty on the Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons, militarisation and securitisation&#xA0;of cyberspace and the impact of explosive weapons&#xA0;in populated areas (EWIPA). WILPF is quite alone in this nische of work and use Human Rights&#xA0;foras&#xA0;like UPR and&#xA0;CEDAW to pursue one of its core values.&#xA0; Indicator 2.1: Evidence of increased strength of analysis, active coalition building and/or shift in thinking/discourse Evidence: Shifting thinking about gender and weapons in disarmament spaces The area&#xA0;is highly&#xA0;masculine and WILPF carried out feminist analysis before the review of the Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT) and raised the needs for a more diverse&#xA0;inclusion in the debate. The awareness raising&#xA0;campaign to Stop Killer Robots provided&#xA0;small grants&#xA0;for local sections to take part, especially in Africa and WILPF Cameroon for example participated&#xA0;in Geneva expert level discussions. Indicator 2.2: Evidence of outreach of analysis and advocacy on militarism, technologies and the arms trade There is an increased interest to take part of WILPF research&#xA0;and findings of&#xA0;this area and&#xA0;WILPF was invited to provide materials in handbooks and briefings and has&#xA0;developed&#xA0;a new resource guide on Killer robots.&#xA0; &#xA0; 3. Promote a feminist political economy -&#xA0;Feminist political economy of peace promoted as a driver of analysis, accountability, and actions at global and local levels After initially working with this approach&#xA0;in Ukraine and Bosnia and Hercegovina, the concept to capture the gendered nature of the political&#xA0;economy in relation to peace building WILPF has taken this work further steps ahead. WILPF shows how gender blind approaches to conflict and post-conflict reconstruction have negative impact on peace and has become the leading analytical tool of WILPF which it aims to promote both internally and externally.&#xA0;&#xA0; Indicator 3.1: Evidence of buy-in/take-up of feminist political economy approach in WILPF&#x2019;s advocacy work Evidence: Feminist Political Economy Analysis in Zimbabwe WILPF Zimbabwe used the tool to present its in-puts to the CEDAW committee on Zimbabwe.&#xA0;Due to security threats the submission as such was made confidential and WILPF country representatives did not participate in the discussion. But the recommendations were adopted by the list of issues&#xA0;for the country and the situation for women human rights defenders were thus&#xA0;high-lighted.&#xA0;&#xA0; Evidence: Creating feminist political economies of peace by mobilising to #MoveTheMoney Activists from the Koreas, Lebanon, Yemen, Palestine, Colombia, Nigeria and Cameroon were supported during the Commission on the Status of Women (CSW63) to mobilise and create feminist political economies of peace, including the #KoreaPeaceNow campaign for a 2020 peace treaty with women at the table.&#xA0; Indicator 3.2: Outreach of FPE analysis and advocacy in different aspects of WILPF&#x2019;s work Evidence: Feminist political economy analysis and disarmament Militarism from a feminist perspective is promoted via an article by the UN&#xA0;Office for Disarmament Affairs and the analysis has broken&#xA0;up perceived&#xA0;assumption&#xA0;to the usual discourse.&#xA0; Evidence: Expanding FPE work into Business and Human Rights WILPF is part of the Feminists 4 Binding Treaty (F4BT) coalition and is advocating to the Intergovernmental Working Group (IGWG) on Transnational Corporations. A result of the efforts&#xA0;the&#xA0;IGWG 5th session makes 12 references to gender-responsive assessments and access to justice and nine references to conflict-affected areas. WILPF has enhanced its partnerships in the intersection of human rights, arms trade and company responsibilities.&#xA0; &#xA0; 4. Movement building -&#xA0;WILPF and its contribution to the peace movement are strengthened The movement continued to be built, using a variety of methods like small grants to sections, regional meetings, &quot;peace louge&quot; etc.&#xA0;&#xA0; Indicator 4.1: Evidence of increased effectiveness of WILPF&#x2019;s internal processes In 2019 both a mid-term learning review and a Sida financed ISK-review were carried out and the MEL system was strengthening to better capture feminist approach. The International board held its meetings as scheduled and the staff has grown to consist of 15 full-time and three part time in Geneva and five staff in NYC.&#xA0;&#xA0; Indicator 4.2: Enhanced community of WILPF (Sections, Groups, members, partners) over five years WILPF has a total of 45 affiliated organisations: 33 Sections and 12 Groups globally. This shows a downward trend from 2018 (47) but it is due to dormant sections and groups being removed by the board. Four new sections were accepted in 2019: Somalia, Sri Lanka, Togo and Senegal. WILPF is growing its engagements and is now part of 14 coalitions and networks, has partnerships with eight international NGOs,&#xA0;takes part in seven multilateral collaborations, has linkages to six academic institutions, and partners with 27 local civil society organisations. In 2019 the feminist FIRE consortium was formed, amongst others with two other&#xA0;Sida partners (MADRE and Kvinna till kvinna) to strengthen the feminist response and WPS.&#xA0; Indicator 4.3: Increased engagement of WILPF in coalition, networks, and with partners Among other things, Partnerships with Syrian NGOs has increased with forwarding of funds, technical support etc, as for the MENA-region, including&#xA0;support to the Iraqi Women&apos;s&#xA0;Network which consists of more&#xA0;than hundred organisations&#xA0;from all over the country. WILPF is on the steering board&#xA0;of ICAN and WILPF was elected&#xA0;Global Organising partner of the Women&apos;s&#xA0;Major group.&#xA0; &#xA0; 5. Amplify local and regional change -&#xA0;Strengthen how women organise, meaningfully participate, and provide gender perspectives on root causes of conflict, conflict prevention, resolution, and peace process at local and national levels Hundreds of activities&#xA0;were carried out by WILPF members and sections during the year. Another three countries were added as prioritised (Yemen, Afghanistan and Cameroon) for 2020 while Syrian, Bosnia and Hercegovina, Colombia, Nigeria and Ukraine remain, as does regions Africa, MENA and the Korean peninsula.&#xA0; Indicator 5.1: Local initiatives and activities implemented in focus countries and regions, and documented outcomes Bosnia and Hercegovina - WILPF kept pushing for an alternative reform agenda with the point of departure in a the Feminist political&#xA0;economy analysis, engaging local communities and activists to collect evidence of the reforms. Submissions to CEDAW, UPR pre sessions and CESCR, having a direct impact on recommendations.&#xA0; MENA - Support to feminist grassroots organisations continued in Yemen, Iraq, Syria, Libya, Lebanon and Egypt, strengthening woman&apos;s&#xA0;participation in a peace tracks, cross-regional exchanges and arabic&#xA0;feminist knowledge production. For example, partners in Egypt made ten consultations on family laws and its effect on violence&#xA0;against women. In Palestine special&#xA0;training was given to activist on WPS, human rights, NAPs&#xA0;and in methods for documenting human rights violations. In Yemen women leaders were supported to influence the peace process.&#xA0; Syria - 13 partner organisations continued to get support in order to enhance influence of women grassroot activists in local and national consultations to identify womens priorities and challenges.&#xA0; African region -&#xA0; the fastest growing WILPF region, many have been active in the Stop killer robot campaign and a lot of cross-learning have taken place between countries etc.&#xA0; Nigeria - During the elections in the country WILPF set up the Womens Situation Room, including election observation,&#xA0;data collection and a report on barriers for female candidates. A protest of the widespread violence was also conducted and a Nigerian Women Mediators Collaborative Initiative was launched.&#xA0; Colombia - LIMPAL&#xA0;(WILPF Colombia) is recognised and is very active actor in Colombia on WPS. LIMPAL runs a Feminist School for Peacebuidling and works with survivors of CRSV.&#xA0;LIMPAL made a special report on the psyco-social strategies for women victims and human rights defenders after the signing of the peace accord as a tool for recovery and&#xA0;the sustaining peace.&#xA0; Korean peninsula - WILPF is part of the Women Cross DMZ and the campaign to stop the war. A report of the impact of the sanctions was researched&#xA0;and launched in 2019. Recommendations brought forward was for the first time to Security Council members, also on women participation and gender conflict analysis.&#xA0; Indicator 5.2: Frequency of dialogue and shared learning spaces for women&#x2019;s civil society, including examples of follow-up and resulting actions for participants WILPF supported five different in-person convenings&#xA0;which provided safe spaces for dialogue and shared learning for Sections and partners, for example women activists from Yemen and Syria, as well as across the MENA region and Africa, and the Bosnia-Syria Feminist Solidarity Dialogue. &#xA0; 6. Improve multilateral actions -&#xA0;Accountability and integrated policies of the states, multilateral forums actively promoted WILPF has a long-term strategy to monitor and advocate multilateral foras to increase accountability and transparency and functions as a cross-cutting methodology. WILPF secretariat functions as a bridge&#xA0;between these spaces and the sections and realities on the ground. Results are captured in other areas&#xA0; Indicator 6.1: Documentation of WILPF monitoring of multilateral processes WILPF produces Security Council Monitor, National Action Plan Monitor and the UN Monitor. In 2019 WILPF made a strategic shift in the&#xA0;Security Council monitoring to focus more on mechanisms for implementation. Some data was even used in the Secretary Generals annual report on WPS. The human rights program for example made detailed monitoring of outcomes of UPR in Afghanistan, DRC and Italy and CEDAW reviews of Colombia, UK and Bosnia and Hercegovina.&#xA0; Indicator 6.2: Documentation of integration of thematic areas in multilateral actions (statements, policies, resolutions, outcomes, etc.) A record number of submissions to multilateral foras by sections and partners is noted in 2019. &quot;WILPF submitted 17 written country-specific submissions to HR treaty bodies (CESCR and CEDAW) as well as six oral statements and three written UPR&#xA0;submissions. Eleven statements (10 oral and one written) were made to the Human Rights Council, as well as one to the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner on Human Rights. Many of these statements were followed up with advocacy delegations from WILPF sections and partners, and resulted in take-up and inclusion of WILPF issues&quot;. Indicator 6.3: Evidence of &#x201C;local to global to local&#x201D; participation and analysis in multilateral forums Evidence: Building capacity of Sections to engage in multilateral forums Trainings to sections and partners were included in this work. Evidence: Supported and amplified the voices of local activists to transform gendered power WILPF is active in the WPS&#xA0;NGO Working Group (supported from UD-KH) and via this link and three civil society briefers within the WILPF family were selected and various delegations got support from WILPF to present themselves in NYC.&#xA0; Evidence: Supporting MENA Region partners&#x2019; engagement with human rights mechanisms Partners in Egypt, Palestine and Iraq participated&#xA0;in human rights mechanisms like CESCR,&#xA0;CEDAW and UPR. Evidence: CEDAW Committee&#x2019;s review of the DRC</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="10697" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1120103" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01" strategy-total-amount="0.0">
    <title>Sustainable peace 2017-2022</title>
    <titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar fred 2017-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
