<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-cd" dstore:index="141" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12206A0102-COD-43060</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Swedish Red Cross Disaster Risk Reduction in Kinshasa</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Katastrofriskreducering i Kinshasa med R&#xF6;da Korset</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The Swedish Red Cross has applied for support for the project &quot;Disaster Risk Reduction in Kinshasa&quot; of SEK 5,639,385 for the period 2019-2021. The project will be carried out in three areas in the municipality of Limet&#xE9;, which are some of Kinshasa&apos;s poorest areas, and where the population is exposed to recurrent floods that cause major health problems, destruction of homes and property, and which annually injure many and harvests lives. The overall aim of the project is to contribute to reducing the vulnerability of girls and boys, women and men in urban communities to disasters in Kinshasa province. 

The project has three principle outputs: (I) Risk awareness among the target population and local authorities is enhanced; (II) Targeted girls, boys, women and men have reduced their vulnerability to disaster and epidemic by 2020 and have undertaken mitigation interventions at community level; (III) Lessons learnt are promoted and shared amongst practitioners and decision-makers at provincial, national and regional levels. 

The project has a strong rights perspective and intends to strengthen the target group&apos;s knowledge of their human rights to protection and health. The project intends to disseminate information on many different levels and has, among other things, planned for a radio and TV campaign, and activities in schools in the project area. The project plans to install an early warning system, and carry out several simulation exercises to train the target group in disaster preparedness. The project also has a large lessons learnt component, which aims to share experiences and lessons learnt with relevant actors in order to create a sustainable project that others can learn from and build on. 

The Swedish Embassy contributes with SEK 5,639,385 and the partner&#x2019;s input is up to SEK 4,309,635 primarily covering administrative costs such as salaries and rents. To a large extent the Project will be implemented by the DR Congo Red Cross, hence project funds will be transferred to them, via the Swedish Red Cross.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Svenska R&#xF6;da Korset har ans&#xF6;kt om st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r projektet &quot;Disaster Risk Reduction in Kinshasa&quot; p&#xE5; 5 639 385 SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2019-2021. Projektet kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras i tre omr&#xE5;den i kommunen Limet&#xE9;, som &#xE4;r n&#xE5;gra av Kinshasas fattigaste omr&#xE5;den, och d&#xE4;r befolkningen &#xE4;r utsatt f&#xF6;r &#xE5;terkommande &#xF6;versv&#xE4;mningar som medf&#xF6;r stora h&#xE4;lsoproblem, f&#xF6;rst&#xF6;relse av hem och egendom, och som varje &#xE5;r skadar m&#xE5;nga och sk&#xF6;rdar liv.

Projektets &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att &quot;bidra till att minska flickor och pojkar, m&#xE4;n och kvinnor i urbana milj&#xF6;ers s&#xE5;rbarhet mot katastrofer, i provinsen Kinshasa. Projektet har tre delm&#xE5;l:

(I) Medvetenheten om risk har &#xF6;kat hos m&#xE5;lgruppen och lokala myndigheter. 
(II) Flickor, pojkar, m&#xE4;n och kvinnor i m&#xE5;lgruppen har minskat sin s&#xE5;rbarhet mot katastrofer och epidemier till 2020 och genomf&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rebyggande aktiviteter p&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5;.
(III) L&#xE4;rdomar fr&#xE4;mjas och delas med utf&#xF6;rare och beslutsfattare p&#xE5; provinsiell och regional niv&#xE5;.

Projektet har ett starkt r&#xE4;ttighetsperspektiv och avser att st&#xE4;rka m&#xE5;lgruppens kunskaper om sina m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter till skydd och h&#xE4;lsa. Projektet avser att sprida information p&#xE5; flera olika niv&#xE5;er och har bland annat planerat f&#xF6;r en radio och Tv-kampanj, och aktiviteter i skolor i projektomr&#xE5;det. Projektet planerar att installera ett varningssystem, och genomf&#xF6;ra flera simulerings&#xF6;vningar f&#xF6;r att tr&#xE4;na m&#xE5;lgruppen i katastrofberedskap. Projektet har ocks&#xE5; en stor l&#xE4;rdomskomponent, som syftar till att dela erfarenheter och l&#xE4;rdomar med relevant akt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r att skapa ett h&#xE5;llbart projekt som andra kan ta l&#xE4;rdom av och bygga vidare p&#xE5;. 

Sveriges ambassad bidrar med 5 639 385 SEK och partnern st&#xE5;r sj&#xE4;lv f&#xF6;r 4 309 635 SEK till framf&#xF6;rallt administrativa kostnader s&#xE5;som l&#xF6;ner och hyror. En stor del av projektet kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras av Kongolesiska R&#xF6;da Korset och s&#xE5;ledes kommer &#xE4;ven projektmedel vidaref&#xF6;rmedlas till dem, via Svenska R&#xF6;da Korset.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the intervention is to contribute to reducing the vulnerability of girls and boys, and men and women in urban communities to disasters in the province of Kinshasa.&#xA0; The intervention is a disaster risk reduction project building on an earlier pilot intervention performed by the Swedish Red Cross together with the DRC Red Cross that focused on risk reduction and enhancing preparedness. The additional value of this intervention is a larger focus on response mechanisms.&#xA0; The chosen target areas situated in the province of Kinshasa are extremely sensitive to hazards such as flooding. The population is very poor, living on less than one US dollar per day and person, making them also very vulnerable to the reoccurring flooding events that destroy homes, livelihood, other property. The floodings are also a main source to spreading disease.&#xA0; This intervention aims at strengthening community engagement to make these already vulnerable areas and groups less exposed to hazards. The project will raise awareness amongst different stake holders, increase the knowledge of rights and different protection measures to protect themselves, their homes and their livelihoods. The project aims at raising awareness and interact with all levels in the target communities to make the population less sensitive to risk, able to demand their rights and to make sure authorities meet the obligations they have towards their citizens. The intervention stretches over two years, and the Embassy sees this as a pilot project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Svenska R&#xF6;da Korset</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43060" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">243234.3827663152</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">35891.3482587591</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">243234.3827663152</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">35891.348258759</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">279125.7310250743</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout 2020 the Swedish Red Cross has worked with the national Congolese Red Cross to deliver against their work plan to the best of their ability considering the challenges proposed by Covid 19. Confinement in Kinshasa and the subsequent lockdown of Gombe proposed challenges during April to September. However, activities did not stop completely, and progress has been made. SRC was also able to reprogramme some of their activities to enable Covid 19 information dissemination in the communities as well as installations of hand washing stations. In the first joint meeting between the Swedish Red Cross, The Congolese Red cross and the Swedish Embassy in March 2020 the following areas of improvement were identified: Implementation was not moving at the expected speed, setting up systems had taken too long Necessity to catch up on implementation before the next instalment was paid &#xA0; In summary the following achievements had been reached from September 2019 to March 2020 1. Lessons learned workshop to build on the foundation of the previous project December 17, 2019 2. Official launch of the project on December 20, 2019 3. Contacting local members Interview with community leaders 4. Elaboration and validation of the annual action plan for implementation Nzadi Vulnerability and Capacity Assessment (VCA) started 5. Process of creation and establishment of community members for the implementation of activities (monitoring of the early warning and response system...) 6. Celebration of International Women&apos;s Day with the target community (ongoing) 7. Community Information Session on Epidemic Risk, Theme: CORONA VIRUS &#xA0; The following activities were planned to take place by the end of August 2020 1. Installation of the Community Early Warning System in all three localities 2. Emergency plan organization in Nzadi Awareness raising activities on flood and epidemic control 3. Organization of simulation exercises for rescue workers Organization of mitigation activities In the second follow up meeting of the year it was noted that some progress had been made towards realizing the targets of the year even though there had been delays at the beginning of the year. However, implementation was mainly moving fast on community based activities and not with the larger infrastructure projects like the recycling stations and WASH facilities which means that the implementation rate of activities and the burn rate of the budget are not aligned. This was motivated in the meeting as follows: The budget forecast for year 1 (September 2019 to August 2020) was 245,000 USD and RC DRC has received from Swedish RC (SRC) the sum of 157,461 USD. Expenses represent 36% of this forecast. And, the cash balance is $ 68,279.47. 48% of expenses represent project activities and 52% are administrative costs and salaries. However, with regard to the overall budget, consumption for the first year (September 2019 &#x2013; August 2020) is 21%. After the restricted measures against Covid-19 were loosened, the project activities gained some speed of execution which is shown in September and October. Activities worth 58,000 USD during the months of September and October took place, which brings the overall spending to 153,419.67 USD. Work Plan for 2021 Awareness-raising activities: radio and television, school competition and deployment of volunteers to fight against floods, epidemics (Covid-19, cholera, ebola, etc.) Develop, print and distribute educational material on the main community risks: floods, road safety, epidemics (covid-19, cholera, ebola) Train and prepare participants in data collection in Nzadi for the design of the mapping of risk areas Develop a mapping of risk areas in the Nzadi quartier Print risk zone maps for KINGABWA PECHEUR, MAMAN NZENZE and NZADI Continue to Install large-scale stationary handwashing facilities in public places and schools construction of two public latrines Construction of two drinking water points meeting to set up procedures which will be followed by a training for the community on the management of materials Carry out an impact and cost-benefit analysis of community-based disaster risk reduction in a complex humanitarian context: DRC (urban approach) Organize a workshop to share the results of impact and cost-benefit research from disaster risk reduction actions Document and promote the results of the project, share the knowledge acquired on urban disaster risk reduction carried out in the province of Kinshasa with humanitarian actors and risk reduction practitioners through case studies after two years of documentation Organize knowledge exchange sessions between provinces, Red Cross Movement.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="12206" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
