<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998d" dstore:index="2174" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-06T13:45:33" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-06T13:45:34" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14401A0101-GGG-72050</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR - Humanitarian Appeals</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNHCR - Humanit&#xE4;ra appeller</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution concerns an agreement with UN High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) for activities in line with UNHCR&#x2019;s Global Appeal, based on a new full appraisal of UNHCR.

The implementation period is only one year, since the Global Appeal only covers activities for 2021. Funding beyond 2021 would need project plans and budgets covering a longer period.

With its mandate to protect refugees, internally displaced persons, stateless and returnees, including possible resettlement solutions, UNHCR is a key partner within protection. UNHCR has an operational duty to protect people of concern (legal assistance, civil documentation, asylum etc.) and a normative duty as the &#x201C;guardian&#x201D; of the 1951 Refugee Convention. UNHCR is the main actor in all refugee crises, with an overarching coordination responsibility for the humanitarian interventions carried out by the UN and civil society organisations, not the least within the Global Protection Cluster. The organisation also cooperates with national and local authorities.

Through the financial support to UNHCR 2021, Sida will contribute to the humanitarian response directed to refugees and internally displaced persons to contribute to protection and basic needs (food, water, sanitation, health care etc.), education, shelter etc. Sida also contributes to strategic coordination within the humanitarian system through UNHCR.

Sida&apos;s financial support to UNHCR 2021 amounts to a total of 270 MSEK. Sida&apos;s decision complements the Swedish Government&apos;s core support to the organisation. Sida&apos;s support is directed to selected operations and situations included in UNHCR&apos;s Global Appeal, including regional refugee response plans. Within the earmarking at country or crisis level, Sida&apos;s support is unearmarked.

During 2021, the financial support will be directed to the following countries/crises: Bangladesh, Cameroon, Chad, Kenya, Democratic Republic of Congo, Ethiopia, Iraq, Mali, Mozambique, Somalia, Sudan, South Sudan,  the Syria crisis, Uganda, Ukraine and the Venezuela crisis.
The decision also includes an unallocated support, which UNHCR can use for new or deteriorating crises during 2021 after approval by Sida.

The grant will be disbursed in the beginning of the year to allow UNHCR to plan and implement humanitarian activities (assistance and protection) without delay and with good planning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Detta beslut avser &#x201D;Beslut om insats&#x201D; (Insatshanteringsregeln 2.9 &#xA7;) mellan Sida och UNHCR f&#xF6;r att m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra finansiellt humanit&#xE4;rt st&#xF6;d i utvalda kriser 2021 i linje med UNHCR:s humanit&#xE4;ra appeller. Som underlag till detta beslut ligger en ny grundberedning av UNHCR.

Implementeringsperioden &#xE4;r endast ett &#xE5;r, eftersom budgeten och aktiviteterna i den globala appelen endast t&#xE4;cker 2021. Finansiering f&#xF6;r efterf&#xF6;ljande &#xE5;r kr&#xE4;ver planer och budgetar f&#xF6;r en l&#xE4;ngre period. 

Med sitt mandat att skydda flyktingar, tv&#xE5;ngsf&#xF6;rdrivna och statsl&#xF6;sa, se till deras m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE5;terv&#xE4;nda, vidarebos&#xE4;ttas eller integreras i sina v&#xE4;rdsamh&#xE4;llen, &#xE4;r UNHCR en central partner inom skyddsomr&#xE5;det. Ut&#xF6;ver sin operativa roll i skyddet av flyktingar (juridisk hj&#xE4;lp, utf&#xE4;rda identitetshandlingar, asylr&#xE4;tt, etc) har UNHCR en normativ roll i &#xF6;vervakning och tolkning av flyktingkonventionen. Inom det humanit&#xE4;ra systemet &#xE4;r UNHCR huvudakt&#xF6;ren i alla flyktingkriser, med &#xF6;vergripande samordningsansvar av FN:s och civilsamh&#xE4;llsorganisationers humanit&#xE4;ra arbete, inte minst inom skyddsomr&#xE5;det. Organisationen samarbetar &#xE4;ven med nationella och lokala myndigheter. 

Genom st&#xF6;det till UNHCR 2021 bidrar Sida till att bist&#xE5; flyktingar och internflyktingar s&#xE5; att dessa bland annat bidrar till skydd mot f&#xF6;rf&#xF6;ljelse och v&#xE5;ld, tak &#xF6;ver huvudet, basf&#xF6;rn&#xF6;denheter (mat, vatten, hygien, prim&#xE4;rsjukv&#xE5;rd, etc.), utbildning med mera. St&#xF6;det bidrar &#xE4;ven till strategisk samordning inom det humanit&#xE4;ra systemet genom UNHCR.

Sidas finansiella bidrag till UNHCR 2021 omfattar totalt 270 000 000 kronor. Sida beslutar om detta st&#xF6;d som komplement till regeringens &#xE5;rliga k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d. Sidas st&#xF6;d g&#xE5;r till utvalda kriser som omfattas av UNHCR:s globala appell, inklusive regionala flyktingappeller och responsplaner. Sida &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rker genom avtal bidraget till UNHCR p&#xE5; land- eller regionniv&#xE5; men st&#xF6;det &#xE4;r o&#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt inom denna niv&#xE5;. 

Under 2021 g&#xE5;r st&#xF6;det till insatser i f&#xF6;ljande l&#xE4;nder/kriser: Bangladesh, Kamerun, Kenya, Demokratiska Republiken Kongo, Etiopien, Irak, Mali, Mo&#xE7;ambique, Somalia, Sudan, Sydsudan, Syrien-krisen, Tchad, Uganda, Ukraina samt Venezuela-krisen.

I beslutet ing&#xE5;r ocks&#xE5; ett oallokerat st&#xF6;d om 25 000 000 kronor som UNHCR kan anv&#xE4;nda till nya eller f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;rrade kriser under &#xE5;ret efter godk&#xE4;nnande av Sida. 

St&#xF6;det utbetalas i b&#xF6;rjan av &#xE5;ret f&#xF6;r att UNHCR ska ha f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar att planera och genomf&#xF6;ra humanit&#xE4;ra insatser utan f&#xF6;rdr&#xF6;jning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution is aimed at supporting the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in selected situations where the organisation has a clear added value to provide humanitarian assistance and protection to people of concern.
In 2021, Sida will support UNHCR&apos;s work in 17 operations and&#xA0;situations. The specific objective of each intervention might differ, but the core objective is to provide assistance and protection to refugees, returnees, internally displaced and stateless. This will be done through protection-specific interventions, cash based interventions, in-kind assistance and through other services (see details below).
UNHCR&#x2019;s core task is to ensure that the 1951 Convention is honoured, by providing protection and pursuing solutions for refugees and the internally displaced, and working to prevent and reduce statelessness. In the Global Appeal for 2021, UNHCR estimated the total population of concern to UNHCR to stand at approximately 97.3 million people.
The high-level results indicated in the Global Appeal are to:
- safeguard fundamental rights - including registration of refugees, child protection, initatives against statelessness and community based protection activities including COVID-19 response.
- respond with life-saving support - including health services, cash assistance, shelter and WASH services.
- build better futures - including education services, livelihoods and economic inclusion, resettlement and access to energy and environmental protection.&#xA0;
UNHCR&#x2019;s strategic directions set out five core directions:
1. Ensuring protection;
2. Effectively responding to emergencies;
3. Promoting inclusion and self-reliance, including through the engagement of development actors;
4. Empowering persons of concern to UNHCR; and
5. Pursuing solutions.
Adding to this strategic direction, UNHCR has decided on a set of Global Strategic Priorities (GSPs). The GSPs steer planning in UNHCR&#x2019;s operations worldwide and were designed as part of UNHCR&apos;s results-based management and reporting on aggregated global results. They also reflect the vision behind the strategic directions and are aligned with UNHCR&#x2019;s commitments made under the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development and the sustainable development goals and the Global Compact for Refugees.
UNHCR&apos;s Global Strategic Priorities&#xA0;identify priority areas when determining the work required to ensuring international protection and assistance standards are upheld. There are also strategic priorities which highlight key areas for strengthening management functions and support for operations worldwide, across divisions and bureaux. The Global Strategic Priorities for the operations are:
1.&#xA0;Safeguarding access to territorial protection and asylum procedures; protection against refoulement; and supporting the adoption of nationality laws that prevent and/or reduce statelessness.
2.&#xA0;Securing birth registration, profiling and individual documentation based on registration.
3.&#xA0;Reducing protection risks faced by people of concern, in particular, discrimination, SGBV and specific risks faced by children.
4.&#xA0;Reducing mortality, morbidity and malnutrition through multi-sectoral interventions.
5.&#xA0;Meeting international standards in relation to shelter, domestic energy, water, sanitation and hygiene.
6.&#xA0;Promoting active participation in decision-making of people of concern and building coexistence with hosting communities.
7.&#xA0;Promoting human potential through increased opportunities for quality education and livelihoods support.
8.&#xA0;Expanding opportunities for durable solutions for people of concern, particularly those in protracted situations, including by strengthening the use of comprehensive approaches and contributing to sustainable reintegration, local settlement and successful resettlement in third countries.
During 2021, UNHCR will continue to develop a new system for results based management (RBM). The new framework will guide the organisation&apos;s work from 2022 onwards. The core mandate does however remain the same.
The UNHCR&apos;s Global Results Framework, which will be used from 2022, has four overarching Impact Areas:
1. Attaining Favorable Protection Environments
2. Realizing Basic Rights in Safe Environments
3. Empowering Communities and Achieving Gender Equality
4. Securing Solutions
These are complemented by 16 Outcome Areas.

This forms the foundation for planning globally and at operational level. Each impact area and outcome area will have indicators connected to them and defined target groups. There will be a set of strategic core indicators, which are aligned with the Sustainable Development Goals and Global Compact for Refugees. There are also four outcome areas for support functions.
According to the Programme Manual, UNHCR should select the modality of implementation that provides the best value for money. Operations are also encouraged to work with partners whenever feasible. Moreover, wherever possible programmes should be implemented through competent national partners who have local knowledge and access. Working with national partners and the civil society also helps to promote sustainability and the development of local capacity.
&#xA0;
Objectives at operational levelUNHCR has planned for a few global initiatives.&#xA0;
The COVID-19 response is one of the global initiatives.&#xA0;UNHCR anticipates that considerable and sustained investment will be needed in 2021 to respond to the effects of the global pandemic on people of concern. Requirements in terms of needs and priorities for 2021 - particularly in relation to the pandemic&#x2019;s lasting socioeconomic and protection impacts, including loss of livelihoods and challenges with education - will be detailed&#xA0;in a forthcoming supplementary appeal but are likely to be focused on health care, protection, cash asssistance, livelihoods and education.
Other global initiatives are the strengthened focus on people living in internal displacement, the strengthened focus on climate action, follow up of the Global Compact on Refugees, enhanced work to strengthen partnerships&#xA0;(including a NGO partnership reform process for simplified agreement structures, engagement with development actors and private sector), Risk Management and strengthened fight against sexual exploitation, abuse and harassment,&#xA0;SEAH.
Each operation has its own contextual challenges. With a view to the overall objectives of the organisation, UNHCR makes informed decisions on what to focus on in every given situation/operation.&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Operations/Situations chosen for support
For 2021, the following situations below have been chosen by Sida to fund. For each of them, a short description is given for focus areas and intended results:
Cameroon (proposed support: 15 MSEK)Cameroon hosts some 1.96 million people of concern to UNHCR, including some 430,000 Nigerian refugees. The country also has over 1 million IDPs, concentrated in the North-West and South-West and the Far North regions where conflict and instability are likely to persist in 2021, as well as 484,036 IDPs returnees. Gabon, also covered by UNHCR&#x2019;s operation in Cameroon, hosts 484 refugees and 84 asylum-seekers.
Key priorities for UNHCR will in 2021 be: Coordination work with other partners; Strengthening UNHCR:s emergency response capacity&#xA0;by reinforcing its leadership role in the protection, shelter and camp coordination and camp management clusters; Supporting local and national authorities to prepare for, prevent and mitigate displacement risks; Seeking durable solutions in Cameroon and in countries of origin, while enhancing resettlement and complementary pathway for refugees, and facilitate the repatriation of 10,000 refugees; Supporting the national and local authorities in the socioeconomic inclusion of refugees and other displaced populations while broadening and strengthening its partnership with key humanitarian and development actors.
In Cameroon, private sector engagement will remain a priority to expand opportunities for refugees and other people of concerns and mitigate the socio-economic impact of the COVID-19 pandemic. Concurrently, UNHCR will work with partners to implement a targeted approach to ensure that that most vulnerable refugee households continue receiving assistance to meet their basic needs.
Chad&#xA0;(proposed support: 8 MSEK)Chad is situated at the confluence of simultaneous and overlapping conflicts in the Sahel, the Lake Chad Basin, Western Darfur and the Central African Republic. This regional instability and insecurity directly affect Chad&#x2019;s operational environment and was exacerbated in 2020 by the COVID-19 pandemic, which severely affected the most vulnerable populations including refugees and IDPs.
UNHCR works closely with the Government to ensure protection and seek solutions for over 470,000 refugees from Sudan, the Central African Republic and Nigeria, as well as 330,000 IDPs, mostly around the Lake Chad region.
Key priorities for UNHCR in Chad will in 2021 be: Strengthening of the security framework; Advocating the adoption of a national law on asylum and consolidating refugee status determination procedures; Strengthening cooperation with development actors for ongoing projects; Restart resettlement activities suspended due to COVID-19 measures; Fast-tracking departure procedures for refugees under consideration; Advocating increased quotas of refugees benefiting from third-country resettlement programmes; Seek additional opportunities for education and health integration as well as livelihoods, with a focus on securing access to land and socioeconomic opportunities, and; Strengthen collaboration with the National Assembly and the Government for the adoption and promulgation of the law on asylum.
Democratic Republic of Congo&#xA0;(proposed support: 40 MSEK)Since December 2019, an increase in violence in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo saw the number of IDPs rise to almost 6 million by the end of October 2020. In the provinces of Ituri, North Kivu and South Kivu, over 1 million people have been displaced in 2020 alone. UNHCR declared an L3 emergency for these provinces in November 2019 that led to the activation of emergency procedures and helped expedite access to additional human, material and financial resources. Fresh violence also erupted in the Kasai region in 2020, causing new displacement. The country has one of the largest IDP situations globally, and the largest in sub-Saharan Africa.
In 2021, UNHCR will strengthen its rapid response to recurrent emergencies, ensure the centrality of protection in all IDP interventions, reinforce advocacy based on its protection monitoring system, consolidate community-based protection approaches, implement solution strategies for IDPs in sites and local communities, ensure targeted assistance to persons at heightened risk, promote peaceful coexistence within affected communities and strengthen community mobilization.
Over 1 million Congolese hosted across 20 African countries make up the largest population of refugees and asylum-seekers in the region. In 2021, UNHCR will continue to lead the coordination of the inter-agency Regional Refugee Response Plan for the Democratic Republic of the Congo situation. UNHCR, in close coordination with more than 60 partners, will provide protection and assistance to Congolese refugees and asylum-seekers, bolster livelihood opportunities and &#x2014; in line with the Global Compact on Refugees &#x2014; support the needs of host populations and strengthen peaceful coexistence.
The health and well-being of refugees and IDPs is a priority, and UNHCR has adjusted its operations in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and in refugee-hosting countries to prevent and respond to COVID-19. These measures will be further strengthened in 2021.
Ethiopia&#xA0;(proposed support: 9 MSEK)Displacement triggered by both climate and political/security reasons will continue to pose serious challenges for IDPs, refugees and host communities in Ethiopia, with an increase in internal displacements anticipated in 2021 triggered by civil unrest, elections or other crisis. Locations in Oromia and Tigray regions remain insecure, with access to services limited. Protection concerns include threats to physical safety, family separation, gender-based violence and violations against children.
UNHCR aims to target close to 900,000 refugees and 2.3 million IDPs in its response in areas like protection (e.g. birth registration, psycho-social support, GBV case management), health, WASH, shelter, pre-positioning and provision of core relief items and emergency shelter and education.
UNHCR will continue to secure durable solutions for people of concern through ensuring the issuance of documentation, increase refugee self-reliance through the promotion of livelihoods, enhance freedom of movement and the right to work, and advocate for the gradual inclusion of refugees in national services.
Iraq&#xA0;(proposed support: 12 MSEK)Inside Iraq, some 1.3 million Iraqis remain internally displaced and more than 4.7 million IDP returnees risk facing protection risks, such as the dangers from explosive remnants of war, constrained access to basic services and insecurity, while contending with limited access to livelihood opportunities and shelter. IDPs are likely to continue to face secondary or multiple displacement where return to areas of origin is not possible or sustainable.UNHCR will focus its activities on 1) identifying and implementing durable solutions for IDPs, including by strengthening access to national services and formal employment opportunities. These projects will support social cohesion, help remove obstacles to return and explore other solutions for IDPs such as local integration in areas of displacement; 2) Providing legal assistance to IDP and returnee populations in the form of legal counselling, representation and awareness-raising, particularly for civil documentation and detention; 3) Providing cash assistance to IDP and returnee families identified as vulnerable and in need, as well as to vulnerable refugees and asylum seekers. This is also a parat of&#xA0;mitigating the medium- and long-term socioeconomic impact of COVID-19; 4) Strengthening refugee registration and case management capacity, with UNHCR assuming direct responsibility for refugee registration country-wide to ensure all refugees and asylum-seekers are effectively documented. A key priority is also to mainstream gender-based violence prevention and risk mitigation, and working to prevent sexual exploitation and abuse&#xA0; through capacity development, awareness-raising, and co-leadership of the Iraq Network to Protect from Sexual Exploitation and Abuse.
Mozambique&#xA0;(proposed support: 7 MSEK)UNHCR has declared an L2 emergency for the IDP situation in northern Mozambique and will continue to co-lead the protection cluster response in Cabo Delgado and Maputo in 2021. UNHCR will work closely with partners to identify and map protection needs, as well as to provide appropriate protection support and services, including in response to genderbased violence. UNHCR will also distribute core relief items to some 45,000 extremely vulnerable individuals.
Sudan&#xA0;(proposed support: 20 MSEK)The humanitarian, political and security situation in Sudan continues to remain fluid.&#xA0;By the end of 2021, Sudan is expected to host more than 1 million refugees, of which more than 70 % will be of South Sudanese origin. A further 20,000 refugee returnees to Darfur are anticipated throughout 2021. An additional 2,5 million IDPs are also anticipated (as per the 2021 Sudan Humanitarian Needs Overview).
Crippling economic instability persisted for much of 2020 and will likely continue into 2021.
UNHCR&#x2019;s main operational priorities in Sudan in 2021 include 1) Refugee and IDP protection, with a focus on refugee registration, documentation, protection monitoring and interventions, child protection and prevention and response to gender-based violence, community-based protection and scaling up cash assistance; 2) Reintegration of Sudanese refugees and IDPs, including peacebuilding and community support projects, as well as durable solutions for refugees in Sudan; 3) Emergency preparedness for refugee influxes, IDP displacement and sudden-onset emergencies through enhanced protection capacity, pre-positioning, and management of the Common Non-food item Pipeline.
Furthermore, UNHCR will implement protection and solutions strategies developed in 2020, as adapted to local conditions and the impact of COVID-19.
Ukraine&#xA0;(proposed support: 2 MSEK)Over 2.4 million internally displaced and conflict-affected people will face protection challenges in Ukraine in 2021, with many needing to regularly cross the contact line for family reasons, or to access services such as pensions. However, the COVID-19 pandemic has restricted such movements, limited access by humanitarian convoys, and increased pressure on health infrastructure in non-government-controlled areas.
UNHCR will continue protection and shelter in support of IDPs and conflict-affected individuals, with a focus on those residing in non-government-controlled areas and around the contact line, along with efforts to prevent statelessness and support fair and efficient asylum procedures. UNHCR will work with local authorities and strengthen partnerships with development actors, while providing assistance to vulnerable families and individuals with heightened protection risks.
Myanmar situation (Bangladesh)&#xA0;(proposed support: 19 MSEK)UNHCR will work with the Government of Bangladesh and partners in Cox&#x2019;s Bazar to meet the needs of some 860,000 Rohingya refugees. UNHCR assesses that there is a risk that, in&#xA0;the fourth year of the crisis, the protection environment in Cox&#x2019;s Bazar will grow increasingly complex with deteriorating security conditions. There are increased security enforcement measures in the camps, as well as ongoing restrictions imposed in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, which limit key activities such as education. This may lead to further increases in negative coping mechanisms in refugee communities, including dangerous onward movements, intimate partner violence, and child marriage, among others.
The Operation&#x2019;s focus remains on building a favourable protection environment for the more than 860,000 refugees in the settlements, advancing protection and gender mainstreaming, access to justice, and improving refugees&#x2019; quality of life through the empowerment of the community and the strengthening of community-based structures already in place.&#xA0;Priorities include expanding access to education and skills development opportunities; prevention of and response to gender-based violence, legal aid and mental health support; and maintaining a critical health and nutrition response.&#xA0;
The Sahel Situation (Mali)&#xA0;(proposed support: 7 MSEK)As the security situation is likely to further deteriorate in the Sahel region, it is expected that up to an additional 2 million people may be displaced in the Sahel in 2021. The population of IDPs in Mali is close to 300,000, and 84,000 refugees have returned to Mali due to the deteriorating security situations in neighbouring countries.&#xA0; &#xA0;&#xA0;
The key priorities for UNHCR will in 2021 be to: Strengthen the capacity of Government and other partners to respond to the needs of refugees and asylum-seekers; Advocate for, and sensitize, people of concern engaging in irregular movements and those at risk of statelessness, and; Identify and secure durable solutions, particularly for those in situation of protracted displacement. For returnees, UNHCR will focus on: Enabling Malian refugees to make an informed decision on return; Facilitate the reception of 35,000 people who express a desire to return, and; ensure durable socioeconomic reintegration.&#xA0;In response to IDPs, UNHCR will promote the Kampala Convention&#x2019;s provisions on the protection and assistance to IDPs. The Office will also strengthen its emergency responses, as well as synergies between the Protection Cluster&#x2019;s actors and the Government&apos;s technical sectors. In parallel, UNHCR will promote the centrality of protection and monitor the integration of protection mainstreaming principles into all humanitarian action.
UNHCR in Mali will also focus on: Advocating for legislation in compliance with international protection standards for refugees, IDPs, and stateless persons, and strengthening institutions for protection; Ensuring safe and dignified returns of Malian refugees; Ensuring that IDPs and returnees are sustainably (re)integrated, with the basic needs of the most vulnerable met, and; Strengthening refugee self-reliance and ensuring access to national services, while working to meet the basic needs of the most vulnerable and ensuring that comprehensive solutions are achieved for 40% of those in a protracted displacement situation.
The Somalia Situation (Somalia and Kenya)&#xA0;The Somalia situation is one of the world&#x2019;s longest-running displacement crises. Despite political developments, the overall security situation in Somalia&#xA0; (proposed support: 5 MSEK)remains unpredictable, with continued high levels of displacement within and outside the country. In addition to the COVID-19 pandemic and its related socioeconomic impact, severe drought and floods will likely continue to displace thousands of families and reduce their access to regular humanitarian assistance.
In 2021 UNHCR will focus on:&#xA0;Improving reception conditions and refugee status determination;&#xA0;Establishing functional protection referral mechanisms;&#xA0;Strengthening accountability and response capacity to recurring and newly-arising emergencies;&#xA0;Strengthening UNHCR&#x2019;s response capacity to IDP situations;&#xA0;Supporting the Government in developing legal frameworks for all population planning groups;&#xA0;Strengthening sustainable returns;&#xA0;Advocating to increase resettlement quotas;&#xA0;Supporting access to livelihoods and education;&#xA0;Supporting the most vulnerable households with assistance to mitigate the effects of COVID-19.
In&#xA0;Kenya&#xA0;(proposed support: 5 MSEK)&#xA0;UNHCR will work with the Government and other stakeholders to ensure access to basic services in addition to the COVID-19 pandemic response, including health, water, sanitation and hygiene services, shelter and education. Protection services such as prevention and response to gender-based violence, support to children, and services for persons with specific protection concerns. UNHCR will also continue to work with the Government on the reduction of statelessness.
The main objectives that UNHCR in Kenya will focus on include: Engaging with the Government to support the inclusion of refugees into national service delivery mechanisms, with a focus on education, health and social protection systems; Strengthening the asylum space and ensuring the principle of non-refoulement is respected; working with the Government on the 2019 Refugee Bill as well as policies to end statelessness; facilitating registration of new arrivals by the Government; Ensuring data integration into the National Integrated identity Management System; Ensuring enrolment and retention of school-aged children in early childhood education, as well as in primary and secondary school levels, and providing them with educational services in line with the national curriculum; Providing refugees and asylum-seekers with access to primary health care through direct service provision, as well as enrolment into the National Health Insurance Scheme; Supporting returns to Somalia and facilitating repatriations.
The South Sudan Situation (regional, South Sudan and Uganda)&#xA0;(proposed regional support: 15 MSEK)As the South Sudanese refugee response entered its seventh year, there were some advances in the peace process, but continued outbreaks of violence may lead to new refugee outflows into neighbouring countries in 2021. The Democratic Republic of the Congo, Ethiopia, Kenya, Sudan and Uganda continued to host over 2.2 million South Sudanese &#x2014; the largest refugee population on the continent &#x2014; and there were a further 1.6 million IDPs. The COVID-19 pandemic has posed significant challenges for South Sudanese refugees due to the high population density in refugee camps and inadequate sanitary facilities. Only 43% of refugee households have a latrine for instance. Although UNHCR is neither promoting nor facilitating returns, the Office anticipates an increase in spontaneous IDP and refugee returns in 2021.
UNHCR plans to continue protection profiling and analysis to support protection-centred returns, peacebuilding, reconciliation and social cohesion. The South Sudan Regional Refugee Response Plan has been updated to reflect COVID-19 prevention and response measures. It brings together 95 partners working across five countries and aims to meet the assistance and resilience needs of South Sudanese refugees in the region.
As part of UNHCR&#x2019;s IDP Initiative, the Office will continue to strengthen its support to the IDP response as a partner in the inter-agency humanitarian response plan.
In South Sudan&#xA0;(proposed support: 10 MSEK), specifically, UNHCR will respond to humanitarian needs in refugee camps and host communities through coordination and delivery of protection services, shelter assistance, core relief items, camp management, health care, education, and livelihoods. &#xA0;
In Uganda&#xA0;(proposed support: 10 MSEK), specifically, the refugee population is estimated to reach 1.5 million by the end of 2021.&#xA0;Due to insufficient funding, food rations for refugees, have been reduced by 30% since April 2020 and are likely to be cut further in 2021. In the context of the COVID-19 pandemic, additional food ration reductions are likely to further affect the well-being of refugees in Uganda, as well as their protection status and access to livelihoods. The incidence of high-risk coping mechanisms reported in 2020 are likely to remain high in 2021, including child marriage and pregnancy, transactional sex and theft. Incidents of gender-based violence and suicides will also likely remain high in 2021.
UNHCR will give priority to education, in line with the Education response plan for refugees and host communities, and self-reliance and livelihoods activities, including through creating&#xA0;linkages with development projects, the private sector, districts and sub-counties to focus direct support to individuals and refugee groups.
The Syria Situation (regional)&#xA0;(proposed support: 45 MSEK)With more than 6 million IDPs and 5.6 million registered Syrian refugees in neighbouring countries as of 2020, the Syria situation will remain the largest displacement crisis in the world. An acute economic crisis, exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic, will also continue to impact the humanitarian situation.&#xA0;
UNHCR will continue to co-lead the protection, shelter and non-food item sectors. In addition, UNHCR will maintain a sizable stock of emergency/ transitional shelters and core relief items in Syria, including assistance provided in the inter-agency COVID-19 response. Moreover, UNHCR will work to ensure the viability of returns, and develop a sequenced return assistance package to support people&#x2019;s access to basic services at the early stage of their return and build up community resilience, with a vision of handing over the communities to development partners for long-term interventions.
Most vulnerable refugees will continue to have access to existing services and assistance, including cash, and providing education and winterization assistance. A strategic use of refugee status determination and resettlement will go hand-in-hand with a review of registration procedures. The roll-out of proGres v4, UNHCR&#x2019;s registration and case management system and postponed twice in 2020, remains a priority for 2021. UNHCR will also co-lead the Durable Solutions, People Resilience and Effective Institutions pillars. UNHCR will engage with multiple partners and stakeholders to maximize the impact of its interventions and to pave the way for engagement in these communities by longer-term development partners.
The Venezuela Situation (regional)&#xA0;(proposed support: 16 MSEK)As of November 2020, some 4.6 million refugees and migrants from Venezuela are outside their country of origin in Latin America, including an estimated 1 million with an irregular status.&#xA0;In Venezuela, humanitarian needs exacerbated by the pandemic will trigger further displacement.
UNHCR activities in border areas &#x2014; including monitoring, identification and referral of the most vulnerable, and basic assistance and counselling &#x2014; will acquire greater urgency. UNHCR will step up assistance to returnees and local communities in need, while strengthening protection and shelter/energy/non-food items cluster leadership and delivery. UNHCR will co-lead the inter-agency response together with IOM, implementing the Regional Refugee and Migrant Response Plan across 17 countries, and will provide technical support to governmental coordination in the Quito Process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR/United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41121" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief co-ordination and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.5 - By 2030, build the resilience of the poor and those in vulnerable situations and reduce their exposure and vulnerability to climate-related extreme events and other economic, social and environmental shocks and disasters.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.5 - Till 2030 bygga upp motst&#xE5;ndskraften hos de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer och minska deras utsatthet och s&#xE5;rbarhet f&#xF6;r extrema klimatrelaterade h&#xE4;ndelser och andra ekonomiska, sociala och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssiga chocker och katastrofer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.7 - Facilitate orderly, safe, regular and responsible migration and mobility of people, including through the implementation of planned and well-managed migration policies.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.7 - Underl&#xE4;tta en ordnad, s&#xE4;ker, reglerad och ansvarsfull migration och r&#xF6;rlighet av personer, inklusive genom planerad och v&#xE4;l fungerande migrationspolitik.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.5 - By 2030, significantly reduce the number of deaths and the number of people affected and substantially decrease the direct economic losses relative to global gross domestic product caused by disasters, including water-related disasters, with a focus on protecting the poor and people in vulnerable situations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.5 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligt minska antalet d&#xF6;dsfall och antalet m&#xE4;nniskor som drabbas av katastrofer, inklusive vattenrelaterade katastrofer. &#xC4;ven tillse att de direkta ekonomiska f&#xF6;rlusterna till f&#xF6;ljd av s&#xE5;dana katastrofer, i form av l&#xE4;gre global BNP, minskar v&#xE4;sentligt. S&#xE4;rskilt fokus b&#xF6;r ligga p&#xE5; att skydda de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.2 - End abuse, exploitation, trafficking and all forms of violence against and torture of children.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.2 - Eliminera &#xF6;vergrepp, utnyttjande, m&#xE4;nniskohandel och alla former av v&#xE5;ld eller tortyr mot barn.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.9 - By 2030, provide legal identity for all, including birth registration.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.9 - Senast 2030 tillhandah&#xE5;lla juridisk identitet f&#xF6;r alla, inklusive f&#xF6;delseregistrering.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2.1 - Senast 2030 avskaffa hunger och garantera alla m&#xE4;nniskor, i synnerhet de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer, inklusive sm&#xE5; barn, tillg&#xE5;ng till tillr&#xE4;ckligt med s&#xE4;ker och n&#xE4;ringsrik mat &#xE5;ret om.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 - By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.D" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.d - Strengthen the capacity of all countries, in particular developing countries, for early warning, risk reduction and management of national and global health risks.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.d - St&#xE4;rka alla l&#xE4;nders, i synnerhet utvecklingsl&#xE4;ndernas, kapacitet n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller tidig varning, riskreducering och hantering av nationella och globala h&#xE4;lsorisker.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.1 - By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla flickor och pojkar fullbordar avgiftsfri och likv&#xE4;rdig grundskole- och gymnasieutbildning av god kvalitet som leder till relevanta och &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenliga kunskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.2 - By 2030, achieve access to adequate and equitable sanitation and hygiene for all and end open defecation, paying special attention to the needs of women and girls and those in vulnerable situations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.2 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till fullgod och r&#xE4;ttvis sanitet och hygien och att ingen beh&#xF6;ver utr&#xE4;tta sina behov utomhus. S&#xE4;rskild uppm&#xE4;rksamhet b&#xF6;r &#xE4;gnas &#xE5;t behoven hos kvinnor och flickor samt m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">29316915.860451482</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">29316915.860451482</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">29316915.860451482</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-06">29316915.860451482</value>
  </transaction>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="14401" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1010104" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01" strategy-total-amount="0.0">
    <title>Humanitarian aid 2021-2025</title>
    <titleSV>Humanit&#xE4;rt bist&#xE5;nd 2021-2025</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
