<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998e" dstore:index="2490" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105030101-GGG-14030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unicef WASH 2018-2021.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Unicef WASH 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF WASH 2018-2021. A global thematic non-earmarked support for UNICEF work on water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH) in line with their strategic plan 2018-2021. The programme has a strong focus on gender equality. The intervention is a thematic support; a financing modality promoted by the Swedish strategy &quot;Strategi f&#xF6;r multilateral utvecklingspolitik&quot; that gives larger room for efficiency and flexibility for the recipient organisation through internal budget allocations, and thereby providing improved conditions for risk management and results based management during implementation. The modality requires Sida to base the assessment mainly on the organisation&apos;s internal systems instead of predetermined details on execution.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNICEF WASH 2018-2021. Insatsen avser ett globalt flexibelt icke-&#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt tematiskt st&#xF6;d till UNICEF&#xB4;s arbete inom vatten, sanitet och hygien (WASH) i enlighet med den strategiska planen 2018-2021. Insatsen har ett starkt j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsfokus.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2019-2020 annual thematic results report by UNICEF for Goal Area 4 - &quot;Every Child Lives in a Safe Clean Environment&quot; presents results and progress within the global WASH programs.&#xA0;&#xA0; 2019 Narrative Annual Results Report The report was delivered on time according to the agreement conditions, nevertheless, this year the date of the annual meetings was scheduled one month later as usual. This was possibly due to the C-19 crisis and the fact that there have been some previous request to have the meetings at a later time than usual so as to allow more time to read the report prior to the meetings. Sida has in the past requested UNICEF to take this aspect into consideration, hence this year it was appreciated that there was reasonable sufficient time for reading the reports.&#xA0; The reports are complete in terms of fulfilling conditions in the agreements and at the annual meetings held virtually during the last week of June and first week of July. Although the video connections worked well, it is indeed important to note the relevance and need to meet face to face in order to go deeper into discussions with time for reflection and deeper and strategic dialogue.&#xA0; A detail description of the report follows, and although Sida had a number of questions we did not have any outstanding comments.&#xA0; Minutes from the annaul meetings have been received and these are found in Dox. Highlights of the report:&#xA0;&#xA0; This years report is of high quality and contains important results, analysis, and information that follows specific request that Sida has made to UNICEF at the annual meetings held in the previous two years, and which were outlined in the minutes from meetings held in June 2019. Some of the extended and improved areas in the reporting include among other specific reporting on climate resilience, urban WASH, conflic and emergencies, as well as on some financing initiatives. A particular area of reporting also included aspects of the Covid-19 initiatives where this program has had signficant engagements.&#xA0; This year in parallel to the results report, the Mid-Term Review response strategy was presented, and has been commended as it is something that has certaintly served as a way to inspire significant thought and analysis in the results, actions, and way ahead described in the annual report.&#xA0; Something worth mentioning is also the fact that due to the MidTerm Review, UNICEF has adjusted some of the 4 year targets (such as in the WASH in schools programs) and this we find important and appreciate the transparency in order to address the gaps that might have been detected. Hence, this ambitious programming is something that Sida will need to continue to follow carefully in the coming years as&#xA0;the relevance of the work within Goal Area 4 and particurlarly with WASH programming is of the highest importance and relevance, as global needs are of unprecedented meassure due to the C-19 Pandemic. The spread not only of this virus but of other waterborn and sanitation related diseases around the world will need to be closely monitored, as well as the needs of poor children and marginalized groups of people around the world.&#xA0; Furthermore, the need to support national sustainable systems for access to WASH are more relevant than ever and an area that ought to be considered of outmost importance within all Sida programs.&#xA0; The work by the WHO&#x2013;UNICEF Joint Monitoring Program (JMP) continues to be of high relevance, and in 2019 they released a progress update report on the status of water, sanitation and&#xA0;hygiene in households and progress on the SDG WASH targets from 2000 to 2017.&#xA0; The following are some highlights of important data on progress and figures included in the report: - The number of people lacking basic water services fell by 315 million to 785 million worldwide, and the number of people practising open defecation was halved from 1.3 billion to 673 million. &#xA0; - At the end of 2017 (the latest available data year), 90 per cent of the world&#x2019;s population had access to at least a basic drinking-water supply, 74 per cent to basic sanitation services, and 60 per cent to basic hygiene facilities.&#xA0;&#xA0;Nevertheless, these gains are uneven and under threat. - An unprecedented number of people are living in situations of crisis and conflict caused, in part, by the widening impacts of climate change on food production, economies and society. The UNICEF Water Under Fire analysis shows that people in extremely fragile countries are eight times less likely to have basic water services than average, and four times less likely to have basic sanitation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Childrens Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Childrens&apos; Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">28767375.494798858</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">28767375.494798858</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-3.7e-9</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3.7e-9</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">28767375.494798858</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">28767375.494798858</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Below are some highlights of relevant efforts, key results, as well as challenges presensted in the annual results report:&#xA0; -Direct UNICEF support provided 5,032 schools with separate sanitation facilities for girls and boys in 2019, about the same as in 2018, but below Strategic Plan targets. This shortfall is mainly due to resource constraints, and in some cases, to a shift in UNICEF programming modalities from direct support in schools to systems&#xA0; support for upscaling results through domestic resources. -Targets for WASH in health-care facilities were exceeded, with 3,341 facilities in 52 countries receiving new water, sanitation and hygiene services. -A publication of the new global SDG baseline data on WASH in health-care facilities by the World Health Organization (WHO)&#x2013;UNICEF Joint Monitoring Programme for Water, Sanitation and Hygiene, by the&#xA0;(JMP) highlighted the challenges ahead, and has become an important new tool in support of the Secretary-General&#x2019;s call for action in this area.&#xA0; -UNICEF support for menstrual health and hygiene (MHH) continued to expand in 2019, including direct support to 20,495 schools in 49 countries with MHH services, exceeding targets. -The UNICEF publication Guidance on Menstrual Health and&#xA0;Hygiene (developed in 2018) was launched in 2019. This is&#xA0;aimed at strengthening the quality of MHH programming as efforts are scaled up to support the achievement of&#xA0;organizational targets on WASH, gender and adolescent. -In 2019, a companion document, the Guide to Menstrual Hygiene Materials, was released, on the selection and procurement of appropriate materials and supplies for menstrual hygiene management, particularly during humanitarian responses. It draws on the extensive MHH procurement experience of the UNICEF Supply Division, along with best practices from the field. -As national programmes accelerate efforts to eliminate open defecation, the need&#xA0;to ensure the sustainability of the achievements is being&#xA0;increasingly prioritized by the UNICEF programs in various countries and regions. In this regard, more efforts to strengthen the enabling environment for WASH&#xA0;in programme countries continued in 2019, including&#xA0;through support for new national policy instruments, the assumption of leadership roles in sectoral coordination&#xA0;bodies (in 85 countries in 2019). There has also been increase in initiatives&#xA0;to promote innovative financing mechanisms, and the&#xA0;participatory analysis of sector bottlenecks through the&#xA0;WASH Bottleneck Analysis Tool (in 15 countries in 2019).&#xA0; This work is extremely challenging and it will be important for Sida to continue to monitor developments in this area as challenges in terms of capacity building and financing will most likely increase due to the C-19 pandemic. -There has been important work during 2019 that ought to be emphaised regarding the importance of the work in relation to public health, the health of children, envirmonement and climate change. In this regard the program emphasis on: WASH in Institutions in particular HCF and schools; Climate resilient WASH and WASH in emergencies and humanitarian crisis, and urban environments; peace and security, as well as on aspects related to education, shhr, gender equality, Key results:&#x2022; Climate Resilience: Ambitious target of having all UNICEF WASH outputs to be climate resilient by the end of 2021 - a quarter of our programming is already meeting the minimum benchmarks.&#x2022; Tangible progress in key areas as water supply &#x2013; exceeded the annual target of 15 million people in 2018 and 2019; &#x2022;Sanitation - increased progress in 2019, 22,267 communities attained certified ODF status with significant progress on key indicators in the 26 high-burden gam plan countries; &#x2022;Handwashing with soap -major expansion in 2020 in response to COVID-19, and increased focus on hand hygiene in schools and health-care facilities; &#x2022;Menstrual health and hygiene - greatly exceeded targets; &#x2022;WASH in Institutions &#x2013; increasing indirect results in many countries, especially for WASH in schools;U &#x2022;Urban WASH: There is a growing proportion of direct beneficiaries are in urban areas&#x2022; Emergency WASH: thought leadership, advocacy and coordination (including Water Under Fire campaign), as well as ongoing large-scale cholera prevention and disease control programmes (now including COVID-19). &#x2022; Enabling Environment: Strengthening systems, particularly polices and strategies at the country level; released the highest number of WASH publications ever last year (178), as well as the Foundational Course.&#x2022; Results show that there are far more indirect beneficiaries than direct beneficiaries from UNCEF programming; UNICEF is developing a more robust system for monitoring indirect results.&#x2022; Results delivered in cross-cutting areas as WASH and Nutrition, WASH and Gender and WASH and Disability&#x2022; Expenditure &#x2013; generally 50/50 Humanitarian and Development fund utilization; overall expenditure across Goal Area 4 of US$1.1 billion in 2019 (WASH ~89% of Goal 4, +9% from 2018)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61050301" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
