<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-co" dstore:index="83" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11603A0101-COL-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Electoral Observation Mission (MOE) 2017-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Valobservat&#xF6;rsuppdrag (MOE) 2017-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The intervention aims to contribute to the transition process towards the democratic strengthening through actions that promote the modernization of the Colombian electoral system by 1) Strengthening social organizations and local institutions during the transition process, through actions aimed to reinforce information processes, formation, and citizen action. 2) Strengthening local institutions through a better comprehension of corruption phenomena associated to the political-electoral system. 3) Influence reform processes of political and electoral matter, aiming for the strengthening of democracy. The program will receive 11 197 645 SEK between 2017-2021.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Insatsen syftar till att bidra till &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsprocessen genom att genomf&#xF6;ra demokratist&#xE4;rkande &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder som fr&#xE4;mjar reformen av det colombianska valsystemet genom att; 1) St&#xE4;rka samh&#xE4;llsorganisationer och lokala institutioner under &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsprocessen genom &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder som syftar till att st&#xE4;rka informationsprocesser och initiativtagande hos medborgare; 2) St&#xE4;rka lokala institutioner genom b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else av korruption associerat till det colombianska valsystemet; 3) P&#xE5;verka reformprocesser som syftar till att st&#xE4;rka demokratin. Programmet f&#xE5;r 11197 645 SEK mellan &#xE5;ren 2017-2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOE/Mision de Observacion Elector</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.7 - By 2030, ensure that all learners acquire the knowledge and skills needed to promote sustainable development, including, among others, through education for sustainable development and sustainable lifestyles, human rights, gender equality, promotion of a culture of peace and non-violence, global citizenship and appreciation of cultural diversity and of culture&#x2019;s contribution to sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla studerande f&#xE5;r de kunskaper och f&#xE4;rdigheter som beh&#xF6;vs f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling, bland annat genom utbildning f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling och h&#xE5;llbara livsstilar, m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet, fr&#xE4;mjande av en kultur av fred, icke-v&#xE5;ld och globalt medborgarskap samt v&#xE4;rdes&#xE4;ttande av kulturell m&#xE5;ngfald och kulturens bidrag till h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.351000351</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">211508.1589272306</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">507370.5305682167</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">148055.7112490614</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">148055.7112490614</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">211508.1589272307</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.351000351</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">507370.5305682166</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1310125.775125775</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">351000.351000351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">211508.1589272306</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">359314.8193191552</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/colombia/contrib-nro-11603_decision.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/colombia/11603-grant-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessment of results The MOE contribution supported by Sida -named A Regional Open Democracy (ROD)-, has 3 specific objectives: 1) Transition and democratic strengthening; 2) Corruption, politics, and democracy; and 3) Advocacy among Society and State institutions. During 2019, the MOE had to operate in a changing environment, where the Duque administration was not fully committed to implementing the peace process, and local elections were held. It came as a surprise to the country that the President&#x2019;s party, the Centro Democr&#xE1;tico, did not secure major victories across the national territory. The MOE has been effective in both responding to requirements of the project&#x2019;s original specific objectives and adapting to the changes in the political and social context in the country. Specific Objective 1: Transition and Democratic Strengthening The main activity conducted in terms of electoral monitoring and observation was &#x201C;2019 Elections Monitoring&#x201D; for the local elections held on October 27, 2019. MOE deployed 3,097 observers, who in turn worked with 287 civil society organizations (CSOs) present in 566 municipalities. This presence is the equivalent of covering 86% of the overall potential electorate, and 76% of the most prioritized post conflict areas (130 municipalities). Similarly, MOE provided authorities with a series of electoral observation reports, which included recommendations on electoral accessibility, biometric identification, jury selections, custody of electoral documents, transparency in scrutiny processes, and trainings for persons with disabilities. As a direct consequence of these recommendations, MOE participated in the committees for the guarantees for people with disabilities requested by the United Nations to fulfill universal access to voting stations standards. For the first time, MOE was able to train 157 people virtually on electoral observation. This innovative tool will allow the organization to expand its training capacity and guarantee quality election information will reach more people. As part of its political power mapping, MOE delivered 3 reports on candidate enrollment, shedding light on candidates allegedly deemed unfit for office. MOE also documented alliance processes in 11 departments, including cases where connivance with illegal actors was present. Similarly, these reports demonstrated the impact of coalitions in candidate enrollment and the disproportionate increase in the enrollment of new Significant Citizen Groups as an alternative to traditional political parties. MOE monitored the evolution of this phenomenon for 9 months, and produced 11 reports in total on the subject matter. It is worth noting that this is the kind of quality work that makes MOE stand out as a civil society organization capable of effecting change in the fight for transparency and against corruption. The MOE&#x2019;s ever-popular Electoral Risk Factors and Maps analyzed political violence in 8 regions and received widespread media coverage. These maps were featured 456 times in 24 out of the 32 departments by the country&#x2019;s main media outlets. Likewise, MOE&#x2019;s political violence reports were essential in providing authorities information for prioritizing prevention and protection mechanisms in election times. MOE reported challenges in following up with sub-activity &#x201C;datoselecotrales.org&#x201D;. This portal usually publishes electoral results and reports for public use, however, 2019 numbers have not yet been fully uploaded because final vote counts are still being delivered in early 2020. To spread a culture that respects democratic values such as transparency and guarantees from an early age, MOE has also provided electoral observation services to citizen electoral processes, including student council elections. Under this activity, 33 individuals observed school elections in 15 departments and in 225 schools in Bogot&#xE1;. MOE also launched a web portal www.votafacil.org to support student council elections across the country. This is another demonstration that MOE is becoming innovative in its work and using technology to its favor to reach broader audiences. Although MOE uses the gender perspective in a cross-cutting way in its investigations, data analysis, public policy proposals, and media and academic incidence activities, it has an investigative branch called &#x201C;Women, Politics and Power&#x201D;. In 2019, this group analyzed the obstacles that women face to obtain parity and occupy publicly elected positions. The group also conducted a workshop to train reporters on how to do electoral media coverage with a gender perspective. Specific Objective 2: Corruption, Politics, and Democracy MOE investigated 253 candidates&#x2019; government plans, focusing on six specific variables that should be included in their plans per National Planning Department guidelines: prognosis, ideological platform, shared development vision, flagship strategies or programs, financing options and inclusion of women and LGBTI population. MOE concluded that 32.8% of the analyzed categories received the lowest compliance measurement (not met). At the MOE&#x2019;s request, the National Registrator allowed it to intervene and supervise the hiring process of that public organization. MOE also provided recommendations for hiring procedures, specifically providing inputs to hiring related to election activities. Specific Objective 3: Advocacy among Society and State Institutions The organization&#x2019;s virtual citizen complaint portal, &#x201C;Pilas con el voto&#x201D; (Careful with the Vote), continued yielding reports on irregularities and electoral crimes. In 2019, MOE received 5,291 citizen complaints (496 more than 2018). These complaints correspond to 68% of the total information received by the government&#x2019;s complaint portal (URIEL). With this information, MOE drafted periodic reports for competent authorities for their due management. Out of these 5,291 complaints, 25 were sufficiently credible to warrant action by the Attorney General&#x2019;s Office. District Attorneys and 60 members of the judicial police were trained on sources and criminal investigation strategies for electoral crimes. As part of MOE&#x2019;s input, the Attorney General&#x2019;s Office opened 1,824 investigations and arrested 68 electoral criminals. This demonstrates MOE&#x2019;s capacity to impact public action on electoral corruption. The MOE carried out advocacy activities surrounding political violence by generating a new follow-up commission with the Ministry of the Interior. 123 of these meetings were held at the national level, with one focusing on violence against women in politics. With Sida resources, MOE designed a strategy to monitor intolerance and fake news in social media. MOE&#x2019;s hashtag #Pol&#xED;ticaSinViolencia (#PoliticsWithoutViolence) generated 40,000 social media interactions. The second most influential organization in this matter only generated 4,600. MOE conducted a survey to congressmen and women on the different gender perspectives on key issues and also investigated their perception on the different acts of symbolic violence that were committed against female members of Congress. This information was shared with UN Women, another Sida partner, who shared some of the results to female parliamentarians. Finally, In terms of media monitoring, MOE tracked over 5,400 news, making emphasis on the coverage provided to female candidates and the gender bias against them in the media. This activity shed light on concerns and recommendations for media outlets on their journalistic practices regarding the gender perspective in political matters. Recommendations were also made to female politicians on how to use communication strategically. Communication Campaigns The organization worked on its visibility with an output of 215 graphic pieces that have a visual and graphic identity easily recognizable as MOE&#x2019;s. It also increased its Facebook followers by 5,000, to a total of 25,116. There was a 14.4% public engagement with MOE&#x2019;s social media content. MOE currently has over 40,000 Twitter followers, 4,000 more than 2018. In conclusion, MOE achieved its objectives, goals and activities during 2019. When presented with a challenge, MOE was able to adapt to the changes in the sociopolitical context and still deliver high-quality, high-impact results. Institutional Strengthening MOE established a safety protocol when three observers reported feeling at risk for their monitoring activities. Furthermore, over the course of the year, the organization conducted workshops that touched upon issues of gender equality, non-violence against women, new masculinities, and peaceful conflict resolution from a gender perspective. These activities have contributed towards breaking gender stereotypes and biases. They also led to a structural review of the internal code of conduct, modifications to institutional policies on gender equality and a reaffirmation of zero tolerance to sexual and workplace harassment. Mid-Term Evaluation In early 2019, MOE was also subject to a midterm evaluation. This exercise yielded 13 main recommendations, of which 7 have already been adopted. The organization was evaluated on the following areas: efficiency, effectiveness, impact, and sustainability. These are the main findings of the evaluation: Efficiency: MOE is highly efficient in the use of economic, human, and technical resources to achieve the expected objectives. Three main obstacles that affect this result are a) the lack of internal knowledge management; b) the ISO certification has not produced any added value to the organization; c) a lack of more structured human resources processes. Effectiveness: MOE was highly effective in terms of increasing transparency in electoral processes in Colombia. It is also effective strengthening institutional capacity both at the State and CSO level. The main challenges in this area are dealing with a lack of political will and little institutional dialogue capacity. Impact: MOE has had a high impact in strengthening CSO&#x2019;s capacities, government institutions and the media. Despite having a great level of incidence over reforms and institutional adjustments, there is a lesser impact in structural reform. Sustainability: This is the area where MOE was most deficient. The organization currently has only one source of income, and this is international cooperation funds. MOE argues this is the one means by which it can guarantee its independence. Despite this challenge, it stands out for its institutional strategy, the territorial focus in its work, the construction of volunteer networks, the high quality of its reports, and good communication with political parties. It could, however, improve its outreach to other areas in the country.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="11603" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1050203" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01" strategy-total-amount="980000000.0">
    <title>Colombia 2016-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Colombia 2016-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
