<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-tr" dstore:index="127" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11167A0101-TUR-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women for Women&apos;s Human Rights 2018-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Women for Women&apos;s Human Rights 2018-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Women for Women&apos;s Human Rights-New Ways (WWHR) has applied to Sida for funding of 24 million SEK to carry out their strategy activities of the NGO during the period 2018-2022. 
The intervention aims at sustainable change and transformation rather than short-cut and transitory solutions to women&#x2019;s human rights issues. WWHR believes that for sustainable change to occur, a mental shift needs to take place at the societal level, reach a critical mass, and converge with strengthened and improved normative systems at the national and international levels. Sustainable change results from:
&#x2022;	Producing and sharing knowledge: Creating enabling spaces to link action-research with knowledge generation and sharing, and disseminating the generated knowledge through publications and other audio-visual, published, and digital means,
&#x2022;	Building capacity, raising awareness, and women&#x2019;s empowerment: Building capacity, raising awareness, and promoting women&#x2019;s empowerment through education and support programs with women, women&#x2019;s rights organizations, activists, youth, practitioners, state institutions, and other rights-based organizations,
&#x2022;	Advocacy: Taking part in joint and participatory advocacy work at the local, national, regional, and international levels by protecting, enforcing, and improving legal rights, putting the necessary mechanisms into practice, and raising awareness to ensure that women&#x2019;s human rights are realized. 
&#x2022;	Networking: Networking and solidarity with all levels of the women&#x2019;s movement and other rights-based movements through efforts to build capacity, raise awareness, promote women&#x2019;s empowerment, and advocacy.
All these domains feed one another and work in a cycle, rather than as a linear process.
The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 24 million SEK for 5 years.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Women for Women&apos;s Human Rights-New Ways (WWHR) har ans&#xF6;kt om finansiellt st&#xF6;d om 24 MSEK fr&#xE5;n Sida f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av organisationens strategiska aktiviteter under perioden 2018-2022. 
Insatsen &#xE4;mnar bidra till h&#xE5;llbara f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar som st&#xF6;djer kvinnors m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter. WWHR anser att h&#xE5;llbara f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar endast kan ske n&#xE4;r en mental f&#xF6;rflyttning skett p&#xE5; samh&#xE4;llelig niv&#xE5;, en kritisk massa deltar, och n&#xE4;r dessa sammanfaller med st&#xE4;rkta och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrade normativa system p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5;. H&#xE5;llbar f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring n&#xE5;s genom:
&#x2022;                    Kunskapsproduktion och spridning: Skapa utrymmen f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka utbytet mellan aktivism och forskning f&#xF6;r att generera kunskap och spridning av denna genom publiceringar och andra audio, visuella, tryckta och digitala medel.  
&#x2022;                    Kapacitetsbyggande, medevetandeh&#xF6;jande och kvinnors st&#xE4;rkta egenmakt: Kapacitetsbyggande, medevetandeh&#xF6;jande och st&#xE4;rkandet av kvinnors egenmakt genom utbildning och st&#xF6;d till kvinnor, kvinnor&#xE4;ttsorganisationer, aktivister, ungdomar, professionella ut&#xF6;vare, statliga institutioner och andra r&#xE4;ttighetsbaserade organisationer.  
&#x2022;                    P&#xE5;verkansarbete: Deltagande p&#xE5;verkansarbete p&#xE5; lokal, nationell, regional och internationell niv&#xE5; f&#xF6;r att skydda, genomdriva och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra juridiska r&#xE4;ttigheter, s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndiga mekanismer anv&#xE4;nds, och &#xF6;ka medvetenheten f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att kvinnors m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter realiseras.
&#x2022;                    N&#xE4;tverkande: N&#xE4;tverka och verka i solidaritet med kvinnor&#xF6;relsen och andra r&#xE4;ttighetsbaserade r&#xF6;relser genom insatser f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja kapacitetsbyggande, medvetandeh&#xF6;jande, kvinnors egenmakt och p&#xE5;verkansarbete. 
Dessa dom&#xE4;ner faller in i varandra samt sker i cykler, och &#xE4;r d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r inte att f&#xF6;rst&#xE5; som en linj&#xE4;r process. 
Insatsen totala budget omfattar 24 MSEK f&#xF6;r en fem&#xE5;rsperiod.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women for Women&#x2019;s Human Rights &#x2013; New Ways (WWHR) is a women&#x2019;s NGO in Turkey that aims to promote women&#x2019;s human rights, equality and non-discrimination at national and international levels. Since its foundation in 1993, WWHR has become a well known NGO in its area. More than two decades of work on activism, advocacy and networking, WWHR has worked for making contributions to various legal reforms, increasing women&#x2019;s awareness and enjoyment of their rights in Turkey, advancing sexual and bodily rights in Muslim societies and also worked on women&#x2019;s human rights at the UN level. Recipient of the 2007 Gruber Foundation International Women&#x2019;s Human Rights Prize, WWHR had held special NGO Consultative Status with the Economic and Social Council of the UN since 2005. In June 2017, WWHR embarked on a new strategic planning process to identify how it can continue to fulfill its mission to spread rights awareness from a feminist and women rights perspective at the local, national, regional, and international levels; contribute to women&#x2019;s equal, influential and unobstructed participation in life and advocate for the protection and strengthening of women&#x2019;s human rights. Based on the lessons learned from the previous Strategic Plan executed over the past five years (2013-2017) and the current sociopolitical situation in Turkey, WWHR aimed to develop an overall strategic framework and roadmap for its operations in line with the Results Assessment framework. The concrete activities and operations proposed with the current Strategic Plan covers the upcoming five years (2018-2022), and is planned to be regularly reviewed and revised on the basis of Annual Operational Plans. This new strategy is an updated version of the previous strategies and by this strategy, WWHR&apos;s mission is set as&#xA0;&quot;to spread awareness of feminist rights at the local, national, regional and international levels; contribute to women&#x2019;s equal, influential, and unobstructed participation in life; and advocate for the protection and strengthening of women&#x2019;s human rights.&quot; &#xA0;This proposal of WWHR is aligned with the latest developments Turkey that has been through such as increased conservatism, shrinking space, Syrian conflicts/migration, challenges/limitations created by conservative central government and local administrations, Feto and PKK operations, State of Emergency (SoE), increased terror attacks by ISIS and PKK, closure of NGOs by the government through decrees, miltary involvement wwith YPG forces in Syria etc. It would be also important to mention here that WWHR is very much dependent on international funding in particular to Sida due to their feminist stance against government&apos;s (unofficial) conservative ideological agenda (gender equity/justice).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWHR/Women for Women&#x2019;s Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">425757.1573230231</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">539345.805264438</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">539345.805264438</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">539345.805264438</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180768</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">425757.1573230231</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">539345.805264438</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">539345.8052644382</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">539345.8052644382</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2761668.0475006904</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">425757.1573230231</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">539345.805264438</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The achieved outputs and results have been summarised below in line with the annual report and the annual review meeting:&#xA0; Results on Thematic Area 1: Increasing Rights Awareness, Capacity Building and Women&#x2019;s Empowerment WWHR has run their trainings and seminars as planned and reached the expected figures. One of the most important programs HREP has been continued by sustaining coordination, follow-up work and logistical support for active HREP trainers, HREP participants and local partners through field visits, supervision visits, meetings and regular phone calls. Under the programme 40 HREP groups completed, reaching 599 women. To date, a total of 16370 women have benefitted from HREP since 1998, via 965 groups held. 12 Gender Equality Seminars jointly organized with various partners, with the participation of 616 participants (435 men and 181 women). Increasing the number of GES participants to 2,720 men and women in total (1,496 women and 1,224 men). HREP has been also supported through conducting five supervision visits for new HREP trainers and 22 field visits to trainers, participants, and implementing partners of the trainings. Also, WWHR continued updating, producing, and disseminating training materials and publications for the training programs. As a negativity, WWHR has lost 20 of their trainers placed in the municipalities due to the appointments of trustees to these municipalities by the government (Diyarbakir, Van, Urfa, Batman, Mus). However also kept in touch with 60 trainers from the MoFSPL(though inactive). In this term WWHR has also developed a new training program, named the Human Rights Education Program for Young Women (Young HREP), and launched the first round of pilot implementation. A very important work for Sida was the External Impact Assessment Study for WWHR&#x2019;s training programs carried out between 2012-2018 as this was a requirement of the QAC for this contribution. This study has shown that WWHR has been highly successful in realising these trainings and seminars and have created a very high positive impact on the trainees with respect to women&#x2019;s human rights and creating change within the targeted women&#x2019; and men&#x2019;s lives. Another very important result is that WWHR has also had the chance to see the positive effects of working with men to create a social change with respect to gender equality. Sida&#x2019;s observation was it was rather difficult for WWHR to allocate resources for men instead of women. However, this now has changed with the obtained results and WWHR is prone to carry out their work with men in the future and changing their plans accordingly. WWHR also continued to maintain and increase its partnerships with various municipalities, local women&#x2019;s CSOs and other CSOs, universities, private companies, chambers etc. which has led to increasing the number of signed HREP Partnership Protocols with municipalities to 13 and signing three more protocols in the reporting period. Results on Thematic Area 2: Local, National, Regional, and International Advocacy WWHR continued its advocacy efforts at the local, national, and international levels during the reporting period in relation to gender equality, the human rights of women and girls, sexual and reproductive health and rights, and violence against women. A very important work that they have continued to realise was related to providing input to international documents (such as the Universal Periodic Review Process of Turkey on gender equality), attending meetings, and disseminating information among women&#x2019;s CSOs about the GREVIO Committee&#x2019;s evaluations process; coordinating the support for Feride Acar&#x2019;s candidacy for the GREVIO Committee among women&#x2019;s CSOs. WWHR has also followed up on the Concluding Observations of Turkey&#x2019;s Seventh Periodic Country Review and the assessment of the CEDAW Committee on Turkey&#x2019;s follow-up report, Providing input to new General Recommendation of CEDAW on Trafficking in Women &amp;amp; Girls in the context of Global Migration as well as actively participated and provided input to the Beijing+25 Process. WWHR has established the Beijing+25 Women&#x2019;s Platform-Turkey and prepared a policy paper that put forward the Platform&#x2019;s demands and proposed the establishment of a &#x201C;Global Independent Women&#x2019;s Body.&#x201D; WWHR has continued to participate to the regional networks, conferences, meetings, feedback, desktop studies, joint advocacy campaigns, interviews, and research related to Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights (SRHR) work. They have realised advocacy and awareness raising work on the draft law on child abuse, against attempts to curtail women&#x2019;s alimony rights, and other lines of activism as well as SDGs internationally and nationally. An important work was to launch the website on SDGs with a focus on gender equality. However, WWHR also noted that the expectations of the organisation has decided to be downsized for the localisation of the SDGs&#xA0; to awareness raising and there is not much of a possibility in realising the outcome due to the fact that even the UN is also having difficulties in the area and localisaton of the SDGs has been re-evaluated as over ambitious under the current negative circumstances. WWHR has also started to work on the global and nationally promoted conservative anti gender discourse and lobbying together with Kaos GL and CSBR. Thematic Area 3: Researching, Producing, and Sharing Feminist Knowledge and Strategies Developing, diversifying, and sharing publications and other outreach materials is another strategic priority for WWHR with the aim of expanding rights awareness on women&#x2019;s rights in Turkey and generating feminist knowledge. Under this area WWHR continued to update, (re)produce and disseminate various HREP, advocacy and WWHR materials and publications such as the We Have Rights! booklets, issues of the Purple Newsletter, and other WWHR and HREP visibility materials. Social media accounts and website is maintained and improved as well as its outreach and the WWHR database is also improved.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="11167" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
