<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-mk" dstore:index="72" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:22" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-02T08:44:23" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12372A0101-MKD-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender budgeting (UNW)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Gender budgeting (UNW)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Macedonia has made commitments to work for improved gender equality by signing international conventions and enacting national laws and policies. An ongoing reform of the public financial management system includes an initative to introduce and institutionalise gender responsive budgeting (GRB). This means that national and local budgets are formulated, planned, executed and evaluated with consideration to the needs of men, women, boys and girls, and that the effects budgets bring are analysed with reference ot these groups. The reform concerns both central and municipal level. UN Women has been involved in GRB work both in Macedonia and in around 70 other countries in the world. The programme in Macedonia involves civil servants both at central and local level, parliamentarians, local politicians and civil society organisations. Sida, together with Swiss SDC, supports the implementation of the programme with 11.7 million SEK during the period 2018-2021.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Makedonien har &#xE5;tagit sig att arbeta f&#xF6;r en st&#xE4;rkt j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet genom dels internationella &#xE5;taganden och dels nationella policies och planer. 
I Makedonien har en reform av den offentliga finansiella styrningen inletts d&#xE4;r man bl.a vill inf&#xF6;ra programbaserad budgetering. Man &#xF6;nskar &#xE4;ven inf&#xF6;rliva en j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsintegrerad budgetprocess. Det betyder att nationella och lokala budgetar formuleras, planeras, genomf&#xF6;rs och utv&#xE4;rderas med h&#xE4;nsyn till de olika behov m&#xE4;n, kvinnor, pojkar och flickor har samt vilka effekter som budgeten ger f&#xF6;r dessa olika grupper. Reformen ber&#xF6;r b&#xE5;de central och kommunal niv&#xE5;. UN Women har sedan tidigare arbetat med j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsintegrering i budgetprocesser, i Makedonien och i ett 70-tal andra l&#xE4;nder. I f&#xF6;religgande programf&#xF6;rslag i Makedonien medverkar, f&#xF6;rutom ber&#xF6;rda stats- och kommuntj&#xE4;nstem&#xE4;n, &#xE4;ven parlamentariker och kommunpolitiker samt civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer. Sida, tillsammans med schweiziska SDC, st&#xF6;djer detta arbete under perioden 2018-2021 med ett belopp om totalt 11,7 miljoner SEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project Promoting Gender Responsive Policies and Budgets: Towards Transparent, Inclusive and Accountable Governance in North Macedonia has an overall objective &#x201C;To improve women&#x2019;s lives and support the inclusion of the most vulnerable groups through systematic and sustainable integration of gender perspective at all stages of national and local policy-making and budgeting processes.&#x201D;
Sida joined forces with Swiss SDC and UN Women in support of this programme implementation by contributing with 11. 7 million SEK (1.2 million USD) , for the period October 2018-December 2022.
Total project budget ammounts 3,655,183.53 USD.
The project supports&#xA0; advancement of implementation of national and international commitments to gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment in line with national SDG priority targets and the EU accession process. It intervenes both at central and local level, as well as in strenghtening the capacity and the role of the civil society sector.
At central level, the project applies strategies focused on engendering the Public Finance Management reforms, by promoting more inclusive and transparent governance, accountable to the needs and interests of women and men. The project supports the longstanding vision of strong national gender machinery, which is taking the lead in ensuring policies and laws to fully embed gender equality principles.
At local level, the project interventions are focusing on policies and budgets to improve the life of women and men from the most vulnerable groups while promoting the use of GRB as a tool that enables local governments to recognize the value and potential for local development and inclusive growth.
CSO networking and advocacy efforts are supported to enable structured and continued oversight and analysis of budgetary allocation and spending from a gender perspective, and to generate missing watch dog evidence and expert policy recommendations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Macedonia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">425987.2963269815</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">391501.6021743039</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">301475.6180983094</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">164989.0875924297</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">425987.2963269815</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">391501.6021743041</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">301475.6180983094</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">164989.0875924298</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1346313.1731565865</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">425987.2963269815</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">391501.6021743039</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">301475.6180983094</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The EC annual report for North Macedonia 2019, reports on some progress on equality between women and men, and the legal framework that is largely in line with the acquis. The gender equality unit at the Ministry of Labour and Social Policy (MoLSP) plays a key coordination role and it needs to be adequately resourced to ensure legal and policy tools are implemented effectively. UN Women is a strategic partner to the MoLSP, and it provides direct support to the capacity development of the institution. Under the project Promoting Gender Responsive Policies and Budgets: Towards Transparent, Inclusive and Accountable Governance in North Macedonia, UN Women reports on substantial progress achieved on the government&#x2019;s public finance management and in the strategic planning processes during the period December 2018-December 2019. Building on realised progress and experience gained within the earlier implemented GRB project 2014-2018, the current project has made important progress in communicating to the Ministry of finance the need for systemic integration of gender budgeting in the new Organic budget law, and for compiling gender aware Budget instructions. Significant progress was made in introducing gender specific measures&#xA0; in the processes of policy making and budgeting on local level. The project has also joined forces with another Sida supported organization (We Effect) in achievement of unexpected result&#xA0; introducing a gender sensitive measure&#xA0; within the National Strategy for Agriculture and Rural Development, by the means of which a 100 rural women who hold agricultural business are enabled to receive financial support from the State. Some examples of results reported: - The GRB Methodology is continuously implemented by the line-ministries and state institutions which prepare statements for sectoral programmes; - The Ministry of finance issued a specific gender budget template as an Annex to the Budget Circular to all central budget users - The General Secretariat of the Government included gender-specific provisions within the Government Strategic Planning Methodology - Decision is made to establish the first Center of Excellence on Gender Equality and Gender Responsive Budgeting under the Leadership of the Ministry of Labour and Social Policy, which has an ambition to become a Regional Center of Excellence - The Ministry of Labour and Social Policy and the State Statistical Office developed the first Gender Equality Index for North Macedonia - Twenty-one municipalities introduced gender specific measures and allocated budgets for selected programmes (over 85 programmes). - Four Local Self Government Units (LSGU) developed new Gender Equality strategies and one LSGU adopted a gender equality Action plan. - Eight LSGUs in City of Skopje have secured funds for establishment of two counselling centres for survivors of domestic violence. - First Forum of Women Mayors in SEE is organized by NALAS on the topic of gender mainstreaming in local policymaking and budgeting process. - First Lobby Group on gender equality at local level is established by the Association of municipal authorities (ZELS) - Several advocacy initiatives are taken by the Parliamentary Commission on Equal Opportunities and the Club of women Parliamentarians. - 25 CSOs are trained to follow on budget processes and their capacity is strengthened to analyse public policies and budget from gender perspective. - A practical tool (strategy) for working with women in local communities is provided to CSO&apos;s.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="12372" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01" strategy-total-amount="10550000.0">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
