<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-ba" dstore:index="117" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11328A0101-BIH-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Institute for youth development, KULT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Institutet f&#xF6;r ungdomsutveckling, KULT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Youth CSOs play a key role in voicing youth priorites, needs and interests. The contribution aims at empowering youth and youth leaders for a more inclusive democratic process</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Ungdomsorganisationer har en nyckelroll n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller att uttrycka och formulera ungdomars prioriteringar, behov och intressen. Insatsen syftar till att st&#xE4;rka ungdomar och ungdomsledare f&#xF6;r en mer inkluderande demokratisk process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within the Project the Institute for Youth Development KULT is implementing the following components: 1. Empowering local youth CSOs through sub-granting 2. Training program Learn Think and Act! (UMiD) 3.The Academy for Youth Political Leaders 4.Training program for Youth Officers 5.Public advocacy campaigns 6. Supporting youth entrepreneurship through sub-granting 7. Promotional and visibility activities These components (under which groups of activities are implemented) are a level below the 3 &quot;outcome&quot; levels or pillars including the following: 1. Improved conditions for democratic accountability to young people and their participation in civic and political processes, including the promotion of free elections. 2. Young women and young men have, to a greater extent, the same power to shape society and their own lives. 3. Increased trust and reconciliation among young people in all parts of BiH. With amendment #4, the following new activities are added: 1. 180 students will use donated equipment in enrolling and studying for the ongoing school year, 2. At least 25 local (youth) CSOs which will be engaged as a Focal Points to ensure smooth collection and donation of the technical equipment to the students in need, 3. At least 25 schools who will be engaged and work closely with the Focal Points on the collection of the data on the students in need, 4. At least 80 teachers will share and gain new experiences on implementing online curricula and create innovative approach into online schooling, 5. At least 120 families obtain means to overcome obstacles in ensuring schooling to their children, 6. 25 BiH local communities in which the initiative will be implemented.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institut za razvoj mladih KULT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.5 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; full och produktiv syssels&#xE4;ttning med anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetsvillkor f&#xF6;r alla kvinnor och m&#xE4;n, inklusive ungdomar och personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, samt lika l&#xF6;n f&#xF6;r likv&#xE4;rdigt arbete.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.5 - By 2030, achieve full and productive employment and decent work for all women and men, including for young people and persons with disabilities, and equal pay for work of equal value.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">468000.468000468</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">518503.1759182546</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">392876.4052073309</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">518503.1759182547</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">392876.4052073309</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">468000.468000468</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1429858.4298584298</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">468000.468000468</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">518503.1759182547</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">392876.4052073309</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/agreement-amendment-2-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 2 to agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/beslut-om-insats-11328.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats 11328</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/amedment-no4_signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 4 to the agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/amendment-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 1 to agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/decision-on-amendment-bih2019-12.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment 3</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/grant-agreement-signed-kult.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/amend-3-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 13to agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/decision-signed-amend-2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/decision-signed-on-amendment.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main results reported in 2019 is the establishment of Youth Councils and their participation in decision making in municipalities. The process of developing youth strategies during 2019 is taking place in 8 local communities in BiH. Young entrepreneurs were also reached out in 8 local communities, and more than 40 received support (out of more than 70 applications) for their businesses and business ideas. KULT has an interesting method of evaluation of call for applications; the evaluation commissions are mixed comprising representatives of KULT, the municipality which cost shares with its own budget and local business. Also important 2019 results is that the second cycle of the UMID training completed and the third has began. In 2019, UMID has 26 participants from 21 communities and half are women. The Academy for political leaders has 27 participants from 12 political parties and 10 female participants. The training for youth officers has 23 public servants(12 women) from 21 communities. The youth officers being trained by KULT enagage with more than one hundred youth daily. Through its sub granting program for local youth CSOa, KULT received 30 project applications and awarded 7 in 2019. In addition KULT awarded the Robokids grant which was made through an addendum of the programme agreement with the Embassy.During the reporting period, the Institute invested efforts into educating young women through trainings for youth leaders and young political leaders. This way, the Institute empowers young women to take on a more active role in election processes during the 2020 election period. Over 40% of program participants are women. 50% of leaders of civil initiatives are women.Other notable result is the grant award to 6 local civic initiatives in 6 communities. In 2019, KULT reports more than 500 youth took part in activities in local communities.KULT has done effective advocacy campaigns in 2019. The #necudaidem had particularly strong messages for youth not to think about leaving BiH. This campaign prompted discussion in FBiH Parliament about the need to adopt a Youth Strategy. Another high profile event of 2019 was the #YouthinkBiH event which attracted hundreds of participants in the programme celebrating International Volunteer Day. Gender equality campaigns were also held and a Youth policy monitoring tool was promoted. Apart from this KULT organizes workshops and participates in major conferences on entrepreneurship together with other Swedish partners like Mozaik. It should also be noted that KULT established cooperation with UNICEF in developing policies and activities for social protection of children and youth at risk, in Sarajevo Canton. Overall it is assessed by Embassy that KULT is delivering as planned on the outcome level and KULT employs a RBM approach to project management. The reported activities in the annual report for 2019 correspond well to the workplan for 2019, indicating good planning and timely implementation of activities. There is a intuitive risk analysis discussed as a &quot;Lessons learned&quot; part of the annual report. There are no major risks identified by KULT. KULT is noting that more work needs to be done with entity ministries on youth strategy and policy and to connect the ministries to the youth officers working on the municipal level. Sustainability risks are not discussed explicitly. However, KULT is not disregarding this part of project management, and its approach which is integrated with the institutions (ministries and municipalities alike) is definitely related to sustainability. 2020 work plan is submitted. It takes account of the COVID19 situation and considers options for implementing the next grant fund call (a plan B option requirement for all proposals will be introduced) Online delivery of UMID trainings is in preparation as well as postponement of trainings scheduled for May.Entrepreneurs&#xA0; KULT is working with are expected to be hit hard by the crisis. Active mitigation could be necessary. For now the option is to extend conditions in the grant contracts according to assessment of situation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11328" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
