<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-tr" dstore:index="292" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:20" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T09:19:21" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5502016001-TUR-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women Gender Equality in Political Leadership</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">J&#xE4;mst&#xE4;llt ledarskap</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
UN Women  has applied to Sida for funding of 3,5 million USD(registered to PLUS as 24,5 MSEK) to carry out the &quot; Gender Equality in Political Leadership and Participation in Turkey during the period 2014-2016. 
The intervention aims to ensure that women are able to participate in all aspects of decision making within the TGNA, including positions of leadership by 1) legal frameworks and policies to advance gender equality and women&#x2019;s right to participate in decision making are reformed/adopted and implemented 2) women&#x2019;s leadership and participation in politics is promoted by gender responsive measures (parliamentary mechanisms, processes and services) and 3) legal frameworks and policies to increase women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation are influenced by gender equality advocates. 
UN Women will implement the intervention together with the Inter Parliamentary Union as the Responsible Party (Responsible Party is defined in UN Women Programme and Operations Manual Part 1: Programme Formulation as the party which: i) Is directly accountable to the IP in accordance with a signed agreement; ii) Acts on behalf of the implementing partner to purchase goods and services from suppliers using the programme budget; iii) and Manages the use of these goods and services to carry out planned activities and produce outputs). IPU will be also a service provider for the expertise that they will provide. 
The primary beneficiary is the Committee on Equal Opportunity for Women and Men of the Turkish Grand National Assembly is to be considered an equal partner in the implementation of the project. UN Women and IPU will provide technical expertise and knowledge and facilitate capacity building.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
UN Women har ans&#xF6;kt till Sida om finansiering om 3,5 miljoner US-dollar (registrerat i PLUS som 24,5 MSEK) f&#xF6;r att utf&#xF6;ra insatsen &#x2019;J&#xE4;mst&#xE4;llt ledarskap&#x2019; i Turkiet under perioden 2014-2016. 

Insatsen syftar till att tillse att kvinnor har m&#xF6;jlighet att delta i alla aspekter av beslutsfattandet i det turkiska parlamentet, inklusive i ledande positioner genom att tillse:
1) att r&#xE4;ttsliga ramar och strategier f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet mellan k&#xF6;nen och kvinnors r&#xE4;tt att delta i beslutsfattandet reformeras, antas och implementeras; 
2) att kvinnligt ledarskap och deltagande i politiken fr&#xE4;mjas av s&#xE4;rskilda &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder (parlamentariska mekanismer, processer och tj&#xE4;nster); och 
3) att r&#xE4;ttsliga ramar och strategier f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka kvinnors ledarskap och politiska deltagande p&#xE5;verkas av j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsf&#xF6;respr&#xE5;kare och personer med relevant kunskap. 

UN Women f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;r att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen tillsammans med Inter Parlamentariska Unionen (IPU) som delvis ansvarig part. IPU kommer att ansvara f&#xF6;r delar av insatsen (unders&#xF6;kningar, utbildningar etc) och leverera enligt avtal med UN Women och programdokumentet. IPU blir ocks&#xE5; tj&#xE4;nsteleverant&#xF6;r f&#xF6;r den kompetens som de levererar i enlighet med programdokumentet.  

Den prim&#xE4;ra mottagaren f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r utskottet f&#xF6;r lika m&#xF6;jligheter f&#xF6;r kvinnor och m&#xE4;n i det turkiska parlamentet. Utskottet blir ocks&#xE5; &#xE4;r en j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lld partner i genomf&#xF6;randet av projektet. UN Women och IPU ger teknisk expertis och kunskap och underl&#xE4;tta kapacitetsuppbyggnad.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">612253.8229420254</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467480.8625021913</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">819000.819000819</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1070146.3684065174</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">819000.819000819</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1070146.3684065174</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">612253.8229420254</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467480.8625021914</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3571480.633828482</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">612253.8229420254</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">467480.8625021913</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">819000.819000819</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">1070146.3684065174</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/turkey/55020160-decision.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/turkey/55020160-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/turkey/55020160-amendment_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/turkey/55020160-amendment_2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OUTCOME 1. Legal frameworks and policies to advance gender equality and women&#x2019;s right to participate in decision-making are reformed/adopted and implemented (Output 1.2 Improved access to parliament to gender equality related knowledge products and tools to formulate and monitor the implementation of gender responsive legal and policy frameworks) Under this outcome it is assessed that the Turkish Grand National Assembly (TGNA) has increased capacity in relation to access to gender equality related knowledge products and tools to formulate and monitor the implementation of gender responsive legal and policy frameworks in comparison to the project start. This is mainly achieved through trainings, training of trainers (ToT) and mentoring sessions for the internal GRB trainers of the TGNA. These are expected to lead to the institutionalization of GRB and the Parliament to formulate the budget in a gender responsive and inclusive way. Where the efforts remained limited UN Women increased their collaboration with other key public institutions like Strategy and Budget Department of Presidency (SBP) and Ministry of Family, Labour and Social Services (MoFLSS) and tried to increase their capacity on how to integrate GRB and gender equality into national and local policies and/or performance documents through these activities. OUTCOME 2. Women&#x2019;s leadership and participation in politics is promoted by gender responsive measures (parliamentary mechanisms, processes and services) Under this outcome the efforts mainly concentrated on output 2.2 (strengthened capacity of Parliament to enhance women&#x2019;s increased participation in politics, including in leadership positions) and output 2.3. (strengthened capacities of newly elected municipal council members in gender equality issues, the staff in equality units in municipalities, and potentially women community leaders). An important initiative was to start to the review of several pieces of legislation (Capital Markets Law, Commercial Code, Cooperatives Law, Law on Agricultural Credit Cooperatives and Unions, Law on Agricultural Sales Cooperatives and Unions, Social Insurance and General Health Insurance Law, and Social Services Law) in partnership with Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU) the Committee on Equality of Opportunity for Women and Men (EOC). UN Women has continued to increase awareness of political parties through &quot;Women in Politics Workshop&quot; on international and national good practices, measures, issues and challenges on women&#x2019;s access to parliament and gender sensitive legislation which may assist cross-party solidarity on women&#x2019;s empowerment issues.&#xA0; At the local level GRB trainings have been conducted for 12 municipalities to enhance the capacity at the local level to incorporate gender aspects into all stages of budgetary processes and public financial management. A good result was that after the trainings Ankara Metropolitan Municipality increased the resources of Women and Family Department of the Municipality which is responsible for design and delivery of services on women&#x2019;s empowerment. Also, university students on media have been targeted in order to achieve increased knowledge and awareness on gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment, media&#x2019;s role in reproducing gender roles and sexist language and to provide hands-on experience to transform traditional media with gender sensitive trainings. Within the framework of the 16 Days of Activism students who joined the training have organized Light the Dark photography workshops providing a free space for Turkish and Syrian women to interact with each other and try photography as a new source of expression. The project also developed several communication and visibility materials and&#xA0; translated them to Turkish on women&#x2019;s political participation and disseminated to relevant stakeholders. OUTCOME 3. Legal frameworks and policies to increase women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation is influenced by gender equality advocates. Under output 3.1 (Strengthened dialogue mechanisms and enhanced policy space to enable gender equality advocates and civil society to promote gender equality and women&#x2019;s political participation) some important activities have been realised in 2019. The local women candidates&#x2019; skills and knowledge on electoral communications and campaign management, fundraising, voter contact and running for office through &#x201C;Local Politics Workshops&#x201D; is strengthened as well as some members of CSOs. The trainings have managed to bring together women candidates from the entire political spectrum and a platform of solidarity to discuss common challenges and a joint public call was possible to encourage more women to enter politics. This is strengthened by two &#x201C;Experience Sharing Workshops&#x201D;. The project has also conducted the monitoring of the local elections in 2019 in collaboration with the CSO platform - Women&#x2019;s Coalition. In order to increase awareness on Preventing Violence against Women in Politics (VAWiP),including cyber violence, a panel and a workshop was organized for MPs of TGNA, local councillors of Ankara Metropolitan Municipality, representatives of CSOs, academia, INGOs and other UN agencies in collaboration with European Women&#x2019;s Lobby.&#xA0; Under output 3.2 (strengthened capacity of gender equality advocates to promote gender equality, women&#x2019;s leaderships and political participation) within UN Women&#x2019;s global theme for International Women&#x2019;s Day 2019 &#x201C;Think equal, build smart, innovate for change&#x201D;, UN Women Turkey initiated an intergenerational dialogue &#x201C;From Beijing To Date, From Today to Future&#x201D; in the eve of Beijing +25 together with UN agencies in Turkey on 4 March 2019. In the context of 16 Days of Activism &#x201C;Light the Dark&#x201D; campaign is organized to draw attention on safety of women and girls in public spaces. The campaign, called upon citizens, local authorities and public institutions to take action to make cities and public spaces safer, healthier, more inclusive and secure environments for all to live and participate in urban life without fear of violence and intimidation. The result report is attached as an annex to the main report by UN Women. UN Women has also started to cooperate with Kader (the Association for Support of Women Candidates, a Sida funded NGO active in WPP) and supported a member of KADER to attend the Regional Beijing+25 Review Meeting held in Geneva in order to strengthen CSO representation in the regional review.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="55020160" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
