<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-et" dstore:index="170" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-11T06:41:41" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11433A0102-ETH-14050</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 UN-Habitat 2018-2020: Promote Sustainable cities</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 UN-Habitat 2018-2020: Promote Sustainable cities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
Support to the Implementation of the UN-Habitat Country Programme for Ethiopia will strive to improve the state of Ethiopian cities and thereby the urban livelihood by supporting the Government of Ethiopia in implementing the urban component of GTP II in alignment with the SDG 11 and the New Urban Agenda, as part of the UN-Habitat Country Programme for Ethiopia 2016-2020. Specifically the project will focus on  selected cities of Ethiopia (Addis Ababa, Adama, Dire Dawa, Hawassa and Mekele) and some regions (Amhara, SNNP and Tigray) in being better planned, more economically productive and sustainable, socially inclusive and environmentally resilient, taking maximum advantage of the on-going development of industrial parks.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Support to the Implementation of the UN-Habitat Country Programme for Ethiopia: St&#xF6;d till genomf&#xF6;randet av FN-habitatprogrammet f&#xF6;r Etiopien kommer att str&#xE4;va efter att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra de etiopiska st&#xE4;dernas stad och d&#xE4;rmed st&#xE4;dernas f&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjning genom att st&#xF6;dja Etiopiens regering f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra stadsdelen i GTP II i linje med SDG 11 och den nya Urban Agenda, som en del av FN-habitatprogrammet f&#xF6;r Etiopien 2016-2020. Specifikt kommer projektet att fokusera p&#xE5; utvalda st&#xE4;der i Etiopien (Addis Abeba, Adama, Dire Dawa, Hawassa och Mekele) och vissa regioner (Amhara, SNNP och Tigray) att vara b&#xE4;ttre planerande, med effektiv avfallshanteringsamt mer ekonomiskt produtiva och h&#xE5;llbara, social  inkluderade och milj&#xF6;h&#xE4;rdiga, samt maximalt utnyttja den p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende utvecklingen av industriparker. Ett kompletterande st&#xF6;d &#xE4;r det globala st&#xF6;det via SKL ( Sveriges kommuner och landsting) till urban planering,</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed intervention aims to improve the state of Ethiopian cities and thereby the urban livelihood by supporting the Government of Ethiopia in implementing the urban component of GTP II in alignment with the SDG 11 and the New Urban Agenda, as part of the UN-Habitat Country Programme for Ethiopia 2016-2020. Moreover, the project specifically assist the selected cities of Ethiopia (Addis Ababa, Adama, Dire Dawa, Hawassa and Mekele) and some regions (Amhara, SNNP and Tigray) in being better planned, more economically productive and sustainable, socially inclusive and environmentally resilient, taking maximum advantage of the on-going development of industrial parks. At the end the intervention the following major results will be achieved; Result 1: City leadership skills are reinforced to enable mayors and city managers to better face the daily challenges of rapid urbanization in their respective cities and towns Result 2: Cities concerned by the development of industrial parks such as Addis Ababa, Hawassa and Mekele, and the SNNP regional state, are able to proactively manage the urban development effects of these parks by enhancing integrated urban/metropolitan planning. Result 3: Municipal staff, communities and local stakeholders of Addis Ababa, Adama and Dire Dawa better understand human-induced and environmental risks and have identified priority actions for building urban resilience. Result 4: Coordination among urban agenda implementing partners in Ethiopia is enhanced. In general, the objective is clearly stated and found to be realistic in addressing urban&#xA0;challenges in the face of expansion&#xA0;of the industrial parks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT/United Nations Human Settlements Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41120" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlement Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46(0)8-698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waste management/disposal</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="11.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.a - Fr&#xE4;mja positiva ekonomiska, sociala och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssiga kopplingar mellan stadsomr&#xE5;den, stadsn&#xE4;ra omr&#xE5;den och landsbygdsomr&#xE5;den genom att st&#xE4;rka den nationella och regionala utvecklingsplaneringen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.a - Support positive economic, social and environmental links between urban, peri-urban and rural areas by strengthening national and regional development planning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">9.2 - Verka f&#xF6;r en inkluderande och h&#xE5;llbar industrialisering. Till 2030 avsev&#xE4;rt &#xF6;ka industrins andel av syssels&#xE4;ttning och BNP, i enlighet med nationella f&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden, och f&#xF6;rdubbla denna andel i de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">9.2 - Promote inclusive and sustainable industrialization and, by 2030, significantly raise industry&#x2019;s share of employment and gross domestic product, in line with national circumstances, and double its share in least developed countries.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">816993.4640522875</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">623949.0688353303</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">623949.0688353301</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">816993.4640522875</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1841112.0316671268</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">816993.4640522875</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">623949.0688353303</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">317262.2383908459</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. CAPACITY BUILDING FOR CITY LEADERSThe capacity of trained personnel in urban planning and management is a major constraint. On top of limited personnel capacity there is also limitations on setting up effective institutions for the effective implementation of targets set in Growth and Transformation Plan (GTP I) 2010-2015. Thus, cognizant to this, UN-Habitat kick-started the First Executive Lab (FEL) in March 2019 to build the capacity of urban sector. 76 trainees, including city mayors, city managers, senior experts and academics, attended the two-day event where an introductory training was given on broad themes related to urban development (Fundamentals of planned urbanization; Managing city Growth; Housing at the centre of urban policies).Around 80 participants with leadership position were eventually joined the City Lab (the initial objective being 100), which is very satisfactory.?&#xA0; Moreover,&#xA0; UN-Habitat has also organized several capacity building and experience sharing events- a series of events open to all throughout the month of October to discuss urban opportunities and challenges in Ethiopia, as well as to present practices and lessons learnt from abroad. 2. INTEGRATED URBAN AND REGIONAL PLANNING A comprehensive ToR is prepared for the preparation of a Regional Development Spatial Plan for Oromia regional state and Bahir Dar city. The regional planing for Bahir Dar is progressing well. Moreover,&#xA0;UN-Habitat&#xA0; presented three papers in three different workshops, including 1) sharing an international experience of urban planning process using Matrix of Function on an annual conference organized by BUPPIF and MUDCo in Bahir Dar; 2) a technical paper on the new strategic development framework model for regional development spatial planning on a workshop organized by BUPPIF in Addis Ababa; and 3) a technical paper on smart planning techniques (i.e. GIS) for staff of Bahir Dar University. Workshops held were positively perceived by stakeholders; the annual conference gathered more than 100 participants from various urban administrations, private consultants and academic institutions; the second workshop was organized in Addis Ababa for private consultants in the urban development realm, to discuss strategic development framework model in the regional development spatial planning. 3. URBAN PLANNING (TECHNICAL SUPPORT TO STRUCTURE PLAN OF BAHIR DAR, ADDIS ABABA AND DIRE DAWA/ JIJIGA City/metropolitan planning that will target some of the cities already concerned by the industrial parks initiative namely, Addis Ababa, Bahir Dar and JiJiga/ Dire Dawa.In the case of the Addis Ababa city, UN-Habitat has deployed three urban planners to be stationed in the Mayors office. The following activities are the major achievements in Addis Ababa city:- A review document to the exiting master plan of Addis Ababa prepared (a summary report enclosed)- Based on the review document of the Master plan, UN-Habitat is finalizing the design guidance for the Sheger project.&#xA0;- UN-Habitat organized a high level vision workshop as part of planning exercise&#xA0; Upon the request of Bahir Dar City (BDC) Administration, UN-Habitat is providing technical support for the urban planning team (i.e. Bahir Dar University) who is engaged in the preparation of the BDC structure plan. To this end, UN-Habitat assigned two senior urban planners (International and National) who are stationed in Bahir Dar city and work closely with the planning team helping to unlock challenges, provide support on spatial data analysis, conceptual plan preparation, prepare and review documents prepared by the team, etc. It is also giving mission-based technical support and trainings from regional and country offices. Based on UN-Habitat&#x2019;s technical support and trainings, the Bahir Dar city Administration has finalized the development the conceptual framework and get it approved by its council on September 2019 (the copy conceptual framework enclosed). 4. IMPLEMENTATION OF THE CITY RESILIENCE ACTION PLANNING (CITYRAP) TOOL The City Resilience for Action Planning (CityRAP) Tool, developed by UN-Habitat and the Technical Centre for Disaster Risk Management, Sustainability and Urban Resilience (DiMSUR), fosters bottom-up planning to increase the resilience of small/intermediate cities or sub-cities of larger metropolis to shock and stress. The tool promotes a participatory approach and results in a concrete framework for action that fully integrates the perspective of local stakeholders. The four phases of the CityRAP tool include: (i) building the understanding urban resilience; (ii) data collection through municipal self-assessment and participatory planning sessions in vulnerable neighbourhoods; (iii) data analysis and prioritization of actions; and (iv) developing the Resilience Framework for Action (RFA). Using the experience from Lideta sub-city in 2016, the tool is currently being replicated in Arada sub-city of Addis Ababa, Adama and Dire Dawa. 5.INSTITUTIONAL COORDINATION IN THE URBAN SECTORUN-Habitat has been working with the Ministry of Urban Development and Construction (MUDC) towards the establishment of the National Urban Agenda Partners platform. The main objective of this platform is to maximize the impact and synergies of sustainable urban development projects in Ethiopia by improving coordination among stakeholders working to promote the urban agenda in the country. Through this platform the government and development partners will work together to implement a single strategy for sustainable urbanization according to global and national frameworks.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11433" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01" strategy-total-amount="3870000000.0">
    <title>Regional Africa 2016-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
