<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="oneacrefund-activities" dstore:index="4" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-08T13:59:59+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-08T13:59:11+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-DOS-64562614-XM-DAC-7-PPR-29032/Uganda</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-DOS-64562614" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading the Charge to Eradicate Rural Poverty</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our prior project with the Dutch Government, &#x201C;Subsistence to Self-Reliance &#x2013; Bringing the Power of Markets to Africa&#x2019;s Lowest-Income Farmers&#x201D; underscored our shared passion for inclusive economic development and showcased the key milestones that we can accomplish together. Core operating support from DGIS facilitated the strategic expansion of One Acre Fund&#x2019;s &#x2018;impact ecosystem.&#x2019; Within two years, we doubled the scale of our farmer network, launched operations in two new country programs (Malawi and Uganda), and rolled out impactful new products like tree planting kits and clean cookstoves at country-wide scale. Simultaneously, we refined our innovative systems-change platform, leveraging our core organizational competencies to improve large-scale public and private actors&#x2019; service to smallholders. This success has now placed One Acre Fund in a position where we can realistically envision moving the needle on hunger and poverty across the entire African continent. Our current project with DGIS, &#x201C;Leading the Charge to Eradicate Rural Poverty,&#x201D; aims to capture this powerful opportunity. The project involves a smartly structured two-part investment spanning September 15, 2018 &#x2013; December 31, 2022: First, DGIS is once again providing critical support to the varied, evolving platforms within our organization that lay the foundation for our growth and impact. Core operating support from DGIS will enhance and extend One Acre Fund&#x2019;s proven model by funding key strategic priorities across our M&amp;E, R&amp;D, and new country expansion units. Secondly, DGIS is also providing working capital to revolutionize One Acre Fund&#x2019;s growth trajectory. This injection to our &#x2018;permanent fund&#x2019; will completely fund our projected expansion of 245,000+ new farm families in 2019, bringing us past the 1 millionth farmer milestone. Crucially, farmers&#x2019; loan repayments will replenish our permanent fund each year, allowing us to re-extend this contribution to provide input loans to an estimated 245,000 farm families (including over 980,000 children) annually. This project will anchor One Acre Fund&#x2019;s expansion to directly serve 1.85 million farm families annually by year-end 2022. Simultaneously, it will help us reach an additional 3.5 million farmers via systems-change partnerships that are expressly designed to transform entire agricultural ecosystems. Together, the reach of these efforts will generate transformative change for rural communities across rural Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Q3 2020 Country Update: Field staff are currently engaged in marketing and enrollment for the 2021 season, where we anticipate reaching an estimated 14,000 farm families. We have ambitious targets to have an average transaction size of $42 and increase the Field Officer:Farmer ratio from 222 to 265.  These are ambitious targets, but we hope to reach more farmers during this time of uncertainty due to COVID-19. In 2021, we will focus on proving our model, and ensuring that our results are consistent before expanding. We may also begin trialing partnerships to connect farmers with cash-crop markets, as we have already been approached by a number of organizations about crops such as chia, passion fruit, soybeans, and sorghum. We are targeting to resume growth in 2022, potentially by reopening a number of sites closed in 2018-19, as well as by looking outward to new sites.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-DOS-64562614" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Note that while project activities commenced on 2016-01-01, the grant agreement was signed on 2018-10-09.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Whitney McFerron</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Associate, One Acre Fund</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+33660474246</telephone>
   <email>whitney.mcferron@oneacrefund.org</email>
   <website>http://www.oneacrefund.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31150" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31193" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31192" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <related-activity ref="US-DOS-64562614-XM-DAC-7-PPR-29032-1" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core Program Scale</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared each Q1, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farm families participating in One Acre Fund&apos;s core program.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="8000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2018, we made the decision to reduce our program size to focus on the districts that had the highest loan repayment rates in 2018: Kamuli, Jinja, and Iganga. In 2019, these districts had a total of 8,000 farmers who signed up for our program. While this is slightly lower than the 10,000 farmers we served in 2018, it is above our initial target of 7,000 farmers this year. Significantly, this streamlining of our program has allowed us to refine our operations as we look towards future expansion.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11602">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the implementation of a second farmer season (short rains), we managed to enroll 14,000 farmers, above our country-wide target of 11,960. We attribute this positive result to farmer interest in our new crop offerings (especially beans and groundnuts), as well as reduced maize package pricing. The latter was made possible by trial findings from 2018 and 2019 that confirmed that farmers could use less fertilizer (and therefore purchase less) without hurting yields.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared in 2020 Q4 or 2021 Q1, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The profit boost achieved by farming with One Acre Fund.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our Uganda program attained an absolute impact of $18 in 2019. Unpredictable weather, droughts, and pests affected our clients&#x2019; harvests and food security, underscoring the need to build their capacities to adapt to climate change. Our insight about the profitability of maize in growth countries such as Uganda has led us to formulate new action plans to both improve the profitability of maize and promote alternative, resilience-focused interventions such as radical crop diversification. In Uganda, for example, we plan to trial new crops for which markets already exist such as beans, coffee, bananas, and vegetables.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="26">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are still collecting data from the 2020 harvest, so our impact estimates remain very preliminary. Based on the information we currently have, we foresee our 2020 impact coming in around $20-25. While a small improvement over 2019&#x2019;s results, the following factors had a negative effect: 1) erratic weather at critical maize development points this season, and 2) limited field agricultural support resulting from COVID-19 movement restrictions. The aim for next year will be to try and provide more precise field weather guidance to navigate more variable weather (climate change), and COVID-19 permitting, double down on field agricultural support.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Systems-Change Scale</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farm families reached through systems-change unit.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-12-08" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are not implementing any systems-change programs in Uganda; we are currently prioritizing our core program&apos;s operational performance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are not implementing any systems-change programs in Uganda; we are currently prioritizing our core program&apos;s operational performance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Return On Investment (SROI)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared in 2019 Q4 or 2020 Q1, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund&apos;s key cost-effectiveness measure.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="0.1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">SROI was below target, primarily due to the aforementioned impact shortfall. We would also like to note that in the early years, Kenya and Rwanda also had SROIs below 1 (it takes time to build client trust and realize higher transactions and economies of scale to improve SROI).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are conservatively expecting SROI to fall short of our 2020 target of 2:1. Our target was set in Q2 of 2019, before some of the impact challenges had emerged in Uganda. However, as we have adjusted the program, we are seeing an upward trajectory in impact and cost-effectiveness, which will drive long-term SROI. Some factors that are expected to drive improved SROI and cost-effectiveness: 
- Healthy repayment: Over 80% of the loan portfolio for the 2020 season has been collected, which is 2% above our healthy path. We are cautiously optimistic that we will achieve high repayment this season, despite the constraints of COVID. 

- Operational efficiency: We are pleased to report that we managed to increase the number of farmers per Field Officer from 137 in 2019 to 218. We were also able to increase the loan transaction size from $37 to $40. These efficiency gains were largely facilitated through roll-out of staff tablets and mobile repayment (now at full scale among our clients).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
