<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ia_nam-o60" dstore:index="29" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-12T11:32:55-05:00" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="56" last-updated-datetime="2017-11-19T01:57:46Z" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/9357" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-PCI-LR-14-9357</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ebola Community Care Center Program (EC3)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EC3 will work in conjunction with PCI&apos;s overall Ebola response activities funded by USAID/OFDA- including activities in the LAUNCH Title II program and OFDA-funded REACT program. Through EC3 PCI will help manage and support Ebola Community Care Centers (CCCs) in Bong and Nimba County and will provide assistance for rapid response efforts. EC3&apos;s activities will help slow the spread of Ebola through better isolation of cases and provide a higher standard of care for suspected and confirmed cases. Support activities will include WASH infrastructure for effective isolation and patient care, building the capacity of health care providers in patient care and infection prevention and control (IPC), and partner with other key agencies to provide key Personal Protective Equipment (PPEs) and other key supplies to CCCs.


EC3 will mobilize communities and key health partners at the local level to generate consensus and participation in the CCC strategy, identify and train staff and community members in the management of CCCs, provide access to key materials as well as supervision of the CCC management, and reinforce the capacity of nearby health facilities to manage the outbreak and prevent the spread of Ebola through CCCs and upgrading WASH infrastructure.

PCI will be using a geo-referenced data to track elements of the outbreak and the supply of services through CCCs. This will include the use of GIS-enabled mobile phones for use in reporting of case loads and other trends and data from CCCs. The data will be shared with the MOHSW and other partners. 

PCI will leverage its existing working relationships with local health staff and health facilities and support trained community health workers to manage the CCCs, as well as mobilize cleaners, security, a community mobilizer and protection officer, and burial teams (in collaboration with broader burial strategies implemented in coordination with the MOHSW and Global Communities). 

Training will cover Ebola transmission and prevention, proper patient triage and patient flows for CCCs;  IPC,provision of ORS, antipyretics and presumptive treatment with antimalarials and broad-spectrum antibiotics when medical supervision is available; specimen collection for laboratory confirmation of Ebola virus; and psychosocial support for patients, their families, children and the disabled. PCI will also provide psychosocial support to staff and colleagues working at the CCCs.

PCI has worked to identify and address the specialized vulnerabilities and needs of community members related to Ebola since the outbreak began. This includes directly addressing the unique vulnerabilities of women in their roles as caregivers, traditional midwives, and in burial practices, for example. PCI will incorporate these lessons learned and messages into information and awareness materials for individuals attending the CCCs. These materials will address a range of topics, such as unique vulnerabilities to Ebola (such as for caregivers, health providers, traditional midwives, and for those regularly participating in traditional burial practices). PCI will also develop materials (and/or utilize standard materials from other agencies) intended for children and youth on how to understand Ebola and prevent its spread. 

PCI will guarantee that all of its CCCs have clear protocols for the handling of unaccompanied minors at CCCs, in collaboration with local counterparts, and will utilize its resources and networks from other USAID-funded programs in the target area to provide follow up for family tracing, re-unification, and reintegration of unaccompanied minors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social and Behavior Change Communication, Community Mobilization, Water and Sanitation, Disaster Risk Reduction, Health Training, Commodity Distribution, Rapid Response</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-95-2248462" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Concern International (PCI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of Foreign Disaster Assistance (USAID/OFDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of Foreign Disaster Assistance (USAID/OFDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="PCI-LR-14-9357" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-05" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-05" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Concern International (PCI)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jim DiFrancesca</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director, Humanitarian Assistance Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>jdifrancesca@pciglobal.org</email>
   <website>http://www.pciglobal.org/ebola</website>
   <website>http://www.pciglobal.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_2274688">
   <location-id code="2274688" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nimba</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nimba, Liberia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2274688" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.81667 -8.78333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_2278292">
   <location-id code="2278292" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bong</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bong, Liberia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2278292" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.96667 -9.63333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="8" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="18" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-05">4128390</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of Foreign Disaster Assistance (USAID/OFDA)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-95-2248462">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Concern International (PCI)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.pciglobal.org/ebola">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-11-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-05"></period-end>
     <target value="17280"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
