<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ia_nam-o27" dstore:index="161" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-31T08:25:08-04:00" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="222" last-updated-datetime="2019-07-30T15:47:36Z" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17866" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ERD-GN-16-17866</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglican Integrated Development Project for Communities Affected by Ebola</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The last two years have been challenging for the people of Guinea, particularly resulting from the Ebola epidemic. Aside from the persons directly infected by the disease, the general health and economic infrastructure in the country was greatly impacted. Many families in-country are without consistent sources of income and food. For the ADG, of it&apos;s four health facilities, one was completely closed down and two lost critical staff posted by the government because the facilities lacked some basic amenities for care, thus placing the health workers themselves at risk. Essential medicines for treatment of diarrhea, malaria and pneumonia at the clinic level are non-available, eroding the system where community health workers are empowered to care and refer severe cases to these health centers. The Anglican diocese of Guinea, is seeking to inspire its diocesans and community members to begin the rebuilding of their lives and possibly from this point achieve greater independence and prosperity than was the situation before the disease outbreak hence this project named Anglican integrated development project for communities affected by Ebola. This project seeks to utilize the assets of the church in the form of over 100 hectares of unused farmlands to empower the diocesans to be able to build their own farms to generate income for the family, community and the church. The project shall support the ADG to develop a group formation structure by helping the participating community members form three farming groups. These groups would receive training in governance of the associations and logistical management. Once formed, delegates from each association and staff of ADG designated would have a participatory training session aimed at agreeing to the use of the land both to generate income, food and for use as a learning space from which all participants could learn something and replicate on their individual farms. This project would provide technical support in growing of identified specific crops for the season. The church has extensive farmlands in the Fallanghia area. Fallanghia is about 90 miles North east of Conakry in the Dubreka prefecture of Kindia province. Fallanghia is home to Guinea&#x2019;s first Anglican church and the church here has farmlands covering about 100 hectares. These would be designated as model farms for three associations constituted around mothers, youth and men respectively. These farms would be cultivated in a climate smart manner. This project seeks to support the ADG to revive the coordination of community based health promotion and clinical referral. To achieve this, the project will refurbish one of the health centers administered by ADG in Fallanghia. The refurbished clinic would also be able to manage referred cases of diarrhea, pneumonia and malaria from the communities. It is envisioned that these interventions by the ADG would be sustainable in that the farms would generate income and food, and a portion of income would be set aside for reinvestment in the land and the program. The health facility will generate income from services, a proportion of which would be used to keep the facility functional.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women of Reproductive Age, Men</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training in climate smart agriculture. Training of 28 health volunteers in identification of malaria, diarrhea and pneumonia and referral, refurbish the Fallanghia health centers administered by ADG.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Guinea</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ERD-GN-16-17866" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="842167BC-0BB8-46EA-8D6A-107EE2C5DDBC" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-73-1635264">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Episcopal Relief &amp; Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>program@episcopalrelief.org</email>
   <website>http://www.episcopalrelief.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_8335088">
   <location-id code="8335088" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kindia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kindia, Guinea (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="8335088" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.08667 -13.21333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6204"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
