<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="acet-activities" dstore:index="43" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-10-01T20:27:45+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-30T15:59:56+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-11-3803281-ATF2020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-11-3803281" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Transformation Forum 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACET in q3 commenced planning for the third African Transformation forum to be held in Kenya. Over the report period, ACET has agreed on the focus and agenda of the ATF. We are clear about the positioning of the ATF in terms of focus areas, key interlocutors and how to integrate the TLP members&#x2019; contributions. We have defined the event objectives and established a plan on how to reach those objectives. ACET also undertook the first recognisant visit to Nairobi, where the Forum will take place, to explore the available facilities and associated logistics. We have since selected a facility for the event that corresponds to our expectations in terms of security, standards and logistics. During the trip to Nairobi, we also engaged with the office of the President, the chief of staff, and the deputy chief of staff. This meeting was highly important to ensure that the President has bought in to the event and are ready to host the event. The deputy chief of staff has engaged a team around her to support the organisation of the event. Lastly, we have enhanced our efforts in terms of seeking sponsorships for the ATF. Several meetings have been held in this regard, and we are currently in advanced negotiations with key potential funders/sponsors. This process has been supported by consultants procured through the TAP procurement system. In mid-November, ACET&#x2019;s COO Daniel Nti, went on a second trip to Nairobi to further advance discussions with the Kenyatta Government as well as other key stakeholders in the country. He was accompanied by Dr. Julius Gatune, Senior Research Fellow with ACET, who serves as ACET&#x2019;s liaison on ground with the Government of Kenya and all institutions with a stake in delivering the ATF. Some key achievements during the period include: &#x2022; The successful selection of facility for the event that corresponds to our expectations in terms of security, standards and logistics. &#x2022; The substantial progress made in solidifying communications plans around the event, finalizing the invitation list, and coordinating with the Government of Kenya as well as the various Heads of States expected to be in attendance. &#x2022; The significant efforts made in terms of seeking sponsorships for the ATF. Several meetings have been held in this regard, and we are currently in advanced negotiations with key potential funders/sponsors. This process has been supported by consultants procured through the TAP procurement system The African Transformation Forum was on course to take place as scheduled June 17th and 18th, 2020 in Nairobi, Kenya. However, in the wake of the COVID-19 outbreak, ACET had to visit Nairobi on March 3rd -6th for consultations with the Government of Kenya on the need to postpone the Forum. The nascent date for the forum is January 2021 in Nairobi, Kenya. Partners and delegates have been duly informed of these developments. In the interim, ACET continues to work in preparation towards the conference with the tentative January 2021 delivery date by reworking and updating the agenda, engaging and updating the current list of panelists, moderators, and other facilitators. We are also developing the various required content for discussions at the Forum and coming up with various scenarios and accompanying strategic interventions factoring the availability of various service providers and suppliers such as the venue. Additionally, ACET will continue liaising with the Government of Kenya to ensure alignment with all plans.


ATF 2020 was initially planned as physical event to be held in Nairobi, Kenya in early 2021. However, given the uncertainty around future developments and implications of COVID-19, ACET is planning to host a series of virtual events in 2021.  Work is currently ongoing to adapt the agenda to the new format, engage panelists, moderators, and other facilitators. This will also require additional communications activities to develop content, a marketing and communication strategy that is tailored for an online audience (videos, interviews with Heads of State, etc).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ATF2020" crs-channel-code="21000" ref="US-EIN-11-3803281" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-16" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The planned date for the launch is 16-18th June 2019</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya is the host country</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">88813.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">121500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">91357.67</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">87460</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC09 Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">32077</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC09 Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">385</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated travel and hotel expeses from April-June 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC09 Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">54741</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from April - June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC09 Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">3000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost for the period July-Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC09 Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">14629.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulatedcost of travel, hotel etc for the months July to sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC09 Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">30593.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the months July to Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET EC09 Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">12770.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost for the period July to Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC09 Q1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">13784</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultatncy cost from Jan -March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC09-Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">2617.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated travel and hotel expenses from Jan to March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC09 Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">73974</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulted staff cost from Jan to March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC09 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">16835.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from Oct-Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC09 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">13842.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated travel and hotel expenses from Oct-Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC09 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">89317.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from Oct-Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET EC09 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">657.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost from Oct-Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
