<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="acet-activities" dstore:index="37" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-28T23:04:50+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-28T23:01:10+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-11-3803281-TLP</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-11-3803281" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transformation Leadership Panel</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transformation Leadership Panel (TLP) is comprised of a number of global leaders that will convene around a common cause: to advocate for action at the highest levels of government and regional institutions&#x2014;including directly engaging with Heads of State, Ministers, and bodies such as the African Union&#x2014;around urgent issues on: climate, population, innovation, and integration. In doing so, the TLP also can help provide intellectual leadership, directional guidance, and technical expertise for the next edition of ACET&#x2019;s flagship publication, African Transformation Report (ATR) 2020, which will focus on these same issues through the prism of leadership requirements and key policy actions. In this context, six broad goals for the TLP are envisioned: 1. To form an influential group of difference-makers. 2. To leverage Panel expertise into something immediate and tangible. 3. To galvanize action. 4. To get institutions to work together. 5. To advocate for Africa on the global stage. 6. To draw our own lessons. There are currently fifteen (15) members of the panel, chaired by Her Excellency Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf. The Inaugural meeting of the TLP is set to take place in Accra, Ghana on the 15th and 16th of July 2019. Currently (first quarter), in preparation towards the inaugural meeting, the TLP Secretariat is working closely with McKinsey &amp; Company based in Johannesburg, to set the agenda for the first TLP meeting. McKinsey will be arranging a short interview with each Panel member to ensure that member concerns, motivations, and expectations for the TLP are noted in advance, and incorporated into the agenda. Most importantly, the interviews will allow members to consider the ways in which they envision the TLP helping them and their organizations achieve goals. In preparation towards the inaugural meeting, the TLP Secretariat worked closely with McKinsey &amp; Company to set the agenda for the first TLP meeting. McKinsey arranged short interviews with panel members to ensure that member concerns, motivations, and expectations for the TLP were noted in advance and incorporated into the agenda. Most importantly, the interviews allowed members to consider the ways in which they envision that the TLP can help them and their organizations to achieve pre-determined goals. The TLP inaugural meeting was held on the 15th -16th of July, 2019. Update for the 3rd quarter :On July 15-16, ACET hosted the inaugural TLP meeting in Accra, Ghana. Twelve of the 16 panel members participated, as well as special guest the Honorable Ken Ofori-Atta, Minister of Finance of Ghana and Chairman of the World Bank&#x2019;s Development Committee. A primary focus of the meeting was to ensure collective agreement on the panel&#x2019;s objectives and the way forward. After considerable discussion, the TLP members agreed on the following vision statement: &#x201C;Our pledge is to influence leaders to take urgent action to achieve transformative change in Africa by 2030. Individually and, together as a panel, we will influence policies on four critical issues: climate, regional integration, digital innovation and demographics.&#x201D; Likewise, the members agreed that the group should be guided by an overall goal. In the spirit of the United Nations&#x2019; goals on gender, the TLP discussed an overarching goal of achieving gender parity in leadership across sectors in Africa by 2030. (A related key discussion point addressed the need for a database of women who can be recommended for leadership positions in the public and private sectors.) Additionally, the panel endorsed the four primary themes for ATR 2020. Key next steps discussed at the meeting include: &#x2022; Agreement that the TLP should meet twice annually. The next meeting was proposed to take place just prior to the African Union Summit in February 2020 in Addis Ababa. Dates will be proposed to the panel as soon as possible. &#x2022; Consideration to expand TLP membership to include youth representatives and additional African and global experts. &#x2022; Agreement that ACET would establish a secretariat for the TLP to ensure effective communication and support functions. &#x2022; Agreement that the TLP will provide continued intellectual leadership, directional guidance, and technical expertise, as well as focused advocacy, for ATR 2020. Following the inaugural meeting of the Transformation Leadership Panel (TLP) in July 2018, ACET has been requested to establish a Secretariat for the TLP. The Secretariat will facilitate the TLP&#x2019;s efforts to influence leaders to take urgent action for transformative change in Africa by 2030, with a primary focus on policy actions in four broad areas&#x2014;demographics, innovation, climate, and regional integration&#x2014;and with an overarching goal of gender parity in leadership across all sectors. Planning for the next meeting in February in Addis Ababa (logistics, agenda, invites) is on track. The second meeting will be a continuation of the agreements made in Accra in July. It will be hosted by the Economic Commission for Africa with a focus on (1) reviewing key baseline inputs for discussion and feedback, and (2) taking definitive steps to move the TLP process forward ahead of the June 2020 African Transformation Forum (ATF 2020). We have added two new members to the TLP, Agnes Kalibata from AGRA and Stefano Manservisi - the DG for International Cooperation and Development (DEVCO) at the European Commission. The second Transformation Leadership Panel (TLP) meeting was held on February 27-28, 2020 in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. The meeting hosted and chaired by Vera Songwe, ECA Executive Secretary was graced by 11 of the panel members. The primary goal of the meeting was to address key areas of thematic focus (gender, jobs, Africa-Europe relations, domestic resource mobilization, ATR, ATI and the ATF) for the TLP and ACET and to seek inputs on flagship deliverables. A brief review of the meeting and key outcomes can be found via the link below https://bit.ly/2ndTLPMeetingReview


ACET held a virtual meeting on May 27,2020 to address the impact of COVID-19 on the African continent and to approve a ten-point action plan to help governments revive their economies after the crisis. The meeting included special guests Mr. Albert Zeufack, World Bank Chief Economist for the Africa Region; and Mr. Stefan Oswald, Director General, German Federal Ministry of Development. The meeting focused on actions currently being taken across Africa, the impacts and challenges of recovery, and urgent focal points for global leaders, policymakers, and the development community at large. Members expressed the urgency to ensure that African governments and development partners grasp the full extent of the crisis impacts and react accordingly.


During the open discussion, members explored the challenges that governments face between caring for lives and caring for livelihoods. In particularly the panel discussed:

&#x2022;	Jobs: Lockdowns across Africa created immense economic hardships and swelled unemployment. Governments responded by creating social protection and cash transfer programs estimated at more than $70 billion. 
&#x2022;	Food security: On the supply side, there has been disruption to the movement of people and other inputs as the planting season has begun in some regions. Additionally, governments largely have inadequate strategic stores. 
&#x2022;	Liquidity: In April, the G20 announced bilateral debt relief programs to help countries respond to the pandemic. However, only two African countries to date have been able to access any relief and even with those countries it is unclear how or if that relief has resulted in increased liquidity. 
&#x2022;	Education: Gains made in access to education and participation may be at a heightened risk as young people are forced to stay home amidst lockdowns. But based on evidence from countries that imposed similar lockdowns during the Ebola outbreaks, enrolment rates may be notably lower when schools reopen, particularly for girls.
&#x2022;	Gender. In addition to concerns over education, members highlighted a range of gender-related issues in need of special attention in the post-COVID-19 recovery period, including increasing employment opportunities and addressing domestic violence.

The World Bank and ACET are collaborating on the implementation of the ten policy recommendations, while leveraging TLP members and their organizations to support African governments. TLP Members tasked the secretariat with placing an op-ed in a global media outlet that will focus on a few key messages in support of the urgent actions that are required of both African governments and the global development community. Members also agreed to develop a call to action for global leaders regarding financing and issue of debt and liquidity.

In Q3 2020, the panel agreed to develop a call to action for African leaders as one outcome of the May 27 COVID-19 response meeting. In July, a ten-point plan was agreed and signed by the members and was distributed to African Union Member countries through the African Union Commission.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">15800</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">65500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">157069.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">60854.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">111683.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">48190.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">33300</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC15-B Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">20034</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from July-September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC15-B Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">11715</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from July-September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC 15-B Q4 2019">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">8663.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy fees from Oct -Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC15-B Q12019">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-31">358.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated Consultancy Cost from Jan- March 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC15-B Q1 2019">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-31">1576.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated travel cost from Jan-March 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC15-B Q1 2019">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-31">13398.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from Jan-March 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC15-B Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">1290</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated cost incurred on communication and publication from July-September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC15-B Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">40568.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated travel and hotel cost from Oct-Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC15-B Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">8268.87</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4 ACET EC15-B Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">2153.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated Administrative expenses from Oct-Dec</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="5.ACET EC15-B Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">850.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost from Oct-Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC15-B Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">27889.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost fro the period July to Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC15-B Q2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">6441.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost on TLP for the second quarter (1 April-30 June 2019)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC15-B Q2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">8826.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated Travel and hotel cost for the second quarter (1 April -30th June 2019)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC15-B Q2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">60651.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the second quarter (1 April -30th June 2019)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC 15-B Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">31294</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC15-B Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">1565</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated trave/ and hotel expenditure from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC15-B Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">13488</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost incurred from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET EC15-B Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">2330</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated expenditure on communication and publication</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC15-B Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">17851.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated travel and hotel expenses for the period July-Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC15-B Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">79220.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost fro the period July to September 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET EC15-B Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">19275.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated cost on lecture and workshop incurred during the period July to Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="5. ACET EC15-B Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">5352.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated cost on Communication and publication incurred from July to Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC15- B Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">34906</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of all consultancy expenses incurred during Q1 2020 (Jan-March)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC15-B Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">48461.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of travel &amp; hotel expenditure for the period Jan to March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC15-B Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">30379</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the period Jan-March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET EC15-B Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">216.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated expenses on Communication and publications for the period Jan -March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
