<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="fomin-rg" dstore:index="12" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-23T13:09:44" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-23T13:09:54" linked-data-uri="https://www.iadb.org/en/project/RG-L1144" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-MIF-RG-L1144</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-MIF" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multilateral Investment Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pago46: Revolutionazing Payments for Vulnerable Populations in Times of COVID-19</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">Pago46: Pagos Revolucionarios para Poblaciones Vulnerables en Tiempos de COVID-19</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="PT">N/A</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">N/A</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project objective is to improve the ability of the region&apos;s consumers to access products and services available through digital platforms, by supporting the consolidation of an innovative payments solution &#x2013;advanced by Pago46&#x2013; that brings together cash and digital transactions and also generates additional income opportunities in the gig economy. To achieve this, the project will provide crisis response financing to Pago46 under the Emergency Financing Line for Startups and Scaleups (LIFESS) Line of Activity, to help this startup cope with the effects of COVID-19 and carry on its business, while it completes its capital raising efforts. Pago46 is a regional startup offering an innovative on-demand cash-to-digital payments solution that delivers payment services to last mile clients. Pago46&apos;s solution is innovative in two ways: (i) it allows unbanked or underbanked consumers to pay with cash for goods and services being offered digitally, right from the place where the consumers are located and with minimized contact with the payment collection agent or the merchant; (ii) it takes advantage of LAC&apos;s growing gig economy market to mobilize a massive network of Pago46 mobile &quot;agents&quot; to facilitate the transactions. This activity also creates additional income opportunities for the agents, who often come from lower socio-economic class themselves. IDB Lab&apos;s contribution of up to US$600,000 will consist of a bridge financing, structured as a senior loan with an option to convert into Pago46&apos;s equity stock, at a future capitalization round. IDB Lab&#xB4;s financing will be used by Pago46&apos;s as working capital to fund its operations and to generate improvements in the company software, applications and technology related to its payment products and services in its current countries of operation and to expand services to Ecuador. As a result, this project is expected to benefit consumers and users of Pago46 payment services in Argentina, Chile, Mexico and, potentially, Ecuador to gain access to the digital economy and small businesses and gig economy workers to benefit from additional income opportunities, as Pago46 agents.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">El objetivo del proyecto es mejorar la capacidad de los consumidores de la regi&#xF3;n para acceder a productos y servicios disponibles a trav&#xE9;s de plataformas digitales, apoyando la consolidaci&#xF3;n de una soluci&#xF3;n de pagos innovadora, promovida por Pago46, que re&#xFA;ne efectivo y transacciones digitales y tambi&#xE9;n genera oportunidades de ingresos adicionales en la econom&#xED;a &quot;gig&quot;. Para lograr esto, el proyecto proporcionar&#xE1; financiamiento de respuesta a crisis a Pago46 bajo la L&#xED;nea de Actividad de Financiamiento de Emergencia para Startups y Scaleups (LIFESS), para ayudar a esta startup a hacer frente a los efectos de COVID-19 y continuar con su negocio, mientras completa sus esfuerzos de recaudaci&#xF3;n de capital. Pago46 es una startup regional que ofrece una innovadora soluci&#xF3;n de pagos de efectivo a digital &apos;a pedido&apos; que ofrece servicios de pago a clientes de &#xFA;ltima milla. La soluci&#xF3;n de Pago46 es innovadora de dos maneras: (i) permite que los consumidores no bancarizados o no bancarizados paguen en efectivo por los bienes y servicios que se ofrecen digitalmente, directamente desde el lugar donde se encuentran los consumidores y con un contacto m&#xED;nimo con el agente de cobranza o el comerciante; (ii) aprovecha el creciente mercado de la econom&#xED;a gig de Am&#xE9;rica Latina y el Caribe para movilizar una red masiva de agentes m&#xF3;viles de Pago46 para facilitar las transacciones. Esta actividad tambi&#xE9;n crea oportunidades de ingresos adicionales para los agentes, que a menudo provienen de la clase socioecon&#xF3;mica m&#xE1;s baja. La contribuci&#xF3;n de BID Lab de hasta US $ 600,000 consistir&#xE1; en un financiamiento puente, estructurado como un pr&#xE9;stamo senior con la opci&#xF3;n de convertirlo en acciones de Pago46, en una futura ronda de capitalizaci&#xF3;n. El financiamiento de BID Lab ser&#xE1; utilizado por Pago46 como capital de trabajo para financiar sus operaciones y generar mejoras en el software, las aplicaciones y la tecnolog&#xED;a de la compa&#xF1;&#xED;a relacionados con sus productos y servicios de pago en sus pa&#xED;ses de operaci&#xF3;n actuales y para expandir los servicios a Ecuador. Como resultado, se espera que este proyecto beneficie a los consumidores y usuarios de los servicios de pago de Pago46 en Argentina, Chile, M&#xE9;xico y, potencialmente, Ecuador para obtener acceso a la econom&#xED;a digital y a peque&#xF1;as empresas y trabajadores de la econom&#xED;a de conciertos para beneficiarse de m&#xE1;s oportunidades de ingresos, como agentes de Pago46.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="ORC" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ordinary capital</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-MIF" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MULTILATERAL INVESTMENT FUND</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="CH-PCSPA" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pago46 Chile Sociedad por Acciones</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="CH-PCSPA" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pago46 Chile Sociedad por Acciones</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="RG-L1144" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multilateral Investment Fund</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-11" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MULTILATERAL INVESTMENT FUND</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone></telephone>
   <email></email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="498" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="FM-INC" percentage="100" vocabulary="99"></sector>
  <sector code="24040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-finance-type code="410"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="11/30/2020-RG-L1144-3-MSF">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-30">150000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement in fourth quarter of 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="7/31/2020-RG-L1144-2-ALL">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-31">600000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment in third quarter of 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.iadb.org/en/project/RG-L1144">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RG-L1144</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
