<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-th" dstore:index="13" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-01T00:00:43" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-15T02:42:54" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-43415</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWC Green Loan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFCs proposed investment is a green loan of Thai Baht (THB) 4,500 million (equivalent of US$137 million) to Asset World Corp Public Company Limited (AWC or the Company). The IFC green loan, expected to be compliant with the International Capital Market Association (ICMA) Green Bond Principles, will be used toward energy efficiency measures in the refurbishment of four hotels, the greenfield development of two new hotels in key tourism destinations of Thailand including Bangkok, Hua Hin, Koh Samui and Chiang Mai and working capital to support the gradual re-opening of hotels following Covid-19-related shutdowns.  AWC is the key real estate and hospitality arm of Thai Charoen Company (TCC) Group (the Group).&#xA0; AWC is the largest hospitality operator in Thailand by number of rooms and has a growing and diverse portfolio of assets in hospitality and lifestyle destinations, retail and commercial workspaces, with ten retail centers and four office buildings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Job Creation: In terms of local employment, IFC expects the Project to create several direct jobs for the two new hotels such as receptionists, cleaners, security, restaurant workers as well as the indirect jobs in the hotel&apos;s supply chain and related linkages such as taxi companies and tour guides. It is expected that [XX%] will be female employment.
2) Domestic suppliers: The Project will also include refurbishments of old hotels, improving the quality of buildings and service offerings, which is in line with the Thai Ministry of Sports and Tourism and the Tourism Authority of Thailand (TAT)&apos;s objective of shifting Thailand&apos;s offering from &quot;mass-market, quantity&quot; to &quot;high-value, quality&quot;.  Local suppliers of goods and services will benefit from greater demand for higher volume and from demand for better quality products and services that allow for greater value added. Close to 100% of AWC suppliers are domestic.  
3) Effect on employees: On average, 60 hours of training will be provided to a hotel employee. The training is given all staff, even hourly employees, and includes essential skill and knowledge areas such as culinary, rooms operation and purchasing, as well as other discipline-specific skills in finance, HR, IT, loss prevention, marketing and sales.  In addition, most of the international hotel brands which AWC use are committed to developing people.  Managerial staff participate in management training programs. . By upskilling its employees, AWC will contribute to the mobility of these employees who can progress to higher level jobs in the same company or move to other companies in the services sector. 
4) Effect on sourcing: Thailand&apos;s hotel supply chain is made up of many small and medium size enterprises (SMEs) including small manufacturing companies and smallholder farmers linked to the hotel food and beverage and procurement value chain. AWC estimates that it procures around 30% from local SMEs including give examples. AWC has worked with local suppliers to improve the quality to meet the standards of the renown global hotel operators such as Marriott, Le Meridien, Hilton and Sheraton.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSET WORLD CORPPUBLIC COMPANY LIMITED.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-43415" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asset World Corp Public Company Limited  Dr. Karn Prativedwannakij  Chief Financial Officer  +6621809999  karn.p@assetworldcorp-th.com  56th FL. Empire Tower, 1 South Sathorn Rd., Yannawa, Sathorn, Bangkok 10120 Thailand  https://www.assetworldcorp-th.com/</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  The SII will be disclosed locally at the following address:       Asset World Corp   Public Company Limited   Head Office    56th FL. Empire Tower, 1 South Sathorn Rd.,   Yannawa  , Sathorn, Bangkok 10120 Thailand</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TH-Thailand">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The refurbishments and new construction activities comprising the Project will be located in key tourism hubs throughout Thailand including Bangkok, Hua Hin, Koh Samui and Chiang Mai.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.5000000000 101.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="7211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U-AA - City and Business Hotel</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $144.83 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-16">144830000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-16">144830000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSET WORLD CORPPUBLIC COMPANY LIMITED.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/43415">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
