<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" dstore:dataset="danida-all_7" dstore:index="1013" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-26T04:45:05" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-26T04:45:07" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286138</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark&apos;</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DACAAR activities in Afghanistan 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims at improving livelihoods, health and life quality on a sustainable basis for returnees, protracted IDPs and their vulnerable host communities. By the completion of the project, beneficiaries would have improved livelihoods as measured by reduced time in collecting water and increased time spent on food production, income generation and girls&#x2019; and boys&#x2019; education, improved health as measured by a reduction in water borne diseases, and an overall improvement in the quality of life as perceived by the targeted men, women, boys and girls. The integrated nature and the diverse targeting strategy of the interventions will enable addressing of the needs and priorities of the communities from different angles; access to and use of safe drinking water coupled with open defecation free villages and improved hygiene behavior will reduce the incidence of diseases (including COVID19) which will in turn enable communities to invest increased time, energy and resources into learning new skills and engaging in various farm and off farm income generating activities offered by the intervention. The interventions planned will particularly target at risk individuals and households such as women-headed households, youth susceptible to embracing negative coping mechanisms, impoverished farmers and individuals with disability. Based on learning since outbreak of Covid-19 in March 2020the interventions for this extension period will also focus on helping communities to reduce the negative economic impact of COVID19 pandemic.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 43118</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>NA</telephone>
   <email>NA</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286138-34690" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
