<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2563" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-06-03T23:06:23+02:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-03T23:06:23+02:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <budget>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01"></value>
  </budget>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1"></country-budget-items>
  <crs-add>
   <loan-status currency="USD"></loan-status>
  </crs-add>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The COVID-19 pandemic is primarily a global health crisis, but it also has far-reaching economic consequences. Worldwide, it is already disrupting millions of people&#x2019;s livelihoods, with disproportionate impact on the poor, thereby jeopardizing the successful achievement of the United Nations Sustainable Development Agenda 2030. In order to meet an unprecedented global challenge of the COVID-19 pandemic, there is a high demand for the international community to provide an agile and suitable response towards the socio-economic impacts worldwide, in particular concerning fragile health infrastructures in developing and emerging countries. Recognizing this challenge and the need for international commitment and solidarity, the Government of Japan (GoJ) is providing the supplementary budget to UNIDO in order to show their responsibility to meet an increasing demand for emergency support. In addition, the GoJ recognizes the need to support Japanese technology providers, especially small and medium enterprises (SMEs), which own their technical know-how but have limited channels to meet the global demand. Therefore, the project aims: (1) to support developing and emerging countries to improve health, sanitary and hygiene environment to fight against COVID-19 and other infectious diseases through technology transfer; (2) to leverage capacity of Japanese enterprises, especially SMEs, to meet the demand in this emergent situation; and (3) to demonstrate UNIDO&#x2019;s commitment to the GoJ to support their efforts for the international cooperation to fight against COVID-19 crisis.
Since UNIDO ITPO Tokyo has a profound experience in promoting sustainable and innovative technologies and know-how owned by Japanese companies to developing countries, UNIDO ITPO Tokyo plays a role to facilitate technology transfer, backstopped by ITPO Coordinator as the Project Manager at UNIDO HQs. The project complements its current project (SAP ID 160239) to promote applicable technologies through demonstration and technology transfer, including the &#x201C;Human Health Technologies&#x201D;, registered in the UNIDO ITPO Tokyo&apos;s Sustainable Technologies Promotion Platform (STePP).</narrative>
  </description>
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200108</iati-identifier>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200108" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the capacity of developing countries to mitigate the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic through appropriate technology transfer from Japan</narrative>
  </title>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
