<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" dstore:dataset="danida-all_7" dstore:index="1120" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T04:11:11" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T04:11:15" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286183</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark&apos;</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing the Safety of Journalists in Africa and the Arab Region - UNESCO (media freedom, freedom of expression)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With its mandate in the field of communication and information, UNESCO leads the efforts of the UN System to secure freedom of expression, media freedom, safety of journalists, access to information and combatting mis- and disinformation. The Organisation has provided an important voice to these issues during the COVID-19 pandemic and will continue to counter its negative effects in the aftermath.
Denmark is a member (2019-2023) of the Intergovernmental Council of UNESCO&apos;s International Programme for the Development of Communication (IPDC) and is heavily engaged in UNESCO&apos;s ongoing efforts on freedom of expression, the rights and safety of journalists, and combatting disinformation. The idea is to build on the political engagement by supporting these efforts in developing countries with a financial contribution to a UNESCO-project (2021-2022), enhancing the safety of journalists in Africa and the Arab region. The project will be closely linked to UNESCO&apos;s Multi Donor Special Account on Freedom of Expression and Safety of Journalists, which is primarily funded by other Nordic countries. The effort will help respond to pertinent issues on rights and freedoms arising from the COVID-19 crisis, where the global media landscape has faced challenges including legislative changes, policies, and other measures, altering the working conditions of media professionals, during and after the Pandemic. The objective is to contribute to peace, sustainable development, and democracy through promoting human rights and the safety of journalists, in support of the UN Plan of Action on the Safety of Journalists and the Issue of Impunity (UN Plan), by focusing on the UN Plan&#x2019;s &#x201C;Three Ps&#x201D;: the prevention, protection against, and prosecution of crimes and attacks against journalists. The work of UNESCO in supporting free, pluralistic, independent, safe, and gender-sensitive media is relevant to several objectives of Denmark. Promoting the safety of journalists and combating impunity incre</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286183-34765" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
