<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2631" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-01T08:30:01+02:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-01T08:30:01+02:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200144</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing the provision of personal protective equipment in Africa: Strengthening the resilience of the industrial and healthcare sectors to COVID-19 and future pandemics</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project objectives are the improved supply of quality-assured, locally manufactured PPE (personal protective equipment), hand sanitizer and disinfectants to reduce the incidence of COVID-19 transmission in Africa and improve the response capacity of national healthcare systems on the continent (medical equipment, specifically ventilators and related equipment, may also be included dependent on inception phase outcomes). The objectives are achieved through the strengthening of both healthcare systems and infrastructure on the continent, as well as strengthening of manufacturers and related value chains such that production and related capabilities are increased. Alongside this, the project aims to reduce the socioeconomic impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on African countries through both securing existing employment positions the relevant manufacturing and related industries, as well as creating additional employment opportunities through industrial expansion.
The project outcome is an increased ability for African countries to meet their needs for COVID-19 PPE, sanitizer and disinfectant supply, through local sourcing of quality-assured products, and consequent reduced reliance on imports. Alongside this, the strengthened manufacturing industry will improve employment prospects, reducing the direct economic impact of the COVID-19 crisis on individuals, countries and the continent as a whole.
The project will apply a series of modular service packages in order to achieve its objectives. These include development and dissemination of guidelines covering PPE requirements for both the public and private sectors, including national regulatory bodies and industry, as well as providing training and strategic support services to companies moving into and/or increasing PPE, sanitizer and disinfectant production. Alongside this, the provision of quality and standards training and support to industry and relevant certifying bodies will assure the manufacture of effective, quality assured products meeting certification requirements.
The project will be implemented in a series of countries across the continent, to ensure broad regional coverage, namely Egypt (North Africa), Ethiopia and Kenya (East Africa), South Africa (South Africa), Senegal (West Africa). The service packages will be designed such that they can both be readily and efficiently rolled out into each country, whilst allowing tailoring to meet individual country requirements. There will be an initial assessment and analytical phase in each country followed by implementation of the required service packages.
The service packages will be designed to allow efficient and cost effective expansion to further territories, beyond the five countries listed above, when opportunities arise for project expansion and associated additional funding has been mobilised.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200144" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Germany</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">107508.57</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200144-1-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-01">4907.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1: Guidelines and standards</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200144-1-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-01">-18.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1: Guidelines and standards</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200144-1-51-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-01">51066.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Management, Monitoring and Self-</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200144-1-51-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-01">24889.03</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Management, Monitoring and Self-</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
