<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-vn" dstore:index="31" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-09-30T22:05:56" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-08-06T02:42:39" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-44006</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCS COVID VPB</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investment consists of a one-year, renewable senior loan of up to US$150 million to Vietnam Prosperity Joint Stock Commercial Bank (VP Bank or the Bank) under the FIG COVID-19 Emergency Response WCS Envelope. The investment consists of: (i) up to US$100 million IFC A Loan from its own account, and (ii) up to US$50 million B1 Loan and/or Parallel Loan including a green-shoe option. The investment aims to support VP Bank&apos;s working capital and trade-related lending program to enterprises in Vietnam, including SMEs affected by the COVID-19 pandemic.  The Project is expected to be supported by the Women Entrepreneurs Opportunity Facility (WEOF) in the form of a performance-based incentive (PBI) of up to 0.2% of the total project cost of US$150 million to incentivize on-lending of the proposed working capital loans to women and women-owned/women-led enterprises.&#xA0; The estimated subsidy provided by WEOF assumes that the Project will fully reach the agreed impact and shall only be paid out upon achievement of the pre-defined gender target.   WEOF is an initiative launched by IFC in partnership with the Goldman Sachs Foundation to help expand access to capital for women entrepreneurs in developing countries and demonstrate the commercial viability of investing in women. Further details and historical information on estimated subsidy levels in IFCs blended finance portfolio can be found at: www.ifc.org/blendedfinance. As is the case with all of IFCs blended concessional finance co-investments, this project has been assessed against the Enhanced Blended Concessional Finance Principles for DFI Private Sector Operations adopted by IFC and more than 20 other DFIs in 2017.&#xA0; Further information on these Enhanced Principles and IFCs blended finance approach and governance can also be found at: www.ifc.org/blendedfinance. To support this increase in trade volumes at this most critical time, IFC is starting this support through existing clients while remaining open to engaging with other eligible financial institutions providing working capital in emerging markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development impact of the proposed project is delivered through (i) improved access to finance/liquidity to relevant stakeholders (VP Bank, and through them, their customers) which will support their capacity to sustain operations and to expedite post-crisis recover; and (ii) promotion of the resilience of trade finance markets and broader stability in Vietnam.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VIETNAM PROSPERITY JOINT STOCK COMMERCIAL BANK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-44006" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam Prosperity Joint Stock Commercial Bank  Ms. Vo Hang Phuong  Head of Financial Institutions and Transaction Banking  +84 24 393 85111  phuongvh@vpbank.com.vn  89 Lang Ha Street, Dong Da District, Ha Noi, Viet Nam  www.vpbank.com.vn</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN-Vietnam">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VP Bank is headquartered in Hanoi, Vietnam. As of December 31, 2019, the Bank had 228 branches, 84 SME hubs, 137 household centers, and 4 Corporate branches, serving 6.3 million clients across Vietnam. The investment can be made throughout the country.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.1666700000 107.8333300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522110" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-AK - Commercial Banking - Trade and Supply Chain</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $100.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">100000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">100000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VIETNAM PROSPERITY JOINT STOCK COMMERCIAL BANK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/10587">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
