<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2626" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-01T08:30:01+01:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-01T08:30:01+01:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200136</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the mitigation of the COVID-19 impact on the dairy sector#s food security and safety in Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project document outlines UNIDO&#x2019;s proposed approach to the International Islamic Trade Finance Corporation&#x2019;s Recovery Response Program (RRP). Discussions between ITFC and UNIDO highlighted the synergies between the RRP and UNIDO&#x2019;s post-conflict programme. The Ministry of Industry and Trade of Sudan requested UNIDO&#x2019;s technical assistance to support the dairy sector value chains, vegetables &amp; fruits processing, and related value addition as well as the meat sector value chains. Amid consultations with the Ministry, priority for an immediate project intervention on the dairy sector was emphasized.

The project therefore aims to: i) provide technical assistance on dairy food safety systems and production practices to mitigate the impact of COVID19 pandemic, ii) contribute direct financial support to selected dairy enterprises to resume production and iii) set up the governance structure for the Entrepreneurial Development Committee (EDC) in Khartoum focusing on building and strengthening the entrepreneurial and technical skills of business ideas promoters as well as established entrepreneurs, to start or expand their own MSMEs.

The proposed project is a 6 months pilot that will, in addition to the direct technical and financial interventions, conduct financial and economic assessments on the dairy sector in Sudan and develop a comprehensive sector recovery plan with set of recommendations for improving the dairy industry to create more jobs and increase productivity, facilitate financial access, and help expand the sector through a scale-up project beyond 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200136" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Islamic Trade Finance Corporation (ITFC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="SD" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.069656 30.212553</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="SD" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khartoum</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.55177 32.53241</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">56074.76</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
