<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-kh" dstore:index="27" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-06-30T22:28:28" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-27T02:40:49" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-44231</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCS COVID AMRET</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project entails an IFC investment of up to US$50 million in a senior loan, consisting of an up to US$25 million IFC A Loan and an up to US$25 million B Loan to Amret Plc. (Amret or the Company) with at least 30 percent of the loans expected to be used on women and women-owned micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs)&#xA0; in Cambodia. The investment aims to support the Companys working capital lending program to Cambodian MSMEs that have been impacted by Covid-19 (the Project), particularly those in the garments, tourism and construction sectors, and will be supported by an IDA Private Sector Window (PSW) Blended Finance Facility.   IFC as implementing entity of the IDA Private Sector Window (PSW) Blended Finance Facility is expected to support working capital loans in PSW eligible countries under the WCS Facility with a first loss guarantee of up to US$215 million (blended concessional finance co-investment). Without the de-risking provided by IDA PSW, IFC will be limited in its ability to support Working Capital loans in IDA PSW countries given the increased demand for financing and the high risk in IDA PSW countries. This support is targeted in the context of responding and helping with the resilience measures around COVID-19 crisis.   The level of concessionality provided to the WCS Facility by the blended concessional finance co-investment is estimated to be approximately 3% of the total PSW eligible facility size, which will be up to US$860 million. This estimate is based on the difference between (i) a reference price (either a market price if available; the price calculated using IFCs pricing model, which comprises three main elements: risk, cost and profit; or a negotiated price) and (ii) the concessional price being charged by the blended concessional finance co-investment.   In addition, the Project is expected to be supported by Global SME Finance Facility (GSMEF)] in the form of a performance-based incentive (PBI) of up to 0.2% of the total project cost of US$50 million to incentivize on-lending of the proposed working capital loans to women and women-owned/women-led enterprises.&#xA0; The estimated subsidy provided by GSMEF assumes that the Project will fully reach the agreed impact and shall only be paid out upon achievement of the pre-defined gender target. GSMEF is a partnership between IFC and other multilateral and bilateral partners, including the United Kingdom&apos;s Department for International Development and the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs, to help expand financing to SMEs on a sustainable basis.   Further details and historical information on estimated subsidy levels in IFCs blended finance portfolio can be found at: www.ifc.org/blendedfinance. As is the case with all of IFCs blended concessional finance co-investments, this project has been assessed against the Enhanced Blended Concessional Finance Principles for DFI Private Sector Operations adopted by IFC and more than 20 other DFIs in 2017.&#xA0; Further information on these Enhanced Principles and IFCs blended finance approach and governance can also be found at: www.ifc.org/blendedfinance. To support this increase in trade volumes at this most critical time, IFC is starting this support through existing clients while remaining open to engaging with other eligible financial institutions providing working capital in emerging markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(i)	Project Outcome: The project provides access to finance and liquidity to relevant stakeholders (Amret, and through them, their customers). This will support stakeholders&apos; capacity to sustain operations and to expedite post-crisis recovery
(ii)	Market Creation: Microfinance institutions (MFIs) provide working capital to support their customers&apos; operating cash flow.  By sustaining MFIs&apos; ability to provide these services, IFC&apos;s facility is intended to promote the resilience of financial markets, as well as broader stability that comes about by providing for the going concern of market participants in Cambodia.  IFC expects the Facility to attract additional private sector investors and partners to support emerging market liquidity, strengthening the market&apos;s ability to absorb shocks imposed by the current crisis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMRET PLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-44231" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amret Plc.  Dos Dinn  Chief Executive Officer  +855 023 880 942  dinn.dos@amret.com.kh  80, St.315, 7 Village, Boeng Kak 2 Commune, Toul Kouk District, Phnom Penh  https://amret.com.kh/</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         International Finance Corporation    11th Floor, Exchange Square,   19&amp;20, Street 106,   Phnom Penh   Tel: (+855) 23 263 200</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="KH-Cambodia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amret is headquartered in Phnom Penh and has nationwide reach through 158 branches and a variety of digital channels.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522110" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-AK - Commercial Banking - Trade and Supply Chain</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/10594">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
