<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2624" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-01T08:30:01+01:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-01T08:30:01+01:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200196</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing Preparedness for Online Sessions of UNIDO Policymaking Organs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The global fallout from COVID-19

Following the World Health Organization (WHO)&#x2019;s declaration of a public health emergency of international concern on 30 January 2020, public health measures aimed at containing the spread of the virus were put in place in an increasing number of countries. As of the WHO&#x2019;s declaration on 11 March 2020 of a global pandemic, countries in every region of the world have followed suit. The majority of UNIDO&#x2019;s 170 Member States have instituted some form of public health measures to limit the spread of the virus amongst their populations, and the number of countries restricting the free movement of peoples and goods has grown to cover the world&#x2019;s major economies and population centres.

As a result of the spread of the virus and the containment measures to combat it, countries around the world are grappling with a significant strain on their health systems, as well as the negative economic and social effects of work stoppages, travel suspensions and supply chain disruptions. In today&#x2019;s globalized economy, no country in the world can anymore claim to be entirely unaffected by the spread and effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.


Host country restrictions

UNIDO&#x2019;s host country of Austria has, as one of around 50 countries, instituted a public lockdown, which took effect on 16 March 2020 and lasted around seven weeks. In coordination with the Government of Austria, the United Nations in Vienna imposed health and safety-related measures in line with those issued by the host country. Chief amongst them was the directive for United Nations personnel to work remotely and to limit physical access to the Vienna International Centre (VIC), the location of UNIDO&#x2019;s headquarters.

An end to measures regulating the size of public gatherings is contingent upon a negative rate of viral replication in the host country. This makes the duration of such measures difficult to accurately predict and plan for. In addition, a second wave of infections and a consequent resumption of containment measures later in the year cannot be ruled out. Information circulated by the inter-organizational Crisis Management Team of the VIC stipulates that in-person meetings and events at the VIC be subject to a cap on the total number of participants and the application of physical distancing measures. Coupled with projected logistical constraints, this considerably limits the ways in which larger meetings can be conducted, at least for the remainder of 2020.  As such, it has become necessary to consider alternative means of staging larger gatherings involving representatives of Member States, such as briefings, consultations, working group meetings, governing body sessions and similar events, traditionally held in-person at the VIC.


Member State expectations and United Nations system responses

Member States of United Nations-system entities have during this period expressed their general support for the use of online-conferencing facilities, leading many organizations to rapidly adopt various means to engage with their Member States online at a time when in-person meetings are not advisable or possible in most countries of the world.

A survey by the United Nations Governing Bodies Secretariats (UNGBS) network &#x2013; an exchange platform which facilitates effective system-wide decision-making by sharing best practices, experiences and guidance &#x2013; was conducted during the first weeks of March to map the different approaches being considered across the UN system for continued governing body decision-making under the existing physical limitations.

The UNGBS network&#x2019;s survey results issued on 27 March 2020 showed that of the 19 responding governing body secretariats, excluding UNIDO, eight were already at that point planning to conduct decision-making processes or meetings via online solutions. An additional 12 had at that point either already commenced, or were about to begin, holding consultative meetings of their Member States online.

In the meantime, individual UN organizations in Vienna are opting for online governing body meetings. In a survey of its Member States by the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) conducted in mid-April 2020, respondents showed a willingness to hold regular sessions of their governing and policymaking bodies (Commission on Narcotic Drugs and Commission on Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice) online, in addition to every other category of meeting or consultation. The question of whether to allow for remote decision-making by its commissions was answered with an overwhelming &#x2018;yes&#x2019;.

From 4 to 6 May 2020, the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) also headquartered in Vienna held its Programme and Budget Committee (PBC) entirely online. The IAEA&#x2019;s Board of Governors, in consultation with the Secretariat and with unequivocal support amongst its ranks, decided to hold the PBC, in a streamlined form and a week later than planned, on a remote conferencing platform already in use at the IAEA.

Additionally, the President of the UN General Assembly communicated in a letter dated 23 April 2020 that he has initiated a process to explore the possibility of online decision-making, upon the request of several Member States. Consequently, a series of scenarios and procedures have been developed by UN Secretariat staff, outlining how decision-making by the General Assembly could feasibly be undertaken through online means only.

The conferencing solutions used to date by United Nations system organisations in Vienna have varied greatly. Member State representatives have communicated to UNIDO, and other organisations, their express desire for a unified online conferencing tool for all Vienna-based United Nations organizations.


The situation at UNIDO

Between the start of the containment measures adopted by UNIDO on 16 March 2020 and 1 June 2020, only three formal engagements were held with representatives of Member States. This is of particular note, since the thirty-sixth session of UNIDO&#x2019;s PBC was to be held on 15 and 16 June 2020, and the period normally leading up to sessions of the PBC are marked by a heavy schedule of regional consultations and meetings of the Informal Working Group on PBC-related issues. In late March 2020, a request by the Policymaking Organs Secretariat of UNIDO to hold online briefings was rejected by the Executive Board in light of the extraordinary situation at the time. As the physical distancing measures continue, it is increasingly clear that UNIDO, as all UN organizations, will have to be able to offer online services to its Member States in the future.

The first formal online meeting of representatives of UNIDO&#x2019;s Member States took place on 22 April 2020, in the form of a meeting of the Enlarged Bureau of the PBC. The meeting served to determine what course of action to take concerning the upcoming PBC, given that a return to business as usual by its scheduled date could not be assumed.

Feedback from delegates during the meeting oscillated between the options of postponing the PBC to a date later in the year, or holding it entirely online on the originally foreseen dates. Those advocating for an online PBC cited 1) the fact that the schedule of meetings after the summer period &#x2013; when meetings at the VIC were set to resume &#x2013; would be unmanageable for all but a few delegations in Vienna, and 2) the understanding that a second postponement necessitated by a resumption of containment measures could not be ruled out.

Ultimately, the decision made by the members of the PBC was to postpone its thirty-sixth session to 29 and 30 September 2020, upon recommendation by the Chair of the thirty-fifth session and the Secretariat. It was however understood by UNIDO&#x2019;s Member States, as explained by the Secretariat, that preparations for an eventual fully online PMO session would continue as a contingency measure.

The postponement of the PBC to a date later in the year also does not resolve the issue of deferred briefings, consultations and working group meetings, which had been foreseen for the second and third quarter of 2020 and will still be required in the run-up to the PBC and later the IDB.

The primary and immediate reason for UNIDO&#x2019;s assistance is to provide its Member States with continuity of governance in contexts when it is needed the most. As the COVID-19 pandemic has demonstrated, UNIDO cannot under any circumstances be rendered legislatively inoperational at the precise moment when the global need for its services is at its greatest. Additionally, by modernizing UNIDO&#x2019;s communications infrastructure with its Member States, the decision-making processes of its policymaking organs will be rendered more efficient and effective.

Constitutionally, UNIDO has three principal organs: the General Conference (GC), the Industrial Development Board (IDB) and the Secretariat. The PBC is a subsidiary organ of the IDB. UNIDO&#x2019;s current business continuity planning is centred around ensuring that the Secretariat remains functional under adverse external circumstances. As the current context has however made clear, there is an urgent need to it does not give sufficient attention toconsider the new requirements for either the GC, IDB or PBC to be fully functional in such cases and allow a smooth and operational decision making process. This project therefore aims to remedy this gap in planning and ensure that the decision-making integrity of UNIDO&#x2019;s Member States through its policymaking organs is guaranteed under circumstances when they cannot physically meet.

The objective of the project is therefore to fully develop UNIDO&#x2019;s capacity to hold full-fledged policymaking organ sessions entirely online, in order to ensure continued governance by its Member States under adverse external circumstances or when expedient.

This straightforward objective seeks to repair a fundamental weakness in terms of the continuity of UNIDO&#x2019;s governance. This weakness has been exposed by the unprecedented effects of the global COVID-19 pandemic, yet it can also be remedied by the similarly unprecedented sophistication and proliferation of digital technology. Accomplishment of the project&#x2019;s objective would therefore allow representatives of UNIDO&#x2019;s Member States to take part in sessions of the Organization&#x2019;s policymaking organs regardless of their or the Secretariat&#x2019;s physical location.

The development of UNIDO&#x2019;s capacity to formally interact with its Member States online is a project which has been foreseen by the Policymaking Organs Secretariat, and which has now been greatly accelerated due to the current circumstances. Therefore, a number of important secondary benefits are expected from the completion of this project. One strategic medium-term benefit to UNIDO is that by staging policymaking organ sessions online, the direct participation of officials from national capitals can be facilitated. This allows for dramatically streamlined decision-making by eliminating the need to relay instructions between Vienna and national capitals. This lag has caused significant slowdowns in the proceedings of recent policymaking organ sessions, most notably the forty-seventh session of the IDB, resulting in the session being suspended and resumed at a later date.

Resumed and special sessions of UNIDO policymaking organs have also been increasing in frequency over the last years. Each time such an unplanned session is held, it results in additional costs for the Organization. Fully developing UNIDO&#x2019;s capacity to hold online sessions of its policymaking organs would however provide a flexible and inexpensive alternative for resumed and special sessions, which often only deal with one agenda item for which an agreement has already been reached in advance by Member States, and thus merely represent a formality.

Looking ahead to the calendar of highly consequential policymaking organ sessions in 2021 - which will include inter alia complex negotiations for the next biennial budget and an election of a new Director General - is imperative that UNIDO&#x2019;s capabilities to effectively consult with Member States is enhanced and that more efficient means of decision-making are developed.

Establishing a regularized online mode of interaction with Member States &#x2013; covering briefings, consultations, working groups and policymaking organ sessions &#x2013; is also expected to result in additional sustained long-term cost savings. Travel-related costs will form the bulk of the savings. By holding engagements with Member States online, the cost of flying UNIDO field personnel or invited speakers in drops significantly, in line with the Organization&#x2019;s carbon footprint. Additionally, costs associated with the rental of venues and the hiring of personnel to coordinate and service physical meetings fall away. Established pricing schemes for meetings and conferences at the VIC often result in UNIDO having to pay for resources that it does not end up using.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200196" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">26227.67</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200196-1-01-01-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">13950.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Online consultative environment establis</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200196-1-01-01-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">14333.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Online consultative environment establis</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200196-1-01-02-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">7377.23</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Effective online consultations/WG</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200196-1-01-02-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">7780.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Effective online consultations/WG</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200196-1-01-03-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">4899.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Online PMO sessions successfully held</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200196-1-01-03-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">5212.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Online PMO sessions successfully held</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
