<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-pk" dstore:index="29" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-12-31T21:15:40" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-18T02:42:29" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-43172</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">POL Expansion</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Originally established in 1935, Pakistan Oxygen Limited (POL or the Company) is engaged in: (i) the manufacture and sale of medical and industrial gases and welding consumables; (ii) marketing of medical equipment; and (iii) provision of engineering service solutions. POL collaborates with customers to provide a wide range of services from supplying gases to technical consultation, design of pipeline systems to safety, quality risk analysis and training for companies in the business of healthcare, energy, food processing, medical engineering, and wastewater treatment. The Company is undertaking an expansion program to add a modern and efficient Air Separation Unit (ASU) of 270 tons per day (tpd) capacity for production of Oxygen, Nitrogen and Argon, and to enhance production efficiencies at its Port Qasim plant and has invited IFC to consider its investment program (the Project).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation of the Project is expected to increase reliable supply of essential gases including Oxygen. An important impact of the Project is that it will increase POL&apos;s capacity to produce Oxygen by around 70%, which is critical for treatment of COVID-19. The project will also lead to an increase in the production of Nitrogen and Argon which have important applications in the health care sector as well as a range of other industries. There is also potential for the project to have environmental benefits. IFC anticipates that the Project will lead to increased market resilience, in light of the effects of COVID-19. IFC&apos;s intervention will help address the sharp supply disruptions resulting from the COVID19 health pandemic by fully meeting the urgent demand for medical oxygen gas. By supporting a market participant withstand the COVID19 pandemic, the Project will help preserve the market&apos;s ability to support the economic recovery effort as conditions normalize.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PAKISTAN OXYGEN LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-43172" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Oxygen Limited  Syed Ali Adnan  Chief Financial Officer  +92-21-3-2313361-9  ali.adnan@pakoxygen.com  P.O. Box 4845, Dockyard Road, West Wharf, Karachi - 74000, Pakistan  www.pakoxygen.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  POL   will make relevant documentation available in   English on its website   and its office in   Karachi, Pakistan.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK-Pakistan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project will be located in Port Qasim in Karachi.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.0000000000 70.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="3251" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">G-BB - Industrial Gases</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/43172">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
