<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" dstore:dataset="danida-all_7" dstore:index="1193" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-28T15:00:40" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-28T15:00:45" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark&apos;</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark&#x2019;s contribution to the United Nations Indigenous Fellowship Programme 2020-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Indigenous Fellowship Programme (IFP) is a comprehensive human rights training programme that was established by the Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) in the context of the first International Decade of the World&apos;s Indigenous Peoples (1995-2004). The programme aims to build the capacity and expertise of indigenous representatives on the UN human rights system and mechanisms dealing with human rights in general and indigenous issues in particular, so they are in a better position to protect and promote the rights of their communities. The IFP is held annually and fellows from the programme are trained together during 4 to 5 weeks in Geneva. The date of the training programme usually coincides with the annual meeting of the UN Expert Mechanism on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples, thus allowing the fellows to participate more actively in international advocacy while participating in the Programme. In 2020, due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the annual Fellowship Programme held in Geneva was cancelled and redesigned into a country-based programme with former Fellows posted as &#x201C;Senior Fellows&#x201D; in OHCHR country and regional offices, UN Country Teams (UNCTs) or UN Peacekeeping Operations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 44658</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286220-34796" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
