<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" dstore:dataset="danida-all_7" dstore:index="718" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-22T04:39:48" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-22T04:39:51" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285957</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark&apos;</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cash assistance to vulnerable households in major cities/informal settlements in Kenya (COVID-19)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cash assistance to vulnerable households in major cities/informal settlements in Kenya


The project will support vulnerable households with unconditional cash transfers in the informal settlements of Nairobi and Mombasa to allow the purchase of food and other basic necessities that will cushion them from the economic and social impact of the Covid-19 crisis, and incentivize them to observe some of the measures in place to curb infection.
&#x2022;	The precise areas of intervention will be selected in coordination with the Government of Kenya/MOL and our established network of Community based organisations. We will carryout a rapid food security analysis and gender/protection assessment in Mombasa to hone in on the areas and the needs &#x2013; to our knowledge this has not yet been done, and will help us determine the MEB for Mombasa. (it may alter the exact number of HH)

&#x2022;	The project will target 13,000 households (52,000 people): 10,000 HH in Mombasa (40,000 people) and 3,000 HH in Nairobi (12,000 people) with three monthly cash transfers starting in July/August 2020;
&#x2022;	We would request flexibility in the Nairobi targeting to perhaps increase direct support to survivors of SGBV &#x2013; we are hearing that the cases are far higher than we first anticipated. 
&#x2022;	The transfer is valued at KES 7,500 per household per month (including transaction costs), which covers 50% of the Minimum Expenditure Basket (MEB) for Nairobi, as endorsed by the CWG, and one additional reusable mask to facilitate protection of at least two members of the households.
&#x2022;	Households benefitting from the Inua Jamii cash transfers, will receive a transfer that will complement the government support to cover the 50% of the MEB.
&#x2022;	The intervention will include a SGBV prevention and response component, with support to Legal, Psychological and Health services to survivors of SGBV, who will be included in the list of cash transfer recipients, as appropriate. The anticipated number of SGBV survivors who will benefit</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 21746</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>NA</telephone>
   <email>NA</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency food assistance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285957-34439" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
