<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-ci" dstore:index="19" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-09-30T22:06:22" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-08-21T02:44:39" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-44054</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCS COVID NSIA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investment consists of a working capital facility of up to Euro 25 million to NSIA Banque C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire (NBCI or Bank) under the FIG COVID-19 Emergency Response WCS Envelope (WCS Envelope). The WCS Envelope is designed to provide funding to existing IFC client banks in emerging markets that will then extend new trade-related or working capital loans to companies whose cash flows have been disrupted by the global outbreak of the coronavirus pandemic.  In addition, IFC as implementing entity of the IDA Private Sector Window (PSW) Blended Finance Facility is expected to support working capital loans in PSW eligible countries under the WCS Facility with a first loss guarantee of up to US$215 million (blended concessional finance co-investment). Without the de-risking provided by IDA PSW, IFC will be limited in its ability to support Working Capital loans in IDA PSW countries given the increased demand for financing and the high risk in IDA PSW countries. This support is targeted in the context of responding and helping with the resilience measures around COVID-19 crisis.   &#xA0;  The level of concessionality provided to the WCS Facility by the blended concessional finance co-investment is estimated to be approximately 3% of the total PSW eligible facility size, which will be up to US$860 million. This estimate is based on the difference between (i) a reference price (either a market price if available; the price calculated using IFCs pricing model, which comprises three main elements: risk, cost and profit; or a negotiated price) and (ii) the concessional price being charged by the blended concessional finance co-investment.   &#xA0;  Further details and historical information on estimated subsidy levels in IFCs blended finance portfolio can be found at: www.ifc.org/blendedfinance. As is the case with all of IFCs blended concessional finance co-investments, this project has been assessed against the Enhanced Blended Concessional Finance Principles for DFI Private Sector Operations adopted by IFC and more than 20 other DFIs in 2017.&#xA0; Further information on these Enhanced Principles and IFCs blended finance approach and governance can also be found at: www.ifc.org/blendedfinance. To support this increase in trade volumes at this most critical time, IFC is starting this support through existing clients while remaining open to engaging with other eligible financial institutions providing working capital in emerging markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience: in the context of the acute shock associated with the COVID pandemic, IFC will, through this facility, support NBCI&apos; capacity to sustain operations and particularly lending to a critical sector of the Ivorian economy.
Increase access to finance: The Project is also expected to increase access to finance for SMEs as it will help NBCI scale up its lending towards SMEs, which in turn is expected to drive economic growth and job creation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NSIA BANQUE COTE D&apos;IVOIRE, S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-44054" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NSIA Banque Cote d&apos;Ivoire  Eliane ALANGBA  Deputy Managing Director  +225 20 20 06 53  eliane.alangba@nsiabanque.com  8-10 Avenue Joseph Anoma Plateau, Tour NSIA Banque 14e etage  www.nsiafinance.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cote D&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CI-Cote D&apos;Ivoire">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C&#xF4;te dIvoire</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.0000000000 -5.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522110" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-AK - Commercial Banking - Trade and Supply Chain</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $27.83 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">27830000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">27830000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NSIA BANQUE COTE D&apos;IVOIRE, S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/10591">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
