<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="34" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-13T03:07:27.807" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-03T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/H-P-N/INGO/17821</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delivery of essential protection, health and nutrition assistance to conflict-affected and vulnerable populations in northern Shan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Shan has continued to be affected by short-term displacement caused by conflict or the threat of conflict.  At end October 2020, RI had tracked through its own incident reporting mechanism that 96 separate incidents had taken place in 2020 (33 of which were categorised as active conflict and many more associated with the presence of armed actors).  Almost 4,000 people had been temporarily displaced, while many more subjected to the constant sense of insecurity and uncertainty from living in a conflict-affected context.  While RI has been working in northern Shan with valued support from MHF since 2018, assistance to those affected by short-term displacement in northern Shan continues to be sparse, while vulnerability and lack of availability to essential services continues to grow. These concerns have been only compounded by the onset of COVID-19 in 2020.  

Building on life-saving activities already taking place in northern Shan, Relief International (RI) proposes a multi-sector approach to this next phase to expand on access, partnerships and progress already made to improve resilience of conflict-affected communities in Muse, Kyaukme, Hsipaw, Namtu, Namhsan and Namhkan townships. The project combines delivery of direct services under health, nutrition and protection while also strengthening existing community resources such as community health and protection focal points.
 
For protection, the response will i) identify and support protection cases through referral and cash support, including direct support of people with disabilities and ii) raise awareness within communities on context-specific protection concerns (child protection, trafficking, forced recruitment, unsafe migration, drug use, mine risk) iii) training and coaching with CSOs and community protection focal points on key protection concerns and responses iv) establishment of protection monitoring systems to identify and monitor protection trends in communities vulnerable to displacement.  
 
For health, RI will i) provide direct health services to underserved populations, most of whom have not received any direct health support before, through mobile health clinics and support to referrals and ii) strengthen community engagement around health concerns (including COVID-19) and iii) improve coordination between local health actors, including EHOs, health CSOs and township health departments.  
 
For nutrition, RI will i) provide direct support to SAM and MAM cases through diagnosis and referral (through the mobile health services) and ii) expand nutrition awareness in communities through community outreach.
 
As previously, RI considers the involvement of local CSOs &#x2013; the backbone of northern Shan first response &#x2013; to be critical to project success and sustainability.  Wherever possible, RI will ensure CSOs are in the driving seat and have the skills sand capacity to do so.  RI also expects to establish close coordination with key ethnic health organisations (EHOs) for them to be able to take on more direct service delivery in the future.

Recognising that COVID-19 has put the healthcare system in Myanmar - including Northern Shan - under huge strain, RI will continue to ensure awareness is mainstreamed throughout all activities, and that staff, service users and vulnerable populations are protected. RI will follow all MOHS guidelines and protocols for COVID 19 prevention and control. 

RI will build on existing community feedback and response mechanisms in northern Shan to ensure communities are familiar with PSEA reporting and the response they can expect.  RI will provide refresher trainings for all staff and partners on their obligations and responsibilities.  

RI proposes a 10-month project, starting from the end of implementation under current MHF funding (#14813), and ending in December 2021, thereby ensuring full 12 months&#x2019; coverage in 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleksandar Kuzmanovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 (0) 9454839705</telephone>
   <email>aleksandar.kuzmanovic@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shan (North)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>23.50285400 98.14198900</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="45" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="15" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-01">303902.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-17821">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-01">303902.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304906904">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-03">182341.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
