<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="9" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-22T02:08:50.31" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-11T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA2/NFI/INGO/17624</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Flood response through Shelter and NFIs  in Bor South, Pibor and Ayod areas of Jonglei State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This 6 months&#x2019; project will focus on &apos;&apos;Providing access to emergency shelter and lifesaving non-food items to the flood displaced people in Bor South, Pibor and Ayod Counties of Jonglei State from November 2020 to April 2020. The project will reach 61,000 persons affected by flooding (17,934 men, 18,666 women, 11,956 boys and 12,444 girls) with an estimated total of 2224 persons living with disabilities (4% of the total target).


The project team will distribute 10,166 shelter/NFI kits to the flood affected people. Each kit will include 2 plastic sheets, 2 mosquito nets and 2 rubber ropes at minimum. The distribution of shelter and NFIs will be based on vulnerability criteria, addressing the needs of large families, households with children under 5, pregnant or lactating woman (PLW), unaccompanied elderly (gt 60 years), people living with disability (PLWD), female headed households, child headed households, unaccompanied minors and the chronically ill.


NRC will work through the rapid response team/mobile teams (RRT) supported by NRC static team in Bor South to register and verify beneficiaries, distribution of Survival/shelter kits will be done. The kits shall be requested from core pipeline through the cluster recommendation.

In line with the allocation strategy, the project will ensure inclusiveness and participation ensuring equitable participation. In assessments, distribution committees will be encouraged and supported, while distribution activities will be scheduled to allow for women and girls involvement

The project will promote timely delivery of assistance through deployment of mobile teams in line with humanitarian response priorities for 2020 as outlined in the HRP as well as the flood response in South Sudan. NRC&#x2019;s mobile response teams will be ready for deployment within 8 days to conduct assessments/validation of beneficiaries and within 14 days for full-fledged delivery of NFIs supported by some staff from NRC static office in Bor South.

The project team will work in close coordination with S/NFI cluster, cluster focal points, and its activities will be informed by the gaps identified through the assessment missions carried out by NRC or other actors on the ground or joint assessments. NRC will also coordinate its operations with CIDO, HDC, CRS, PAH, IDEAS South Sudan, South Sudan Red Cross and Health Link among others that are already operational in some of the locations e.g. Bor South.

The specific needs of the persons displaced by floods have shortage of shelter and WASH supplies. Other actors like PAH are responding to the WASH needs and NRC will focus on distribution of  Shelter and NFI kits to meet the shelter needs of men, women, boys and girls. These beneficiaries will be selected  jointly with the community and will put into considerations the minimum standards of protection and shelter due diligence guidelines. 

The project team will ensure that women and girls are not exposed to risk of sexual exploitation and abuse (SEA) at the distribution points and to have the distribution site within short walking distances from the beneficiaries&#x2019; homes/areas of displacement. In case drinking water is not available in nearby locations, water will be provided by NRC team at the distribution sites. Elderly, physically incapable, pregnant women and others who require special attention will be prioritized during distribution so that they are served early and comfortably. Feedback desk will be provided at each distribution site so that beneficiaries register their complaints with NRC on the entire project process and quality of the supplies/Kits. NRC will conduct post distribution Monitoring (PDM) in at least at 50% in locations of distribution.

The project will be implemented in line with the COVID-19 guidelines ensuring that the staff and beneficiaries ensure social distancing, using face masks and washing ha</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-SHL-160941-2" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sultan Mahmood</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211922761506</telephone>
   <email>sultan.mahmood@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sirak Mehari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211922761501</telephone>
   <email>sirak.mehari@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-02">113493.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-02">330612.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-17624">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-02">444106.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304822957">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">266463.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
