<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="59" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-02T02:06:16.233" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-02T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA5/FSAC/INGO/17234</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Food Security assistance to food insecure families in Achin and Mohmandara districts of Nangarhar province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will provide emergency response to the most vulnerable households (HHs) in Nangarhar who are food insecure as they are living under the poverty line and were already struggling to manage their minimum essential food needs, it is worsened by the loss of income/earning opportunity and thus purchasing power, as a result of COVID-19 pandemic in Afghanistan. The beneficiaries of this project are also living in recently cleared districts that are facing degraded food security situation due to long exposure to conflict. The most vulnerable people are included, specifically female headed HH, and HH with PWD and or where the primary breadwinner has lost their employment due to COVID-19.
Through the proposed project Oxfam and long-term strategic partner Organization for Human Welfare (OHW) will provide cash assistance to a total of 15,000 individuals (2143 HHs) in Achin and Mohmandara districts of Nangarhar province to buy food items/commodities - these districts were recently cleared by Afghan National Forces from existence of ISIS. Based on the cluster standards and the allocation strategy paper, every eligible beneficiary HHs (those who experienced multiple resilience eroding shock in the past 6 months, and those subject to recent COVID-19 pressures, including lack of employment). they will receive half basket cash for food for 2 months (USD 90 for a period of 2 months in local currency) in one off. Cash for Food was preferred by the majority of the persons interviewed during the needs assessment since the local markets are operational. The Market Assessment confirmed that access is available and there is no restriction for both male and female while accessing/approaching market. 

The assessment revealed that, 40% of respondents identified cash, 18% preferred food, 6% education, 6% shelter, 25% WASH, and the rest of the 5% health facilities as first priorities. Similarly, 15% identified food, 27% cash, 25% preferred education, 11% preferred health facilities, 4% preferred shelter, and the rest 5% preferred WASH as second priorities. 
Oxfam&#x2019;s interventions will be guided by the Integrated Food-Security Phase Classification (IPC) and Seasonal Food Security Assessment (SFSA) findings. As per IPC 2020 and SFSA, Nangarhar province was already in Crisis Situation (IPC3). Around 46% of the population in Nangarhar (1,237,262 individuals) were estimated to be at IPC3 or above during the period of April-May 2020 and 40% of the population (559,938 individuals) were estimated to be at IPC3 or above during the projection period June to November 2020. This project will support the most food-insecure population/communities in rural areas of Nangarhar Province, Achin and Mohmandara districts. FSAC identified that communities affected by COVID-19 are among the worst hit in terms of food insecurity. This project will target them so that they can survive without adopting harmful coping strategies and reduce their risk of exposure to the further shocks and build their resilience. A beneficiary selection committee using a weighted vulnerability score will be set up and also mention that post distribution monitoring (PDM) will be conducted and will include questions related to risks associated with cash distribution and efforts made to facilitate inclusive, safe and secure access of all beneficiaries (women, children, PWD, elderly) to cash assistance.

COVID-19 Awareness raising messages developed by Ministry of Public Health (MoPH) with the support of World Health Organization (WHO) and UNICEF in the languages of Afghanistan will be used for this purpose. 
Oxfam will integrate conflict sensitivity into the action, by conducting context and conflict analysis of the target areas. This is especially important as cash assistance can work as potential flashpoint in creating new conflict or exacerbating existing tensions. 
The grant of USD 300,000 will provide immediate response and save lives of 15,000 persons (USD 20 per person).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Human Welfare</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fraidoon Amiri</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Humanitarian Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0728308368</telephone>
   <email>fraidoon.amiri@oxfam.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ashish Damla</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0797 540 447</telephone>
   <email>ashish.damle@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rahim Popalzai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93798968989</telephone>
   <email>rahim.popalzai@oxfam.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nangarhar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.17183130 70.62167940</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-23">131215.25</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-23">161994.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-17234">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-23">293209.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304777972">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-02">234567.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
