<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="29" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-21T02:06:18.74" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/E-WASH/INGO/17828</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting quality education and WASH in schools for conflict-affected children in Kachin State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to respond to the critical unmet humanitarian needs in education for students and teachers in 29 target locations  (22 IDP camps in Hpakant, Mogaung, Momauk, Myitkyina, Shwegu and Waigmaw and return/relocation sites in Bhamo, Chipwi and Waigmaw townships)  who have been displaced because of the ongoing protracted crises in Kachin. PIN, together with partner KBC, will support inclusive education for children in all 29 learning spaces by reducing barriers to access education and supporting home-based learning opportunities for conflict-affected children who are out of school due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Within this comprehensive strategy for inclusive education, PIN will distribute home-based learning and wellbeing materials and the EiE Sector Parent Guide to Home-Based Learning to mitigate the effects of COVID-19 on students&#x2019; education and help parents to support their children&#x2019;s learning. Parent skills workshops will be held which aim to promote the well-being of children and adolescents through improving parents&#x2019; stress management skills, positive parenting practices, and strategies for supporting children and adolescents with psychosocial needs. Back-to-school outreach sessions reach those children most likely to not return to school including boys and children with disabilities. Finally, access to education will be increased both in IDP camps and relocation sites through the use of locally-led School Improvement Plans and funding to improve school facilities (including WASH facilities) and hygiene promotion . 


To improve the quality of education for children, PIN staff will monitor the use of home-based learning materials and support night study guides in GCAs to help ensure students are utilizing the materials in an appropriate and structured manner. Teachers (NGCAs) and night study guides  GCAs)  will be provided with incentives, as set through a standardization workshop for Kachin state, enabling them to focus on their teaching related tasks and learning. At the beginning and the end of the project a numeracy and literacy survey (ASER) and a psychosocial needs survey (SDQ) will be carried out to identify to measure learning and wellbeing levels and needs following the period of school closures due to Covid-19,  as well as measuring the results of the proposed intervention. 


The needs of the target locations have been determined through baseline and endline surveys by PIN and implementing partners and conversations with key stakeholders. PIN and KBC will ensure continuity of projects, in line with the desires of teachers and parents, by supporting 22 learning spaces which were previously supported under MHF projects 13607 and 14859 as well as new return and resettlement areas. This will ensure that home-based learning materials are being utilized, parents are supporting their children&#x2019;s learning and wellbeing and that schools and learning spaces are well equipped to support inclusive access to services while minimizing the risk of COVID-19. 

Overall, this project will benefit 2840 children (1,434 boys and 1406 girl), as well as 96 night volunteer student guides (17 male and 79 female). At least 787 parents (237 male and 550 female) will benefit from parent skills sessions to support their and their children&#x2019;s well-being. Finally, 50 staff from EiE sector actors and local partner staff will benefit from EiE capacity building and training initiatives aimed at improving the overall quality of education in emergencies programming.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention (KBC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andrius Kudaba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 92 51269716</telephone>
   <email>andrius.kudaba@peopleinneed.cz</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hpauyam Hka Li</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KBC Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 94 22209601</telephone>
   <email>hpauyamhkali@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR001">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00000000 97.50000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="11" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="89" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">336892.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-17828">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">336892.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304876495">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-14">202135.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People in Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
