<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="33" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-15T03:06:23.477" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-22T06:30:18.27" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA3/H/UN/18021</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving integrated primary health services; prevent detect and respond to disease outbreaks among the vulnerable populations in Greater Pibor Administrative Area (GPAA).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute to the reduction of excess morbidity and mortality resulting from common infectious diseases, vector-borne diseases and epidemic-prone diseases as a consequence of severe food insecurity being driven by multiple shocks (effects of Covid-19, economic crisis and high food prices, impact of flooding on livelihood, and sub-national violence) among 28,000  (10,839 Men,  11281 Women, 2999  Girls and 2881 Boys) in Greater Pibor Administrative Area (GPAA) of South Sudan particular  Western part payams (Pibor and Verteth payams) . This aim will be obtained  through the provision of time-critical, life-saving frontline quality health services, capacity building of health care workers, and strengthening of disease surveillance systems in the GPAA. The WHO Mobile Medical Teams (eMMT) provides integrated health services in deep field locations through mobile medical outreach modality. The eMMT comprise of experts from different fields of medicine often deployed strategically to provide gap-filling services in areas with serious unmet health needs. Such areas may include locations without static health facilities or those with no active health partners, locations with access constraints and those receiving high numbers of returnees, IDPs or refugees. The mobile clinics will offer outpatient consultations for common conditions, minor procedures, screening and treatment for malnutrition, immunization services, and referral services. Besides, WHO will train community health care workers to ensure continuity of health service provision in GPAA. 
Rapid assessments has been conducted in the GPAA to identify unmet needs and allow for ongoing health service provision, meanwhile, the Rapid Response Teams (RRT) will be deployed alongside the eMMTs to conduct case verification and investigation of suspected disease outbreaks. In addition, WHO will enhance capacity for disease surveillance and reporting to enhance detection of epidemic-prone diseases and continue to provide timely technical support for appropriate response by the Ministry of Health and other health partners 
The routine surveillance system will be enhanced through the deployment of mobile phone-based EWARS reporting by the static and mobile clinics attending to the needs of the community. This will enhance weekly reporting by facilities to ensure early detection of and response to disease outbreaks.

WHO will also conduct a risk assessment for common diseases such as measles and cholera in GPAA to ascertain the need for preventive vaccination campaigns and guide the planning process for preventive vaccination campaigns as well as secure adequate vaccines as guided by the risk assessment findings.
Through its network of experts, both within and outside the country WHO will conduct targeted and focused capacity building of health workers working in the health facilities. The proposed capacity building will cover how to run mobile outreach programs, disease surveillance and outbreak response, case management, and infection prevention and control (IPC) within health facilities, and Clinical Management of Rape.

This project will also aim to procure and distribute emergency health kits to support health partners responding in the six prioritised Counties: Pibor, Akobo, Tonj East, Tonj  North, Tonj South, and Aweil South. The distributed emergency health kits will benefit 377, 236 (Women151987, men 146029, girls 40402, and boys 38818).

This project is a scale up of  the ongoing WHO emergency health in GPAA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-HEA-161458-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr Argata Guracha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211926144384</telephone>
   <email>guyoa@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Okabo Benson Gard</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planning  Performance Management officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211922656839</telephone>
   <email>okabob@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr Chol Thabo  Yur</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Health Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211924444802</telephone>
   <email>yurc@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-22">999999.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-18021">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-22">999999.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="13737">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-19">999999.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
