<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="128" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-11T02:05:12.193" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-08T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/H/NGO/16315</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting Quality Secondary and Reproductive Health Care Services in NWS.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEMA, under the direct support of SCHF, seeks to maintain the introduction of health services, and to continue the essential life-saving interventions including: critical inpatient therapies, reproductive health services, in addition to maintain the availability of essential medication and supplies.
To reach this end, SEMA proposes to support Jisr Ash-Shugur and Al-Ikha&apos;a hospital, in Jisr Ash-Shugur and Dana sub-districts, and thus ensuring the provision of secondary, and reproductive health care to people in need, as the two hospitals are located in under-served areas, whose people are suffering from the lack of medical services and are having difficult living conditions.

SEMA tries to respond to the critical needs of newly displaced population and to address the most urgent gaps by supporting Al-Ikha&apos;a hospital for 12 months and thus ensure the availability of its services, in addition to support Jisr Ash-Shugur hospital for five months.
Jisr- alshoghour hospital:(HeRAMS code: G0704013):

A trauma and surgical hospital, serving a population of 70k in Jisr Ash-Shugur city and surrounding areas including the most vulnerable groups (IDPs, women, children and the elderly) will have access to the following services: OPD (General, Orthopedic), IPD, surgeries, emergency, surgical ward, lab, X-Ray, pharmacy, as the hospital contains 20 beds and two operation theaters.
This hospital was supported by WHO till 15th of March 2020 through SEMA, and currently out of support, it was supposed to be supported by other partner at the beginning of April, but this partner apologized due to funding, and it is now a priority (according to IHD).
Al-Ikha&apos;a hospital:(CEmONC) (HeRAMS code:G0703071):
It is a maternity and childhood hospital in Atmeh (Harim District), and considered as the most major facility in the area, which is crowded with IDPs (total population of 250k IDPs in Atmeh). The hospital has been supported by SEMA through several grant&apos;s since 5 years, and will be out of funding after 20th of June 2020.
Al-Ikha&apos;a hospital includes the following departments:
pediatric and neonatal Department: Provides pediatric consultations and neonatal health care services and equipped with operating new-born incubators. 
Inpatient Department: Where major and minor surgeries are implemented, in addition to the hospitalization of patients. 
ER Department: Where all trauma cases are received and provided with emergency services, then referred to the needed specialty. 
Laboratory: The hospital contains a well-equipped lab to perform the needed tests for the beneficiaries in the hospital. 
X-Ray Department: The hospital contains a well-equipped x-ray department with a variety of different services.
It is worth-mentioning that waste management and disposal in Al-Ikha&apos;a hospital is applied by collecting the medical waste and transporting it for about 50 K from Atma to the incinerator in Idleb. This process is occurred ten times per month where this grant will secure the cost of transportation.
Both hospitals are critical and crucial to their areas, and SEMA has coordinated with IHD to prioritize them for any coming opportunity to support.
Due to the very volatile environment and the development of novel COVID-19, SEMA managed to be flexible in responding to the immediate and urgent needs on the ground, so a dynamic and strong risk management strategy and plan &quot;B&quot; is already set up based on the security developments in the area where activating mobile clinics to reach the elderly and vulnerable cases (people with chronic diseases), in addition to tele-medicine component where some consultations related to COVID-19 and others may be introduced via phone to avoid gatherings.
Moreover, As SEMA always tries to acheive long-term impact and to leave the community in much-stronger case, so the project team will conduct training for the two hospital staff about: BLS, ATLS, resuscitation of new born, COVID19 detection and referral pathway.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-HEA-164132-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-HEA-164599-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-04">545006.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-04">563274.88</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16315">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-04">1108281.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304667968">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">664968.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
