<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="15" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-05T03:06:14.08" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-12T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/FSAC/INGO/17920</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Emergency Food Security Response for IDPs in Al Dhihar and Dhi As Sufal Districts of Ibb Governorate YHF allocation priority 2.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Identified by FSAC as having food security gaps/needs that require immediate cash assistance aligned with YHF SA1 to provide immediate funding to assist people in acute humanitarian needs with a view to mitigati the risks of famine and negative consequences of COVID-19 in Yemen as we The project will provide six-month unconditional cash assistance to meeting the basic food needs of the most vulnerable 1338 IDP households or 9336 individuals (2778 men, 2724 women, 1965 boys, and 1894 girls). The two districts are among the most highly affected districts in Ibb due to the huge number of IPDs who fled from conflict areas and settled among already vulnerable host communities. Most of the displaced population (over 1000 HHS) has been living in host communities for two years or more, placing a significant burden on host communities who now face similar levels of vulnerability. Dhi Al Sufal and Al Dhihar districts are categorized by 2018/2019 IPC analysis as IPC4 (emergency phase) with a population in an IPC5 ( famine-like situation) and identified by the FSAC as having acute food security gaps/needs that require immediate food assistance. Key project activities include conducting a contextual and market assessment, community selection of beneficiaries through a participatory and inclusive process, monthly cash disbursements, market monitoring, and PDMs.Oxfam&#x2019;s recent rapid market and food security needs assessment showed that men, women, boys, and girls are practicing negative coping mechanisms due to their inability to purchase food in the market. The most vulnerable households are reducing frequency amp size of meals, face high levels of debt/loans, and are selling household productive assets, whilst begging can be observed. Oxfam will respond to the most vulnerable households with monthly food assistance, through a cash-based modality of six months unconditional cash transfer (UCT), based on FSAC&apos;s recommended minimum food value to cover 80% of household food needs. Cash will be distributed through identified FSPs at safe locations identified in consultation with target communities. The rapid market assessment shows that markets in Dhi Al Sufal and Al Dhifar are safely accessible by the general population selling basic food commodities and NFI items. Oxfam will continue to monitor and analyze market conditions during the period of UCT cash distribution, ensuring beneficiary acceptance of UCT cash modality. Oxfam will directly implement the project ensuring the quality of program delivery and compliance with FSAC and OCHA YHF accountability measures. Oxfam will conduct a safe programming risk assessment before project implementation to identify possible risks amp put a monitoring system in place to reduce and manage identified risks such as sub-agreement delays and changes in market availability/prices. Oxfam has relevant tools and experience in identifying project risks and mitigation measures, including mainstreaming protection and COVID-19 pandemic response measures in line with organizational protocols and as per Oxfam&#x2019;s approved SOPs. Oxfam has been operational in Ibb since 2019 and has excellent experience and capacity to implement the cash-based proposed intervention in a participatory, collaborative, transparent, and accountable manner, whilst addressing specific and differentiated needs of particularly vulnerable groups including women, and girls, and people with disabilities. Oxfam will closely work with SCMCHA, FSAC community leaders, merchants, traders, and affected communities, to successfully implement the project, engaging all key stakeholders to implement the project in line with local, international, and FSAC standards.Oxfam will coordinate and collaborate with the IDP Executive Unit, NGOs, INGOs, RRM, UN agencies, amp Nutrition, Protection, WASH, Health amp FSAC clusters on inclusive food security activities, including specific and differentiated needs relating to men, women, boys, and girls, and people with disabilities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taha Alraeeini</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>739705557</telephone>
   <email>talraeeini@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.05521633 44.26319019</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">912648.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">36505.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17920">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">949154</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304915934">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-12">379661.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
