<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="7" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-08T03:05:53.893" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-20/DDA-3558/COVID 19 RA/COVID-19/INGO/15788</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency support for COVID-19 affected vulnerable communities in Aleppo Governorate through risk communication, community engagement and specialized protection services.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project proposal addresses the protection needs of the most vulnerable IDPs, returnees and host communities exposed to COVID-19 risk of infection, through different sets of activities to be implemented in Jabel Saman, As-Safira, Zerbeh and Abu Tuhul sub-districts. It is based on COOPI previous and ongoing implementation of community-based protection programs in Aleppo, Rural Damascus and Dara&#x2019;a Governorates. Individual assistance for the most vulnerable women and girls will be provided through the distribution of dignity kits, both in remote and unserved urban areas. The identification of women benefiting from dignity kits will be done in collaboration and through the engagement of women committees&#x2019; members, supported by COOPI protection staff. Dignity kits will also be provided to women sheltered in quarantine/isolation facilities as currently SARC only has access, beneficiaries list will be handled by SARC and distribution will be done through SARC personnel. To promote risk communication and community engagement (RCCE), the use of remote communication channels will be prioritized to provide culturally appropriate and targeted awareness messages and information related to COVID-19. Community-based communication will be pursued mainly engaging volunteers, committees and stakeholders, as preferential sources of risk information dissemination about COVID-19, in the set-up of the risk information campaign. Acknowledging risk perceptions, behaviors, existing barriers and specific needs, COOPI will target communities/groups with accurate and tailored information, spread through the appropriate communication channels. Depending on the network coverage and beneficiaries&#x2019; access to media, radio, phone, social media will be used alternatively. Through regular and proactive communication, COOPI will contribute to reduce social stigma about COVID-19, by providing accurate information, to improve dialogue and avoid misunderstandings. In collaboration with community members and in line with WHO and Protection sector guidelines, relevant IEC materials will be developed to be context specific and immediately applicable. Children will be targeted with specific awareness materials and parents will be previously trained to support children in understanding the basic prevention measures on COVID-19 and overcome psychological distress. Community-based protection will be carried out through volunteers, mobilizers and committees. Based on the experience gained during the implementation of protection interventions in Nashabiyeh and Aleppo, Women, Elderly and Child Welfare Committees will be established ant trained to identify and monitor the increasing of protection risk related to COVID-19 pandemic, to facilitate the access of the most vulnerable to remote case management services and to raise awareness on protection (PSS, CP, SGBV, mine risk education). Support activities will be carried out to ensure continuation of critical protection activities, such as remote case management, counseling and psychological first aid (PFA). COOPI will engage with key actors in the area, to ensure a set up/strengthening and constant update of the referral pathways, ensuring that PoCs have access to accurate and relevant information to access the services needed. PWSN requiring physical, hearing, speech therapy will receive specialized assistance through video sessions prerecorded by therapists. Caregivers will be remotely trained from specialized staff and some tablet per targeted area will be distributed with the support of volunteers to be used on a rotational basis by the people assisted. To further enhance social cohesion, COOPI will sustain the development of a community self-support groups. Volunteers trained on COVID-19 prevention measures and provided with PPA, will be in charge to assist the most vulnerable, as elderly, PWSN, women headed HHs, to carry out daily activities, reduce the family burden and facilitate the supply of basic items.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPI Cooperazione Internazionale</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPI Cooperazione Internazionale</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Floriana Bucca</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection FP / Project Manager Aleppo</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0969330041</telephone>
   <email>pm.damascus@coopi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Severin Vandewalle</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Administrator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+963 969 33 00 23</telephone>
   <email>admin.syria@coopi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-05">299139.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-05">82860.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-15788">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-05">382000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPI Cooperazione Internazionale</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304639923">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-10">305600</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPI Cooperazione Internazionale</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304915975">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">76400</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPI Cooperazione Internazionale</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
