<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="64" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-21T02:05:11.543" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-08-26T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/Shelter/NGO/16900</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving emergency shelter kits and NFIs to vulnerable populations with a focus on newly displaced and protracted  IDPs, and affected IDP hosts in Dollow, Luuq, and Garbaharey Gedo Region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to provide lifesaving assistance to 3954 HH (Boys=4744, Girls=7118, women=7828, Men=4034) in Gedo region (Dollow, Luuq and Garbaharrey) through the distribution of Non-food Items (NFIs) and Emergency Shelter Kits (ESK). They will be distributed to newly arrived IDPs, protracted IDPs and affected host who did not receive any assistance in 2019 or early 2020 and mainly affected by flood. The target population (women, girls, men, boys, elderly and people with disabilities) living in the IDP site reside in small makeshift structures made of sub-standard materials that jeopardize their physical security, privacy, and from vagaries of nature and diseases. 


Under this project, HAPEN will distribute 3954 NFIs and 3954 ESKs as in-kind to 9 IDP site in Gedo region Dollow: (Kabasa = 655, Qansahley = 550, Host 100), Luuq: Jazeera =314, Xero kowad= 470 and Boyle=420 Host =100), and Garbahrey: (Towfiq =270, Tula qorah =345, Hashi Weer =380, Tafta taag =250 and Host 100).


Beneficiaries will be selected through a participatory process driven by a representative project and site management committees while ensuring marginalized groups interests are catered for and vulnerable approach, considering issues such as women-headed and child-headed households, orphans, disabled, the old among and new arrivals, protracted, and distribution.

The proposed intervention targets 3654 IDP HHs (21,924 IDP persons) and 300 IDP host HHs (1,800) in Dollow, Garbaharey and Luuq. The protracted IDPs targeted are those living in Grabahrey. These families belong to most vulnerable IDPs who live in makeshift buuls without adequate access to NFIs and Emergency Shelter. 

Following a need-based and transparent selection of beneficiaries and on local market conditions, HAPEN will facilitate a direct-distribution program through which targeted IDPs and select host communities will receive ESKs and NFIs. HAPEN will employ an owner-driven approach in the construction of emergency shelters by capacitating the IDPs to undertake the construction process.

Protection and GBV concerns will be factored during site selection and will be integrated in all aspects of the response. Proper site planning will be undertaken to ensure effective mitigation of hazards and reduce alarming congestion levels in target settlements.

On monitoring and evaluation, Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) and Post Construction Monitoring (PCM) will be conducted after distribution and construction respectively. Therefore, two PDM exercises will be conducted for the two phases of NFI distributions. The monitoring exercise will provide beneficiary feedback on the effectiveness and collate lessons of the distribution. 90% of the beneficiaries will take part in the exercise to ensure proper representation and accurate reflection on the process and quality of the intervention. 

The PDM will support measuring beneficiary satisfaction of the items distributed and identify the needs and feelings of the community better. The exercises will inform on the effectiveness of the activities and achievements of targets while providing guidance towards the overall objective. 

3 Community Response and Feedback Mechanism (CRFM) desks, one for each district of operation will be established, in addition to the hotline and PDM /PCM. COVID-19 preventative mechanisms will be adopted in CRFM and during distribution to minimize any occurrence of infections.

The desks will be manned by two personnel and the anticipated data to be collected include among others both compliments and complaints: the quality of the ESKs and NFIs, beneficiary selection processes, shortness of items distributed, delays and other unexpected feedback. HAPEN&#x2019;s staff will analyze the collected data and respond accordingly. This will ensure that community participation and AAP are enhanced.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa Peace Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa Peace Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibrahim Abdi Dubat</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+25261756018 / +254791371159</telephone>
   <email>ibrahimdubat@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-08-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-18">911667.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-18">388074.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-16900">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-18">1299742.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa Peace Network</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304701677">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-26">779845.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa Peace Network</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
