<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="24" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA2/WASH-FSL/INGO/17644</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency flood response with WASH and EFSL integrated interventions targeting flood affected population in Rumbek East and Rumbek Center, Lakes State in South Sudan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This flood response project will provide emergency WASH and EFSL interventions targeting 42,000 of the flood-affected population, i.e. 7,000 Households (ICCG report, October 2020) in Rumbek East and Rumbek Center counties within Lakes state, South Sudan. These communities have been affected by flooding since July 2020. The impact of the floods has varied, with some families having lost their homes after these were submerged, while others lost valuable assets to the floods but have been able to remain close to, or in, their homes. Lakes state is among the flood affected counties which also includes Jonglei, Unity, Central and Western Equatoria and Upper Nile states. This flooding comes barely a year after another round of devastating floods in the same locations in 2019. According to the ICCG report of 12th October 2020, a total of 42,000 people in the two counties require immediate humanitarian assistance. The floods have destroyed homes and forced people to move to higher grounds. The outwards migration from the flood-affected areas into other neighboring locations has increased pressure on existing services in those locations, hence increased deterioration of the humanitarian situation.

This project will provide emergency assistance in WASH and EFSL, as per the Second Reserve Allocation, towards reducing morbidity, mortality and suffering among the most vulnerable populations and facilitate safe, equitable and dignified access to critical basic services to enable populations to meet their basic needs. This will include improving access to adequate and safe water, appropriate sanitation, solid waste management and raise awareness related to good hygiene practices and behavior through dissemination of hygiene messages. The emergency WASH assistance will involve distribution of point-of-use/household level water treatment chemicals and storage containers to targeted households which have no access to safe water sources. Water quality monitoring and testing will be carried out by trained Community Hygiene Promoters (CHPs) targeting free residual chlorine in water at the point-of-use and faecal coliform contamination. Good hygiene practices will be promoted through distribution of hygiene and dignity/Menstrual Hygiene Management (MHM) kits, COVID-19 risk communication, hygiene awareness raising and dissemination of messages through available media, house-to-house visits and campaigns by the community structures which include CHPs, Community Health Volunteers (CHVs), community leaders and WASH and Protection committees. Key hygiene messages will include safe water chain through household water treatment and safe storage, hand washing with soap, proper use of latrines, drainage of stagnant water and management of solid waste including safe disposal of animal carcasses in consultation with health partners. The early recovery phase of the project will involve repair and rehabilitation of the existing WASH facilities in the target locations which includes boreholes/hand pumps, sanitation and solid waste management facilities. All activities will be carried out after a Gender and Protection risk mitigation analysis/audit has been conducted in consultation with women and girls to ensure that that safe locations are selected for intervention sites and appropriate, gender sensitive facilities are designed and implemented.
EFSL targets1500 beneficiaries (900 Females amp 600 Males)  in Rumbek Center the project will train targeted beneficiaries on good agronomic practice,training on modern fishing methods including better ways of fish preservation,transportation of fishing and vegetable kit from Juba to Rumbek and distribution of fishing and vegetable kits,formation of production groups and social audits.

The project will be implemented by Oxfam directly but in close coordination with key Clusters, including WASH, FSL and Protection, other partners on ground and the local authorities so as to ensure complementarity and avoid duplicati</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-FSC-160488-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-WSH-161317-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ohisa James Claudios</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211923104940</telephone>
   <email>OJames@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lakes</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.60307990 29.97405340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="7" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="93" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">70092.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">305290.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-17644">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">375382.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304822951">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">225229.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
