<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="24" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-21T02:05:33.237" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-05T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/WASH/INGO/17408</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Provision of WASH Services to the Flood Affected Populations in Jowhar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The floods in Jowhar have affected many villages such as Buulo Maxamud, Khalafow, Guumeys, Gumarey, Guumeysta, Caliwarabey, Duray, Maryan Keynan, Dhay-Gawan. The villages are home to pastoralists and agrarian communities.  Other villages that are affected by the floods include Athale, Haji Ali, Mahaday, Sabuni, Congo, Grasweyn and Adow uul. According to OCHA updates 1 on Deyr Season Floods Update, as of 4 November 2020, the flood in Jowhar affected 27,364 person living in Jowhar .The update also reported that on 3rd and 4th November 2020, flash floods cut the road linking Jowhar to Mogadishu at a location 10 km south of Jowhar.  The floods also affected the road to the airport. On 12th and 13th October 2020, heavy rains triggered flash floods in the riverine villages affecting about 3,600 people.  The Jowhar authorities reported that two children drowned as the result of the flash floods.The floods caused various impact to the WASH facilities the findings indicate that only less than 10% of the total affected population have access to safe water drinking water. Most of the infrastructure such as latrines have submerged and destroyed as the result of the floods. Sanitation is a serious issue due to the inadequate number of latrines in comparison to the population in need and many people are practice open defecation due to lack of sufficient latrines against the population. Lack of adequate and safe sanitation puts women, girls and at risk of physical violence and sexual assault as they relieve themselves in the open field.The water have been contaminated and not fit for human consumption leading to potential outbreaks of water-borne diseases and acute water diarrhea.Therefore, in order to fill the gaps Islamic relief Somalia with funding from OCHA is planning to fill the gaps by rehabilitating of 5 shallow wells, two 2 boreholes and construction of 200 flood latrines.The project aims to tackle the effects emanating from the floods by providing emergency WASH services in Jowhar district, Somalia. The intervention is in line with the WASH strategy. It will also link to recovery and resilience building of the communities by rehabilitating WASH infrastructure that will assist 16,500 direct beneficiaries affected by Hagaa floods in Jowhar .The project will install solar power systems to the two (02) boreholes that are to be  rehabilitated  in jowhar depending on the needs while the rehabilitation of five (05) shallow wells will be undertaken at Mahaday,gumeysta,congo,marerey and cali warabey. The shallow wells will be rehabilitated, protected and upgrading including the installation of Two (2) boreholes that will be rehabilitated will be connected to water piping system including construction of four (4) water kiosk from the main borehole, gender balanced water management committees will be formed and trained. Islamic Relief Somalia will provide emergency water trucking to 4,000 beneficiaries in the rural areas of Jowhar district Each beneficiary will receive water in accordance with sphere standard of (7.5 liters/ per person per day). Water through tricks will be delivered on daily through blanket system which ensured beneficiaries know the quantity and where water should be collected.The displaced population in Jowhar are at risk of contracting malaria, acute bloody or watery diarrhoea, measles and other sanitation related diseases, The project will construct 200 emergency pit latrines to reduce AWD cases and improve the sanitation services. The latrines will be designed in line with the protection guidelines and segregated according to the sex. 20 latrines will be designed to meet the special requirements of people with disability.The project will construct and install 10 COVID-19 hand washing stations in order to  prevent COVID-19.The IDPs and the host communities will benefit from hygiene promotion campaigns focusing on hand washing with soap and production of IEC materials.1500 HHs will receive hygiene kits.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide - Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide - Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-17" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aliow Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252616337439</telephone>
   <email>Aliow.mohamed@irworld.wide.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shukri  Mohamud Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Area Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252618952867</telephone>
   <email>Shukri.ali@islamic-relief.or.ke</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-23">31149.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-23">402550.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17408">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-23">433700.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide - Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304859964">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-05">216850.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide - Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
