<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="42" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-24T02:08:01.12" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-21T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/Protection/INGO/17910</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 2 - Integrated emergency protection response for the most vulnerable conflict-affected people in Aden (Dar Sa&apos;ad)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS is seeking to sustain the Community Center (CC) in Dar Sa&#x2019;ad (Aden), established under SA1 2018 and further supported with SA2 2019. The CC is located in a prioritized district with highest needs severity score (level 6). 
At the CC, the team will provide individual case management (ICM) services for PoCs with acute and ongoing protection needs &#x2013; focus on CP, GBV and PwSN provide collective PSS for adults (men and women) and children aimed at enhanced family resilience and community solidarity enhance community based protection mechanisms and community resilience by enrolling community outreach volunteers run livelihoods/skills training that permit the social-economic integration of women/girls at risk and GBV survivors and lastly run awareness raising and information sharing on protection related services and issues. Meanwhile, the CC will continue to be a place of opportunity for integration of services with other sectors, running ad hoc and regularly recurring activities, such as health and nutrition. The ICM package comprises: identification, psycho-social first aid (PSFA), psychosocial counseling (PSC), and internal and external referrals for specialized services, in addition to follow-up and case closure. Internal referral within the project for specialized services include: legal assistance, psychological counseling, cash for protection and livelihoods. Cash for protection is an integral part of the assistance package for case under ICM, conditional to risk assessment and ensuring that cash assistance will contribute to direct protection outcomes. Integration with other sectors is covered: INTERSOS will continue to run mobile health-nutrition services (DG ECHO and potential OCHA YHF) and the MCT is visiting the CC weekly. For any CP amp GBV related activities, INTERSOS will coordinate with the sub-national CP amp GBV sub-clusters.

INTERSOS ensures outreach through a network of community outreach volunteers (COVs) supporting the protection staff at the CC with screening/identification, referral, follow-up and help to build community engagement (bridge between community and center) and raise awareness on INTERSOS services. While outreach is firstly in function of service delivery and the project does not cover protection monitoring &#x2013; as this is covered under UNHCR programming in the targeted governorates (the  actions complement each other), still the team will monthly conduct a number of FGDs to zoom in on some protection trends and permit more in-depth analysis, feeding into the monthly protection monitoring reports and bi-yearly protection trend analyses produced. The team will be able to support any rapid protection assessment (RPA) needs. Also, protection related trends and issues will be reported by COVs to activity coordinators and the verification and information collection will be done by protection monitors working under UNHCR grant. 
Over the past years, INTERSOS developed excellent relations with local stakeholders, demonstrating its ability to deliver, within budget and close on target, with effective access and presence in the targeted area. INTERSOS has a long-term experience in the protection sector, in particular for integrated individual case management (since 2008 in Yemen) and community center modality.

INTERSOS also demonstrated its high adaptability and focus during 2020 COVID-19 peak, being able to continue to run its protection programming, with the necessary adaptation and preventative measures Where life became complex, people felt unsafe and abandoned, the CC was for many the only remaining safe space to get away from the daily hassles and dangers/risks.
The approximate budget that INTERSOS is looking for 649,949.49 US$, for 12 months, for 7,991 direct beneficiaries (without double counting) for 72% IDPs, 4% Returnees and 24% Host Community, and 22% men, 47% women, 15.5% boys and 15.5% girls, at average cost of 81 US$ per beneficiary.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evelyn Lernout</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967 715 555 001 / 736 846 999</telephone>
   <email>yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Miasa Al-Matari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Finance Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967 778004508</telephone>
   <email>admin.yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aden</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.84865928 45.00201169</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-15">644592.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-15">5356.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17910">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-15">649949.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304883787-788">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-21">519959.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
