<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="39" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-11T02:07:35.79" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/WASH/INGO/17751</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing Critical WASH Needs in Kachin State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to provide essential WASH services to 12 host communities and one IDP camp in locations of identified need in Injangyang and Waingmaw townships, Kachin State. Of these 13 locations, 12 are located in KIO-controlled Non-Government Controlled Areas (NGCAs), with the IDP camp located in a Government-Controlled Area (GCA). Through this action, Trocaire and partners will ensure that targeted communities have safe access to drinking water, adequate WASH infrastructure (through both construction of new infrastructure and renovation of existing infrastructure) and receive key messages to promote good hygiene practices in the camps. There will also be awareness raising on the risks of COVID-19 and provision of hygiene materials. 


Tr&#xF3;caire is the lead organization on this project, providing technical support and guidance to implementing partner organisations Community Health and Development (CHAD) and Serve the World (STW), both of whom have established presence and track records in the targeted locations. Locations and approaches have been identified by partners themselves, in close consultation with the Kachin WASH Sub-Cluster and guided by the priority locations and approaches identified in the 2nd Standard Allocation Strategy. 


Activities will focus on construction of new WASH infrastructure, rehabilitation of existing WASH infrastructure, covering operation and management costs of infrastructure, distribution of hygiene materials (including menstrual hygiene materials), community awareness-raising water treatment with an emphasis on locally-managed solutions, community hygiene promotion (with an emphasis on COVID-19 prevention) and distribution of targeted IEC materials. Communities will be sensitised on Safeguarding and Accountability, and given clear information on how and where to raise complaints and grievances. Activities are designed to be deliverable within the timeframe and adaptable to developments related to COVID-19 and its impacts. A Monitoring and Evaluation plan has been established, and clear steps taken to deliver an Exit Strategy that will help ensure the sustainability of the impact of the action. 

Protection is mainstreamed throughout this action, in recognition of the high levels of vulnerability of many in the target communities, including women and girls, the elderly and persons living with disabilities. Disability inclusion will also be mainstreamed throughout project activities, and to this end Tr&#xF3;caire has enlisted support from Humanity and Inclusion (HI), an aid organisation with specific expertise on ensuring the inclusion and meaningful engagement of all in society, to ensure that persons living with disabilities are not left behind by the action, and are effectively consulted and engaged in the activities. This will include: guidance on the Washington Group Questions, foundation training followed by refresher training on disability inclusion for implementing partner organisations, and recommendations over the course of the project, in addition to other areas. 

Tr&#xF3;caire has established ongoing working relationships with CHAD and with Humanity amp Inclusion, and will seek to build upon and leverage learning from these prior experiences to influence ways of working on this action. Serve The World come with a strong recommendation from the Kachin WASH Sub-Cluster, and will undergo Trocaire&#x2019;s tried-and-tested procedure for new partners, including assessments on the minimum requirements expected of partner organisation, capacity support and inductions on our ways of working.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Handicap International Federation (doing business as Humanity amp; Inclusion) - HI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Health and Development (CHAD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Serve The World</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sam Godolphin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 9895731372</telephone>
   <email>sam.godolphin@trocaire.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seng Kai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director (CHAD)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+959893021852</telephone>
   <email>chadmka09@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hkawng Dau</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director (Serve The World)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+959403249034 +959793409732</telephone>
   <email>stw.director2018@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR001">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00000000 97.50000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-08">145741.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-17751">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-08">145741.77</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304876498">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-14">116593.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
