<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="91" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-09T03:07:29.967" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-17T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA6/N/INGO/17747</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Lifesaving Nutrition Services in the low coverage high caseload districts in Badghis Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The designed project aims at ensuring delivery of adequate nutrition/health services, including the malnutrition treatment compromised due to the movement restrictions and other stressors. The disruption of nutrition service provision due overburdened health facilities is expected to deteriorate the nutrition status of children, as well as pregnant and lactating women in the pre-defined high-risk districts (Qadis, Jawand and Abkamari in Badghis province). World Vision (WV) Intends to deliver the required nutrition services through the establishment of 3 Mobile Health and Nutrition teams as well as strengthening decentralized nutrition services in 10 Sub-Health Centers (SHC) in these districts.
World Vision will also focus on CHWs, Family Health action Groups to learn key Maternal Infant and Young Child Feeding and nutrition (MIYCN) to increase community awareness on key respective practices. In addition, under this project World Vision promote mother MUAC approach to put mothers at the center of malnutrition screening. The mother MUAC strategies acknowledge that mothers are in the best position to detect the earliest signs of malnutrition and leverages the fact that mothers want to participate as fully as possible in promoting the health and nutrition of their children. The mothers will report on MUAC screening once a month. Further the proposed project will work to strengthen the capacity of Family Health Action Groups, female volunteers and CHWs in Infant and Young Child Feeding to promote key IYCF practices and counselling based on the WHO guideline under the COVID-19 circumstances. These groups will be trained to respond the question of key community members and women in childbearing ages in relation on promotion of breastfeeding and be able to respond any questions that may be asked by each member of the community. The project will focus on early action to avoid severe malnutrition so the project will cover the, borderline&#x2019; cases of acute malnutrition through prevention-oriented services such as counselling on optimal care practices to mothers of children who are borderline in terms of their Mid-Upper Arm Circumference (MUAC). This approach has potential to reduce the risk of rapid deterioration of the nutritional status of children with a MUAC result of 12.5-13.5 cm. This will be done at the MHNTs level by nutrition nurse and at the community level by community nutrition promoters. The adaptation mechanism will be taken into consideration during any capacity building efforts, IYCF promotion session based on the WHO/MOPH and WV Standard Operating Procedure for training, public gatherings, IEC distribution under the COVID-19 circumstances. The project will focus on the provision of lifesaving referral for those cases that require inpatient services and will ensure that a transportation and treatment facility are provided for them. WV attends the EPR meetings on a weekly basis and will update the key actors including DoPH, UNICEF and WHO on the project progress the project report will be shared on a weekly and monthly basis to the key nutrition cluster focal points and DEWS surveillance focal points. In the EPR meetings, various issues are discussed such as places where the new MHNTs should operate and take proper measures to avoid overlap of same interventions. 


The project will focus on provision and maintenance of the heaters for each section of the MHNTs activities and in particular on the nutrition spaces and will make sure solid and proper winterization plan in place. 


The project will use the community health promoter and nutrition nurses to record all the children with disabilities as well as disabled PLW in a separate registration book and ensure they receive proper medical assessment and receive curative and counseling health and nutrition service. Through GIK WV will distribute the wheel-chair to them and ensure MHNT and SHC are friendly enough for the children and PLWs with disability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asuntha Charles</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799 209 720</telephone>
   <email>Asuntha_Charles@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonathan Chifamba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799 490 407</telephone>
   <email>Jonathan_Chifamba@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Faisal Danesh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance/Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 792 494 002</telephone>
   <email>Faisal_Danesh@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">44198.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">455801.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-17747">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">500000.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304839923">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-17">400000.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
