<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="67" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-29T02:06:03.997" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-26T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA2/H/INGO/15994</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment of 14 CCTCs in NW Syria in response to COVID-19 preparedness plan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to provide life-saving and life-sustaining coordinated, equitable health services for all age and sex groups boys, girls, women, and men, with attention to people with special needs without any sexual discrimination, among IDPs and host communities in 14 sub-districts in Idleb and Aleppo governorates-Syria through establishing (installation) of Community-Based Isolation Centers (CBICs) that provides sample collection and observation of suspected COVID-19 cases, accommodation and follow up of the confirmed mild cases and short monitoring and surveillance of the recovered cases till they are discharged. Estimated direct beneficiaries: 2,800 while total population in the catchment area of CBICs  is 673,246
This project reflects the high coordination with other Health NGOs in COVID-19 Task force which is the umbrella for other complimentary activities (such as training of health staff, triage, lab testing and surveillance, referral and checkpoints managing) to compose a coherent system that efficiently contains COVID-19 outbreak in case it comes up. CBIC is composed of 6 rub hall tents+ 12 smaller ordinary tents each rub hall is divided into patient wards for different purposes to serve a pre-designed patient flow to guarantee the isolation of the suspected and confirmed mild cases and to provide them with the supportive therapy till they recover and discharged. This flow design was created in the COVID-19 Task force under technical advisory of the World Health Organization (WHO) to serve as a buffer system designed to protect vulnerable communities in Syria from COVID-19 spread, especially residents of overcrowded areas, specifically camps, where the patient does not have the possibility of home isolation in case he/she is became a suspected or confirmed COVID-19 case.

Patient flow in CBIC will be as follows:
Stage 1: accommodates 10 patients, which is the registration and survey point that records the suspected patients before they enter to move to the control area (stage 2). Suspected patients will be transferred from different health facilities (after screening) via the referral system. The suspected COVID-19 patient will be decontaminated, the sample will be withdrawn and sent to the laboratory. The patient will remain in the observation area pending the results of the laboratory. Hygiene measures will be taken (hand washing, wearing suit and face mask). If the laboratory results are negative, the patient will be discharged after decontamination. If the results of the laboratory are positive, then the patient will be transferred to the case management area where will remain until recovery.

Stage 2: accommodates 20 patients, which is the space for managing and isolating minor cases: supportive treatment will be applied. If the patient deteriorates, he will be transferred to the specified referral isolation hospitals. The average period for a patient to stay in this department is 14 days, until he has fully recovered.
Stage 3: accommodates 20 patients, after the patient improves, s/he will be transferred to the healing area where s/he will be re-tested/ if it is negative, will be discharged after decontamination.

A scheme of the Community-Based Isolation Unit is attached.

The main activities of the project are: 
 Carry out the planned procurement process for materials needed to establish CBICs.
 Coordination with stakeholders at the sites in need that were previously identified for setting up units.
 Install and setup units.
 Handing over the units to partner concerned with operating the units in coordination with the COVID-19 Task force and health directorates.
 Paper and media documentation.
 Close the project with the final report.

From the perspective of gender-based violence, QC will ensure that the standards of gender-based violence are integrated into the design of CBICs where there will be women&apos;s areas (for patients and personnel) separate from men&apos;s areas in line with th</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">830007.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-15994">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">830007.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304660521">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-26">664006.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
