<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="18" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-26T03:06:49.497" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/FSAC/NGO/17908</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prrority 2: Provision of immediate life-saving emergency food assistance to the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs living in deplorable conditions with host families in Ad Dhale&apos;e District of Al Dhale&#x2019;e governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposed project is implemented under Priority  2: Covering gaps in clusters&#x2019; ongoing emergency response for people in acute need of the 1st SA YHF 2020, with the objective to provide immediate funding to assist people in acute humanitarian needs to mitigate the risks of famine and negative consequences of COVID-19. The 12-months intervention will provide immediate life-saving emergency food assistance to the 400 acutely IDPs HHs living with host families (2,800 individuals disaggregated:666 men, 764 women, 662 boys, 708 girls) in Ad Dhale&apos;e District of Al Dhale&#x2019;e governorate allowing them to meet their basic food needs through unconditional cash or value voucher assistance for 6 consecutive months to the same H/H.This project will contribute to FSAC objective of increasing access to food for highly vulnerable families across the country. MFD will select beneficiaries based on FSAC vulnerability and targeting criteria and will adhere to the amount of cash assistance as the FSAC Minimum Food Basket. The targeted beneficiaries are composed of Severely food insecure Vulnerable IDP HHs living with the host community, with children under 5 with SAM or MAM, pregnant amp lactating women, Child headed, Female-headed, HHs headed by Elderly, chronically, physically challenged. This project has designed based on the rapid needs assessment conducted in Ad Dhale&#x2019;e district in the late of Nov. 2020 to identify the needs of the targeted beneficiaries. The project activities including a detailed needs and market assessment that will be conducted in the start of the project to determine the localized needs of the IDPs and to determine appropriate modality (Cash/value voucher) of the food assistance.Further, MFD will conduct a rapid food security assessment to measure the food security indicators before the start  the project. In addition, Selection of CFMCs with the representation of at least 50% of women, beneficiaries registration and verification process according to FSAC vulnerability and targeting criteria, Provision of unconditional cash or value voucher assistance to  400 IDPs HHs in Ad Dhale&#x2019;e district for 6 consecutive months to the same HH. MFD has the technical capacity and access to implement this project. In terms of capacity, MFD has already implemented a YHF-funded food security project in Qattabah district of Al Dhale&#x2019;e governorate during 2018 which was evaluated by the third Party Monitoring (TPM) as &quot;good performance&quot;. In addition, MFD is currently implementing other FAO-funded food security and livelihood interventions in many Governorates (Abyan, Shabwah, Hadramuot, Aldhalea and Lahj). In terms of access, MFD has its main office in Aden governorate and can easily access and presence in Ad Dhale&#x2019;e district and have built excellent good relation with authority and other stakeholders through the previous YHF food security project in Qattabh district..MFD has assumed some risks that might be faced during the implementation of this project and planned to mitigate them:1.access constraint in the target areas which can be mitigated by enhancing the coordination with local authorities and issuing the required documents to facilitate the distribution of assistance.2 exclusion of some beneficiaries which can be mitigated by raising the awareness on beneficiary selection criteria, introducing different channels of complaints and feedback mechanism, ensuring beneficiaries are aware of complaint mechanisms and feel able to access them, learning from feedback and take corrective actions.5 conflict escalation in Al Dhale&apos;e where the target district is located which can be mitigated by coordinating with local authority at the level of district as well as governorate to ensure safe access to project location and deconflicting the activity sites and routes on the days of assistance distributions. MFD coordinates its activities with FSAC amp other stakeholders conducting similar Food Security projects to avoid overlapping amp duplication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayar Foundation for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayar Foundation for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awsan Saeed noman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>734966584</telephone>
   <email>awsan@mfd-yemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Dhale&apos;e</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.85996808 44.67423913</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-08">304647.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-08">8605.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17908">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-08">313253.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayar Foundation for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304869337-338">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-13">125301.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayar Foundation for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
