<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="99" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-06T03:07:42.33" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-08T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/FS/INGO/16283</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture based livelihood support for the vulnerable Syrians</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project seeks to improve the livelihood situation of 1,050 households (5,309 individuals) through livestock and agricultural support in Harim District of Idleb Governorates. The project is developed based on the primary need assessment conducted through focus group discussions and key informant interviews in Eleven communities including Merat Elshalaf, Sardin, Kafr Hind, Tellemar, Saidiyeh, Abu Talha, Allani, Hamziyeh, , Tilaada, Selwa, Hezreh in Idleb Governorate. 
Islamic Relief will conduct a detailed household level need assessment to identify, 500 families to provide with agricultural input (winter) including wheat seeds, fertilizers and basic tools. These families will be provided with ongoing technical support to improve their knowledge and practices to get best yield. The estimated yield will be sufficient to cover the food needs of the household and any excess can be sold in the market to create income generation. The direct recipient of Agriculture support will be 250 men and 250 women. 

550 families (who have existing livestock) will be provided with sheep feed and dry fodder (straw). During the gestation period the sheep will be provided feed. This will be the winter period when the feed is most expensive and unaffordable. The sheep will be vaccinated to prevent them from prevailing diseases. The households will also receive livestock kit to help them in collecting and processing milk. The expected milk production is sufficient to cover the household diary needs and any excess can be sold in the market to contribute to the income. The direct recipient of this component will be 275 men and 275 women. 
The beneficiaries of both component will be connected to the markets by providing all the necessary information about where agricultural and livestock products are sold near to their lands and the current market prices, which help beneficiaries not to travel long distances in addition to linking wheat producers with the beneficiaries of the same project in order to conduct an exchange of products, which contributes to reducing the costs of selling through intermediaries and contributes to the beneficiary&apos;s access to various animal products in the same place in order to obtain various products that meet their requirements. All information is provided through continuous communication with the groups of formed committees through awareness sessions conducted by the Islamic Relief Team.

Both beneficiary groups (livestock and agriculture) will continue to receive follow-up advice and training over the course of the project from field project team hired for this purpose. it is anticipated that this improved knowledge will be shared by the direct beneficiaries with their relatives, PEER and friends living in the close by area. hence the knowledge transfer will help to improve the agriculture-based livelihood practices for the other community members also.
Given the particular sensitivities related to women engaging in project activities a careful weighing of the risks associated with providing such support will be undertaken to ensure that no harm comes to beneficiaries or field staff. The project will seek to prioritize women and those with disabilities by tailoring the support provided, in an effort to better respond to their specific needs and concerns. 
IR staff will organize an awareness session for IR staff and gather Medical face masks, Alcohol sterile, LaTeX gloves, and thermometer for COVID-19 protection.
The project will target both the IDP and host population so that the social tensions among the two groups are minimized and equal opportunities are provided to help the extremely vulnerable families to stand on their own feet and build a culture of resilience. 
IR will implement cluster proposed sector integration strategy whereby the households shifting from food support to agriculture base livelihood are prioritised.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-164510-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">199530.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">197349.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16283">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">396879.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304667965">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">238127.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
