<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="85" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-17T03:07:59.313" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-28T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/NFI/ES/INGO/17539</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency CRI and Cash for Rental Housing for conflict affected people in Nejo, Mana Sibu and Boji Dirmeji woredas of West Wollega zone, Oromia Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IDP/returnee landscape in Ethiopia has changed drastically throughout 2020. The Ethiopia DTM Round 22 report indicates that, the number of IDPs currently stands at 1.8 million (329,084HHs, of whom 50 percent female IDPs), located across 1,297 sites in five regions. Out of the total displaced people, 100,405HHs  were identified in 437 sites in Oromia region. Conflict was the primary reason for displacement for an estimated 426,881 IDPs (72%), while 78,243 IDPs (13%) were displaced due to other reasons and 72,324 IDPs (12%) due to drought (Ethiopia National Displacement Report 5, July 2020). Many IDPs do not have access to shelter and are forced to sleep in overcrowded spaces including emergency shelters or in communal sites. These IDPs share household items, and with limited or no possibility to quarantine safely, they are at a higher risk of COVID-19. 
In Oromia region, Borena, Guji, East Hararge, West Hararge and West Wollega zones are amongst the prioritized areas for multi-sector intervention (HRP Mid-Year Review, August 2020). According to the Inter -Agency Multi-Sectoral Rapid Needs Assessment conducted from June 8-12, 2020, IDPs experiencing a secondary displacement are being hosted in West Wollega Zone, Oromia. The situation of the IDPs in West Wollega is complex, some of these IDPs live with the host communities while other settle in the rural areas living in substandard living conditions. The secondary displaced IDPs are living dispersed throughout the host community in rental houses and it has been difficult for the IDPs to afford the expensive cost of rental houses due to limited incomes from displacement. In addition, although IDPS received NFIs initially, that was over a year ago and many of the supplies are now damaged or were sold for food. The inter-agency assessment team, therefore recommends cash for rent intervention to address the needs of secondary displaced IDPs. 

In West Wollega, three woredas Nejo, Mana Sibu and Boji Dirmeji were identified as priority woredas for IDP responses (COVID-19 mitigations and IDPs responses) by the cluster. In the three woredas, there are 33,190 IDP: 5,361 in Mana Sibu 20,902 in Nejo, and 6,927 in Boji Dirmeji. The national Shelter and NFI cluster recommended to provide a six-month rental support for IDPs living in the host communities and Core Relief Items(CRI) V1 for IDPs. Accordingly, CRS with its partner Ethiopian Catholic Church Social and Development Commission Office of Nekemete (ECC-SDCON) will target a total of 2,690HHs in Nejo, Mana Sibu and Boji Dirmeji. Among them 1,460 HHs will receive cash for rental and 1,230HHs will receive in -kind and/or cash for CRI V1. 

Among 1,460HHs who will be targeted for cash for rental, 530HHs will be in Mana Sibu,490HHs in Nejo and 440HHs in Boji Dirmeji. The cash will be provided for six months with an average cost of cash for rent is 12.5USD per month per HH and the cash will be provided to targeted households in 2 rounds (distribute 3 months house rental in one round). Among the 1,230HHs who will be targeted for CRI V1, 450HHs will be in Mana Sibu, 410HHs in Nejo and 370HHs in Boji Dirmeji woredas. The average cost of each CRI V1 kit is 82USD. CRS/partner will provide sensitization to the targeted HHs and the community including families who are renting out their house. The orientation for the targeted HH will focus on best use of the CRI and cash for rental. An orientation will be provided to families who are renting house and to vendors on code of conduct.

Before determining the modalities for the CRI, CRS will conduct a market assessment in the three woredas and consult communities to understand their preferred assistance modalities. If cash is feasible, CRS will use Cash and Asset Transfer platform for beneficiary registration and distribution. To enable HHs purchase the items in their nearby, CRS will deal with vendors to bring the market close to the beneficiaries and provide a code of conduct orientation/</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopian Catholic Church Social and Development Commission Office of Nekemet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zemede Abebe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-91150-7305</telephone>
   <email>zemede.zewdie@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fasil Tefera</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-973-344-120</telephone>
   <email>fasil.tefera@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-27">22027.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-27">287820.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17539">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-27">309848.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304897657">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-28">309848.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
