<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="129" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-29T02:06:03.997" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/H/NGO/16397</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated and Community-based Specialized and Non-Specialized Mental Health and Psychosocial Support Services for Unserved Communities in the Euphrates Shield Area</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to support the MH specialized facility in Azaz, which includes acute MHPSS center, chronic MHPSS center, and OPD. Those departments are supported by two MHPSS mobile clinics. 
Objectives of the project:

1- Supporting community-based acute mental health center with 20 beds acute mental health care 
2- Supporting home-based care facility for the chronic mental health patients

3- Support of two MHPSS mobile clinics/ PSWs teams for far-flung unserved communities in Euphrates Shield areas.
mental health services will be provided in three levels of care, namely: 
a. Specialized Mental Care: Azaz MH center with Acute Inpatient Care.
MH Center with Acute Inpatient Care where has both OPD and 20 beds (male and female) to accommodate 20 acute mentally ill patients that may stay until a maximum of 2 weeks, and ensure provision of community-based care by caregivers/families thru follow-ups, and home visits.
This will also include 24-hour crisis intervention services, patient-focused of quality care, provision of extracurricular activities for the physical and mental well-being of inpatients including regular PSS individual or group counseling.
b. Home-based MHPSS Care: Azaz House of Hope for around 130 chronic mental health patients (males and females), providing a community-home based type of mental health care(residential home) where they will all be housed in a big home and provide support for a better quality of living condition, develop nurturing relationships, providing basic responsibilities and provide self-help activities and sports/ music activities that are tailored for them. 
Two MHPSS mobile clinics with PSWs Team at the community level where these will be providing outreach services in the unserved communities in Al-Bab in northern eastern of Aleppo governorate in the far-flung areas in Azaz and its neighboring areas
Mobile clinic consists of MhGap doctor and two PSWs male and female to respect the cultures of the targeted community.
The three-level of MHPSS services will be delivered based on humanitarian principles from designing, implementing, and finishing the project. Ensuring that the beneficiaries are providing dignity and respect his/her rights to access the said service, equal treatment for all beneficiaries from all genders and ages, not supporting nor helping either side in a conflict, and operational independence. Integrating mental health care into general health services produces a positive impact as reduced stigmatization of persons with mental disorders and a more efficient use of health resources. 
All the services shall be in a line of preparedness and response plan for COVID-19 in NWS, thru focusing on the following activities:
- Distribution of IEC MHPSS materials on COVID19. 
- Conducting individual Psychoeducation sessions for community leaders, Imams, Local Councils, youth leaders, and women&#x2019;s group to unify community messages, ensure that it is delivered through the appropriate outlets.
- Protect the staff and ensure that they can deliver safe mental health and psychosocial care to beneficiaries and apply do no harm policy.
A referral plan to Ibn-Khaldun mental health facility in Aleppo city will be applied according to approved selection criteria and after coordinating with all stakeholders ( WHO, Turkish DOH, local council, Ibn-Khaldun hospital, SARC ) for transferring the 79 inpatients by the provision of safe and secured passage from Azzaz Asylum Hospital into Ibn Khaldoun Hospital.
Herams code: B0204003 (Mental Hospital). UOSSM is committed to providing monthly updates to the health cluster about the project progress and activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-HEA-164691-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-09">263570.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-06"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-09">278461.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16397">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-09">542031.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304672007">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-14">325219.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
