<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-jordan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="12" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-01T03:05:53.587" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-08-06T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR-20/DDA-3560/SA1/H/NGO/16317</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the prevention of coronavirus (COVID-19) and non communicable diseases (NCD) prevention and management services for vulnerable and marginalized groups in Jordan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The new coronavirus (COVID-19) has spread to 213 countries and 2 cruise ships. There are 5,900,527 COVID-19 cases across the world: 2,577,181 recovered and 361,764 have died (Worldometer, Coronavirus, May 27, 2020). COVID-19 is an unprecedented global emergency, both in terms of the scale of public health preparedness and response, as well as its broader social and economic impacts due to associated lockdowns, particularly for vulnerable and marginalized groups.


The urgent COVID-19 health response in Jordan negatively affects the capacity of the health system to respond to the high prevalence of non-communicable diseases (NCDs) and associated health needs of the population. NCDs are the leading cause of mortality in Jordan, accounting to almost 80% of all deaths (World Health Organization, Jordan Health Profile). Equally, the economic consequences of COVID-19 and NCDs are massive due to the combined healthcare costs and lost economic productivity from the lockdown due to COVID-19, NCDs, and premature deaths caused by COVID-19 and NCDs. Current and projected repercussions from COVID-19 and an uncontrolled NCD burden on vulnerable host communities, specifically refugee populations, requires an urgent, enhanced, enlarged, integrated health system response, and development of a robust NCDs programme in Jordan. 


The Royal Health Awareness Society (RHAS) will prioritize the Health sector in this project proposal, based on its previous experience with Healthy Community Clinic (HCC) program since 2011 providing NCDs prevention and care and recent COVID-19 national campaign, as well as local consultations with the Ministry of Health (MOH), United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), World Health Organization (WHO), its partners, international and national non-governmental organizations (INGOs/NGOs), The project will support saving lives, alleviate suffering, and increase access to humanitarian assistance for vulnerable People with Special Needs, such as People Living With NCDs (PLWNCDs), NCD patients, elderly people at risk, Syrian refugees, refugees of other nationalities, and vulnerable Jordanians, inclusive of people with disabilities, prioritizing female-head households, incorporating gender mainstreaming, when possible. RHAS will provide safe and effective clinical care for NCD patients through care for individuals who are at the highest risk for poor outcomes, ensure that older patients, patients with comorbid conditions, and other vulnerable people are prioritized. The project&#x2019;s interventions will be multi-sectoral, with the aim to prevent and control COVID-19 and NCDs to foster a healthy societal environment, in which people are encouraged to make and maintain healthy living choices promote health literacy so that people can protect and improve their health build the capacity of health care providers provide health services focused on early detection of COVID-19, cost-effective management of NCDs and their risk factors respond to the specific needs of vulnerable groups with NCDs affected by the COVID-19 crisis, and keeping communities as protected as possible from the impact of COVID-19 and NCDs. To maximize the project&apos;s impact, the project activities will address critical needs in the Health sector and address the needs of healthcare providers, prioritizing areas with the highest needs, complementing sector projects and interventions in targeted geographical areas (primarily north and central governorates of Jordan), to support coherence and added value. The implementation of the project would promote a focus on COVID-19 and NCDs by the public health system in Jordan, specifically at primary care and community levels, whereby COVID-19 and NCDs are prevented and managed for refugee populations and Jordanians through an integrated national response. This would be embedded within the idealized transition towards &#x2018;universal health coverage&#x2019; for all, galvanized by the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Health Awareness Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Health Awareness Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arabian Medical Relief Jordan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Jordan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hanin Odeh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director General</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962777544433</telephone>
   <email>hodeh@rhas.org.jo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ragheed Darwazeh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962798254272</telephone>
   <email>finance@rhas.org.jo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amal Ireifij</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962778484960</telephone>
   <email>aireifij@rhas.org.jo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Mafraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.19290323 35.69146862</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amman</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.91905968 35.92902353</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Irbid</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.55798676 35.84675724</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zarqa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.07577806 36.08100277</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-30">130649.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-30">155576.04</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="JOR73-16317">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-30">286225.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Health Awareness Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304688532">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-06">228980.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Health Awareness Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
