<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ukraine-allocation-2020" dstore:index="2" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-05T02:06:43.933" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-24T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-20/UKR_CBPF/RA1/COVID-19/INGO/15731</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening COVID-19 emergency response for conflict affected vulnerable and disabled older women and men in settlements located in the 5km zone in the GCAs locations of Donetsk and Luhansk Oblasts.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine had its first confirmed case of COVID-19 on 3rd March, 2020. As of 9th April, the country has had 1,892 confirmed cases, including in the conflicted affected areas of Donestska and Luhanska, and 57 deaths, with many more suspected cases likely undetected due to a lack of access to testing. The daily rate of new cases per day has been increasing, the spread of the virus has caused major concern among the population in the country, especially for older men and women who are most at risk. 


Around 23% of the nation is above the age of 60, a similar percentage to that of Italy, the country that currently has the highest absolute number of mortalities caused by the virus, despite a more sophisticated health system than in places such as Ukraine. Over 80% of people who have died from COVID-19 in China were aged 60 and over and emerging data from the outbreak in Italy suggests an even more stark pattern by age. COVID-19 fatality rate also increases with pre-existing conditions such as cardiovascular disease, diabetes, chronic respiratory disease and hypertension. This highlights the correlation between COVID-19 severity and other medical conditions and complex needs, such as a disability that are highly related with old-age.This in addition to these vulnerable groups limited financial resources and access to basic hygiene items, food and health services in areas of Ukraine already compromised by conflict is especially concerning. 


Whilst the nation as a whole faces extreme challenges from the health, economic and social consequences of this virus, humanitarian agencies are particularly concerned about its impact in Donetska and Luhanska Oblasts, which are affected by the protracted conflict with already overstretched health systems. Older people constitute a third (36%) of the conflict affected population in eastern Ukraine, reaching 41% in areas closest to the LoC. People with disabilities account for 12% of those in need, again with increased numbers closest to the LoC, most likely due to their increased isolation or reliance on others, limited physical mobility, poor economic resources, and their emotional attachment to property and assets, all of which inhibits their ability to move out of these areas.

This project builds on previous and current multi-sectoral humanitarian interventions implemented by HelpAge International in Ukraine, to provide direct support to conflict affected older women and men, including those with disabilities, who are most at risk from the effects of COVID-19, through Psychosocial Support (PSS ) activities, Home-Based Care (HBC) for the most vulnerable households, the provision of COVID-19 adapted hygiene kits and food packages, and the dissemination of age-friendly information materials on how to combat the virus. 

The HBC activities will be implemented by existing HelpAge trained community-based volunteers, including in COVID-19 awareness and safety measures, who will safely conduct outreach visits while minimizing social contact and incorporating do-no harm practices to at least 2000 vulnerable older women and men, and persons with disabilities located in 17 of the 53 prioritised settlements of Donetsk and Luhansk. These locations are considered to be in high need and be the most isolated and hard to reach areas with limited services and infrastructure, near to the line of contact. The HBC services provides support to promote greater levels of Independent living capacity, reduce isolation, improve awareness/understanding on COVID-19 and to facilitate the distribution of Hygiene Kits and Food Packages.

Through these activities and by using a multi sectoral approach addressing protection, health and nutrition and WASH concerns, older people and persons with disabilities will be identified and their critical needs supported through appropriate interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akbar Nazriev</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380504052955</telephone>
   <email>akbar.nazriev@helpage.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kate Haggerty</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44(0)2030331101</telephone>
   <email>kate.haggerty@ageinternational.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UKR14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04760900 37.67396200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UKR44">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luhanska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.98548500 39.01766300</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-20">300049.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-15731">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-20">300049.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304584727">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-01">240039.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304741897">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-24">60009.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
