<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="4" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-01T03:07:22.857" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-22T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/Ed-Prot-WASH/NGO/17340</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Access to lifesaving and Sustaining Education , Child Protection and WASH  Services to Flood Affected Children(Boys and Girls) in Jowhar and Mahaday  Districts, Middle Shabelle Region, Hirshabelle State of Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed to respond to education, WASH and protection needs of children affected by floods in seven rural villages of Jowhar District of Middle Shabelle in Hirshabelle State of Somali for six months. The villages have either been affected by floods due to River Shabelle breaking its banks and flooding the settlements and farmlands in the riverine areas or flash floods sweeping the villages as a result of above-normal heavy Hagaa rains experienced in the region. The Guu rains expected between October and December are likely to result further deterioration of the situation.
Education facilities in the targeted villages are closed since most of them were affected either flood from river bank breakage that saw them completely inundated or marooned by water. 

The villages are generally food insecure as the population is faced with acute unemployment, the prohibitive cost of living, and lack of skill sets by majority of the dwellers to eke meaningful living. The situation is further exacerbated by cyclic droughts and flash floods that are making agro-pastoralism lifestyle untenable and thus many are dropping out to join the ever-increasing population of vulnerable persons in the riverine regions. The worst affected are children and women who often bear the brunt of neglect and abandonment during these hard times. This often makes them susceptible to abuses and exploitations such as Gender-Based Violence, sexual exploitation, early marriages, child labor and recruitment to armed groups. 
The project intends to use school attendance as an important preventive factor for child protection, particularly the girl-child. The project will employ such interventions as, training of teachers on basic child protection skills, provision of child-friendly environment through improvement and repair of damaged temporary/ permanent classrooms. Aid Vision will establish and strengthen the capacity of CtC clubs to provide peer interaction forums to learners, provision of teaching and learning materials-including recreational materials, capacity building of CBCPCs to raise awareness on risks of child abuse and enhance children&#x2019;s access and retention at schools. The CBCPCs will contribute to service mapping, identification of referral pathways and disseminate the information about available child protection service for children in the community. CP Focal Points, trained on PSS/PFA, will facilitate structured gender sensitive recreational and PSS activities at the schools for both boys and girls throughout the project live and conduct child safety walk and audit/ /risk mapping exercises with the guidance of project CP supervisor.

To address urgent WASH needs at the schools and ensure continuous learning for 2000 learners, Aid Vision will supply water to 7 schools for 6 months which will be delivered by trucks. Each school will have water storage tank with taps placed at strategic location for easy access. 23 twin gender-sensitive latrines will be constructed at schools that lack sanitation facilities. All latrines will have sufficient water, hand washing facilities and lockable doors for meaningful access. Girls and boys will attend CP awareness sessions to be organized for all schools. This is aimed at ensuring they have preventive skills on violence against children. Girls latrines usage will be monitored and corrective actions taken to address safety concerns. Regular hygiene promotion campaigns focusing on handwashing and safe water handling will be conducted at schools for 14 days to prevent the risk of AWD/Cholera outbreak. Hygiene promotion sessions will follow where schools&#x2019; health clubs will disseminate messages on good hygiene practices at schools. To ensure schools have sustained access to water 2 shallow wells damaged by floods will be rehabilitated and protected with hand-pumps. 9 manually operated hand-free hand washing stations will be installed and soap for hand washing provided to reduce risk/transmission of COVID-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdi Ahmed Dagane</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252616756553</telephone>
   <email>dagane@aidvision.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibrahim Raghe Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">President/CEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615555249</telephone>
   <email>ibrahimraghe@aidvision.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-16">33141.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-16">166810.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17340">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-16">199951.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304839931">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-22">159961.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
