<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="14" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-19T03:08:11.833" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-18T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA1/H/INGO/16013</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Health Response in Oromia and Somali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The recent Hot Spot Classification puts Babile, Chinaksen and Mediagtola woredas as priority 1. According to the woreda Disaster and Risk Management office current report (April 2020) there are 45,789 IDPs in Chinaksen and Babile. Out of these 34,287 IDPs are children under the age of 18 years. In Chinaksen, Mediagatola and Bablie there are 43,086 returnees of which 24,211 are children. Health service in the three woredas is under stress due to increased number of beneficiaries (IDPs amp returnees), low numbers of functional health centres and health posts providing comprehensive preventive and curative services, and limited number of trained Health Extension Workers (HEWs) and health professionals. Not all health facilities are fully functioning, and the community often accesses Primary Health Care services from health centers in neighboring woredas. The delayed onset and erratic nature of rains in these areas is resulting in scarcity of water and pasture, crop failure, as well as the deteriorating security situation which leads to tensions and clashes between Somali and Oromo ethnic groups. As per the report from the three Woreda Disaster and Risk Management office the annual Therapeutic Feeding Program (TFP) which demonstrates Severe Acute Malnutrition (SAM) admission trends in Babile, Chinaksen and Mediagatola woredas admission rates typically increase in May and reach their peak in June and July, before decreasing again in August. This spike is expected to be much larger this year.

Lack of access to protected water and improved sanitation increases the risk of disease outbreak and malnutrition which significantly affect physical and mental well-being. In the above mentioned three woredas including the IDP sites, there is inadequate access to safe water and low awareness in hygiene and sanitation. To respond these challenges, CRS proposes to implement an integrated Health, Nutrition and WASH activities in Babile Woreda, Fafan Zone, Somali Region, and in Chinaksen, and Medigatola woredas, East Hararghe, Oroma region including Providing essential health care services to targeted population: basic primary health care services (treatment and prevention) of common illnesses at outpatient and outreach-based will be provided. These includes OPD consultation, vaccination of children, Ante natal Care (ANC) and delivery by skill birth attendant, and providing behavioral change messaging. Providing quality care for people with physical injuries and disabilities and mental health needs: mainly targeting people with disabilities in IDPs and returnees, the project will provide psycho-social support to IDPs, returnees, people with disability and gender-based violence survivors. In addition, clinical care will be given to survivors of sexual and gender based (SGBV) violence. 

Based on the data collected from East Harereghe and West Arsi Zone, CRS will use mobile Health and Nutrition Teams (MHNTs) in Babile, Chinaksen, Meyu Muleke and Medigatola to increased disease surveillance to identify risk factors and identify malnutrition, danger signs of illness, including COVID-19 to provide free outreach/mobile health and nutrition services with a focus on women and children, particularly in the IDPs and returnees.  MHNT Service package include Child health services Maternal health services, capacity building, e.g. attachment of HEWs to MHNTs as on job training, logistics, reporting, referral, functionalizing and strengthening non-functional HPs. The team will regularly rotate in all Kebeles to deliver the key service. CRS will use the existing health facilities in Siraro and Shashemena Zurie of west Arsi, the project will discuss with Woreda health office to identify specific health facilities to serve the most vulnerable populations, a team of midwives, Clinical nurse and health officer will carry out the day to day activities of child health, maternal health services and messaging, and provide psycho social and mental health to IDPs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopian Catholic Church Social and Development Coordination Office of Meki SS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HCS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zemede Abebe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programming</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 911 507305</telephone>
   <email>zemede.zewdie@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mekonnen Tesfamariam</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM - Health and Nutrition</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 912 606080</telephone>
   <email>mekonnen.tesfamariam@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>43.32903576 6.92946999</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-11">194339.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-11">55660.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-16013">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-11">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304644713">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-18">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
