<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="36" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-20T02:07:03.027" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-18T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA1/WASH/INGO/15509</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PREVENT WATER-BORNE DISEASE OUTBREAK THROUGH CRITICAL MAINTENANCE TO CRITICAL WASH FACILITIES AND DISINFECTION OF WATER SOURCES IN THE GAZA STRIP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposed project is an extension of Human Appeal&#x2019;s project funded in Gaza Strip under OCHA&#x2019;s oPt Humanitarian Fund as part of the Reserve Allocation. Under that project, HA will deliver 3 month&#x2019;s supply of chlorine to all water wells, reservoirs and desalination plants in Gaza. As a short-term support, the project aimed to temporarily provide chlorine and support essential maintenance of pre-identified water wells, until CMWU receives additional support for the remaining year. However, the current provision for chlorine delivery will exhaust by the end of June 2020, with no commitment or pledges in the horizon to support this critical activity. 


To address this, the proposed project aims to extend chlorine delivery for an additional 3 months i.e. July to September 2020. This will enable continuity of support to CMWU to improve collection and allow more time to secure financial resources to cover the cost of chlorine for the remaining year. This activity is critical at a time when WHO considers oPt as a high-risk country/region for COVID-19 epidemic outbreak, especially with 48 confirmed cases in the West Bank and hundreds in Gaza quarantined under precaution. Furthermore, the proposed project is in line with WASH Cluster&apos;s Objective 1 amp 2  Strategic HRP Objective 2) The basic needs of vulnerable Palestinians living under occupation are met through the provision of quality basic services and improved access to resources and Sustainable Development Goal 6) Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all. 


The project aims to support the entire population of the Gaza Strip i.e. 2,047,969 individuals with access to safe water for drinking amp domestic use, and reducing the risk of outbreaks of water-borne diseases in Gaza by biological contamination. This includes 44.1% children, % 27.7women, 28.2% men and 7% PWD (PCBS, 2020). Although the project does not directly respond to the distinct needs of women, men, or elderly the services provided will ensure everyone has equal and meaningful access to safe drinking and domestic water regardless of their age, gender or disability.

Key interventions will include:
- Conducting critical maintenance works for 11 essential water wells, including: 4 wells in the north, 4 wells in the Middle Area, 2 wells in Khan Younis and 1 well in Rafah 
- Distribution of 200 Hygiene Kits for WASH Facilities Technical staff, to ensure protection and safety of all field staff working on site
- Strengthen preparedness and response by rehabilitation of Abu Rashid Storm-water Basin in northern Gaza to minimize risk of flooding. 
- Ensuring over 99% disinfection efficiency of all water distribution system in the Gaza Strip through provision of chlorine to cover 288 water wells, 55 water reservoirs, 26 water lifting and booster stations, over 2,987 km of water networks and carrier lines, 48 small-medium sized brackish water desalination plants (50m3/day to 1000m3/day), and three connections of Mekorot water supply across the Green Line with Israel with average total annual supply capacity of 10MCM.
- Carry out regular and consistent water quality testing for 3 months Samples from 580 locations across the Gaza Strip will be tested monthly for monitoring water quality and/or residual chlorine level to ensure safe water delivery to beneficiaries. All test results will be logged into the monitoring database to inform actions required for water safety plans.

This project aims to fill in short-term funding gap by providing chlorine amp essential maintenance to pre-identified water wells. After 3 months, CMWU will be responsible for mobilising resources and collection mechanisms to cover the cost of chlorine for the remaining year. Carrying out critical preventive and corrective maintenance of essential WASH facilities will increase the lifespan of WASH facilities amp improve service delivery on the mid-term and possibly longer-term.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-16" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmed Kehail</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programmes Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00970599909782</telephone>
   <email>ahmed.kehail@humanappeal.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-18">339150.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-18">23800.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-15509">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-18">362950.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304799395">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-18">290360.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
