<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-jordan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="27" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-08T03:07:04.32" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-24T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR-20/DDA-3560/SA2/P/NGO/17526</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancement of the protective environment of Syrian and Jordanian Boys and Girls through Legal Support and Cash Distribution</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is a response concerned with the enhancement of the protective environment of Syrian and Jordanian boys and girls, including those with disabilities, that are at risk residing in vulnerable communities affected by COVID-19 in the governorates of Amman, Irbid and Zarqa. Each of the targeted locations are those with a high concentration of Syrian Refugees and host communities. ARDD maintains permanent offices in each area from which it can base its operations which allows for efficiency and effectiveness of the response through eased access to targeted communities and having already formed relationships with CS within the local communities easing access to beneficiaries. The response is built upon the provision of legal services and cash distribution. 
The first portion is focused upon the increasing the legal protection and PSEA awareness of Syrian and Jordanian boys and girls, including those with disabilities, and parents and caregivers, with a specific focus on single mothers and caregivers. This is completed through the provision of legal protection and PSEA awareness sessions which mainstream gender, GBV, and child protection to 600 parents and caregivers in the targeted area. There will be 30 sessions in total given by ARDD lawyers, 10 in each area, with each session having 20 beneficiaries. The sessions will follow relevant health and safety guidelines and procedures. Furthermore, the beneficiaries under this intervention will be accessed mainly through outreach and mobilization activities conducted through CSO and CBO members of the Jordan National NGO Forum (JONAF) operating in the targeted areas and outreach will also be conducted online. The inclusion of JONAF members is vital to the outreach activities as it allows for access to hard to reach communities and allows ARDD to leverage the trust the CBOs and CSOs have leveraged within the targeted areas. 

The second portion is focused on the provision of legal support for at risk Syrian and Jordanian boys and girls, including those with disabilities, and parents and caregivers, with a specific focus on single mothers and caregivers. The types of cases to be addressed could vary in nature, from cases associated with SEA, GBV, registrations, child labor, among others. ARDD will firstly provide its lawyers a refresher training on PSEA, GBV, and Child Protection. ARDD lawyers already have significant experience in each of these areas, especially in child protection as ARDD has recently completed a program for OCHA concerned with child protection. ARDD lawyers will provide consultation and mediation services for 1500 beneficiaries with 500 beneficiaries in each area. ARDD will provide litigation services for a total of 90 beneficiaries with 30 litigations in each areas. According to past experience in child protection, it may be expected that 70% percent of the consultations, mediation, and litigation services provided to minors will be for boys, and 30% to girls due to boys being more likely to be in conflict with the law. However, ARDD will strive to provide the services to as many girls as possible. ARDD will refer cases identified during the provision of legal support activities using the inter-agency referral mechanisms for multi-sectorial support. Furthermore, ARDD will provide the 265 most vulnerable beneficiaries of the legal services, with a particular focus on families with single mothers or caregivers, with cash support amounting to USD 282.5  in order to preserve their ability meet their basic needs and thereby enhance their ability to meet their child&apos;s needs and safety. In light of the COVID-19 Pandemic and its economic effects, this  cash assistance will be essential in ensuring the protection of children from the most vulnerable families and contribute to allowing the children to refrain from economic activities, mainly informally, that would place the children at increased risk.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Renaissance for Democracy and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Renaissance for Democracy and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lobna alkhatib</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Finance and Administration</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0779911694</telephone>
   <email>lkhatib@arrd-jo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samar Muhareb</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962777611177</telephone>
   <email>smuhareb@ardd-jo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zainab Alkhalil</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962778484455</telephone>
   <email>zkhalil@ardd-jo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amman</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.91905968 35.92902353</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Irbid</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.55798676 35.84675724</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zarqa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.07577806 36.08100277</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-19">26865.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-19">272232.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="JOR73-17526">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-19">299097.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Renaissance for Democracy and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304807829">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-24">239277.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Renaissance for Democracy and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
