<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="21" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-06T03:06:01.987" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-23T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/Health/INGO/17901</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Life Saving Health Care Services in Al Mukha district, Taiz Governorate (Parameter 1)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IMC proposes to maintain the gains made under the second allocation 2019 Yemen Humanitarian Fund awarded project, entitled: &#x201C;Provision of Emergency Health Services in Lahj and Taiz.&#x201D; With the support of the first allocation Yemen Humanitarian Funds, IMC will extend life-saving health care services within the western coast of Taiz governorate in Al Mukha district to the currently supported six health facilities: Al Sahera, Al Zohari, Kodiha, Nobat Al Ameri, Yakhtal and Hassi Salem health units. Complementary to the support extended to the health facilities, IMC will deploy one mobile team to at least six out of the 84 IDP locations in Al Mukha District. Targeted locations include: Al Qahira, Al Hali, Al Rowais, Al Oshaira, Al Zahira, and Al Shatheli. The target population will include a total of 18,058 host and 6,535 IDP individuals disaggregated as follows: 3,443 men, 3,935 women, 8,863 boys, 8,362 girls. These communities continue to be considered as hard-to-reach areas due to the security risks such as mine fields, proximity to frontlines and distance from basic services. Furthermore, the governorate of Taiz ranks as the third highest governorate with COVID-19 confirmed cases, adding to the vulnerability of the targeted communities. With the fragmented state of the health care system and scarcity of facilities, with only 2 operational COVID-19 facilities, the health system cannot manage an outbreak of coronavirus cases. The project will support the 6 health units and 1 mobile health team with health hazard allowances to health care workers, in accordance to the health cluster grid, essential medical commodities for the diagnosis and management of common morbidities which includes communicable and non-communicable diseases and non-medical commodities that includes stationary and cleaning materials. The services to be supported include general medical consultations for communicable and non-communicable diseases, provision of essential medications, maternal and childcare through the services of trained nurses and midwives, IMCI, disease surveillance including COVID-19 screening for all beneficiaries utilizing the services in the clinic, infection prevention and control and community health promotion. These services will complement the services supported through the nutrition project which includes nutrition screening for infants and young children as well as pregnant and lactating women, growth monitoring and community management of acute malnutrition. Other services which will be complemented are the EPI services delivered through the GHO, and emergency referrals of critically ill patients which is supported by IMC through another project. IMC have coordinated with the health cluster and the respective local health representatives to ensure that support is not duplicated, and the most vulnerable populations are provided with the needed services complementing nutrition services offered through a separate nutrition project. International Medical Corps (IMC) is a US-registered independent affiliate organization of International Medical Corps UK (IMC UK), with which IMC UK shares the same name and charitable objectives and mission. IMC UK and IMC work together to deliver assistance programs in an accountable and effective manner in pursuit of their commonly-held charitable objectives. IMC UK will engage IMC to implement its programs in the field, with IMC UK oversight, according to the terms and conditions of the agreement that results from this proposal and the terms of the parties&#x2019; administrative service agreement. Together with IMC Croatia, IMC provides administrative and operational support to IMC UK and to the programs on the ground, including but not limited to financial management, banking and cash management, procurement management/international procurements and logistics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tawanda Guvi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 739 222 555</telephone>
   <email>tguvi@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sharif Uddin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance and Administration Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 188 077</telephone>
   <email>suddin@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-12">347999.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17901">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-12">347999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304918201">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-23">208799.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
