<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="70" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-20T02:05:07.11" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-23T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/SA1/NFI/NGO/15462</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of sustainable integrated and COVID-19 Preparedness and Response emergency shelter and lifesaving non-food items to 16,667 newly displaced, protracted IDPs, and host communities through both Cash-Based  In-Kind modality in Yirol East County of Lakes state</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCOSS proposes to respond 2779 HHs (16,667 individuals) of most vulnerable newly displaced persons and host communities in Adior, Lekekadu, Pagarau, Malek, Tinagua, and Yali villages (Yirol East). CCOSS will respond as a static partner using both Cash-based and In-kind modality. There is a functional and accessible market in Yirol town that will serve participants in these locations through voucher fairs.  The proposed mode shall be the restricted voucher modality. Based on previous experience these locations, vendors supplied the agreed-upon NFIs to the participants using the voucher fairs. Participants were then allowed to redeem their restricted vouchers during these voucher fairs. For In-kind modality, Shelter and NFIs will be prepositioned from the nearest Core Pipeline warehouse and transported by the Cluster to CCOSS stores in respective locations. 


CCOSS proposes to integrate COVID-19 preparedness and response strategies as we implement this project into the standard activities. The proposed activities will include supporting the provision of separate shelters for isolation for the elderly and most vulnerable populations and, Shelter upgrades and partitioning for communal shelters to reduce transmission and exposure. CCOSS will ensure the WHO and Ministry of Health guidelines will be upheld throughout the project implementation.


For the CBI modality, CCOSS will target Malek 3,000 individuals (500 HHs) and Adior 2,000 individuals (333HHs). Malek and Adior are targeted for both CBI and In-kind modalities because they have newly displaced IDPs, and these two locations have not previously been targeted by CCOSS for the S/NFIs interventions. For the In-kind modality, the disaggregation will be as follows Yali 334 HHs (2004 individuals) Titagua 334 HHs (2004 individuals), Lekakedu 334 HHs (2004 individuals) and Malek 334 HHs (2004 individuals), Adior 275 HHs (1647 individuals) and Pagarau 334 HHs (2004 individuals).

A detailed market assessment will be conducted to identify the availability of ES-NFIs in the market, assess the supply chain of items, check the quality of ES-NFIs, and identify the suppliers/vendors of products and to identify risks of the CBI programme and mitigation measures. Meetings will be contacted with the potential traders and the local authorities to explain the programme modality and contracts will be signed with the selected traders for the supply of the ES-NFIs. In order to mitigate the risk of double-dipping, tokens with CCOSS identification numbers will be distributed during registrations and then withdrawn during the distribution of vouchers. The registration will be done simultaneously in all the settlement areas to avoid double registrations. The commodity vouchers will be printed with security features and expiry dates, serial numbers, and duplicates that will remain in the voucher book. The beneficiaries will have a window of time to access the ES-NFIs from the vendors in the market or during voucher fairs. The beneficiaries will redeem their vouchers for a selected number of ES-NFIs determined during the needs assessment. All beneficiaries will get the same types of ES-NFIs. At agreed times the traders will then redeem the vouchers for payment by CCOSS through an agreed payment method. A detailed Post Distribution Monitoring will be conducted at the end of the project to find feedback and impact of the cash-based intervention and lessons learned will contribute to improvements in future response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-SHL-160227-2" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mabior Wel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211925029884</telephone>
   <email>info@ccoss7.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mundia Akala</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211921399960</telephone>
   <email>mundia.akala@ccoss7.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lakes</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.60307990 29.97405340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-09">234926.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-09">65073.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-15462">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-09">300000.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304650202">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-19">120000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304804192">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-23">120000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
