<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syria-allocation-2021" dstore:index="10" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-20T03:06:05.313" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-23T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-21/DDA-3558/RA1/WASH/INGO/18060</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Undertake light rehabilitation of sanitation facilities for affected people in Deir Ez Zour city in Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On the 11th year of conflict, the scale amp diversity of WASH needs, overall people in need of WASH assistance are 10.7 m, which is complemented by figures presenting specific WASH needs for sanitation (4.7 m), amp heavy financial burden linked with purchasing water amp/or hygiene supplies (7.9 m). (WASH HNO 2020).
The main objective of this intervention is support sanitation management systems to ensure regular services for affected people in Al Omal district who need network rehabilitation to ensure safe disposal amp waste management. The main line size is 2&#x201D; which is not sufficient to the needs of the increased returnees&#x2019; population. Lines of 2,210 ML were probed, scanned, or examined results 1330 ML was identified for replacement (880 polyethylene + 450 PVC pipes). Rehabilitation of undamaged pipes using Sewage suction truck equipped with tanks, sewer jet vacuum amp high-pressure water jet equipment to open the blockage of waste water pipelines to be operational after connection with the newly replaced pipes to ensure optimal performance. Cleaning the tunnels amp re-cover the pipes per the approved technical standards. This will save local community amp 430 HHs returnees while the sanitation was not functioning from serious health risks.
In DEZ, access to safe sanitation system is compromised based on the fact of lack of maintenance amp rehabilitation of the networks which are not functioning due to un-addressed damages, consequently increasing the likelihood of waterborne diseases spreading due to poor sanitation amp limited ability to practice good hygiene. The project impact with improved sanitation infrastructure amp will support Covid-19 response as locality hygiene is a main requirement to ensure pandemic amp contagion control. As Rescate amp Syria Trust worked together in DEZ since 2018 in assessments seeking to implement projects such as damaged houses rehabilitation. Our goal is to provide integrated response to help in building resilience amp creating sense of stability for the returnees amp population in the city. Rescate will deliver the services of pipelines rehabilitation through reinforcement of available service providers related to WASH sector. A candid review of the rapid technical assessment to ensure detailed BOQ inclusion in the tender call for the works. Rescate intervention in response to 4 severity score city (SYRIA 2021 HNO). This project will enhance beneficiaries&#x2019; resilience by enabling them to direct their resources to more tangible needs amp to safeguard their health amp hygiene under the current deteriorated health pandemic especially Covid-19. Rescate will enter agreement with experienced local contractors to provide works under close supervision of Rescate experience team. A claim mechanism will be introduced MampE officer will monitor implementation amp prepare reports about progress, maintain track of works vs budget amp action plan, amp about beneficiaries&#x2019; segregation (gender, age amp PWDs) amp social impact. A questionnaire to assess beneficiaries&#x2019; satisfaction during amp after the project implementation. Rescate maintains a schedule for financial amp narrative, share info via WASH Sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ONG Rescate Syria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ONG Rescate Syria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soura Al Joundi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission Syria</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+963930500722 and +973944216161</telephone>
   <email>soura.aljoundi@ongrescate.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Francisco Fuentes</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+34622650929</telephone>
   <email>francisco.fuentes@ongrescate.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deir-ez-Zor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.33188500 40.14607100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-18">258902.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-18060">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-18">258902.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ONG Rescate Syria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304923798">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-23">207122.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ONG Rescate Syria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
