<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="185" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-05T03:07:34.813" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-31T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA2/FS/NGO/17664</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving in-kind food assistance to the most vulnerable people (COVID-19 patients and health staff) in 5 CCTCs in Northwest Syria.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will contribute to Support immediate and critical measures responding to the COVID-19 pandemic through the provision of life-saving humanitarian assistance as in-kind food assistance to the vulnerable people affected by COVID-19 during the treatment period and also health staff in the COVID-19 Community Treatment Centers (CCTCs) which are located in Maaret Tamsrin, Atareb and Daret Azza sub-districts, which were affected by the spread of COVID-19 in NW Syria since September 2020, in additional to the economic deterioration, and insecure situation.
The numbers issued by the WHO health cluster upward trend of the injured with COVID-19 as the number of sick reached more than 7500 in NW Syria.

During the project&apos;s designing and planning phase, SADAD Organization has coordinated and collaborated with ALSERAJ Organization and Based on the coordination with ALSERAJ and FSL Cluster, priority was given to the five CCTCs Atareb ( CCTC-3), Hazano ( CCTC-5), Kelly(CCTC-20), Daret Azza (CCTC-7, CCTC-8) that are located in Maaret Tamsin and Atareb sub-districts, which were classified in terms of priority between high and medium according to the So1 COVID-19 priority locations in the Second Standard Allocation 2020. 
The CCTC centers in ALSERAJ accommodate 500 patients and 200 health workers per month in all centers.

The total estimated beneficiaries number for 9 months (4700 persons) males and females from the host communities and IDPs including ( pregnant and lactating women PLW, the elderly, people with chronic diseases, and the disabled).
Sadad will provide patients and health staff in  5 CCTCs with RTERs furthermore, in addition to providing RTERs is necessary to support the same patients and health staff with cooked meals especially for those patients will stay in CCTCs for 15 days without any kind of nutritions resource in Kelly (CCTC-20) and Daret Azza (CCTC-8) Sub-districts, while the others three CCTCs will be supported by ALSERAJ with cooked meals. those contain ( vitamins, nutrients, proteins, carbohydrates, and amino acids..) are important to enhance and support the immune system to resist covide-19 impacts which may lead to death if those not be provided.
Project&apos;s interventions &quot;life-saving humanitarian assistance&apos;&apos; as in-kind food assistance is including both Ready To Eat Rations  and cooked males to COVID-19 patients and health staff during project duration as following:
-Distribution of 18,900 RTEs to (13,500 Covid-19 patients and 5,400 for health staff&apos;s) within 9 months in 5 CCTCs, where three rations are RTEs during the treatment period (two weeks) for each patient, in addition to three RTEs rations per month for each health staff.
The RTEs weighs 5.02 kg and contains 2,100 calories per person per day, enough for one person for 5 days (this is in line with the recommendations of the FSS on RTE ).
Each RTERs contains a variety of food items designed to cover all basic nutritional needs for the people in NWS which include (0.4 KG Fava Bean, 0.4 KG Chickpeas Paste, 0.335 L Olive oil, 0.165 KG Canned Tuna, 0.2 KG Zaatar dried, 0.25 KG Halva, 0.25 KG dates, 625 ml canned juice, 2.4 kg bread will be in 5 pouches packed  &quot;4 loaves in each pouch packed.
-Distribution of 39,060 cooked meals to (27,900 for COVID-19 patients and 11,160 for health staff) during 9 months in 2 CCTCs where one cooked meal per day for each person covers the 2,100 kcal and to be in line with sphere standards and FSL Recommendations as well as maintain food diversity.
The centers are pre-equipped with basic cooking from Al-Seeraj. Sadad is committed to secure the primary food items needed for cooking.
the centers are divided into three zones, green zone is the last place that sadad is allowed to work and carry out all activities, so Al-Seeraj staff will complete the operations that are in direct contact with patients this is under the indirect supervision of the SADAD team and within the required standards work WHO, FSS standa</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-163125-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-22">299876.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-17664">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-22">299876.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304860945">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">179925.63</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
