<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-pakistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="20" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-04T02:05:13.283" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-15T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/WASH/NGO/17443</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of WASH assistance to the 5000 Flood-affected families in five Union Councils Satriyoon, Araro Bhurguri, Samaro road, Samaro, and Gulzar Khalil of Tehsil Samaro, district Umerkot.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWARE will provide WASH assistance to approximately 5000 families (Approximately 38,700 individuals (11,940 men, 12,265 women, 7133 boys, and 7362 girls) in through integrated WASH assistance over a period of three months. Based on the identified needs, to the most vulnerable and flood-affected persons targeted five Union Councils, Satriyoon, Araro Bhurguri, Samaro road, Samaro, and Gulzar Khalil of Taluka Samaro in district Umerkot are selected for humanitarian assistance in close coordination with District authorities, local communities, and civil society organizations.


Along the needs assessment conducted by One UN Provincial Programme Team Sindh, local partner&#x2019;s coordination with relevant stakeholders in Umerkot also guided the planning of culturally sensitive and locally relevant activities for emergency WASH assistance for sustainable resistance of the flood-affected communities. The AWARE team is already working in the proposed area since last decade and based on the information collected during recent flood assessment, regular coordination meeting with district authority during this emergency, reports of different stakeholders (government, I/NGOs, media, etc), generated a Flood Situation Report in August 2020.


Due to heavy rain torrential rains, many districts of Sindh (Umerkot and others) were severely affected by the floods The floods damaged the areas that were already extremely poor and added to the miseries of the people by creating food insecurity, shortage of safe drinking water (62%) and widespread of water-borne diseases in the area. Although there were efforts under a tent, cooked food by Government but there are many still pockets which still have an unmet need for improved quality of drinking water, sanitation, hygiene, and food security. AWARE being one of the organizations already worked with communities of the flood-affected area in the year 2011 with UNICEF and water Aid with the mandate for the provision of WASH services to the flood-affected communities.
&#x2028;The focus of the proposed interventions will be on the provision of access to potable water and the economic survival of flood-affected households. WASH interventions will include 02 water filtration units and 03 water tankering and aqua tabs to access and availability of safe drinking water for 5000 most flood-affected populations. For access to safe sanitation in flood-affected areas, the pit latrines will be provided with the inclusion of men and women, girls and boys of the communities&apos;. AWARE also will carry out hygiene promotion activities through inclusive and culturally compatible utilization approaches and NFI ( Mosquito nets, Jerrican and Tarpaulin sheets, and hygiene kits will be provided to ensure the personal hygiene along with these awareness-raising sessions on personal hygiene and COVID-19 will be conducted according to social distancing in designated SOPs.&#x2028;Transparency and accountability will be ensured through maximum participation of the right holders in beneficiaries selection coupled with cross verification of selected households through community-managed structures, project staff, and monitoring team members to office. The AWARE team will ensure compliance of PHPF gender criteria, CHS, and SPHERE standards. &#x2028;In close coordination with PHPF and WASH cluster will deter duplication of efforts through regular information sharing on the flood portal of UNOCHA and at district / provincial coordination forums. The main purpose of this project is to prevent excess morbidity, mortality and to help reduce the incidence of water, sanitation and hygiene, and related disease by providing WASH humanitarian assistance to most flood-affected families.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association for Water Applied Education  Renewable Energy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association for Water Applied Education  Renewable Energy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ali Akbar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00923337092067</telephone>
   <email>awareumarkot@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shewa Ram Suthar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>003332739294</telephone>
   <email>programs.aware@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK8">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sindh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00970000 68.77360000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">231629.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">16350.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-17443">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">247979.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association for Water Applied Education  Renewable Energy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304778587">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-04">148787.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association for Water Applied Education  Renewable Energy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304877056">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-15">99192</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association for Water Applied Education  Renewable Energy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
