<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="20" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-15T03:06:27.19" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-10T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/FSAC-Education/NGO/17890</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response to Food and Education Gaps for the Most Vulnerable IDPs and affected People in Marib city, Marib, and Al Abr districts of Marib and Hadramout governorates (Priority 2)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this project, food security amp education interventions have been designed, an aim to cover the cluster priority gaps (priority 2) for the most vulnerable IDPs who living in collective sites, amp living with host families as well as host communities in Ma&#x2019;rib amp Hadramout governorates, that will contribute to achieve YHF SA1-2020 &#x201C;to provide immediate funding to assist people in acute humanitarian needs to mitigate the risks of famine amp negative consequences of COVID-19&#x201D; through YHF-SA1 2020. An integrated approach has been tailored to respond to FSA amp education clusters gaps in Ma&#x2019;rib City district only. 
FSA:
The FSA intervention align with YHF SA1-2020 (priority 2) amp FSAC SO1 to increase access to food FSAC SO1 by covering food gap in FSAC ongoing emergency response fort the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs living in deplorable conditions at collective sites in Al Abr district for 370 HHs (2590 individuals 550 men, 559 women, 833 boys, 693 girls), amp with host families in Ma&#x2019;rib City for 1100 HHs (7700 individuals 1727 men, 1884 women, 2090 boys, 1999 girls), amp Ma&#x2019;rib district for 814 HHs (5700 individuals 1229 men, 1254 women, 1670 boys, 1547 girls) through provision of immediate life-saving emergency food assistance (unconditional cash/value voucher transfers) each month, allowing them to meet their basic food needs. Six distribution rounds will be carried out for 2284 IDPs HHs on monthly basis.
It is linked to FSAC strategic Objective (SO) 1 increase access to food for the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs living in the target areas, which is under FSAC 1st line to reduce severe hunger among highly vulnerable families.
Education:
The education intervention is directly in line with YHF SA1-2020 amp education cluster SO by covering priority gaps Ma&#x2019;rib under priority 2 as identified by cluster, amp focusing on the IDP response. It will contribute in maintaining basic education services, particularly in areas, where schools are damaged, closed or unable to fully operate because of budget, payroll amp other conflict related constraints. NFDHR will provide education supplies (education materials for 6000 students. Establish nine  semi-permanently classrooms, rehabilitate affected schools including latrines amp provide 600 new desks. Around 6000 students (2940 boys amp 3060 girls) will benefit from education services
a detail needs assessment (DNA) will be conducted as first activity to understand the context, gap amp needs. The most affected groups like women amp children, disparities will be addressed during coordination amp verification amp registration exercises during mobilization amp sensitization activity in FSA sector. Target IDPs will evaluated before amp after interventions through baseline amp endline survey. The transfers modality will be identified through market assessment. The distribution will be monitoring after each round through post-distribution monitoring (PDM). The IDPs amp relative local authorities will be involved in project activities through community committees as a part of the projects activities.

NFDHR has the capacity amp access in the targeted districts as it has long experience to provide emergency food assistance amp support the education through projects funded by various donors amp implemented by skilled amp qualified staff, amp more than 3 projects are ongoing managed by NFDHR field Offices in the targeted governorates.
The potential risks have been taken into consideratio. The Low/over-registration/target, functional market, exchange rate, price of fuel amp items, cash liquidity, access constraints to BNFs/IDPs, market, conduct project activities, programmatic, financial, logistical risks, ID Proof Issue, exclusion of BNFs, manipulation information amp data, incidents, protection issues, amp no Show BNFs are the main risks in the project may face during implementing the projects their mitigation have been mentioned in the risk management amp FSAC analysis risk matrix.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Salah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967730190808</telephone>
   <email>msalah@nfdhr.orh</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maher Morait</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security and livelihood Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967 730190800</telephone>
   <email>mmoraiet@nfdhr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hadramaut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.80924424 48.84638589</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="11.28" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="88.72" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">1634538.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">65381.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17890">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">1699919.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304910994-995">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">679967.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Development and Humanitarian Response</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
