<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="28" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-16T03:05:52.32" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/E-P/NGO/17770</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection and Education Response for Affected Host and IDP communities in Rakhine State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Social Integrity (CSI) first began working on Mrauk-U and Kyauktaw townships under the 2019 FSA, which was implemented by CSI under a subgrant from Save the Children (SCI). This first project aimed to deliver education, protection and WASH at school support to children and their parents living in temporary displacement. In 2020, CSI continued to provide support in these areas, this time as the lead grantee for the 2019 SSA. In 2021, CSI aims to continue working in its existing operating area under the 2019 SSA, and to support 6,371 affected persons by building upon its existing IDP network in camps as well as its existing teacher network, and school support efforts. 
Education activities:
In IDP camps, CSI will maintain its existing CFS as they are familiar locations which parents and children already know about. In collaboration with government teachers, CSI will use these spaces to gather parents, within small groups coming at different times, and to diffuse Home-Based Learning (HBL) material for IDP children. The Ministry of Education (MoE), which is currently planning a long-term HBL program, begins to disseminate its materials and trainings, CSI will support dissemination of this material within the 9 targeted school, which comprise over 40% of IDPs. CSI has already sent a request to attend the training organized by the MoE on HBL and wellbeing during COVID-19 ToT, and will order the books and HBL materials to use them at schools (grades 1-4).
Meanwhile, CSI will continue to work in schools, in order to further improve WASH conditions and prepare schools for the children&#x2019;s eventual return. In 2020, CSI ensured the construction/renovation of latrines and handwashing points. This year, CSI would focus on access to water. This cross-year effort would ensure positive sanitary conditions for children&#x2019;s return to school in the pandemic context. Portable handwashing stations will also be made available to be installed in front of each school room, in order to facilitate frequent handwashing.
Finally, CSI is proposing to provide 63 primary school teachers with information on conducting classes in the COVID-19 context (based on CSI&#x2019;s current teacher mentoring program for community teachers delivering non-formal education in northern Rakhine) as well as on mine risk awareness. 
Protection activities:
CSI will actively step up its protection activities in 2021. Firstly, CSI will heighten in awareness spreading on various protection risks and issues, in an effort to improve communities&#x2019; capacities to avoid, prevent or respond to key protection risks. 
1) Awareness on human rights and civil documentation: which would include Rakhine IDPs currently staying in the 5 camps supported by the project, and Rohingya IDPs from 2012, who are staying in villages together with host communities. 
2) Awareness on Child Protection (continuation of 2019 SSA activities) among Rakhine and Rohingya IDPs
3) Awareness on Gender amp GBV, with the support of the Gender Equality Network (GEN), to be provided by CSI volunteers among Rakhine and Rohingya IDPs
4) Awareness on mine risks in schools and in IDP camps and locations and the creation and dissemination of IEC material in local languages (a video, and an animation in Rakhine and Rohingya)
CSI will also provide landmine survivors with access to protection services, by setting up various support mechanisms in the early stages of their recovery (financial support to cover patient attendance) and through initial reintegration into society within the following months (lumpsum to cover modification of the house vocational training or private tuition to fill in the gap in school attendance when/if relevant).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Social Integrity</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Social Integrity</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aung Kyaw Moe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 (0) 9 97877 8600</telephone>
   <email>aungkyaw.moe@csi-global.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clarisse Tistchenko</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistant Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 (0) 9 75011 7269</telephone>
   <email>clarisse.tistchenko@csi-global.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="56" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="44" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">306115.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-17770">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">306115.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Social Integrity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304876501">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-14">183669.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Social Integrity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
