<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="17" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-04T03:06:41.05" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-15T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/FSAC/NGO/17898</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 2 - Provision of immediate life-saving emergency food assistance to the most vulnerable acutely in-secured IDPs at Khanfar District of Abyan Governorate and Wusab Alaali  Jahran Districts of Dhamar Governorate through unconditional cash transfer modality.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is aligned with the main objective of YHF SA1 Yemen humanitarian fund (YHF) &#x2013; the First Standard Allocation 2020 Food Security and Agriculture Cluster (FSAC) strategic objective is by providing immediate fund to assist people in acute humanitarian needs with a view to mitigate the risks of famine and negative consequences of COVID-19 in Yemen under the priority of Parameter two of &#x201C; Covering gaps in cluster&#x2019; ongoing emergency response for people in acute need through providing the assistance to the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs living in deplorable conditions by increasing their access to food and enhancing their resilience. YFCA plans over 12 months under this project to provide unconditional cash transfer (UCT) interventions to the most vulnerable and acutely food insecure IDPs living within host communities as well as those at collective sites at Jahran amp Wusab Al Ali districts in Dhamar governorate, and at Khanfar district in Abyan governorate.


Total number of 2,329 HHs will be provided with UCT for 6 consecutive months (16,300 individuals, Men 3749, Women 4401, Boy 3912, Girls 4238) at the three targeted districts via cash transferring company distribution points at targeted locations according to the cluster standards.


In close coordination with the national and sub-national FSAC clusters in Sana&#x2019;a and Aden and other stakeholders, YFCA will implement the interventions of UCT and all related managerial tasks including targeting, registration, verification and monitoring activities to make sure that the transferred financial assistance over 6 rounds are matching with the cluster criteria so the activities will include conducting baseline, PDM, satisfaction and end-line surveys at all 3 targeted districts.

In coordination and engagement of the local communities at the targeted 3 districts, YFCA research unit jointly with Dhamar amp Aden offices conducted an RNA to assess the needed details for preliminary needs along with a market assessment in the targeted districts in order to obtain the maximum preliminary quantitative and qualitative data about the targeted communities and functionality of local markets, the detailed RNA report was shared with the cluster and relevant stakeholders.

The possible risks of: COVID -19 escalation, security deterioration, governmental imposing, market disruption, fuel shortage and other possible risk factors are considered under this project and will be addressed through proper measures based on close coordination with FSAC cluster and sub-clusters as well as with all stakeholders specifically influential administrative and security institutions SCAMCHA and MOPIC at IRG an AA sides at the central and field levels, more details are provided in corresponding chapters of this proposal.

YFCA will ensure the mainstreaming of the concepts of protection, gender and accountability towards affected people in all stages of this project starting from their involvement at planning amp designing stages and ending by their participation in monitoring and evaluating of this project through their representatives at community committees or their direct voices over complaining and feedback mechanism that will be established and tailored for this project specifically. 

YFCA through the head office in Sana&#x2019;a and sub-offices in Aden amp Dhamar has the full capacity to implement this project being armed with the needed experience in this field, excellent acceptance by the local communities and good institutional capacities in related supportive tasks needed to perform the specific tasks of this project, this includes the great capacity in MampE, reporting, HR and Finance capabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nabil Mohammed Alammari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>774090200</telephone>
   <email>n.alammari@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fares Ali Atef</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FSL Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>776010561</telephone>
   <email>f.atef@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.69554850 46.50340692</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dhamar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.50737016 44.42760976</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-08">1390259.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-08">129423.59</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17898">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-08">1519683.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304914993">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-15">607873.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
