<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="15" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-25T02:05:24.557" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-24T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/Nut-H/NGO/17400</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of integrated life saving health and nutrition services to flood affected population in Jowhar district in Middle Shabelle Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The current triple effects of floods, locust infestation and COVID-19 Pandemic coupled with heavy rains in the Ethiopian highlands have led to increasing water levels in the Shabelle and Juba rivers in southern Somalia, causing widespread flooding in low-lying riverine communities and displacing more than 270,000 people out of their homes, The project is in line with Somalia Humanitarian Fund (SHF) Reserve and will provide integrated life-saving emergency primary health care and nutrition needs of flood-affected women, men, boys and girls of proposed project targets in Jowhar district. ARD is proposing  6-month integrated Health and Nutrition project targeting flood affected populations in Jowhar district reaching a total of 14,600  persons including 2,950 women, 2,180 Men, 5,025 boys and 4,445 girls) 
HEALTH: The proposed project will support two mobile (IERT) in Jowhar district. ARD plans to deliver an integrated package of promotive, preventive and curative maternal, newborn amp child health services and scale-up outbreak early warning and response (EWAR) and case management of epidemic prone diseases through IERT response team as part of the efforts to support the flood affected communities in Jowhar. The project aims to establish mobile clinics in Jowhar IDP and host community&#x2019;s sites and scale up the health care through skilled health professionals. ARD through this project will provide regular medical supplies and life-saving drugs to established health facilities, establish referral mechanisms and   improve the coverage of measles vaccinations, support safe motherhood and reproductive health while also ensuring readiness to prevent and respond to outbreaks such as malaria, measles or AWD/Cholera and promote health update through health education and beneficiary sensitization

NUTRITION: The proposed nutrition activities will be integrated with the health interventions with the aim of addressing underlying causes of high levels malnutrition as well as to enable early identification of SAM cases for treatment in 2 mobile and 1 fixed OTPs and 1 SC) in targeted IDPs and host community in the floods affected areas in Jowhar district. This program will establish a strong community network through competent community nutrition volunteers for early detection/case finding and referral of children and pregnant and lactating mothers with acute malnutrition. In addition to the treatment of acute malnutrition, the project will be promoting positive infant and young child feeding (IYCF) practice by providing IYCF promotion and counselling. ARD is strong partner for the nutrition cluster and therefore, will have close coordination with other partners in the district for identification of vulnerable communities and avoiding overlapping of responses. Through this project, a total 12,420(2,950 women, 5,025 girls and 4,445 boys) floods affected individuals in Jowhar will have access to a package of Emergency lifesaving integrated health and nutrition services in six months&#x2019; period. The mobile team will provide comprehensive community screening, identification, treatment  and referral services from community, IDP areas to the fixed outpatient therapeutic program(OTP) and Stabilization Center (SC) to improve access to the integrated package for the vulnerable community prioritizing rapid referral of the most critical cases (priority will be given to under 5 children and pregnant and lactating women), it shall also capacity building of nutrition staff on IMAM/IYCF services, infant young child feeding best practices (IYCF. Referral of malnourished children with complicated cases will be done to the Outpatient Therapeutic Programme (OTP) centers integrated with primary health care services managed by ARD and other actors in the program areas thus providing more holistic opportunity to the target beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hassan Gedi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252616565703</telephone>
   <email>ard.relief@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-17">258896.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-17">505163.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17400">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-17">764059.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304800340">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-24">331312.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
