<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-sudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="83" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-30T03:07:15.387" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-15T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/SA1/WASH/INGO/16130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IAS WASH-IWRM  COVID-19 Intervention: Transforming the Vulnerable Disabled into Able Responders in Leri and Umm Durein, South Kordofan State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IAS will implement this project in Al Leri and Umm Durein in South Kordofan, targeted Um Dorein accessible parts ( Alhamra, Higer Afool, Alatmoor and Almushtaraka). There are overwhelming basic needs for most of the population as Alirri has a number of refugees and Um Dorein locked for long time. This project targets 35,460 direct beneficiaries and approximately another 20,250 indirect beneficiaries of mainly destitute host community, returnees from conflict in emerging areas, and pastorals. The main objective of this project is to contribute to saving and protecting lives (especially vulnerable children, women and disabled citizens), while increasing the resilience of protracted displacement groups and addressing malnutrition, livelihood needs and education infrastructure, through an Integrated Water Resource Management solution intervention, responding to immediate water, sanitation and hygiene, and protection needs and gaps for more than 55,000 direct and indirect beneficiaries, while mitigating the COVID19 pandemic in Leri and Umm Durein Localities, South Kordofan State, Sudan. The role of targeting the disabled is a key facet of this intervention. Th disabled will not only be given humanitarian support, but will be recruited to help design, plan, and participate in project activities, including monitoring amp evaluations hence the title .&quot;..Able Responders&quot; - the disabled in these communities will no longer be considered or consider themselves as useless and pitied, but as respected, participants and contributors. 
Wash activities include the construction (with beneficiary participation)of four solar-powered mini water yards with added pipe extensions to serve potential livelihood needs as well as the schools and reproductive health centers in the area. Current water points will be surveyed for highest water yields to support the MWYs. IAS will drill 5 new boreholes with 5 new hand pumps after surveying the region with our geologist using a terremeter to discover safe water sources underground. Representatives of diverse backgrounds within communities will be consulted to ensure that chosen locations will not start conflicts between rival groups. 12 hand pump rehabilitations will be completed. Piped water will serve 4 Health Centers and Schools. 4 hand-washing units for schools and health centers made of strong Tiga with  taps and cooler and thermal bricks. IAS will construct four new 6 drop latrines for the Health Centers and schools. They will be gender sensitive and disability-friendly. All water and sanitation hard components are to provide safe water to be used by patients and staff of the Health Centers, schools, as well as the host communities. To improve sanitation and hygiene practices  IAS will also provide Sanitation and Hygiene Awareness and cross-cutting issues training to community committees who will then share with the remainder of targeted beneficiaries. Each new or rehabilitated water point will be maintained and operated by Water Management Committees (WMCs), 50% women who will also receive mechanic training to ensure operation and maintenance of water points. The project includes a cash-based incentive for purchasing tool repair kits to be used by the WMCs for maintaining water-points. The disabled will be involved by collecting water usage fees and monitoring and evaluating construction and training classes. More sanitation needs will be met by the beneficiary centered Community Led Total Sanitation (CLTS) campaigns in 4 villages. 10 Mass Media campaigns will be conducted by girls, boys, women men and those with disabilities in an effort to advocate and inform communities about the looming COVID19 pandemic threat using hundreds of IEC materials. 

Throughout the project, Integrated Water Resource Management (long term water for all sectors of society including water economics and conservation) will be advocated so that durable solutions, resilience, and sustainability will become a realit</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To be determined (NGO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSDN20-EDU;PRO;WSH-162694-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paul Murphy</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>249964463123</telephone>
   <email>paul.murphy@ias-intl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Kordofan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.19901920 29.41793240</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSDN20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-18">111924.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-18">567082.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-16130">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-18">679006.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304828148">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-15">407404.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Aid Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
