<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="31" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-23T03:07:42.543" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-17T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/FS/UN/17826</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farming and Livelihood support  to 1,200 Landless and Most Vulnerable Farmers in Maungdaw and Buthiduang Townships, Rakhine State, Myanmar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine State is one of the poorest states in Myanmar with more than 40% of food-insecure households (HHs), more than half of which are moderately or several food insecure. The most vulnerable communities are unable to access sufficient food and livelihoods. Clashes between the Myanmar Armed Forces (MAF) and Arakan Army (AA) over the past year have increased in regularity and intensity, and geographical scope expanded and the civilian toll has grown. These interrelated crises have severely reduced access to food due to insecurity, displacement, and disruption of agricultural production with consequent increase of poverty levels especially for smallholder and landless farmers. 
A FAO baseline survey last August 2019 in Buthidaung and Maungdaw township, small-scale farmers, landless farmers and daily workers especially women-headed HHs, that have a lower asset base, limited access to productive inputs, are less resilient and more prone to food insecurity. As COVID-19 spreads in Rakhine State further restriction of movement and stay-at-home order of government authorities, it has compounded the vulnerable HHs precarious situations of decreased production, livelihoods, and purchasing power. In a survey by International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI) in July 2020 in rural areas in Myanmar the continued increase in COVID 19 the landless HH more likely to have lower incomes than landed HHs due to further movement restrictions. Coping mechanisms brought by this reduction in income were use of savings, reduction of food expenditure and selling of assets. A recently concluded FAO - WFP COVID-19 impact assessment covering shops selling agricultural inputs revealed potential impacts on agriculture and food market chains as 64% of responded agriculture inputs shops confirmed less clients and decreased customer demand. 
The proposed project will provide urgent support to conflict-affected vulnerable farmers and landless (including stateless) seasonal workers in Buthidaung and Maungdaw Townships, where 49% of people in need in Northern Rakhine are concentrated as identified by the 2020 HRP. It will ensure continued food production and livelihoods through the provision of multipurpose cash and agriculture inputs, increase capacity to use inputs effectively while enhancing communities&#x2019; knowledge of nutrition and hygiene to also mitigate COVID -19 risks and impacts. The planned actions will target extremely poor HHs with limited access to land, productive assets, landless farmers, women-headed or HHs with malnourished children etc. including the stateless. FAO will target villages outside its present geographical coverage under an EU funded project in the same Townships.
The project will partner with Action for Green Earth (AGE) to support the community consultations, validation of beneficiaries, beneficiary communication, provision of agriculture inputs procured by FAO, multipurpose cash distributions and awareness-raising activities, with FAO technical inputs, supervision and quality control. AGE will  ensure close coordination and maintain good working relationship with their respective townships administrators and village tract administrators covered by the project.
There was no gender analysis as such but since few years of presence in the same townships in central and northern Rakhine, through regular data collected, FAO manage to have a comprehensive gender profile of the population living in the relevant townships. Added in section 3 (Logical Framework)
The project will provide agriculture inputs to     500 HH in Buthidang and Maungdaw, complemented by information materials on paddy and vegetable production, and nutrition. A multipurpose cash grant amounting to USD$ 80 per HH will be provided to 1,200 vulnerable conflict-affected HH, including the 500 HH that will engage in monsoon production and 700 landless HH who depend on labour as the main income source that is most affected by restricted movements.**Pls see in comment</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action for Green Earth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Reda Lebtahi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency and Rehabilitation Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+959899007055</telephone>
   <email>Reda.Lebtahi@fao.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U Chit Mya</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 9421 725 637</telephone>
   <email>tintinmu21@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">249671.66</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-17826">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">249671.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304917071">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-17">249671.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
