<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="6" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-04T02:06:07.227" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-21T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA2/N/INGO/17619</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency Nutrition interventions for the flood-affected vulnerable populations (Children 6-59 months, pregnant and lactating women) in Panyijar County of South Sudan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps is requesting emergency funding from SSHF to provide critical lifesaving nutrition services to approximately 23,993 people (8,576 males and 15,417 females) affected by the floods in Panyijar County, Unity State. The main objective of this project is to prevent further deterioration of the nutrition status among the severely affected population groups in the county &#x2013; the children under 5 years old and PLW. The proposed nutrition response will focus on the treatment and prevention of acute malnutrition among boys and girls aged 0-59 months and PLWs with acute malnutrition through management of severe acute malnutrition (SAM) and moderate acute malnutrition (MAM) in IMC&#x2019;s nutrition facilities. In addition, the project will support life-saving improvements in Maternal-Infant Young Child Nutrition (MIYCN) practices focusing on the first 1,000 days of a child&apos;s life. 


Through this funding, IMC will also enable to rehabilitate the existing seven static sites, and establish three additional mobile nutrition services delivery points in Panyijar County. These will enable IMC to expand its response capacity to reach more under five children and PLWs who are affected by the flood increase their access to treatment for SAM and MAM, prevent acute malnutrition, and ensure continuity of nutrition services across IMC&#x2019;s nutrition facilities.  Ultimately, this proposed project will ensure timely nutrition services delivery to the flood-affected under five children and PLW regular supply of specialized food to children adequate resources to carry out the response (human, equipment and supplies), and proactive community mobilization (active screening, effective referral and treatment, and behavior change activities) by static and mobile teams. These interventions will be augmented by the ongoing capacity strengthening efforts of IMC at facility and community levels. The duration of this proposed project is for 9 months, from 01 November 2020 to 30 June 30 2021.


IMC will maintain and continue to implement nutrition interventions in the same locations and will scale-up the nutrition services into hard to reach and flood-affected areas. This project will be implemented in nine OTP/TSFP sites (7 static and 3 outreach sites) in Panyijar County. The proposed interventions will complement the ongoing activities funded by UNICEF and WFP, and will benefit from the available resources of IMC in Nyal, such as its office and trained field staff, which will minimize its HR, logistics and distribution costs. It will also leverage on IMC&#x2019;s existing active program cooperation agreement (PCA) with UNICEF and Field level agreement (FLA) with WFP, which will ensure consistency of provision of nutrition supplies for SAM and MAM treatment. Furthermore, IMC will reinforce integration and linkages with other sectors (Health, Food Security, WASH, and Protection) to address the key drivers of malnutrition through enhanced coordination and joint programming targeting vulnerable groups, in coordination with other partners in the area. 

This proposed project will be implemented with full adherence to COVID-19 IPC measures per the WHO, Ministry of Health and Nutrition Cluster guidelines. IMC has also put in place its COVID-19 Preparedness and Response Plan, which will be adapted for this project, to ensure continuity of its life saving nutrition operations while guaranteeing the safety of staff, partners and beneficiaries. Specifically, IMC will provide training to all its nutrition staff, including Community Nutrition Volunteers and Mother-Support Groups on COVID-19 IPC measures. Additionally, IMC will carry out the following: strengthening its community mobilization efforts on COVID-19 risks and mitigation measures distributing/posting of COVID-19 IEC materials pre-positioning of PPE for staff and training them on its rational utilization, and mounting bigger sheds to ensure physical distancing in waiting areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-NUT-161043-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dugsiye Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211927000124</telephone>
   <email>dugsiye@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anwar Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director - Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211927000112</telephone>
   <email>anwarali@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-16">75000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-16">225000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-17619">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-16">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304844434">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-21">180000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
