<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="183" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-04T02:06:19.873" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-31T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA2/ER-FS/NGO/17690</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the underserved communities in rural Idleb by life-saving aids and COVID-19 preventive masks.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project endeavors to implement integrated activities between FSL and ERL clusters in the humanitarian field in western rural of Idleb province in Jisr-Ash-Shugur district in Janudiyeh sub-district which is considered as high-needs and underserved areas, for both host community and IDP. This intervention will support 340 IDP households in the camps with live-saving food baskets to enhance their food security which will strengthen their immunity during the outbreak of COVID-19 as well. Also, the project will contribute to develop the household&#x2019;s livelihood through establishing sewing workshop as CFW activity for 20 women from host community and IDPs to fabricate 149500 masks wherein wearing mask is an essential preventive measure to break the outbreak of COVID-19 pandemic nowadays for specific where the daily statistics from NW Syria about the numbers of people contracted with COVID-19 do not bode well, as the numbers are increasing at an alarming rate that threatens the entire society, which already suffers from poverty and neglection.
The proposed location is ranked as high priority for both COVID-19 outbreak and food security coverage for PIN wherein the HNO severity in this location is 4 out of 5.

The project includes:
I-Distribution of food basket for 340 IDP-households in the camps for eight consecutive rounds where the food basket will cover 100% of the household needs for food in order to achieve their nutrition status and healthy conditions, especially for children, women, pregnant, elderly during winter season and the outbreak of COVID-19 pandemic. The food basket&#x2019;s weight is 78.3 kg and it will provide the households members with 2100 Kcal/person/day which is equal to 100% per day as per Sphere standards. The FSL cluster recommendation was taken into account in the food basket design and determined food basket distribution modality because the markets in this area consider non-functional. We added 4 boxes of soap to the food basket as a protective measure against COVID 19.

II-CFW activity for 20 women form the most vulnerable households from both host community and IDPs by daily 5 working hours and daily wage 5 $ according to the CWG, by establishing sewing workshop for fabricating 149500 fabric re-usable masks according to the Public advisory on the use of fabric facemasks in the context of COVID-19 with low cost , and distributing the produced masks (4 masks for each beneficiary), according to the COVID-19 task force recommendation to, camps and host community. There will be 2 sizes of the produced masks, one suitable for adults 18 and above and other suitable for children 2 to 18 years old.
This project will support 37375 beneficiaries affected by the Syrian crisis (8016 men, 8429 women, 10203 boys and 10727 girls divided as the following 11755 HCs, 25480 IDPs and 140 returnees) by promoting their accessibility to the humanitarian assistance significantly.
All the people in the target locations and markets will benefit directly/indirectly from the project where the purchasing of the needed materials of both activities will be form the local markets. 
The project is designed with consideration to the clusters and WHO recommendation on prevention and mitigation measures related to COVID-19 especially during the distribution of support. Also,protection cluster recommendations were taken into consideration, wherein all the population in the targeted locations will benefit from the awareness session of MASRRAT protection team in terms of GBV referral cases, early marriage and child labor risks awareness raising sessions. 
The target locations:
- Janudiyeh village 9055 HCs and 7167 IDPs
- Foz-Zuf village 2700HCs and 18313 IDPs with its camps (Az-Zawf 1 (Sham), Az-Zawf 2 (Sadaka Tashi), Az-Zawf 3 (Al Ikhaa), Bayt Soufan, Itshgiz, Mezgileh, Astara, Kafilt Alkhair, Jinan, Katea Jinan, kafr Dlbeh, Al Shaikh Saiah, Al Amal, Kalaat Al Sendian.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-164488-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="21" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="79" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">257305.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-17690">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">257305.15</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304860965">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">102922.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
