<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="174" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-24T02:07:00.697" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-07T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/WASH/NGO/16336</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehabilitation of WASH infrastructure to ensure IDPs, returnees, and host communities have access to water and sanitation services in northwest Syria.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To improve the living conditions of vulnerable conflict-affected households IDPs, returnees, and host communities, WATAN will implement integrated WASH assistance in western Aleppo governorates. This will ensure that basic needs are addressed at the household level, while also building the capacity of conflict-affected communities to cope with COVID-19. WATAN through this intervention will focus on the urgent needs of 47,833 individuals (11,152 men, 11,534 women, 12,243 boys, and 12,904 girls) (20,534 residents, 12,550 returnees, and 14,749 IDPs) residing in 4 communities (Abin Samaan, Babka, Daret Azza and Kafr Naseh in western Aleppo governorate). The planned intervention will include the following:
Water (Abin Samaan, Babka, and Kafr Naseh):

This project will cover the rehabilitation of 3 water systems to ensure 20,557 individuals (4793 men, 4957 women, 5263 boys, and 5544 girls) are receiving enough and safe water with at least 45 L /capita/day. Following the rehabilitation, WATAN under this grant will support the operation and maintenance (OampM) cost for 5 months with descending coverage as follow (100% for the first month, then 80%, 60%, 40%, and 20% by the fifth month)
This methodology will give the space of the newly established cost recovery to contribute to the OampM under the supervision of WATAN field staff. Thus, confirming the functionality of the cost recovery system and ensuring a smooth exit strategy.

Trough the operation and maintenance support, WATAN will pay special attention to the water quality. WATAN will monitor the water quality in two main points, the water source, and the end-use.
As the project targets mainly 4 communities (Abin Samaan, Babka, Kafr Naseh, and Daret Azza), Daret Azza was not supported with water activities since after the coordination with the WASH cluster, it was noticed that SECD is covering the water part in the community. Thus, the intervention in Daret Azza is complimentary with SECD intervention in the area.
Sanitation, sewer network rehabilitation (Daret Azza, Abin Samaan, and Babka):
The project will cover the rehabilitation of three sewer networks in Daret Azza, Abin Samaan, and Babka to ensure 42,831 individuals (9,986 men, 10,328 women, 10,962 boys, and 11,555 girls) have safe access to sanitation infrastructure.
As ACU reported, the number of water-borne disease (WBD)  cases have sharply increased by 1,278 cases in Atareb sub-district (ACU report 18/04/2020 to 09/05/2020), and by 945 cases in Daret Azza (ACU report 18/04/2020 to 09/05/2020). In addition and as ACU reported, Atareb sub-district has faced an incremental increase in the number of leishmaniases cases by 253 cases and by 39 cases in Daret Azza. This intervention will contribute to decreasing the number of WBD as well as the number of leishmaniasis cases in the area of implementation through ensuring safe disposal of the sludge with no drinking water contamination as a result of and not limited to broken and not functioning sewer system.  
Moreover, Kafr Naseh was not supported by the rehabilitation of the sewer system as this activity was conducted earlier by IYD. Thus, the activities in Kafr Naseh are complimentary as a result of coordination with the WASH cluster and IYD on the field.
Hygiene and COVID-19 response (Kafr Naseh, and Babka):
This intervention will pay special attention to the concerns related to COVID-19 outbreak, the response will include the distribution of essential hygiene items (Soap and washing powder) to support 8,074 individuals (1,883 men, 1,947 women, 2,068 boys, and 2,176 girls) for two rounds to tackle hygiene issues and thus contribute hopefully to eliminate the possibility of the outbreak in Jabal Samaan district in Aleppo governorate. Moreover, this project will provision of hygiene promotion sessions which will include messages related to COVID-19 prevention and will be lead by female hygiene promoters where possible and under the supervision of the protection specialist</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-WSH-164454-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">628366.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">412043.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16336">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">1040410.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304666959">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">624246.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
