<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-sudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="40" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-14T02:05:34.643" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/RE/H-WASH/INGO/16032</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated HEALTH and WASH COVID-19 intervention in Red Sea State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is planned and designed according to the Sudan Humanitarian fund (SHF) reserve for emergency fund allocation guide in line with CPRP, three prioritized pillars, risk communication and community engagement, infection prevention, and control, case management support in   Red sea Port Sudan   SMOH Isolation center hence the state share border and at high risk. 
The project will address the critical need of  Port  Sudan  SMOH  40  bed capacity  Isolation center  Medical equipment and furniture as per MOH list,  Medical supplies and consumables as per bed capacity and consumption projection for the project period, Isolation center staff incentive as per MOH rate.

The proposed training will include IPC( infection prevention and control) protocols, SOPs, and triage procedures. The isolation center rehabilitation work included making partition inside wards,  rehabilitating the water system and latrines (Male and Female), minor renovation to emergency rooms,  incinerator for waste management,    fixing the electric line, a shelter for security staff and fence at the entry point.  Furthermore, Provide PPE and other medical supplies: medical masks, including protective gowns, sanitizers, and other disinfectants. SC will work to strengthen the SMOH  capacity to on COVID19 case detection and diagnosis and case management to slow down community transmission reduce case fatality and increase recovery rate. Furthermore, the other 15 Rural primary health care facilities will be supported by training on    COVID19 case definition, detection, and referral, mainly on triage procedures and Infection prevention control.  Provision of necessary equipment and personnel protection equipment (PPES) and guidelines will be part of the intervention each primary health facility will assign IPC focal point for easier tracking of the progress and strengthen the surveillance system.
The provision of safe WASH conditions plays an essential role in protecting human health during infectious disease outbreaks, including the current COVID-19 outbreak. In Sudan, an estimated 7.6 (1.7million  IDPs, 291,000 returnees, and 5.5 million are non-displaced conflict-affected communities)  million people are in need of wash services, with populations across the different areas experiencing critical and protracted WASH needs.  COVID-19 is a significant threat to the well-being and safety of children across the world and expose them to health risks and disrupt their healthcare, education, as well as access to basic needs like food, protection, and social interaction with the family. There is a need for a swift and comprehensive response in Sudan to help mitigate COVID-19&#x2019;s impact and, as much as possible, preserve children&#x2019;s rights to Survive, Learn, and be Protected. 

Save the Children (SC) will leverage its existing presence in the country and health expertise to support the most marginalized children and their caregivers. They will face the most severe impacts.   
Under this project, SC  will support the Red Sea State MOH to in prepare and respond for to the COVID-19 pandemic with followings :
	a focus in Case management via supporting MOH isolation centers in centers in Port Sudan with equipment, furniture, supplies, staff training and incentives, and 
	IPC: Supporting 15 primary health facilities in Algonob and Haya Localities by strengthening IPCstrengtheningIPC practices via staff training, supervision, and provision of IPC supplies, and 
, Infection Prevention amp Control (IPC) activities in 15 health facility catchment areas in Red Sea State. Risk Communication and Community Engagement (RCCE) through the distribution of IEC materials and awareness campaigns at the community level.
SC will also work to ensure the provision of adequate WASH services within isolation center and health facilities through the provision of water, construction/rehabilitation of toilets, medical incinerators, and handwashing facilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waeil Musa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249912536800</telephone>
   <email>Waeil.musa@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Davina Jeffery</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progamme Development  Quality director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249900905880</telephone>
   <email>Davina.Jeffery@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arshad Malik</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249912395174</telephone>
   <email>arshad.malik@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Red Sea</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.45560630 35.21484690</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-09">250000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-16032">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-09">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304672006">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-14">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
