<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="90" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-22T02:07:38.767" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-30T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/N-H-P-E-NFI/ES-WASH/INGO/17549</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Multi-Sectoral Life-Saving Response to Crisis Affected Children and their Families in Dubti woreda of Afar Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 26 August 2020, the sudden release of water from the Koka and Kessem dams caused significant flooding in Aysaita, Dubti, Afambo and Mille woreda in zone 1 and Awashfentale, Dulsa, Gewane and Gelalo woreda in zone 3. The flooding displaced more than 69,831 people and damaged 20,500 hectares of cropland and killed 15,818 goats and 986 cattle, severely affecting the lives and livelihoods of pastoralists in affected areas. The flood has also demolished schools, rural roads, bridges, and killed domestic animals. All displaced people lost their assets, including their shelters, water collection, utensils and clothing. The displacement did not only tear apart livelihoods of affected people, but also generated serious child protection, health and nutrition, educational and aggravated immediate needs of E/SNFI concerns. Save the Children (SC)&#x2019;s proposed integrated multi-sectoral emergency health, nutrition, education, one-off cash transfer and protection interventions are designed to save the lives, nutritional, educational and the protection needs of thousands of severely flood-affected children and communities in Afar Dubti. The project targeted  5  Kebeles/IDP such as   Babadeyta and korela, Dabal and halibayiri, hanakise and gasuri, Bayahile and Lehada(Ayrolaf)where peoples affected and displaced due to the last flood crisis that affects their livelihood, these IDP is recently living with host communities in these Kebeles not in camps. The project will reach these kebeles and provide the proposed services for both IDP and returnees. The proposed health and nutrition support includes the provision of basic health and nutrition services and contribution to the reduction of morbidity and mortality due to disease and malnutrition in drought and flood affected woredas (Dupti) of Afar region of Ethiopia by deploying one MHNT and one CMAM team. Through child protection response, Save the Children will provide psychosocial services through Child Friendly Spaces (CFS) such as Psychological First Aid/PFA and referral for traumatized boys, girls and families who have witnessed or personally experienced physical injuries including death. SC will also ensure identification and registration of children with different CP concerns ( including number, age, sex, special need/disability) to facilitate referral to other services providers. In addition, we will establish/strengthen child protection committees by using this emergency as an entry opportunity for community members with a composition of different groups working on addressing the needs of children including sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV). In addition, Further to this SC will establish/strengthen case management systems among service providers to respond to cases of violence including SGBV and provide dignity kits for reproductive age girls. Coordination and CP referral mechanisms with different stakeholders like government bodies, law enforcement bodies, UN agencies, NGO, CBO, and community based structures will be strengthened to ensure a comprehensive response to the different needs of children and their families. Further, SCI will increase awareness and improve the sanitation and hygiene practice through hygiene promotion activity of the target population. The Afar Education sub-national cluster report reveals that 61 schools are immersed by water and 81 are partially damaged. Moreover, 19 schools are occupied by the IDPs across Afar region. The report shows that 41,076 students are affected by the current flood. In Dubti woreda, 8 schools (including 1 ABE) have been damaged by flood. Two schools are occupied by IDPs. Apparently, 1,884 students (900 girls and 984 boys) are affected. Due to COVID -19 pandemic, it is clear that schools were closed, teachers stopped teaching and children did not go to school for the last six months. The current flood is making the plan to reopen schools more difficult in flood affected areas than other places.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ekin Ogutogullari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (0)113 728 459</telephone>
   <email>Ekin.Ogutogullari@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nathalie Mendes</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Regional Portfolio Team</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44 (0)20 3763 0813</telephone>
   <email>N.Mendes@savethechildren.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.77273098 12.03628232</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="24" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="18" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="8" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">16574.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">483425.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17549">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304859971">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-30">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
