<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="23" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-17T02:05:57.517" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-11T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA2/WASH/NGO/17631</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Sustainable WASH response services by enhancing access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene for 32,000 flood and disease prone-affected individuals through a single approach in Cueibet and Wulu Counties of Lakes State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This single cluster approach project will address concerns of 32,000 flood-affected, hard-to-reach, and disease-prone affected populations by providing WASH services to vulnerable populations in Cueibet and Wulu Counties (Lakes State). This will improve water supply, sanitation, and hygiene behavior and mitigate WASH-related GBV for the vulnerable IDPs and host families. This project will ensure WASH and GBV interventions are incorporated to increase the cost-effectiveness of the response by networking and closely working with existing partners within the target locations. Care for Children amp Old Age in South Sudan will engage with Gender-Based Violence partners in Cueibet and Wulu and will request the collaboration of Gender-Based Violence personnel to co-chair the Gender-Based Violence risk analysis planned within the activities.


Prior to project implementation, Care for Children amp Old Age in South Sudan will conduct, focus group discussions with women, men, boys, and girls at targeted community settlements to get feedback on the design, implementation, and monitoring of sanitation facilities, ensuring safety and mitigation of Gender-Based Violence risks, especially for females. These focus group discussions will also be utilized to trigger community action towards ending open defecation and other poor hygiene practices such as not washing hands. 


The project proposes to provide 9500 persons &#x2013; 6650 female &#x2013; 70%) with adequate clean and safe water in Cueibet and Wulu East through rehabilitation of 19 boreholes as follows:- Wulu &#x2013; (Hai Jebel, Marial Keng, Hai Jebel Two, Doketu , Makor, Bar &#x2013;Bol , Gul mar and MatonyI), while in Cueibet &#x2013; (Panakol, Abar-kouc, Langdit, Bargel, Alel, and Akecok ). Safety audits and Gender-Based Violence risk analysis before the selection of any WASH facility to be rehabilitated to enable girls and women safely access the facilities. This will be done jointly with the Gender-Based Violence actors in these localities.  

900 people (500 women amp girls) will be provided sanitation and hygiene facilities that are safe and gender-appropriate through rehabilitation of 10 toilets in settlements. The rehabilitation of this sanitation infrastructure will be based on Gender-Based Violence risk mitigation analysis/ safety audits conducted jointly with the Gender-Based Violence partners in these settlements. 

18 Hygiene promoters (12 female) will be trained and engaged, planned to reach 32,000 people (22,000 female) 1 Hygiene Promoter is planned to reach 15 households per week. 

MHM kits will be distributed to the 1,500 (900 girls and 600 women) who are most vulnerable identified using the following criteria: low-income girls in schools of adolescent age and women, unaccompanied or orphaned girls, and persons with disabilities. Women and girls will also be provided with information on how and to whom they can share feedback or criticism about the kit contents and distribution practices by female staff. One dignity kit will be for two-three women in a household. A needs assessment will be conducted at the beginning of the project implementation phase.

CCOSS will also assess the target population and identify at least 1500 most vulnerable households in Cueibet and Wulu  (total 9,000 individuals) for distribution of WASH NFIs &#x2013; which will include:- filter cloth Pur sachets Aquatabs collapsible jerry can/bucket, and soap. 

All interventions will follow Covid-19 protocols including those guidelines laid down in the WASH cluster Covid-19 Preparedness and Response Strategy document.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-WSH-160332-2" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mundia Akala</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0921399960</telephone>
   <email>mundia.akala@ccoss7.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mabior Wel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0925029884</telephone>
   <email>info@ccoss7.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lakes</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.60307990 29.97405340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">83333.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">216666.7</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-17631">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">300000.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304822952">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">180000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
