<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="71" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-24T03:05:22.653" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-02T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA5/WASH/INGO/17216</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive COVID-19 Emergency WASH Response in Hard-to-Reach Areas of Badakhshan and Kunduz</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Afghanistan, the pandemic comes at a time when the country is grappling with deadly conflict, severe food insecurity, and a dire economy that has plunged over 80% of the population below the poverty line (C-19 MSHCP). Existing WASH services including water and sanitation facilities were already unable to adequately support escalating WASH needs from conflict and natural disasters, without the added burden of COVID-19. According to IOM, the number of confirmed cases suggests that Afghanistan could have one of the highest infection rates in the world, with the Ministry of Public Health projecting over 25.6 million Afghans will be infected with the virus if serious action is not undertaken. With over 60% of COVID-19 tests allocated to just three of the country&#x2019;s 34 provinces, humanitarian agencies continue to voice a lack of attention and support to other increasingly vulnerable areas. Accordingly, Kunduz and Badakhshan Provinces&#x2015;the proposed area of intervention&#x2015;have largely been neglected in terms of both testing and response, with 1,040 confirmed cases considered a severe underrepresentation of the current context (MoPH, 9/15/20). The lack of confirmed cases combined with rumors and limited access to reliable information have created a false sense of security, prompting communities to disregard vital prevention measures required to mitigate or reduce the likelihood of an outbreak. 

Through a whole of community approach, Concern Worldwide is proposing inclusive and accessible COVID-19 emergency response in underserved, hard-to-reach areas of Yaftal and Arghanch Khwa districts of Badakhshan and Khanabad and Aliabad districts of Kunduz, entailing: 1) the installation of age, gender, and disability-inclusive handwashing stations at remote health care facilities and public gathering areas 2) the rehabilitation of damaged village hand pump wells that are safe and accessible to different vulnerability groups and 3) the targeted construction of safe and appropriate latrines for disabled and female-headed households. Specifically, Concern will install 960 communal handwashing stations at pre-identified vulnerable sites of target communities, taking into consideration age, gender, and disability access to ensure equal assistance. This includes sex-segregated facilities (where applicable), soak pits for water drainage, and an appropriate height for comfortable access and use by children, elderly, and people with a disability. Handwashing stations will be provided alongside a three-month supply of liquid soap, and will require the signing of an MoU that details sustained community-led maintenance and management, including proper transportation and storage of water. Additionally, through a community-based participatory approach, Concern will identify and rehabilitate 80 damaged hand pump wells that are accessible and safe for the whole community in order to address the prevalent lack of access to clean water. Existing CBOs, community leaders, and representatives of MRRD will be involved in the site selection process to ensure local buy-in and sustainability of the repaired infrastructure. Guided by inclusive Beneficiary Selection Committees (BSCs), Concern will identify 415 disabled and female-headed households that lack able-bodied members for the construction of sanitary latrines. Concern will abide by UNHCR&#x2019;s protection checklist for sanitation facilities, including a safe location, proper lighting, minimum space standards, and locks on the inside for privacy and safety. Throughout project implementation, Concern will mainstream COVID-19 risk communication and awareness campaigns, including gender-sensitive hygiene promotion, rumor management, contextual mitigation measures, and available channels for health support. The timely provision of the WASH minimum package will establish the conditions that allow 63,720 people to live with good health, dignity, and comfort&#x2015;which is particularly crucial in the context of a pandemic.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Martha Medhanie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93796797655</telephone>
   <email>martha.medhanie@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gregoire Borgoltz</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interim Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799489507</telephone>
   <email>gregoire.borgoltz@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badakhshan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.73477250 70.81199530</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunduz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.85993070 68.71549750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-23">170168.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-23">229837.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-17216">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-23">400006.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304777996">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-02">320005.13</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
