<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="11" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-17T03:07:59.313" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-26T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA1/H/INGO/15846</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensuring Continuity of Lifesaving Primary Health Care Services in Disease Outbreak and Drought Affected districts of South Omo zone (SNNPR) and West Arsi zone of Oromia Region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millions of Ethiopians are affected by man-made and natural disasters and disease outbreaks each year. The Government of Ethiopia, along with its partners, has been responding to these crisis through distinctive, targeted sectors in the most affected corners of the country. A few of these sectors include Health, WASH, nutrition, NFI distribution, GBV prevention, and shelter. The IRC has been similarly responding to the aforementioned problems, targeting IDPs, refugees, and host communities.
The ongoing outbreak of cholera in South Omo and Gofa zones of SNNPR claimed the lives of people due to delay in intervention and limitation of local capacity to start initial response when cases were initially identified. There is also a weak surveillance system to identify the cases and timely report and respond. During the current wave of cholera outbreak the IRC has treated 337 cases of cholera in South Omo zone, Salamango district, although 11 patients died before intervention. During the same wave of outbreak, in the Hamar district of South Omo, 81 patients were treated, with four dying before receiving treatment. Additionally, 200 patients in the Bena Tsemay districts of South Omo were also treated by other partners.
Oromia region, like the SNNPR, has several emergency hot spots attributed to both man-made and natural disasters. Conflicts along the regional borders with other regions such as Somali, BGRS and SNNPR resulted in massive displacement crisis in 2018. Moreover, drought, locust infestations and outbreak of different communicable diseases such as cholera and measles have been continuously reported from most of the regional zones. 
Nensebo district of West Arsii zone with total population of 159, 912 has 20 kebeles has frequently been affected by disease outbreaks including measles and malnutrition among underfive children is also common problem. 680 cases of measles and 231 cases of malnutrition has been reported from this district over the last one year (Distric HMIS data). Dodola, an adjacent district with more than 230, 000 population has similar health problem additional IDP crisis during the recent unrest in Oromia. 
Covid-19 has been a globally identified infectious disease since the end of last year, quickly developing into a pandemic affecting millions of people in the world. Ethiopia reported its first case of Covid-19 on the 13th of March, and as of of May 15th there are 287 cases of Covid-19 with five deaths. Cases have been reported in the capital Addis Ababa and other regions. Cases have been gradually rising every day, some acquired through local transmission. This has led to heightened concerns about how many people have been infected thus far. Additionally, Covid-19 is not only affecting the physical health of those infected, but it is also contributing to mental health strain for all, as a result of stress related to the overwhelming uncertainty surrounding the disease.
The national health systems attention has shifted towards the Covid-19 preparedness and response using the scarce resources available. This is believed to further impair the health system, potentially depriving millions from getting lifesaving health services.
IRC under this project will focus on building the local capacity to quickly identify potential outbreaks and respond without delays and work on prevention of the Covid-19 by community sensitization using different IEC methods and other supports for health facilities. The PPE which will be provided by WHO will also be distributed to health facilities.Special attention will be given to infection prevention protocols and guidelines as well as supplies in health facilities. Proper triage and systematic screening of Covid-19 cases in health facilities will also be reinforced. Suspected cases will be kept in temporary isolation unit and moved to MOH-designated isolation centers in coordination with district health office.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frank McManus</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2510116636735</telephone>
   <email>Frank.McManus@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yodit Tsegaye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2510116636735</telephone>
   <email>Yodit.Tsegaye@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Israel Ossana</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2510116633735</telephone>
   <email>IIsrael.Ossana@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNNP</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.80636061 6.46546930</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-10">250000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-15846">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-10">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304643154">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400322533">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-26">1762</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
