<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="21" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-09T02:06:25.59" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-03T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA1/SNFI/INGO/16932</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive reconstruction of temporary shelters for IDPs in Rakhine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In coordination with the Shelter Cluster, this intervention will address the urgent unmet reconstruction needs of shelters by working to provide dignified and safe living conditions to IDPs in the camps and displacement sites in either Sittwe township, both priority sites of the first standard allocation.


Christian Aid (CA) in partnership with Organisation for Building Better Society (BBS) will construct 33 shelter units for 1,320 individuals with integrated accessibility features for persons with disabilities and privacy and protection measures for women. A Gender and disability-focused technical survey will be conducted targeting shelters/households as well as a beneficiary assessment to directly inform the demolishment, reconstruction, handover and post-distribution monitoring of shelters. Specific needs will be identified and mapped using Washington Group of Disability Questions which will identify impairments and facilitate the expression of needs. As current stocks are insufficient to meet need, tarpaulins will be distributed while shelters are reconstructed.


Building upon learning from previous and ongoing shelter interventions in Rakhine, the project targets the wider community through sensitisation initiatives for the promotion of disability rights and inclusive participation so that persons with disabilities, women and other vulnerable groups are welcomed in community-based activities and are encouraged to meaningfully participate in discussions and decision making. Though orientation to the CMC on inclusive shelter design, disability rights and gender and learning document, the project intends to generate insights, initiate conversations, and raise awareness among technical groups and the Shelter Cluster on the importance of mainstreaming disability and gender in planning and implementing humanitarian action. 

The project will follow CA&#x2019;s Localisation Partnership Model. It will be locally led, owned by partners and rooted in target communities. CA will enhance BBS&#x2019;s capacity to deliver inclusive and accountable programmes especially in the context of COVID-19, with training on Inclusive Humanitarian Programming, refresher training on PSEA and Accountability to Affected Population, and finally, support on Business Continuity Planning and Remote Working/Monitoring. 

CA&#x2019;s new digital feedback collection system, COMPASS aims to collect feedback and/or misinformation in a more centralized and systematic manner that would allow a faster response to need or modifications in services. The project site will have information boards/banners which outline programme information, relevant budget information, timelines, feedback mechanisms and contact information. The project will strive for adequate representation of persons with disabilities, older people and women in project planning, community meetings and orientations activities. 

CA and BBS both have access in the preferred camps in Sittwe and will closely coordinate with the Rakhine State Government with regular approvals sought for project activities from both the state government and the CMC of the assigned camp. 

CA and BBS have robust risk management and mitigation measures in place to manage risks associated with operating in insecure contexts. In light of recent violence, a communication strategy to address issues locally together with existing relationships with communities, sound knowledge of local language, appreciation of customs and practices will minimise the risk to staff and produce an open dialogue with communities. Risks posed by COVID-19 and movement restrictions are carefully considered to protect staff and community activities are conducted with preventive measures in place.TCA and BBA have contingency plans which include front-line measures for ensuring safety and security in conflict and pandemic environment.

Regular coordination activities will be held and a learning document will be produced by the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Building Better Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charlotte Petrie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Development and Funding Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00447715466950</telephone>
   <email>cpetrie@christian-aid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joana Paula Villaflor</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00639997944300</telephone>
   <email>JVillaflor@christian-aid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ko Ko Lwin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>009595186101</telephone>
   <email>kokolwin@bbs-mm.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-31">228942.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-31">111633.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-16932">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-31">340576.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304722838">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-03">272460.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
