<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="14" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-05T03:06:14.08" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-18T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/FSAC/INGO/17919</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Emergency Food Security Response for covering Gaps in on-going Emergency Assistance for CrisisAffected Vulnerable Population in Zinjibar District, Abyan Governorate, Yemen- YHF allocation priority 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPC analysis published in July 2020, warned that economic shocks, conflict, floods, locusts, and COVID-19 could reverse food security gains in Yemen. This project will provide immediate life-saving emergency cash assistance to the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs living in deplorable conditions in collective sites or with host families in Zinjibar, Abyan Governorate, meeting basic food needs of the most vulnerable 690 households or 4,830 individuals (1,051 men, 966 women, 1,449 boys, and 1,364 girls). The target district has been identified by FSAC as having food security gaps/needs that require immediate cash assistance aligned with YHF SA1 to provide immediate funding to assist people in acute humanitarian needs with a view to mitigating the risks of famine and negative consequences of COVID-19 in Yemen as well as parameter 2 priority (covering the gaps in clusters ongoing emergency response for people in acute need). Each target household will receive six rounds of monthly support through the appropriate cash modality. Oxfam activities will align and focus on covering food gaps for people in acute needs in the ongoing emergency response in Zinjibar District of Abyan Governorate. Zinjibar District has the highest percentage of people in Aden Governorate (55% of the total district population) in Crisis or worse (IPC Phase 3+) with the most vulnerable IDPs living with host families/households. Oxfam&#x2019;s recent rapid market and food security needs assessment showed that men, women, boys, and girls are practicing negative coping mechanisms due to their inability to purchase food in the market. The most vulnerable households are reducing the frequency and size of meals face high levels of debt/loans, and are selling household productive assets, while children are seen begging in communities. Oxfam will respond to the most vulnerable households with monthly food assistance, through a cash-based modality of six months unconditional cash transfer (UCT), based on FSAC recommended minimum food value to cover 80% of household food needs. Cash will be distributed through identified FSPs at safe locations identified in consultation with target communities. Oxfam&#x2019;s rapid market assessment shows that Zinjibar markets are safely accessible by the general population selling basic food commodities and NFI items. Oxfam will continue to monitor and analyze market conditions during the period of UCT cash distribution, ensuring beneficiary acceptance of UCT cash modality. Oxfam will directly implement the project ensuring the quality of program delivery and compliance with FSAC and OCHA YHF accountability measures for direct and indirect beneficiaries. Oxfam has ongoing food security and livelihood projects in Abyan (Khanfar District), good access to Zinjibar District, and good working relationships with local authorities and target communities as these will support project implementation. Oxfam has identified project risks and mitigation measures i.e. humanitarian access, aid diversion, exclusion and inclusion errors of beneficiaries&#x2019; selection, and COVID-19. Oxfam will mainstreaming mainstreaming COVID-19 pandemic response measures as per organizational SOPs. Oxfam will conduct a safe programming risk assessment before implementation to identify possible risks and put a monitoring system in place to reduce and manage identified risks such as sub-agreement delays and changes in market availability/prices. Oxfam will coordinate with the IDP Executive Unit, NGOs, INGOs, RRM, UN agencies, and Nutrition, Protection, WASH, Health and FSAC clusters on inclusive food security activities, including specific and differentiated needs relating to men, women, boys, and girls, and people with disabilities. Oxfam has been operational in Abyan since 2019 and has excellent experience/capacity to implement the proposed intervention in a participatory, collaborative, transparent, and accountable manner, whilst addressing specific needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taha Alraeeini</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>739705557</telephone>
   <email>talraeeini@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.69554850 46.50340692</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">542923.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">13764.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17919">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">556688</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304914651">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-18">222675.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
