<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="35" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-20T02:04:59.393" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-30T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/Ed/INGO/15270</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved Access to Quality Education in IDP schools in Galkacyo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed 11 months intervention will improve access to quality education and increase access to critical WASH inputs and IEC material for prevention of COVID-19  in 16 IDP schools of conflict-affected IDP students and their surrounding communities in Mudug region of Puntland State of Somalia. 


Relief International (RI) is already implementing an SHF funded project in 6 IDP schools in Mudug continuing until mid-May 2020. Under the proposed project, support will be extended to these 6 schools for an extended period while 10 more IDP schools will be added to ensure access to more IDPs children and to cover the educational needs of existing children in Galkacyo district. The project will target 3,893 enrolled children (1,892 boys and 2,001 girls). 


Education specific activities with inclusion of COVID-19 response  will include the provision of education supplies based on the minimum standards of education cluster emergency take-away food rations with inclusion of soap for students to meet student&#x2019;s minimum caloric needs and to better hygiene practices emergency teacher incentives to motivate teachers sanitary kits with soap for adolescent girls to encourage their regular attendance at school once school are open in new academic year based on  and teacher training on INEE/TICC with adding contents of PSS and inclusive education. these training will be conducted on safe opening of schools. however, measures will be in place to stop the spread of COVID-19. The measures will include, arranging training in small groups, availability of sanitizer/soap and masks at training venue, a session at the start of training to brief the participants for maintaining social distancing. 
Specific WASH activities in schools will include increasing schools&#x2019; water storage capacity through the provision of PVC storage tanks, rehabilitation of latrines and construction of water storage tanks. Child- and gender-friendly latrines in the targeted schools will be rehabilitated or, where necessary, constructed to minimize disruptions in learning for girls and boys. Hand washing facilities will be constructed in schools. The project will provide hand washing soap when schools reopen. The schools will also be provided with posters with vital information on hygiene but also other thematic areas that may be relevant to COVID 19 as they reopen. Where possible, murals will be developed in strategic places to further enhance the communication
   . A refresher training will be arranged for CECs with the addition of new contents related to psychosocial first aid, hygiene promotion, and prevention of COVID-19, school improvement plans, and child protection along with the refresher of previously covered content. RI will also integrate child protection in different trainings with CECs and teachers. Focus will also be given on developing messages for child protection and  positive parenting. Through CECs, RI will deliver messages to schools and communities on key protection concerns affecting the community. These messages will target prevention as well as the response in the event protection incidents arise. 

RI will coordinate a back-to-school campaign with CECs and religious leaders to encourage school enrollment with an emphasis on girls and children affected by displacement and to ensure that children are back to school and COVID-19 break Parents of respective communities will also be trained on psychosocial first aid and child protection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Khalid Mehmood</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director Education</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252906065677</telephone>
   <email>muhammad.khalidmehmood@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9672">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mudug</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.49100000 48.01000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-24">272176.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-24">141037.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15270">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-24">413214.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304657702">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">247928.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
