<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="104" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-12T02:05:07.817" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-07T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/16192</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting wheat value chain and income generating activities in Northwest Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed to improve the level of sustained food security in northwest Syria through supporting wheat value chain for one hectare for most vulnerable 1500 farmers (85% M, 15% F, 4% PwD, HCs and IDPs), 7500 individuals (1725M,1800F,2250B,1725G) in Sharan, Jandairis, A&#x2019;zaz&#x2019; and Aghtrin.
Targeted locations were identified based on need and market assessments (Annex 7), where assessment shows that ,many farmers moved from wheat planting as a strategic crop towards planting cash crops which provide more income.

Meetings and FGDs with local actors and farmers (males and females) will be held to explain the project goals and take any suggestions and ensure their support.
The project will achieve its objectives through a combination of five interventions:

1. Preparing farmers&#x2019; lands through supporting agriculture machine owners by contracting with them to plow the targeted farmers&#x2019; lands in order to be prepared for planting seeds
2. Providing the farmers with agriculture inputs (seeds, fertilizer, pesticides) through $250 restricted value E-voucher which maintains farmers dignity and gives them flexibility to choose the best inputs for growing wheat from a set of pre-appointed items from multiple vendors who were selected through a committee based on pre-specific criteria.
Vouchers distribution will be in Aug while the loading of balances will be done in 4 phases ($52.5 for phosphate fertilizer,$60 for seeds,$87.5 Urea fertilizer,$50 Pesticides), where balances will only be uploaded after field verification visits verify that the farmer used the received materials.
The project team will follow up the redemption process. After the end of distribution, we will conduct a PDM to measure beneficiaries satisfactory.
3. Providing farmers with theoretical and practical extension training sessions in order to strengthen their knowledge about the best practices for wheat growing which avoid environmental harm, and detecting the wheat deceases, as well as the continuous providing of consultancy services, through a team of expert agronomists, who will conduct two rounds of field visits to farmers locations in addition to following up WhatsApp groups to verify the progress of project and provide the farmers with technical advises.
4. Supporting farmers in marketing their crops through distributing packaging bags to be filled by wheat during harvest, in addition to contacting with organizations working in supporting value chain to ensure better marketing of the supported crops.
5. Supporting vulnerable CFW female workers with temporary income, through hiring 252 women for a month to assist farmers in weeding and Sunn pest management.
Takaful will ensure that the farmers will be positively involving in the project to achieve the objectives, through funding 61% of the total costs (seeds, fertilizers, pesticides, plowing, Packaging bags), while farmer will fund 39% (fuel for irrigation and harvesting costs).
Protection measures based on FSL cluster recommendation &#x201C;FSL Prevention and Mitigation Measures for COVID-19 on the Implementation of Agricultural Projects&#x201D; will be implemented. 
In case any problems and missing access for any of the targeted areas, we will change the location according to specific criteria in coordination with FSL Cluster, where Takaful conducted need assessment in 4 other locations.
We will ensure that the principle of Do No Harm is applied in all project&apos;s activities through markets visits, distribution monitoring and exit surveys. In addition, we will target group of women and PwD who are in charge of agricultural work, where we will take into account the difficulties of some of them related to accessing the market, where we will verify their needs and deliver items to their homes. 
We will coordinate with FSL cluster, agriculture working group, local communities and NGOs who are working in same locations, in addition to sharing the eligible locations with FSL and ER clusters to avoid any overlap</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-164708-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">443160.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">438317.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16192">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">881477.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304666965">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">528886.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
