<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="19" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-21T02:07:40.513" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-10T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/FSAC/NGO/17930</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 1 and priority 2: Providing immediate life-saving emergency food assistance to acutely food insecure IDPs living in deplorable conditions in collective centers or with host families in Al Mukha and Tarim districts.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is aligned with the YHF S1 strategic objective which is providing immediate funding to assist people in acute humanitarian needs with a view to mitigating the risks of famine and negative consequences of COVID-19 in Yemen. It is also aligned with the FSAC strategic objective which is to increase the access to food for highly vulnerable families across the country through assisting 10 million severely food-insecure individuals plus 2 million newly displaced and host individuals in high-priority districts. So, according to YHF 2020 standard allocation strategy and FSAC, Al Mukha district is among the hardest to reach areas due to the ongoing conflict and its proximity to the frontline where 50% of the population classified in IPC3 and above, and it is hosting over 20664 IDPs. While Tarim district considers a suitable place for the IDPs where it receives continuous waves of IDPs and currently hosting over 3500 IDPs. Adding to the IDPs influxes, 60% difference in population classified in IPC3 according to the updated IPC projection (Jul-Dec 2020) compared to Feb-Apr 2020 IPC numbers all these numbers reflects the high need due to the deteriorating economic conditions and high food prices multiplied by the low income of households in the Tarim, which may not be enough to meet their basic food needs.
The project aims to respond to priority-1 to provide assistance for people in acute need. As both districts are classified from the 34 districts that are hard to reach areas. This project will provide support to the emergency needs of 1000 IDP HHs (7000 direct beneficiaries) women, men, and children living in deplorable conditions in collective centers in Al Mukha district in Taiz and Tarim District in Hadhramaut. The main project activities include the coordination with the local authorities, conduct baseline survey, the establishment of the CC, beneficiaries&#x2019; registration and verification, market assessment, awareness sessions to the IDPs and host community, cash assistance distribution, conduct DDM, PDM, and baseline and end-line survey.

FMF will employ the field teams from the same targeted districts to facilitate the movement and increase access. As well as preparing the distribution points to receive persons with disabilities and special needs to enable them to access equally and fairly following the protection principles. The project will also ensure that IDPs have access to basic food needs through this intervention, with a well-thought approach to address the specific needs of women, children, elderly, people with disabilities, and vulnerable groups while ensuring their participation in planning, implementation, and monitoring of interventions.
The project may face some risks related to insecurity and increase the flow of IDPs, COVID-19 outbreak, Instability of the YER against USD, rising food price, and difficult to target IDPs who live within the host community. All these can be mitigated through close coordination with FSAC, CCCM, and all stockholders in the targeted districts from the beginning of the project, adhering to protective measures against COVID-19, continuous coordination with the local and security authorities in the targeted districts, rising awareness of the community and engaging them in the discussions that will be held during the project period.

FMF has 7 ongoing projects in Hadhramaut, 3 of which are in FSL with more than 23149 targeted HHs. and 4 ongoing projects in Taiz, 2 of which are in the FSL with 14334 HHs. As a result of FMF&apos;s ongoing projects in the targeted districts, the presence of FMF offices and staff, FMF has established strong and close relationships with local authorities and communities which will provide a high level of advocacy for the project&apos;s activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayada Nabih</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundraising Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770578894</telephone>
   <email>mayada.nabih@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qaboos Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>773729462</telephone>
   <email>qaboos.ali@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Al Sharafy</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>736263641</telephone>
   <email>mohammed.alsharafi@fmfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hadramaut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.80924424 48.84638589</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">688092.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">37894.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17930">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">725986.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304911006">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">217796.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Medical Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
