<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-nigeria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="32" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-25T02:06:03.06" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-20/NIG_ERF/SA1/P/INGO/16641</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving wellbeing and access to lifesaving protection of conflict affected children, adolescents and caregivers through comprehensive case management and psychosocial support mechanisms in NE state of Adamawa.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Nigeria will implement an 8-month protection intervention focusing on GBV prevention and response to improve access to quality lifesaving and well-coordinated protection of children, adolescents and caregivers at risk of GBV, through comprehensive case management and enhanced psychosocial support mechanisms in Michika and Madagali in Adamawa States. At project start-up, Plan International Nigeria will prioritize access to life-saving services for survivors of GBV including those vulnerable and at risk of GBV, and will seek to address the risks of Gender-Based Violence including sexual violence and Sexual Harassment, Exploitation and Abuse (SHEA) faced by women and girls including men and boys. We will strengthen capacity of case workers including community capacity to prevent and respond to incidents of GBV and will work closely with communities and partners to establish safe and confidential spaces taking into regard WHO COVID-19 guidelines where survivors as well as individuals at risk of GBV can access safety and psychosocial services. Strengthening referral pathways, clinical management of survivors including remote case management on child helplines and coordination. IDPs, returnees and host community members including community-based protection mechanisms and local leaders will be engaged to identify and provide appropriate referrals to psychosocial services including free helpline services for counseling and educational information. Plan International will hire and train a team of Case Workers with gender consideration (male and female) who will be deployed at the community level to provide case management and psychosocial services for survivors of GBV and to support individuals at risk of GBV especially women and girls. The approach to recruit and build the capacity of Case Workers from the Local Government Area (LGA) will ensure that project beneficiaries have access to Case Workers as well as sustainability of support by fostering ownership and involvement of community-based structures in all relevant processes and discussions. Plan International will integrate inclusive service delivery within this project using our mobile protection approach to reach out to hard to reach communities and mobile population. Plan&#x2019;s Mobile programming approach is designed to provide multi-sectoral services to survivors of GBV in communities where referral services are practically inaccessible. Women and adolescent survivors will receive culturally appropriate safety and dignity kits. The mobile Protection operates from a pick-up truck and composes of health worker (Certified nurse), Social Worker, Community Mobilization Officer who provide a package of services including Case Management, counselling, Health screening and referral for complex cases for clinical management and improved information management through the GBVIMS+. The project will strengthen accountability to beneficiaries through the establishment and strengthening of a child-friendly community-based complaints and feedback mechanism that will allow women, girls, men, and boys safely report concerns of Gender Based Violence including Sexual Exploitation and Abuse. Plan International will work with the communities to identify the preferable and safe method of reporting concerns related to GBV including SEA. Plan Nigeria is part of the PSEA network collaborating with other partners in support community report on SEA. This project will support the operation of the free helpline telephone services in collaboration with the MWASD (Ministry of Women Affairs and Social Development) and GBVSS (GBV Sub Sector) to deliver free helpline services including professional counseling and psycho-education on self-protection as well as report cases of abuse and violence for appropriate services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hussaini Abdu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348037861288</telephone>
   <email>Hussaini.Abdu@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daniel Lartey</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348113763221</telephone>
   <email>Daniel.Lartey@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG002">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adamawa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.32322733 12.40024078</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">52644.63</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">87355.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-16641">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">140000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304833654">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">112000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
