<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="119" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-01T03:05:30.68" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-07T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/FS-WASH-NFI/INGO/16181</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-sectoral emergency assistance for vulnerable people in Euphrates Shield Area and Afrin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is linked to the OPS project HSYR20-FSCSHLWSH. WHH intends to deliver immediate support to people in need in the Euphrates Shield area and Afrin. The proposed intervention has three components: (1) distribution of multi-sectoral (FSL-WASH-SNFI) vouchers to internally displaced persons (IDPs) living in camps and unconditional cash assistance to the most vulnerable (2) Cash for Work (CfW) activities to enhance the hygiene in camps and (3) COVID-19 awareness campaigns in the camps.The first component of the project aims at covering the basic needs of IDPs in camps in the areas of food security, NFI and hygiene through multi-sectoral vouchers, unconditional cash assistance and CfW activities. 
Vouchers: 

Beneficiaries will be able to redeem the food, nonfood and hygiene items from a list based on nutritional dietary and basic personal hygiene needs. The voucher value will be 120$ per  HH per month and each HH will receive it for eight months. The activity will take place in two locations, one in Afrin and one in Azaz, and in each one 487 HHs will be targeted. In total, 975 HHs will benefit from the activity. The distribution will take place in IDP camps through blanket distribution. Vendors will be selected based on the proximity to the settlements and their supply capacity as well as the quality and price of items. 
Cash for Work: 

Regarding CfW activities 300 people will be selected to work for 96 days each with a salary of 1.9 USD per day. The main purpose of this activity is to increase the financial liquidity of the most vulnerable camp population to enable them to meet their basic food needs and to enhance the hygiene in camps by cleaning the streets, irrigation systems and open channels. Furthermore, 30 of the most  vulnerable disabled people and widows who don&#x2019;t have a person at home to work will be selected to receive the assistance unconditionally. 
To complement this, the third component aims at increasing COVID-19/hygiene awareness in the IDP camps. Taking into account women empowerment, female camp members will be selected from the same camps and trained as hygiene mobilizers and develop a hygiene awareness campaign plan in the TOT. The TOT will also cover protection issues, allowing the mobilizers to recognize protection cases and act on them. This activity will also take place in two cycles in each one 20 women will be identified and trained followed by the implementation of the hygiene awareness campaign plan over a period of three months. It is targeted at women specifically, as they are mostly the ones who take care of the children and the hygiene and sanitation of the settlement places. Also considering female hygiene needs, women are more vulnerable. In a second step, the hygiene mobilizers will be sharing the information they learnt in the training by implementing the awareness campaign, which will include household visits inside their camps. Lastly, they will reflect on their experiences and gather lessons learnt in a report. They will also have the chance to reflect on their experiences and discuss lessons learnt in a one-day-session with the trainer of the TOT in a follow-up session after performing the HH visits. The hygiene mobilizers will receive incentives for their work.
By training and engaging female hygiene mobilizers from among the target population WHH supports further engagement and participation of women in the humanitarian response. In order to create a combination where people in need will be able to redeem hygiene items through the vouchers and learn practical knowledge on hygiene, both components address the same target group. The selection of camps will be based on humanitarian principles, where the most vulnerable camps will be targeted based on the less access they have to food, nonfood and hygiene items. The project will be implemented inside IDP camps since the people living there had to leave their belongings behind, which puts them into a more vulnerable position</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC;SHL;WSH-165380-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="14" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="72" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="14" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">603296.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">596703.19</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16181">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">1199999.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304666950">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">719999.87</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
