<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ukraine-allocation-2020" dstore:index="16" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-28T02:05:50.363" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-06T15:21:50.66" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-20/UKR_CBPF/SA1/WASH/NGO/17493</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing assistance to the most vulnerable conflict-affected population in some settlements of Donetska oblast, NGCA to address acute WASH needs during the winter.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this project is to address acute humanitarian needs of the conflict-affected population of Donetska oblast, NGCA during the upcoming winter season. The project is aimed at the most vulnerable category of the population, such as PwD, incl. those with chronic diseases, elderly and impaired. In the framework of the project it is planned to implement the following activities: 
-distributing hygiene kits (HKs) to people with special needs to prevent deterioration of their physical and psychological conditions

-distributing portable toilets to elderly and impaired to improve sanitary condition at household (HH) level. 
During the project implementation, the special needs of men and women will be taken into account, considering the aspect of age. Particular attention will be paid to the matters of personal hygiene and sanitation, which is generally of a sensitive nature and should be treated with privacy and observing dignity to beneficiaries. For instance, the gender of the beneficiaries will be taken into account during the planning and conducting home visits. Moreover, while composing the hygiene kits, individual characteristics of the beneficiaries will be taken into account as well, e.g. size. During the project implementation, there might be some challenges related to security, bureaucratic and legal obstacles, as well as with access to NGCA, including restrictions due to the COVID-19 epidemic. In this regard, special attention will be paid to risk management. For that purpose, a detailed analysis of potential risks indicating proposed mitigation measures has been elaborated (see the attached Risk Analysis amp Mitigation Matrix). 

NEW WAY is planning to implement the project in partnership with another local NGO, namely ICF Mira (Mira), to maximize available resources of each partner in terms of access and organizational capacity. NEW WAY (NW) is a local NGO which continue activities started in 2016 by German NGO arche noVa. Over these years, NW has become a noticeable local actor in the WASH sector, supporting the conflict-affected population through the implementation of humanitarian relief projects in eastern Ukraine. There is a well-established structure as well as necessary technical and support staff in place to oversee the implementation of activities.
With this regard, NW will take the role of a leading agency with the following duties:
- compiling programme documents, incl. Logframe, Workplan, etc.
- general coordination of the project implementation to avoid potential overlapping with other agencies
- carrying out procurement of goods for the distribution
- arranging delivery of goods to NGCA within the humanitarian convoy
- reporting to UHF
- monitoring the progress of the project implementation and evaluating the results.
In turn, Mira, as a local NGO represented and registered in NGCA, will take the role of a sub-implementing partner. The organization has satisfactory experience in implementing projects of similar nature, including those in partnership with INGOs, due to which Mira has established a work relationship with local authorities. There is a clear understanding of the local context, as well as principles of the humanitarian response. Within the framework of the project, Mira will perform the following duties: 
- compiling a database of beneficiaries
- coordination of the activities with local authorities
- obtaining accreditation of the project from local authorities
- distributing goods.
Despite NW has limited access to NGCA, it is planned to employ a local staff for the entire period of the project implementation to oversee the activities. See detailed description of his/her tasks and responsibilities in the project Budget.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Foundation &#x201C;NEW WAY&#x201D;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Foundation &#x201C;NEW WAY&#x201D;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Children`s Fund `Mira`</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dmytro Drizhd</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Foundation</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380501979941</telephone>
   <email>ddrizhd.newway@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andriy Kryvchenkov</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380664606448</telephone>
   <email>akryvchenkov.newway@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lina Potaeva</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance / Admin Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380953919791</telephone>
   <email>lpotaeva.newway@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UKR14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04760900 37.67396200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-06">22063.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-06">154447.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-17493">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-06">176510.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Foundation &#x201C;NEW WAY&#x201D;</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
