<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="35" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-15T03:06:02.34" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-20T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA2/N-H/INGO/17750</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of essential services for highly vulnerable population in Central Rakhine through promotion of child developmental milestones, early detection and prevention of long term disability especially among children with acute malnutrition and assistance to children with disabilities, for a more resilient and inclusive community</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine State suffers from underdevelopment, inter-communal conflict, institutional discrimination, and a depressed economy. As consequences, Rakhine State has the worst nutritional status among children in Myanmar. According to the survey done by the government before the 2017 crisis, under nutrition rates are very high showing 38% Stunting (Chronic malnutrition), 14% Wasting (Acute malnutrition) and 34% Underweight among children under 5 years, especially among low wealth quintile population (Myanmar Demographic and Health Survey, 2015-16). With recent major changes in the context, it is expected that the situation of health and nutrition in Rakhine becomes even worse.The overall objective of the project is to strengthen early detection, referral and treatment of developmental delays and physical impairments, to prevent long term impairment and thus strengthen the resilience of girls, women, boys and men highly vulnerable and living in displaced and local communities in Sittwe. The project will achieve this objective by addressing barriers to accessing services and ensuring early responsiveness and action to prevent and treat malnutrition and provide assistance to children with disabilities. This project is structured in two main components. The first is aligned with the Nutrition Sector priorities and HRP objectives and aims at providing inclusive and equitable preventative services for children under 5, and pregnant and lactating women (PLW). The project will promote access to essential health services such as Stimulative Physical Therapy, and will be preventing the development of impairment through provision of early detection and referral among children, including Severe Acute Malnourished (SAM) children under five. Early detection and intervention can act as a protective factor to reduce the change of developmental delays and impairments. It is therefore crucial to promote better childhood development and to improve the rate of survival of those children born with severe and life-threatening birth defects and/or impairments by referring children and providing access to preventive services at an earlier age. The project will also be raising the awareness of Nutrition partners and community workers on links between malnutrition, disabilities and children developmental milestones. The second component is aligned with the Health Sector priorities and HRP objectives, aiming at building upon current structures, making principled health actions as local as possible, to relieve suffering, save lives and prevent disabilities in humanitarian emergencies. Under the Health component, the project will be responding to the specific needs of children with disabilities and/ or under 5 with SAM, to access essential health services such as functional Physical Rehabilitation. If children with impairment are detected it is essential to provide available services, or to refer patients to services such as pediatric or physical medicine services. This will also ensure coordination with other actors, in particular ICRC, TLMM and Sittwe General Hospital, to include impairments and people with disabilities in the existing referral pathways and mechanisms.Finally, HI will adopt a COVID-19 sensitive approach while implementing each of the proposed activities, ensuring due diligence and duty of care of the project staff and beneficiaries and mainstreaming COVID-19 prevention. The project will cover 4 IDP camps, 4 Muslim villages and 6 Rakhine villages in Sittwe township, making services available to displaced and Host communities living in conflict affected areas. The project will be adding off the ongoing ACF and MHAA Outpatient Therapeutic Program (OTP) at 3 centres, located in Say Tha Mar Gyi, Hla Ma Chay, and Mayzali Gone, and complements the existing HI intervention currently covering 4 IDPs camps, Muslim villages and Rakhine villages.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Michael Horita</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+959979136425</telephone>
   <email>mr.horita@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jerome Bobin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 977 145 0356</telephone>
   <email>j.bobin@hi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-12">212152.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-17750">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-12">212152.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304884508">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">212152.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Handicap International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
