<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="73" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-10T02:06:29.61" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-30T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/H-N/INGO/17544</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Health and Nutrition response for returnees and host communities of Oromia region, West Hararghe zone Hawi Gudina and Daro lebu Woredas in Health and East Hararghe Zone, Fedis and Chinakson Woredas with Nutrition support.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps (IMC) is an US-registered independent affiliate organization of International Medical Corps UK (IMC (UK)), with which IMC (UK) shares the same name and charitable objectives and mission. IMC (UK) and IMC work together to deliver assistance programs in an accountable and effective manner in pursuit of their commonly held charitable objectives. IMC (UK) will engage IMC to implement its programmes in the field, with IMC (UK) oversight, according to the terms and conditions of any agreement that results from this proposal and the terms of the parties&#x2019; administrative service agreement. IMC maintains a branch office in Croatia, IMC Split that provides administrative and operational support to IMC (UK) and to the programmes on the ground, including but not limited to financial management, procurement management/international procurements, and logistics. 


Based on Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) Ethiopia midyear review, issued on August 2020, 6.5million people are in need of emergency health response and there is a concern over the likelihood of further COVID-19 spike given that at least 63% of recent cases resulted through community transmission. 
Weak health systems is already stretched beyond capacity, with shortages of oxygen and beds for COVID-19 patients being reported. The pandemic also threatens gains made on other health threats. To overcome the challenges, IMC health program will focus on the immediate needs of vulnerable populations and the associated basic emergency health response activities to IDPs and returnees by improving access essential lifesaving primary health care services through mobile health and nutrition team at Hawi Gudina woreda and deploying one medical officer as a surge team at Daro Labu woreda of West Hararge zone. The support extends to existing government effort to strengthen health services in the context of COVID-19. The health planned activities also includes supporting the government measles campaign and routine surveillance for early identification and response of COVID-19 pandemic cases and other reportable epidemic-prone diseases, mental health and psychosocial support for the affected population using the MHNT and to enhance awareness of the community through community mobilization campaign and house to house sensitization and awareness creation by HEWs and community volunteer will be conducted. 


According to the Ethiopian Food Security Outlook August update Staple food prices in August 2020 remain higher than in 2019 and the five-year average. The Acute Food Insecurity Analysis July 2020 &#x2013; June 2021 reported as East Hararge zone including the two woredas Chinaksen and Fedis are under crisis / IPC phase 3 which means People facing high levels of acute food insecurity. 
IMC will focus on delivering life-saving, community based managed of acute malnutrition (CMAM) to the woredas using the revised MOH guideline , and infant and young child feeding (IYCF) activities which is in line with the . All components of the CMAM program which includes treatment of moderate acute malnutrition (MAM), severe acute malnutrition (SAM) with and without medical complications will be carried out as well as community activities such as sensitization and screening and ensured jointly with MoH/Zone/Woreda Health office, WFP, and UNICEF. All the nutrition intervention will be targeting vulnerable populations with immediate needs and associated with basic response activities to ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.
To improve the Infant and Young child feeding (IYCF) practice
of caregivers and large community nutrition education and counselling will be provided in organized complimentary feeding sessions, breast feeding corners at the health centers and nutrition education sessions during TSFP/OTP and SC service provision.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Roger Kadima</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 (0)114 701033/53</telephone>
   <email>rshambuyi@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="56" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="44" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">23867.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">246132.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17544">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">270000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304859970">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-30">270000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
