<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="45" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-23T02:07:11.85" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-28T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/FSC/NGO/15384</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustaining Life-Saving Support for Identified Vulnerable Households in Adado District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The planned FSL project intervention is cluster specific response conforms to the Humanitarian Response Plan for 2020 and the 1st 2020 SHF Standard Allocation for the Food Security and Livelihood as it applies to project planned target District of Adado (South Mudug Region). The project will provide lifesaving support to 750 HHs assessed to be in acute food insecurity, &#x2018;Crisis&#x2019; phase of IPC (3)  by providing them with a means to sustained access to food and safety net support. The 750 beneficiaries will receive UCT amounting to a food transfer value of US $100 for 4 months to support a food purchase that meet the minimum 2100 kcal/person/day.


The project proposes lifesaving interventions that are gender sensitive, adapt centrality of protection and that mainstream gender and protection in the delivery methods proposed. The project will specifically prioritize destitute pastoralists and IDP households, women from the destitute households left behind in identified accessible settlements (hard to reach areas especially such as rural areas of the Adado Districts) and other households as identified in the Adado District that fall into the IPC 3. The planned project activities will help mitigate the effects of the poor recovery from the 2016-17 drought that were followed by below average Deyr 2018 and Gu 2019 season rains in Central Somalia Region. The project will also support the Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) from Haradhere District who have sought refuge in Adado District after being displaced by the Non-State Actors keen on forcibly recruiting the children (boys) to be trained in their militia and also being forced to part with their animals on what amounts to illegal taxation for the Zakaat.


The project seeks to improve households&#x2019; immediate access to food to 750 vulnerable households in Adado District of Galgadud Region through Unconditional Cash Transfers (UCTs) for 4 months.  The project will undertake a vulnerability assessment in selected locations of the targeted 6 locations in the District (3 settlements with IDPs and 3 settlements with high number of vulnerable host households) with the findings being used in developing the criteria for selection of the planned UCT beneficiaries and informing on protection needs.  Priority for the UCTs beneficiaries will be given to women-led households from the most vulnerable among recently displaced and socially marginalized communities in the District. The UCTs planning will also be supported by a market analysis undertaken in the District (undertaken by the FSL Team) to determine the capacity of local markets to absorb the resources extended to the beneficiaries. 

The project will provide for continuous community engagement during the implementation process to ensure that the project gets feedback from the beneficiary community necessary for determining the effectiveness of the response and arising gaps that will require humanitarian response. This is particularly necessary given the prediction of a possible effects of the locusts that are expected to spawn again with the coming Gu 2019 season. In addition the project will monitor the trends of COVID-19 pandemic and support groups that may be at risk of a lockdown in case of an increase in food prices given the interruption of supply chains as will be authoritatively captured authoritatively captured by WFP Somalia in its Supply chain monitoring briefs.  The project will also mainstream gender and protection components in order to ensure it supports inclusiveness of both genders but in particular helps make women a priority in the design as direct beneficiaries ensuring the resultant benefits of the project accrue to them. The project will also ensure there is adequate protection of women in all the venues and staging points of the project to ensure it provides the women safety and protection require</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Yarrow Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252618137983 and +252615844133</telephone>
   <email>mohamed.yarrow@cpd-africa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">373913.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">26086.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15384">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304604115">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-14">240000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304744914">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">160000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
