<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="12" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-06T02:06:17.617" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-10T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA2/NFI/NGO/17638</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Quality Access to Emergency Live-Saving Shelter and Non Food Items (S/NFIs) to Flood Affected IDPs, Returnees and Vulnerable Host Population through a Single Sector Approach in Rumbek Center and Rumbek East Counties of  Lakes State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims at meeting the immediate need of the newly flood affected population in Rumbek Centre and Rumbek East in Lakes States through provision of life-saving NFI and Emergency Shelter Items to the newly Flood affected households. According to Multi-sectoral IRNA assessment Report (July 7, 2020) conducted in Lakes State, shelter and NFIs has been identified as the most immediate need following the ongoing flush floods (July- October rainy season) that has created a humanitarian crisis to people already affected by high levels of poverty, impact of COVID-19 and yet to recover from effects of previous floods of December 2019. The assessment report indicates that since July at the beginning of the long perennial rains, Rumbek has received unexpected rainfall that has caused serious flooding affecting most the lowland parts of the State. Being flat land Rumbek also receives a lot of water from upstream especially from rivers originated from Ethiopia and Uganda. The effects of the floods are unprecedented and devastating on recently cultivated and crops, livestock and other livelihood options. The Floods have come very early before main cash crops (Ground nuts, Sesame, Beans and Maize) are harvested, soon hunger will crop up. Houses and dwelling are either destroyed or submerged as many people are displaced to higher grounds having lost their personal belongings. Most people who are displaced have no shelter to sleep and thus fears of contracting water born diseases such as malaria and cholera amidst COVID-19 outbreak. Additionally, there are still many IDPs living with host communities in the target areas who are yet to resettle from 2019 displacement by floods and communal conflict and who are expected to host new flood displaced people. This has caused burden and displacement of Host Communities while the situation of IDPs situation has been made worse on the other hand. TITI Foundation (TF) is one of the active national NGOs supporting communities in the affected locations plans to provide lifesaving assistance the most vulnerable men, women and children affected by floods. The project builds on the TF&#x2019;s ongoing and planned multi-sectoral project in the area. The target beneficiaries for this project are IDPs, Returnees and the vulnerable Host Communities and number to be reached is 40,300 according the Cluster assigned caseload. 6,716 Households comprised of (14508 Men and 21762 Women), (1612 Boys and 2418 Girls). The project contributes towards resolving the situation of the affected population by supporting them with unimpeded and sustained access to plastic Sheets, and other NFIs as stipulated in the Central Emergency Response Fund Reserve allocation policy, process and standards and will improve the living standard of those targeted with the intervention in question as their need for Shelter and NFIs will have been addressed, maintained or increased hence minimizing incidences of water borne diseases. The mode of delivery of this project is through requisition of the Shelter and NFIs from the core pipeline (IOM) in Juba and Rumbek Town respectively. The items will be prepositioned in the target locations before actual distribution is finally conducted to the beneficiaries. The identification and registration of beneficiaries will be done using NFIs/Cluster approved methodology and will involve community participation through participatorily selected of AAP committee and trained enumerators comprising of male and female. The approved quantities of these items will be transported by heavy and light Trucks to Rumbek Center and Rumbek East storage facilities before they are transported for distribution points in Bomas and Villages. TF will work in close partnership and collaboration with the ESNFIs Sub-Cluster and Partner Organizations on ground (International, National, and Community Based Organizations), Beneficiaries, Community Leaders, Chiefs, Youth and Women Leaders, elderly and People with special needs (PSN)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TITI Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TITI Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-SHL-160846-2" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLORIA MODONG</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0921704553</telephone>
   <email>somagloriah@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BENNET KENYI</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROGRAM MANAGER</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0924176987</telephone>
   <email>kenyibennet@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">suzanne liyong</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FINANCE MANAGER</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0921704546</telephone>
   <email>somaliyong331@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lakes</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.60307990 29.97405340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-07">69872.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-07">236884.7</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-17638">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-07">306757.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TITI Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304828162">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">184054.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TITI Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
