<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-pakistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="1" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-09T02:07:23.89" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-28T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/FS/INGO/17133</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preserve the ability of people vulnerable to pandemics and disasters (Natural/Manmade) to meet their food consumptions and other basic needs through productive activities and access to other humanitarian assistance in district Washuk Balochistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is proposed for duration of 6 months amp intends to provide support to vulnerable communities of 20 villages in 02 UCs (1. Garang 2. Jangiyan of district Washuk Balochistan. As per WFP Vulnerability Assessment amp Mapping (VAM) study in Dist. Washuk these both Union Councils were prioritized due to higher vulnerability to food insecurity. Muslim hands also conducted a need assessment exercise in same area and assessment findings indicated that these areas are much neglected and need immediate support in terms of food security. The total funding solicited is USD 481275.90 while the contribution of Muslim Hands is USD 47,200. Total beneficiaries families will be 800 through different interventions and 5200 individuals. Proposed project aligns directly with VAM findings and Food Security and Livestock Cluster/ Working Groups enabling them to meet their emergency needs and hence protecting them from related risks of food security. The socioeconomic impacts for these circumstances are vivid on incomes, nutrition and livelihood of the population especially small land holder farmers. The proposed interventions are in response of recent pandemic COVID-19 in Balochistan. Beneficiary families are small land holder farmers, women headed households, poor and needy who lost their income and livelihoods sources.
The proposed project would be executed with close coordination of Food Security and Livelihood (FSL) working group nominated by PDMA, local administration, agriculture, livestock and health department at district level as well as provincial level, which would complement their efforts and services. Assuming health amp wellbeing benefits certain behaviors hand washing practices with soap at critical times, utilization of good practices regarding livestock and farming will be measured for reporting. Additionally, MampE will be focused on Improve/install/repair/rehab of existing food security systems to create more durable sources and options at community amp institutional level, improve/increase water storage at community amp HH level, MampE will also focus on set indicators in Log Frame, participatory monitoring amp evaluation through stakeholders i.e. PHED, Local Administration amp village committees from concern community i.e. pre-KAP to post-KAP..

The activities are designed to address any gender disparity and harm full traditional practice, Protection Mainstreaming with the principle of &#x201C;DO No Harm&#x201D;. Proposed project would thus enable to mainstream women and girls protection issues in the light of security, harsh weather, risk and other types of vulnerabilities faced at different time.
Below mentioned are main activities proposed for this project under three major components including agriculture/food security, livestock amp poultry farming.

	Unconditional Food Grant for immediate food provision is being given to 300 highly vulnerable, PWD, Widows and destitute. 
	Cash for Work  (Ground Leveling, Water Ponds Construction, Water channelization through water supply from pond to HH Leveling for agriculture/ Kitchen gardening, Livestock sheds (Construction/ Repair/ refurbishment of animals shed) through this activity 800 beneficiaries are being proposed to facilitate. 
	Rain Water Harvesting structures (Water Ponds) Construction 
	Training on Good agriculture Practices (GAP) is proposed for 200 Farmers 
	Kitchen gardening (Specific to 100 Women)
	Provision of Agriculture Inputs like Seeds, Fertilizers, Agriculture Tool Kits, Fodder seed and fertilizers to 800 beneficiaries
	Training on Livestock Management to 300 vulnerable Household
	Provision of Milky Goats ( 02 Goats to each targeted beneficiaries and in total 600 Goats to 300 beneficiaries
	Total 20 VET workers will be trained, one for one targeted village. 
	Vaccination of animals target is 1200 animals at least in project targeted area. 
	Training on Poultry Management to 150 Households
	Inputs (9 Hens + 1 Cock) along with Cage.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muslim Hands International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muslim Hands International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syed Javid Gillani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director Operations/Advisor International Partnerships</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00923215175974</telephone>
   <email>javid.gillani@pk.mhworldwide.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.32720000 65.89310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-23">267375.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-23">213900.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-17133">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-23">481275.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muslim Hands International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304748877">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">385020.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muslim Hands International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
