<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-jordan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="29" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-10T02:07:29.243" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-30T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR-20/DDA-3560/SA2/Sh./INGO/17533</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Securing Shelter in the Face of COVID-19 for Refugees and Vulnerable Host Community Members in Jordan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secure shelter protects vulnerable households and supports prevention of the spread of COVID-19. Particularly as the number of cases in Jordan grows, the ability to quarantine at home in case of confirmed or potential infection is crucial, as well as the ability to isolate, particularly among populations more susceptible to COVID-19, including older persons or those with underlying health issues. Having secure shelter, which is already a challenge among refugees and vulnerable Jordanians, becomes even more important during a pandemic.


In response, this project aims to secure tenure of shelter and support prevention of COVID-19 among refugee and vulnerable host community women, girls, boys, and men (WGBM) with special needs in Jordan through provision of four-month conditional cash-for-rent assistance.


Upon conducting assessments, IOCC has identified the need for rent assistance among 300 refugee (70%) and vulnerable Jordanian (30%) households in Amman (150 households), Irbid (75 households), and Mafraq (75 households) that include persons with disabilities (PWDs), older persons at risk, and women at risk, as well as those with chronic health issues, who are most threatened by COVID-19 and its impacts in Jordan. The inability of these populations to secure shelter can have compounding negative impacts on their health and future, result in forced movement and potential increased exposure to COVID-19 (i.e. due to eviction), and prevent them from isolating or quarantining as needed and in line with requirements of local authorities.

Building on its assessments, calls to its hotline, referrals received, and coordination with local actors, such as Ministry of Social Development (MoSD), IOCC Field Coordinator and Project Officer will oversee the finalization of beneficiary selection. Project staff will follow up with landlords regarding needed documentation (such as valid lease contracts and other supporting documentation) coordinate the signing of a tripartite agreement between IOCC, the landlord, and the beneficiary and finalize the list for rental payments. In line with the Shelter Working Group Cash-for-Rent Guidelines, rent will be paid directly through landlords. IOCC will provide payments through transfers via a local money exchange company (Alawneh Exchange) with which IOCC has experience providing conditional and unconditional cash transfers during COVID-19. IOCC will cover rent for a four-month period (via two transfers of two months each). 

Provision of cash-for-rent assistance will secure tenancy among vulnerable populations and ensure that eviction is avoided among those most vulnerable and susceptible to COVID-19. Additionally, this assistance will ensure that vulnerable households do not resort to negative coping strategies to make rental payments and also free up beneficiaries&apos; financial resources typically put toward for other needs, such as paying debts, purchasing hygiene items to support COVID-19 prevention efforts, needed medical care, and other important costs. Particularly as livelihoods have been negatively impacted by COVID-19 and prevention efforts in Jordan, this assistance is crucial.

Throughout project implementation, IOCC will ensure regular monitoring of activities and communication with beneficiaries and landlords through IOCC&apos;s Monitoring, Evaluation, Accountability, Learning (MEAL) Officer with oversight and support from the Country Representative. At the conclusion of the project, this will include conducting post-distribution monitoring (PDM) surveys to ensure satisfaction, gather information on the impact of assistance, and ensure that no issues arose during implementation.

IOCC has successfully implemented cash-for-rent activities during the COVID-19 pandemic and has utilized lessons learned and best practices from projects implemented in previous months to inform the design of this proposal.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Orthodox Christian Charities</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Orthodox Christian Charities</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Loren Hyatt</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0790220592</telephone>
   <email>lhyatt@iocc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qasem Al-Ayoubi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Field Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0791578294</telephone>
   <email>qalayoubi@iocc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shereen Al Haddad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0795696718</telephone>
   <email>salhaddad@iocc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Mafraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.19290323 35.69146862</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amman</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.91905968 35.92902353</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Irbid</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.55798676 35.84675724</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-24">42654.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-24">257345.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="JOR73-17533">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-24">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Orthodox Christian Charities</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304812820">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-30">240000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Orthodox Christian Charities</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
