<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="145" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-31T03:08:13" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-08T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/NFI/NGO/16278</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lifesaving emergency and winter support through Cash and GIK distribution for the newly displaced and returnees in NWS.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">the project at hand aims to contribute to the emergency amp winter response by applying a flexible approach that allows Violet to cover the needs in a timely manner and appropriate modality. it aims to help the most vulnerable coping with the displacement amp harsh winter conditions through implementing the following activities
1. &#x650;&#x650;Addressing the needs of 3166 HHs for essential NFIs by the distribution of new arrival kits and/or cash for NFIs (120$). the new arrival kit was designed based on the SNFI cluster guidance and cash amount was designed based on the SMEB


2. provision One-off winter cash (180$) provision for 3000 HHs. The winterization cash amount was designed based on the SNFI cluster guidance but also based on the lessons learned from previous projects to cover heating fuel needs of 5-members HH (4 liters of fuel/day) for 60 days in the winter.  while designing the cash amount, Violet took considered the fuel price differences between winter and summer ( according to REACH,  average fuel price in the last winter was 0.75 USD, while the average price in summer is 0.45 USD). The cash value was discussed with CWG and SNFI. However, Violet will adopt the SNFI and CWG recommendations in case of any change. winterization cash will also contribute to mitigating the risk of storing fuel for a long time by BNF. Additionally, based on the WASH cluster recommendations, each BNF HH will receive 750 g of soap sufficient for 1 month to contribute to COVID-19 response


Cash modality was selected to allow BNFs to secure their needs in a dignified and flexible way. Moreover, it contributes to market recovery through disposing of cash in the market and may create new job opportunities
the project will focus on the newly IDPs in the areas that have been identified with the highest needs, and hosting newly IDPs who fled their homes as a result of GOS offensive, but also the returnees and IDPs who returned to their original communities, or communities of displacement. moreover, winter cash support will be implemented in the areas with a high percentage of damaged shelters like Sarmin, Ariha amp Atareb (According to HNAP report for April 2020) since the IDPs and returnees who living in damaged buildings are the most vulnerable and not protected against the harsh winter conditions.
both groups will be targeted as they are the most vulnerable groups to the shocks. BNFs will be nominated by the community representatives based on the selection criteria including displacement and returning duration taking into account prioritizing women-headed HHs, HHs with children, elderlies, PWD, pregnant, and lactating women
Violet will ensure close coordination with the other actors and SNFI/ CCCM clusters to ensure the coordinated response and to avoid potential overlapping. it also confirms its readiness to immediately start the implementation as soon as the SGA is signed since it is in the final stage of contracting with the new arrival kits supplier, and also has FWA for MTA services and transportation, which will be utilized under this project. The contractors and MTA have been identified through competitive bidding process based on their experience, accessibility, and financial offer.
While the NFI kits and cash coupons will be distributed by Violet teams, the MTA will be responsible for redeeming the BNFs coupons. Before cash distribution, RNA, and market assessment in terms of availability of the NFIs, their prices, and the accessibility will be conducted to ensure the markets are functioning and all BNFs have good and equal access markets. 
In order to ensure the selection criteria are respected and to avoid terrorism financing, fraud, and Forgery, cash coupons will be equipped with light thermal stickers. Moreover,  the verification and antiterrorism check (ATC) will be conducted for all cash BNFs
Finally, Violet will ensure the COVID-19 preventive measures, accountability and SEA mitigation measures are applied.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-SHL-164305-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">1093536.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">627438.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16278">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">1720975.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304667977">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">714630.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
