<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-jordan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="18" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-23T02:06:44.653" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-22T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR-20/DDA-3560/SA1/WASH/INGO/16303</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 WaSH Response for Vulnerable Refugees in Zarqa Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the onset of the novel coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic, access to necessary cleaning and personal hygiene items has become even more critical for vulnerable populations. Syrian refugees in Jordan in particular often live in overcrowded and unsanitary conditions, with already depleted financial resources for basic purchases. Given that COVID-19 can be easily transmitted in crowded places and that the virus can live on surfaces for hours, days, or potentially weeks in some cases, it is important that vulnerable populations have the proper access to resources to protect themselves from virus transmission risks. Refugees living in Azraq Camp, the Emirati Jordanian Refugee Camp, and nearby Informal Tented Settlements (ITSs) have been underserved in recent months, with minimal or no hygiene or cleaning kit distributions. Given the precarious economic situation of these populations, especially after governmental restrictions on movements and economic activities, they are less likely to prioritize hygiene and cleaning items over other basic necessities. Additionally, refugees in Azraq Camp and some ITSs use communal water distribution points, requiring multiple trips to carry water back to their shelters. Often these water collection jugs are small, broken, and/or dirty, requiring extra trips and potentially contaminating the water. As women are often more responsible for water collection and care giving duties, this can cause an extra burden and exposure risks for women to the water collection point and in using the communal latrines themselves and to help children or elderly family members. This project therefore aims to support vulnerable Syrian refugee men, women, boys, and girls living in Azraq Refugee Camp, the Emirati Jordanian Refugee Camp, and ITSs in Zarqa Governorate with critical water, sanitation, and hygiene (WaSH) support in response to COVID-19 in Jordan. An estimated total of 8,492 men, 8,778 women, 12,970 boys, and 12,260 girls will benefit from the project across all targeted locations. Action Against Hunger will utilize its well established experience leading in WaSH support in Azraq Camp while expanding to nearby areas (ITSs and the Emirati Jordanian Refugee Camp) also in need of receiving these critical items. Specifically, this project will aim to improve access to hygiene and cleaning supplies, water containers, and hygiene promotion messaging to mitigate the risk of COVID-19 transmission for Syrian refugees living in the aforementioned areas, while considering the different needs and roles of men, women, boys, and girls. This will be completed through the distribution of standardized hygiene and latrine cleaning kits, clean and secure water containers, and contextualized hygiene promotion and awareness raising messaging. Hygiene promotion messaging will utilize a variety of modalities, including WhatsApp messaging, phone calls, SMS, and the distribution if Information, Education, and Communication (IEC) materials to ensure individuals have access to key hygiene behaviors to complement the distribution of hygiene and cleaning items. Action Against Hunger will ensure that the implementation of all activities promotes the &quot;do no harm&quot; principle and considers the different needs, wants, and abilities of the beneficiaries to promote equal access for men, women, boys, and girls. Feedback will be solicited, analyzed, and considered throughout all stages of implementation through various channels, such as Action Against Hunger&apos;s established Feedback and Complaints Mechanism (FCM) hotline and through all community mobilization interactions to promote accountability to the affected populations, and different communication channels will be utilized to increase accessibility for men and women. Post distribution monitoring will also allow beneficiaries to provide feedback on the implementation of activities and ensure Action Against Hunger can measure the impact of the project against the project indicators.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la faim</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la faim</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wouter Schaap</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962 (0) 778 304 474</telephone>
   <email>cd@jo-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andrea Bigio</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 962 (0) 778 465 150</telephone>
   <email>dcdprograms@jo-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Naddaf</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Finance Head of Department</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 962 (0) 778 465 129</telephone>
   <email>financedhod@jo-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zarqa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.07577806 36.08100277</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-16">244421.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-16">105578.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="JOR73-16303">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-16">350000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la faim</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304676190">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-22">280000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la faim</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
