<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-nigeria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="38" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-08T02:04:56.25" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-19T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-20/NIG_ERF/SA1/P/UN/17525</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mine action in assistance of victims and survivors of explosive incidents and mass media campaign for explosive ordnance risk education (EORE) in Borno State,
northeast Nigeria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNMAS Nigeria is a programme implemented by the United Nations Office for Project Service (UNOPS) in accordance with the Financial Regulations and Rules of UNOPS, under overall oversight and strategic direction of UNMAS. 
This project spans for twelve months and focuses on the assistance of victims and survivors of explosive incidents through survey, mapping and establishment of a referral mechanism,  and on a mass media campaign to effectively spread  EORE messages.

This project is in line with the NHF Allocation Strategy, Humanitarian Response Strategy 2019-2021 and Country Programme Strategy of UNMAS Nigeria 2020-2021, and centres on two pillars of Humanitarian Mine Action: Victim Assistance and Risk Education. Proposed interventions in support of these pillars are outlined below.
1.The survey, mapping and establishment of a referral mechanism for victims of explosive incidents.

This project will support the survey and mapping of explosive incidents, as well as victims and survivors of those incidents, including their families and communities. By conducting survey and mapping, mine action partners will be able to identify the situation, challenges and needs of victims and survivors, including physical challenges and mental stigmas, disseminated by gender, age and locations, which will enable the design of a functional referral mechanism, facilitating effective support for victims and survivors and strengthening inclusiveness of the humanitarian response to the most vulnerable. 
This project will also support the design and establishment of a referral mechanism, with particular attention to needs of women and girls, through which victims and survivors can access immediate and long term medical and socioeconomic support, and through which UN, international and local partners can report, record and coordinate protection for victims and survivors of explosive incidents. Such a referral mechanism will enable well-coordinated, effective and efficient protection assistance as well as allow for a holistic and integrated multi-sector approach to affected populations.
UNOPS will partner with existing medical, protection and community support capacities of UN, international and local organizations and train them for the survey of victims and survivors of explosive incidents. Training will emphasize the importance of ensuring collection of all necessary information on the number of victims, gender, age, type of explosive, location, the situation in which the incident happened, as well as existing support for the victims, including medical, healthcare and socioeconomic support. A victim assistance expert will be hired to coordinate and oversee the collection of information and data, conduct analysis and identify the gaps and challenges in assistance of victims of explosive incidents, and design an efficient referral mechanism,  which will be available to those who suffered injuries or impairments from other causes.
2.Mass media campaign to deliver EORE messages to develop knowledge and awareness of the risks of explosives, and preventive behaviour amongst the communities. 
This project will launch a mass media campaign using mobile talking devices to deliver life-saving EORE messages amongst refugees, internally displaced persons (IDPs), returnees and host communities raising their awareness, fostering safe behaviour to mitigate the threat of landmines and explosives, and enabling safe movement and socio-economic activities.
Use of mobile talking devices will facilitate reaching hard-to-access areas and at-risk populations to deliver messages to develop life-saving knowledge and behaviour. As the threats of mines and explosives are imminent in northeast Nigeria, this project aims to urgently spread safety messages to the most at-risk populations to those areas in partnership with a local NGO who will distribute the talking devices.
This activity also helps enhance protection amid the COVID-19 situation with less interactions</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Awakens Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tomoko Nakayama</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+13478432700</telephone>
   <email>tomokona@unops.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eloho Jose</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Service Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234 708 035 6424</telephone>
   <email>ElohoJ@unops.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lionel Pechera</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234 816 174 5411</telephone>
   <email>lionelp@unops.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG002">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adamawa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.32322733 12.40024078</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="NG036">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yobe</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.29868022 11.43706584</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-13">149168.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-17525">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-13">149168.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304883352">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-19">149168.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
