<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="87" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-17T02:06:45.313" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-15T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA6/FSAC/INGO/17771</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Assistance for 2486 Vulnerable Households in Daykundi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the November 2020 IPC Acute Food Insecurity Analysis, 284,077 people in Daykundi, 55% of the population, will be in IPC Phase 3 and 4 and will experience acute food insecurity through the winter season. The Covid-19 pandemic has led to widespread illness and mortality, a deep economic recession, and starkly reduced income opportunities in the province, which in turn has depleted productive assets and reduced communities&#x2019; capacity to cope with the long lean season, which lasts through May. Afghanaid&#x2019;s recent needs assessment (Annex A) found that the vast majority of households in Daykundi province are unable to cover their basic needs and require urgent assistance, with virtually all households surveyed (98%) citing food assistance as one of their most important needs. 


In line with FSAC priorities detailed in the Joint Winterization Strategy and the cluster&#x2019;s specific priorities for this allocation, Afghanaid proposes to provide crucial food assistance to 2486 vulnerable households in Sang-e Takht and Khedir districts of Daykundi, both of which are prioritized by the cluster under this allocation. Based on communities&#x2019; preference for cash transfers and a recent market assessment (Annex B) confirming market access and the local availability and affordability of standard food items, Afghanaid proposes cash as the modality for the assistance. 


As per cluster priorities for this allocation, the intervention will provide 1286 households in Sang-e Takht and 1200 households in Khedir district with 4 standard half rations for a total of US$180 per household. The proposed food assistance will complement a separate, ESNFI-funded response in Daykundi and Samangan through which Afghanaid will provide 500 of the same households in Sang-e Takht and 500 of the same households in Khedir with standard 4-month heating packages of US$260 per household, and 359 of these households will also receive an in-kind blanket package. This ensures that the most vulnerable households&#x2019; multiple needs are met in these areas of great need, and the complementarity of these responses helps reduce the incentive to sell-off winterization assistance to cover food consumption needs, in line with cluster priorities as detailed in the Joint Winterization Strategy.

Afghanaid will establish participant selection and distribution committees including representatives from local communities (e.g. CDC and DDA heads), government (e.g. ANDMA and DoRR) and Afghanaid. Participants will be selected according to FSAC vulnerability criteria to ensure the most acutely in need are targeted, including IDPs, women-headed households and households with a large number of dependent children.

To ensure a cost effective and rapid response, the project team will work with a reliable saraf in each district to distribute the cash for food from central distribution points in two tranches of US$90 each. Participants with limited mobility will be brought to the distribution point or receive the assistance at home. 

Afghanaid is well placed to implement this project, with several years of presence in Daykundi, current operations in the target districts and excellent access and strong relationships with communities as well as district and provincial authorities. Afghanaid has extensive experience in humanitarian programming, with current and recent humanitarian assistance projects in multiple provinces including Daykundi, funded by AHF, WFP, FAO, and ECHO. The projects include emergency food, livelihoods, winterization, and shelter assistance, using both in-kind and cash modalities.

This intervention will provide 17,400 vulnerable men, women, boys and girls with crucial food assistance, reducing illness and mortality as a result of food shortages and increasing the participants&#x2019; capacity to rebuild their livelihoods by avoiding the sale of productive assets, so that they are more resilient against future shocks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Johannes Jansen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93728630493</telephone>
   <email>jjansen@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Najibullah Namiq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants and Partnership Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799733944</telephone>
   <email>najeebullah@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ayub Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director of Finance amp; Administration</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93790897166</telephone>
   <email>akhan@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zodiac Maslin-Hahn</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Programme Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+442035596647</telephone>
   <email>zmhahn@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daykundi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.66949500 66.04635340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-06"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">110005.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">550027.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-17771">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">660033.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304835620">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-15">528026.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
