<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="61" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-23T03:06:47.26" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-19T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/WASH-CCM/NGO/17900</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of integrated minimum WASH package services  for IDPs and most vulnerable host communities  under parameter 1  2 at Alhusha  Qa&apos;atabah districts of Aldhalee Gov. Marib City district  of Marib Gov. and CCCM supportive interventions at Aldhehar, Dhi-Sufal of Ibb Gov, Maqbanah, Mawyah, Samee, Altaizziah and Dumnat Khadeer districts of Taiz Gov.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In line with 2020 SA1 strategy objectives amp cluster objectives, this project aims to provide comprehensive WASH and CCCM assistance to estimated 83,069 IDPs in sites, host communities amp most vulnerable affected individuals (19936 men, 21598 women,19106, boys, 22429 girls) from the most vulnerable groups with focus on IDPs in sites and most affected communities hosting IDPs to respond to the humanitarian needs in WASH,CCCM sectors in  HTR , high priority areas Taiz,Al-Dhale,Ibb,amp Marib Gov. 
WASH interventions will be providing a comprehensive response to 23255 IDPs in sites , within host communities  and 35,686 most vulnerable host communities in 3  districts covering 1st line response for newly amp most affected IDPs amp Host communities with focus  on covering critical WASH gaps within 1st  and   2nd line response to improve wash conditions amp reduce risk of WASH related disease , malnutrition , improving conditions for IDPs , vulnerable host communities ,ensuring the durability of basic WASH services.   
The WASH interventions will be provided to conflict- affected beneficiaries to improve their access WASH services through:
Rehabilitation/repair of 5 community water assets ampprovision of operational support for 3 water system in Qatabah district.
Provision of emergency water trucking for IDPs in sites, in Qatabah, district 
Distributing 9000 CHKs,3000BHKs for malnutrition cases supported by UNICEF.  
Conduct water quality surveillance.
Conducting Solid waste management and disposal in 1 district
Construction of 40 latrines in Al-Husha amp Qatabah district amp Emptying /desludging 130 full or overflowing cesspits, septic tanks in IDPs collective sites in Marib City amp Qatabah. 
Covering 80 open cesspits in Qatabah 
Conducting Hygiene awareness sessions in the 3 targeted districts.
The CCCM intervention aims to address lifesaving needs amp support the improvement of living conditions and access to essential basic services for (IDPs) living in settlements and advocating for gaps with the cluster, other related INGOs ampNGOs targeting 1447 HH located in 16 sites/29 sub-site. Ensure continuation of essential coordination of the previous partners namely AOBWC, IYCY, TYF amp YWU with established proper coordination with them to facilitate the handover process amp ensuring the involving of the established community community&#x2019;s participation, duty bearers and other service providers and service delivery. 
The targeted districts are located within Ibb and Sana&#x2019;a Hubs where YFCA has its two main sub-offices to carry out the main implementation task with backstopping support from the main office in Sana&#x2019;a. Coordination with WASH, Shelter/CCCM clusters, RRM, GARWASP, Local authorities is already done to facilitate the planned interventions amp to avoid any duplication. 
The potential risks that might face YFCA while implementing the activities include the delay in signing the SA for districts under Ibb Hub amp IDPs influx in Taiz amp Marib, security deterioration, airstrikes, prices fluctuation, supplies shortage in the local market, outbreaks of diseases especially Cholera and COVID-19 resulting in lockdown and the delay in handing over of the sites.
These risks can be mitigated through close amp early coordination with sites&apos; current partners, stakeholders authorities in both sides, obtaining de-confliction for sites, contracting with suppliers for the whole project to avoid prices fluctuation, amp coordinating with health cluster amp on ground actors regarding the spread of diseases: cholera, COVID-19 amp hiring local staff. A close coordination with local authorities, IOM, RRM partners, both WASH amp CCCM clusters and to joint response forces for IDS influx especially in Marib. close coordination with SCAMCHA to obtain the permission and get the SA signed within the first 3 months of the project.  
YFCA will monitor the project activities to ensure effective implementation, accountability towards affected people, stakeholders amp donor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nabil Mohammed Alammari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>774090200</telephone>
   <email>n.alammari@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Dhale&apos;e</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.85996808 44.67423913</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.05521633 44.26319019</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="73" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="1" percentage="27" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">922984.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">50831.04</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17900">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">973815.77</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304915933">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-19">389526.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
