<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="32" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-06T03:07:05.557" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-09T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA1/NFI/ES/INGO/15984</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter/NFI and COVID-19 integrated response for IDPs/returnees in Guchi, Moyale (Oromia), and Wachile Woredas of Borena Zone, Oromia Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The negative impact of recurring climate conditions, conflict, overcrowded shelters, limited or no household items, lack of privacy, and sub-standard living conditions continue to expose displaced and returned populations to multiple protection risks. The situation is further exacerbated by insecurity as well as limited funding. According 2020 Ethiopia Federal Government COVID-19 National Emergency Response Plan, the Shelter and Non-Food Items (S/NFI) Cluster in Ethiopia strives to improve the living condition of vulnerable conflict- and climate-affected vulnerable populations through the provision of life-saving emergency shelter and non-food items (NFIs). The Cluster seeks to coordinate appropriate services to displaced, host, and returnee populations living under substandard shelter situations. As COVID-19 continues to spread in an unpredictable manner it presents a growing risk to partners and beneficiaries, particularly during distributions. The COVID -19 virus could see a rapid transmission in IDP collective sites, formal sites, and informal sites due to overcrowding and lack of essential hygiene facilities and items.  
The Ethiopia Displacement Tracking Matrix (DTM) Round 21 report indicates that there are 1,735,481 IDPs across 1,237 sites in Ethiopia. These IDPs are in 310 woredas across Afar, Amhara, Benishangul Gumuz, Dire Dawa, Harari, Gambella Oromia, Somali and Tigray regions.  According to the ES/NFI Cluster, 55 woredas in Somali, Benishangul-Gumuz, Afar, and Oromia regions host climate-induced and conflict-affected IDPs are categorized as Priority 1 for Emergency Shelter and NFI responses.

Accordingly, in Borena zone, Oromia region, three woredas Guchi, Moyale, and Wachile identified as Priority 1 for both the IDP and COVID-19 responses. The prioritization of Shelter and NFI needs of March 2020 report indicates, there are 60,413 IDPs in Guchi, 41,394 in Moyale and 13,874 in Wachile. To respond to the need of IDPs and returnees, CRS will target 3,224 households(HHs), 17,732 individuals, in the three woredas. The type of response will be tailored to IDP living conditions. It consists of provision of in-kind emergency shelter(ES) and, a mix of in-kind and cash for ES repair kits, and Core Relief items such as bedding set, kitchen set, and hygiene set. In addition to distributing essential materials, the project will provide community sensitization on COVID-19 and best use of the items.


The project will target a total of 3,224 HHs in Moyale, Guchi and Wachile woredas of Borena zone, Oromia Region. In Moyale woreda Goro Soda site 1,450HHs  in collective center will receive core relief items. In Guchie woreda Saden Gofa site 1,260HHs in spontaneous camp/site will receive ES kits (700 HHs) and Core Relief items (560 HHs). In Wachile woreda 514 returnee HHs will receive shelter repair kits.  A total of 2,010 HHs will receive a mix of in-kind and/or cash for Core Relief item with an average rate of $89/HH 514HHs receive a mix of in-kind and/or cash for ES repair kits with an average cost of $250/HH. While 700HHs will receive in-kind ES kit with an average cost of $100/HH by ECC-SDCOHa. Before determining the response modalities, CRS will conduct market assessment in each woredas and consult communities to understand preferences. 
If Cash is feasible and going to be distributed to beneficiaries, CRS will use Cash and Asset Transfer (CAT) platform for beneficiary registration and distribution. To enable HHs purchase the items, CRS will deal with vendors to bring the market close to the beneficiaries and provide them orientation on code of conduct.The CAT Platform is CRS&apos; Information and Communication Technology for Development (ICT4D) software for managing beneficiary data and multiple asset transfer modalities. CAT offers an online platform with a cloud-based database and Android applications that can be used for both data collection and the implementation of cash or voucher disbursements and e-voucher transactions</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biruk Tesfaye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency and DRR Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-911-718450</telephone>
   <email>Biruk.tesfaye@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-02">353105.67</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-02">131968.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-15984">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-02">485074.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304666100">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-09">388059.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
