<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="19" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-24T02:05:22.58" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-09T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/Prot/NGO/17290</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening and sustaining integrated protection services for the flood affected IDPs through prevention and response to gender-based violence (GBV), and mitigation of child protection risks (including abuse, neglect, violence, exploitation, and severe distress) as well as family tracing for those separated from families in Lower Shabelle region (Afgoye and Marka)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is designed to provide immediate lifesaving services and risk mitigation to GBV survivors and vulnerable women and girls in the IDPs and host communities affected by floods in Afgoye district through the following interventions: - Provision of Clinical Care for Sexual Assault survivors (CCSAS), Case management (CM) Psycho social support (PSS), tailored material support including emergency support for safe spaces, tailored material support and dignity kits to survivors of GBV and extremely vulnerable women affected by the floods. Addition, SOYDA will provide transport cost to GBV survivors to facilitate access to post exposure prophylaxis in different health facilities.
SOYDA will provide Clinical Management of rape services to GBV survivors as well as training 20 health staff on CMR in order to improve their skills of provide competent, confidential and compassionate clinical care services. PEP kits will be received from UNFPA upon submission of the request and will be facilitated by the MoH to different MCHs in Afgoye. SOYDA will consider the needs of women, girls, boys and men separately and focus on identifying gaps and trends to improve programming and identify the protection risks, analyses and develop action plans to reduce the risk and prevent the GBV and other protection issues in the community. Jointly with the protection monitoring activities, the key focus of the project will be providing Case management services to GBV survivors. Strengthen and improve the protective environment of vulnerable people in areas affected by flood from further risks of exclusion, exploitation and violence. SOYDA will mobilize 20 PSS counselors to deliver one on one and group psychosocial support and counselling for traumatized women and girls in the IDP camps. The counselors together with community mobilizers will sensitize the community and provide basic psychological support to the GBV survivors, to early or forced marriage and vulnerable girls. 


On the child protection aspects, The proposed project is designed respond to child protection needs by addressing multiple protection risks faced by girls and boys through a comprehensive set of activities in well-coordinated and gender-sensitive approach by supporting children at risk and survivors including unaccompanied or separated children through case management services that meets their unique needs, as well as preparedness measures for speedy family tracing and reunification (including psycho-social support). The project will also work with volunteers to prevent and mitigate risks to children by building their capacity on rights approach of whom support identification and basic support to vulnerable children (including psycho-social first aid - PFA). SOYDA will also work with caregivers on positive parenting as well as provide psycho-social support to vulnerable caregivers affected by floods and made worst by the pre-existing emergencies related to conflict in Somalia as well as COVID-19. Additionally, the project will engage with the community on protection awareness raising on prevention messages on recruitment/or use of children by armed actors, gender-based violence, harmful practice, family separation and risk of dangers in the community (including in IDP camps or the local community) while coordinating with the CP AoR in service mapping operation of the standardized thematic tools and procedures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Young Doctors Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Young Doctors Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr Mariam Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615881993</telephone>
   <email>somyoungdoctors@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">159103.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">240865.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17290">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">399969.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Young Doctors Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304783710">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-09">319975.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Young Doctors Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
