<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-sudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="69" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-05T03:06:19.503" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-12T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/SA1/H-N/INGO/16498</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Health and Nutrition Project for vulnerable populations in Gedaref State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020, approximately 9.3 million people across Sudan are anticipated to be in need of humanitarian support. Of these, a significant proportion (approximately 1.5 million) live in Sudan&#x2019;s Eastern states, including Gedaref. The number of people in need is expected to rise significantly in the coming months as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic. 


Mercy Corps and our local implementing partner, Green Peace, will work with local government authorities, including State Ministry of Health (SMoH) and Humanitarian Aid Commission (HAC), UN partners including the World Health Organization (WHO), UNFPA UNICEF, WFP, (I)NGOs and communities to provide important support and peripheral services to four primary healthcare centers (PHCC) in the East El Galabat locality of Gederaf State. The program will aim to support the SMoH to increase the availability of, and access to, the life-saving primary health care services the health centers provide. We will also support the SMoH to improve the availability of quality preventative and curative nutrition services at these PHCCs. These interventions will be supported by awareness-raising activities and promotion of healthy behaviors within the target communities.  


The proposed project will strengthen integrated health and nutrition services in four PHCCs at Alsaraf, Rashid, Gireeb and Mahala. Mercy Corps, in collaboration with the SMoH, WHO, UNICEF, UNFPA and WFP, will support public healthcare providers in delivering a standard minimum package of primary health services, including outdoor management of common communicable and non-communicable diseases, maternal and child health, reproductive health, and immunization. All activities will be carried-out in line with COVID-19 specific guidance provided by SMoH and WHO. We will support the local referral system by providing PHCCs with transportation options and will help to strengthen the existing surveillance system and disease outbreak control efforts by providing communication equipment (mobile phones with air time and tablets) and supplies where required.

The project will also support integrated nutrition services to contribute to the reduction in nutrition-related morbidity and mortality among children under five and pregnant and lactating women. Our nutrition interventions will focus on community-based management of acute malnutrition (CMAM), including support for outpatient SAM and MAM treatment (OTP/TSFP) in four PHCCs, as well as screening and multi-level referrals 
(community/PHCC/Stabilization Centre/Isolation Centre). This will be done while ensuring strict compliance with the latest national guidelines on CMAM during the COVID-19 pandemic at all times. Our approach to IYCF will similarly be in-line with national guidelines on IYCF programming during COVID-19 and informed by the evolving situation on the ground throughout the year. Current guidelines recommend adapting the size and frequency of Mother Support Group meetings and maintaining distance between participants. We will also train lead mothers and community nutrition volunteers to communicate SMoH-approved key messages on improved hygiene, physical distancing and proper nutrition, to support the screening and referral of PLWs and acutely malnourished children (whether through family led MUAC or via enhanced safety and hygiene measures), and to provide individualized support and where necessary referrals for mother-child pairs experiencing feeding problems.

Mercy Corps will draw on its extensive experience of implementing nutrition programs in Sudan in South Darfur State and health programs in several countries, including Pakistan, Tajikistan and Indonesia. In addition, Mercy Corps will rely on its past experience working in Gedaref, as well as on the experience of Green Peace who is currently working in several localities within th</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps Europe (formerly Mercy Corps Scotland)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps Europe (formerly Mercy Corps Scotland)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Peace</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arif Noor</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249 91 216 8042</telephone>
   <email>anoor@mercycorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedaref</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.03333300 35.38333300</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="57.5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="42.5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-30">423669.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-30">850840.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-16498">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-30">1274510.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps Europe (formerly Mercy Corps Scotland)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304790093">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-12">705000.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps Europe (formerly Mercy Corps Scotland)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
