<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-nigeria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="6" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-25T02:06:55.343" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-10-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-20/NIG_ERF/SA1/DMS-P/INGO/16632</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-sector lifesaving response for conflict-affected populations in Borno and Adamawa State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project seeks to increase access to legal and civil documentation (LCD) in Monguno, Mobbar, Konduga, Gwoza, Yola North and Biu Local Government Areas (LGAs) by providing information, counselling and legal assistance (ICLA), and by strengthening the capacities of relevant government registration bodies to protect rights of their respective communities. NRC will provide information on LCD rights to 3,000 beneficiaries, through group sessions with 10-15 individuals within the communities. Counselling will be provided to beneficiaries from the information sessions that self-identify as needing further support. Legal assistance to obtain LCD (ID slips and birth certificates) will be provided through the provision of logistical support to National Information Management Commission (NIMC) and National Population Commission (NPC). NIMC currently operates in Maiduguri and Yola, however, NRC is advocating to support their expansion to other LGAs through a mobile modality. NPC currently operates through a mobile modality, traveling to the communities to provide birth certificates and operates in all areas that this project will cover. COVID-19 considerations will be integrated through the response, with group activities limited to sizes of 10-15 people, and the issues of stigmatisation raised during the information sessions. All activities will be implemented in-line with NRC&#x2019;s Temporary Distribution guidance (Annex 1. By improving access to LCD, NRC contributes to the sector response by enhancing the protection environment for internally displaced persons (IDPs), returnees and host communities and recovery in Northeast Nigeria. NRC&#x2019;s current strategy is to become more responsive to displacement and COVID-19 needs and provide services that support initiatives to build community resilience. In particular, a secure legal identity is a pivotal right for socio-economic development it is a guarantee for exercising fundamental rights such as freedom of movement and access to basic services, and reduces exposure to other risks like harassment and extortion.
In Maiduguri, NRC is currently providing a mobile site management response in 38 sites (36 informal and 2 formal), which NRC is proposing to continue, while also expanding to an additional 12 informal sites. Furthermore, NRC proposes to provide 12 out-of-camp settings with NRC&#x2019;s Urban Displacement and Out of Camp (UDOC) response. 

For the expansion of the mobile site management response, NRC will ensure a continuous focus on increasing provision of services through enhanced coordination of partners in those sites that are currently facing significant gaps. NRC will particularly ensure that these sites are being covered by health and WASH services, with regards to COVID-19 preparedness and response plans, and will advocate and coordinate with the relevant actors accordingly. The response will also aim at supporting community engagement and governance structures, in order to increase the meaningful participation of all community groups in decision making. Specific care and maintenance activities will also be undertaken to guarantee that site facilities and infrastructures are functional and safe. 
In accordance to the DMS/CCCM sector strategy, NRC also proposes to establish a community center to address out&#x2013;of-camp displacement gaps through an area-based approach, using the UDOC response. The community center will be a platform where beneficiaries living out-camp would be able to receive services and to be referred to service providers. NRC will also respond with a mobile outreach team that will deploy in the different settlements to conduct awareness campaigns, referrals, collect and receive feedback. NRC will particularly focus in building preparedness to prevent the spread of COVID-19 in those sites where very little or no support has been provided. 

The start date of 1 November 2020 has been set to ensure there is no double funding of NRC&#x2019;s CCCM activities by NHF.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HNGA20-CCM-161872-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jennifer Ismail</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348025576373</telephone>
   <email>jennifer.ismail@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridgette Lane</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234 9024340826</telephone>
   <email>bridgette.lane@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG002">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adamawa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.32322733 12.40024078</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="27" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="73" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HNGA20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-12">74052.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-12">375197.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-16632">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-12">449250</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304763226">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-14">269550</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
