<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="47" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-28T02:05:09.853" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA2FT/HNC/NGO/17331</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Response Jerusalem- primary health continuation and scale-up of communication and awareness within the communities.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Jerusalem, in particular, has been facing many challenges in recent months. These pressures have reached unprecedented levels since the outbreak of COVID-19 earlier in March. An already fragile economy in both the West Bank has fallen further since the pandemic and is forecast by the world bank to need more than 10 years to start its recovery. Poverty and unemployment are at an all-time high, with more than 60% of households living under the poverty line and unemployment reaching more than 60%. 


In East Jerusalem, many families are facing additional pressures as a result of further land annexation with many losing their homes and living under constant stress and exposure to violence. In addition to the pressures to the health sector with the reality of a COVID-19 outbreak in the world&#x2019;s most densely populated area with inequitable access to basic necessities such as electricity and inadequate access to clean/safe water. Again in areas such as EJ due to geographical restrictions imposed on them by the IOF,  Palestinians do not have access to emergency or primary healthcare, safe/clean water sources or reliable electricity. All of these factors further compound the risk of COVID-19 spread, the impact on the communities health and the health of the local economy. Furthermore, in EJ due to their unique position they are caught between two worlds, whereby it is often difficult for them to access healthcare, technically not under PA and neglected by the Israeli authorities. Their unique closed off geographical position only further exacerbated the existing inequities. 


Across the oPT but in particular, due to tensions relating to Jerusalem, the violence in EJ continues to escalate, with home raids carried out by the IOF (usually at night).  There is an increase in mental health complications, including suicide. IOF imposes Restrictions to movement prevent people from being able to access essential healthcare or support and due to the lockdown restrictions preventing work and trade, many families cannot afford essential health items like PPE or medication, further adding to the risks faced by those with a chronic non-communicable disease such as diabetes- which left uncontrolled can lead to secondary health issues such as blindness, kidney damage or death. Noting that the leading cause of death in Palestine is non-communicable diseases, which is entirely preventable, it is essential that primary healthcare continues to be a focus as leaving this demographic without continual health education, screening and support would be disastrous. Therefore, most Palestinians are currently extremely vulnerable to the irreversible health, personal and societal damage resulting from uncontrolled COVID-19 spread. 

In addition, there has been a documented rise with organisations noting a 10% increase in calls from women regarding GBV in just the first months. As the pandemic crisis continues and the mounting pressures of Palestinian family units only increase and become more entrenched women become further vulnerable demographics. 

The project aims to address the inequities and gaps, whilst manning access to equitable healthcare, concurrently, scaling up COVID-19 care via the distribution of PPE and hygiene kits in addition to education and communication with the public regarding their role and responsibility in flattening the curve. In addition to a scale up of services to tend to those with positive cases of COVID-19/or those in isolation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bahia Amra</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of projects and donor relations</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972598886944</telephone>
   <email>bahiaamra@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-06">73739.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-06">141532.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-17331">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-06">215271.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304792781">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-13">215271.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
