<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="22" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-02T03:06:24.59" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-28T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA1/H-N-WASH/INGO/16015</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Emergency Health Nutrition and WaSH response to conflict affected IDPs, returnees, and host communities in Oromia Region, Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project planned to respond to the Health, Nutrition and WaSH needs of IDP, returnees, and host communities in Oromia who have been affected by conflict, Acute food insecurity and the COVID-19 pandemic. Drought, shortage of clean water and occurrence of other emergencies such as Deseret locust infection (DLI) in the proposed woredas has led to emergence of multiple public health concerns such as outbreak of human disease epidemics(measles, Cholera, scabies), undernutrition and other health problems. The proposed areas of intervention hosted significant number of displaced people (IDPs and returnees) while the existing primary health care services are downing because of multiple factors such as tribal conflict, insecurity, shortage of resources, and emergence of the COVID-19 pandemic. This situation has been raising the need for humanitarian response intervention primarily Health, Nutrition and WaSH. The government of Ethiopia in coordination with UN agencies and INGOs has been providing support. Yet, the support is far less than the need and the strain of local resources and health service provision continue to exist because of the influx of IDPs and returnees among other factors (DLI). CARE has conducted need based prioritization considering WASH, Health and nutrition sectors among affected communities in East and West Hararghe zone and the targeted woredas are among the top priority woredas, which needs integrated response.


CARE proposes an integrated Health, Nutrition and WaSH- project to respond to the pressing needs of IDPs, returnees, and host community in Doba, Gumbi bordodie, Miesso and Gorogutu of west and East Hararghe zones. Doba, Gumbi bordodie, and Miesso are ongoing with nutrition. Hence, this proposal entails health and WaSH for the three woredas and Health and Nutrition for Goro gutu of East Hararghe. The proposed woredas of intervention are among the woredas with the highest SAM case load (admitting over 100 per month on average), all selected for integrated HNW response, and TSF priority. This project identified supper specific activities, that are proved to be beyond the capacity of local government, provide direct support while planning to strengthen the service delivery system to most health facilities through coaching and mentoring. The action emphasize inaccessible sites and organize outreach program where integrated HNW service will be provided to remote seated communities through MHNT. CARE will also focus on building local capacity to consistently deliver Health Nutrition and WaSH services in line with local priorities and the recommendation from HNW technical working group. The health response will focus on strengthening the provision primary health care immunization, consultation and treatment of common illnesses and other maternal and child health services such FP, antenatal consultation and referral. The nutrition response will also support identification and enrollment to treatment of cases with acute malnutrition (SMA and MAM) and the SBCC IYSF-E in particular. The WaSH response will work on creating access to safe water and sanitation facilities and the hygiene and sanitation promotion activities through awareness raising. 
With this action, CARE plans to reach the following beneficiaries: 

9782 IDPs, returnees, and host community will have access to PHC service including consultation and treatment, referral, immunization, and RH services such as ANC, and FP 
385 children under 5 suffering from severe acute malnutrition (through OTP/SC)
5487 Children under five and PLW suffering from MAM 
11200 persons will get COVID-19 prevention and control messages
38,449 people will get access to safe water 
1,200 IDPs will have access to improved latrine facility
3 health facilities (one hospital, 2 health posts) will get access to safe water supply through pipe connection.
50,000 people will get hygiene promotion messaging on hygiene and sanitation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Esther Watts</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Directior</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>251 911 120 731</telephone>
   <email>esther.watts@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elizabeth Milten</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Program Coordinater</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>251 911 237 582</telephone>
   <email>elizabeth.milten@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="27" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="33" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-17">457907.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-16015">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-17">457907.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304676743">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">366325.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
