<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="72" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-17T02:05:33.267" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-24T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA2/H/NGO/16030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operating and management of  two community based isolation centers in Idleb governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the 6-months project at hand, Violet aims to contribute to the joint efforts of the COVID-19 taskforce and preparedness plan through equiping and operating two community-based isolation centers (CBI) in Idleb and Kafer takharim in Idleb governorate with a capacity of 50 beds each to receive and accommodate the suspected/detected cases of COVID-19 in Idleb governorate. Where basically home care may have considered for those presenting with mild illness, hospitalization may not be required unless there is concern about rapid deterioration. However, due to the current overcrowded living condition and potential inefficient housing space for self-isolation in the camps and host communities, this project proposes to operate community-based Isolation, which will contribute to isolate the suspected and confirmed cases and restrict their movement.  The community- based Isolation will be operated by trained health personnel community health workers and IPC workers and other support staff to basic health care services.


The 2 centers will be supported by Violet in coordination with WHO, Health Cluster Task Force and Idleb health directorate and will be receiving the suspected/ detected cases referred by a specialized center with COVID-19. 


The community isolation center CBI will be designed in accordance with WHO guidelines where each center will be equipped with 50 beds allocated for both men and women, and the women section will be operated by female nurses and staff taking into consideration the privacy of female patients. The 50 beds distributed as following:

1. Observation areas with a capacity of 15 beds defined for highly suspected cases/ contact developed symptoms and undergoing laboratory confirmation testing and provision of basic supportive therapy, HE and maintaining premise hand and respiratory hygiene. 
 
2. Isolation and case management areas with a capacity of 30 beds, run by medical (1 MD, 23 nurses per shift) to provide medical assessment and supportive therapy for confirming COVID-19 infection with mild symptoms and without underlying chronic condition  
 
3. Recovery areas capacity of 5 bed run by an on-call doctor and 1 nurse/8hrs shift to provide final assessment and preparation for discharge cases.  

Moreover, Violet will ensure the centers are managed and operated by a sufficient and well-trained medical and non-medical staff to maintain the center and patients sanitized and keep centers clean to prevent the infection spreading among staff and patients. Additionally, The CBI will also provide services other than treatment like (food, internet basic needs &#x2026; etc)

This project is supplementing and complementing Violet&#x2019;s current COVID-19 response, in which Violet emergency plan has key priorities: 1) hygiene awareness and hygiene kits for the target group, 2) training Violet&#x2019;s volunteers on how to handle a potential COVID-19 outbreak and 3) equipping existing health infrastructure and staff with required materials to be prepared for a potential outbreak. Moreover, Violet has dedicated 5 ambulance vehicles and 35 paramedics to transport suspected cases.

However, this project would largely contribute to ensuring the professional handling of a potential outbreak and mitigate the risk of infection through the community. Additionally, this project is complementing Violet&#x2019;s emergency response in the targeted areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">383654.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">216143.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16030">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">599798.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304656742">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-24">479838.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
