<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-lebanon-allocation-2020" dstore:index="17" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-22T02:08:03.84" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-20/DDA-3604/SA1/H-P/INGO/16649</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Healthcare and Protection support to the most vulnerable women at risks and/or head of households, older persons, persons with serious medical condition, disabilities or specific needs, from the refugee, host and other vulnerable communities, in BML (Beirut, Aley, Chouf districts)  and the South Governorates (Saida, Jezzine, Nabatiyeh districts) and Provision of Emergency Cash Assistance as part of a holistic protection approach to the those most vulnerable affected by the Beirut port blast.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will provide critical support to most vulnerable populations regardless of nationality (Syrian and Palestinian refugees, vulnerable Lebanese, other nationalities), whose exposure to protection and health risks and limited access to basic needs and services including health, has been severely impacted by the socio-economic crisis, and further aggravated by the Covid-19 pandemic. The project will particularly target Persons with Special needs including Person with Disabilities (PwD), Persons with Serious medical conditions, older persons, women head of households and women at risk, and households who lost all their income as a result of the pandemic and socioeconomic situation
PU-AMI will address health needs by providing subsidized consultations at 3 currently unsupported Primary Health Care Centers (PHCCs) in the MoPH network  in Chatilla, Old Saida city and Aley.The subsidized consultations will be complemented with free Laboratory, Imagery and Diagnostic tests (LIDT) based on 50%discount from NSSF list if approved by PU-AMI medical Advisors.

The first PHCC supported under this project will be Binet Hoda PHCC located in Chatilla (BML). This PHCC is currently within the MoPH network and is recommended by both the MoPH and the UNHCR. Already supported by the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) for Reproductive Health Coverage, PU-AMI will provide complementary services including subsidized and waived consultations for persons with special needs. Persons with Mental Health (MH) issues diagnosed and identified at PHCC level will be provided with subsidized and waived consultations as well, and referred to the nearby MH clinic when relevant, and upon approval.
The second PHCC is the Durze Women association&#x2019;s PHCC located in Aley (Beirut Mount Lebanon (BML)), within MoPH network and recommended by the UNHCR regional focal point due to the 4700 registered Syrian refugees hosted in the city, and the gap in terms of healthcare coverage. PU-AMI will subsidize and waive consultations fees with a special focus on persons with special needs.

Finally, Rafic Hariri PHCC in Saida old city, the third supported PHCC, also is within MoPH network. Recently reopened, the PHCC faces a gap of financing. PU-AMI&#x2019;s action will be subsidizing consultations to support the diversity of nationalities present in the area, with a special focus on elderlies and chronic patients. PU-AMI will be providing subsidized and waived consultations to the newly identified and diagnosed MH cases in the PHCC and refer them upon approval and relevance  to Moussat MH clinic.
PU-AMI will encourage the supported PHCCs to comply with MoPH&#x2019;s recommendations to have vaccinations carried out free of charge by a registered nurse for children with no indication for a medical check-up. 

Based on its experience and current activities PU-AMI will provide Emergency Cash Assistance (ECA), in line with the Inter-Agency/PWG Guidance Note, in complementary to its case management and social counselling activities already funded and secured in the South and BML Governorates, to tackle imminent protection threats such as the risk of eviction due to the inability to cover rents and the accumulation of debts, to mitigate the resort to harmful coping strategies (reduction of food quality and quantity, reduction of medical expenditures, indebtment, engaging children into work or begging, etc) and to tackle critical situations leading to a deterioration of living conditions and access to basic needs and health care. ECA proved to be a flexible modality and will allow to support households in a timely-manner, with a special attention to the most vulnerable and at risk profiles, in order to alleviate their financial difficulties and remove financial barriers to access services and/or their basic needs. The concerned persons/households will benefit from a comprehensive approach and be referred to relevant services, based on their needs, wishes, capacities and access.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Premi&#xE8;re Urgence Internationale</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Premi&#xE8;re Urgence Internationale</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Duc-Bang NGUYEN</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission Lebanon</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+961) 76 520 995</telephone>
   <email>lib.hom@pu-ami.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Matthieu BARBARY</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+961) 76 520 995</telephone>
   <email>lib.dhomp@pu-ami.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">S&#xE9;bastien LESNE</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+961) 76 520 995</telephone>
   <email>lib.grants@pu-ami.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beirut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88690000 35.51310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">El Nabatieh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.36666700 35.46666700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN3">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mount Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.83330000 35.53330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.55000000 35.38330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="35" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="65" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-09">519694.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-09">1043683.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-16649">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-09">1563378.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Premi&#xE8;re Urgence Internationale</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304792778">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-13">1250702.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Premi&#xE8;re Urgence Internationale</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
