<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-sudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="34" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-17T03:06:41.963" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/RE/H-WASH/INGO/16017</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Health and WASH Response for Covid-19 in South Darfur State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposal outlined aims to support the Humanitarian Country Team (HCT) and UN Country Team (UNCT) COVID-19 Country Preparedness and Response Plan (CPRP) which is also aligned to  the FMOH COVID&#x2010;19 plan. In particular, the proposed activities will address pillars 2 &#x2018;Risk communication and community engagement&#x2019; pillar 6 &#x2018;Infection Prevention and Control&#x2019; and pillar 7 &#x2018; case management&#x2019;.
In agreement with the SMOH, ARC will set up 5 isolation units to house screened COVID-19 suspects prior to transfer to the State Quarantine and Management Center in Nyala. These units are for temporary housing (up to 24 hours) suspected COVID-19 cases while they wait for onward referral to the State Center. These units will be housed in Kalma camp, Gereida camp, Abujazo, Dialangra, Dimso in South Darfur. In these locations the ARC team will repurpose space previously used to manage Cholera and make minor updates, including cleaning and ensuring proper ventilation and supplies. In locations without cholera units, tents will be procured and set up.
ARC isolation units are a temporary area to house suspected COVID-19 cases for a maximum of 24 hours, after they have been screened and while they are waiting for the SMoH Rapid Response team to transport suspected cases to the  State Covid-19 hospital. ARC will coordinate with SMOH on referrals and transfer of suspected COVID-19 cases to the state quarantine and management/treatment center in Nyala in South Darfur. ARC will call for and utilize SMOH ambulances to transfer patients and costs are included to rehabilitate a number of ambulances which are currently out of service. As no specific treatment for COVID-19 is currently available, these temporary isolation units will focus on supportive medical care and safe transport of patients. If necessary, persons will be provided with acetaminophen for pain and to help reduce fever.
The isolation units will be open for 24/7 and additional staff will be identified and hired as needed to support the triage and temporary isolation unit. Adherence to strict PPE protocols will mitigate the risk of transmission and IPC measures following WHO guidelines on COVID-19 will be instigated to ensure consistent measures to prevent transmission to healthcare workers and between patients
Medical staff working in the temporary isolation unit will be trained on case management for mild symptoms. Further, staff will be trained on Covid-19 awareness and IPC. ARC will coordinate with the SMOH on all trainings for COVID-19. In locations, where the SMOH is unable to send staff, ARC will deploy its lead trainers to facilitate trainings and ensure that all the staff are trained in proper protocols. 
ARC&#x2019;s proposed activities include critical WASH support services to the proposed isolation centers in South Darfur. This includes helping boost the access to water to the patients using our standard services as well as the staff operating them, to be able to practice frequent handwashing, as well as the WHO recommended disinfection practices. In communities, ARC WASH team will work closely with the Community Health Workers (CHWs) who will be in charge of raising awareness about the symptoms, transmission risks, prevention practices and treatment options.
ARC recognizes that refugees are particularly vulnerable to COVID-19. In South Darfur, there are estimated to be 11,154 currently living in the state. Refugees are included as a specific beneficiary of this project and they will have equal access to services at the health and isolation facilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heidi Dierich</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>099004218</telephone>
   <email>HeidiD@arcrelief.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.64886390 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="75" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">335164.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">164835.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-16017">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">500000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304671941">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-14">400000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
