<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="164" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-19T02:06:01.643" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/P/NGO/16343</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing access to GBV prevention services in Western rural of Aleppo.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project endeavors to implement complemented activities in the humanitarian field in western rural of Aleppo province. This intervention will make contribution towards strengthening community-based protection interventions and life-saving protection assistance depending on the expansion of the activities of two existing protection centers WGSS specialized in GBV in Atareb and Kafr Karmin villages and conducting of outreach activities. The project will target women, men, older women, girls, boys, and people with disabilities and include implementation of the following activities: 
- Forming of two mobile teams in order to provide of psychological first aid (PFA), information/awareness, case management, GBV services, referrals to GBV services and other services. The teams will cover the Daret Azza and Atareb sub-district in rural Aleppo in addition to the surrounding camps.(every sub-team will consist of two mobile teams, two social workers and case management workers). 

- Providing support for case management activities (Case fund) for 100 survivors. This assistance will be provided in kind and cash and the amount estimated for each beneficiary is 100 USD. Based on Cash Assistance in GBV Case Management Guidance Note June, 2019.By GBV-sub cluster.
- Engaging women and girls in making COVID-19 prevention IEC material &#x201C;masks&#x201D; where the women survivors and volunteers are not only contributing to protect the health of essential workers, they are also feeling empowered and valued.

- Increasing availability of remote staff well-being services to support to all team members and keep them Productive by undertake a range of activities to improve their health and wellbeing. Ina addition to, collect, analyse, interpret, evaluate and present data regarding protection and wellbeing activities for reporting and decision-making purposes.

This intervention will support 14525 beneficiaries affected by the Syrian crisis (2942 men,5714 women, 2214 boys and 3655 girls) in Atareb and Daret Azza - sub-districts by promoting their accessibility to the protection assistance significantly. The project is designed to fit and be flexible to deal with conditions of constant changes and continuous of flows of IDPs who move between several locations. Also, the project team will ensure data protection, confidentiality at all stages, protocols of information sharing and acquiring informed consent from beneficiaries. The project activities will be in line with Protection Cluster Recommendations, SOPs, Inclusive COVID-19 response - NWS Disability - TWG on Inclusion Guidance Note April 2020 and GBV SC guidance note on GBV service provision in the time of COVID-19 such as Hand sanitizing when conducting the sessions/ Gathering of five beneficiaries per session and social distance/Measure the temperature for each beneficiary as a precaution/ Plan has been put for online sessions/ Put awareness posters about Corona disease during sessions.

MASRRAT is providing GBV service in Jabal Saman district by two WGSS centers in coordination with Ihsan and SRD.
MASRRAT is a member of the protection cluster since 6 years ago and a focal point in Jebel Seman district to provide GBV services.
This project will complement the ongoing UNFPA project through covering of more area of intervention in Jebel Samaan ,where the two teams will work together under the same management and technical support, also the project will support the centers by vocational activity.
Each outreach team will be accompanied by a case manager who identifies the cases and coordinates with the GBV technical supervisor on UNFPA project to receive the cases in WGSS centers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">75274.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">74451.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16343">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">149725.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304670451">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-13">59890.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
