<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="41" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-14T02:06:51.62" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA2FT/FSL/NGO/17277</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urgent support to daily agricultural laborers and small- scale farmers// female producers   affected by the outbreak of Covid19 in the Gaza strip</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed to contribute to achieving the HRP response Plan strategic Objective # 3 SO3: The capacity of vulnerable Palestinians to cope with and overcome protracted crisis, including from environmental threats, is supported&#x201D;.the project is also designed to contribute to achieving the Covid19 Response Plan objectives under fast track. 


The most affected will be the poorest and most vulnerable groups and communities will be targeted as they do not have resources to cope with the loss of jobs and incomes, the increase of food prices and the instability of food availability based on humanitarian needs overview report OPT (2020) accordingly have less ability to adapt to the crisis. OCHA COVID19 emergency report 17s  stated that more people have become food-insecure amid an unprecedented economic crisis. These include, among others, daily workers. In addition to many small-scale farmers continue to be affected.
This project is designed to provide quick relief aid for the most affected groups by the COVID-19 pandemic in the Gaza Strip. Specifically targeting two main groups lost their livelihood opportunity during the pandemic: First, 500 HHs of agricultural daily laborers who will be provided with 6 rounds of food parcels and personal protection equipment PPE (1 round every 3 weeks). Second, 150 farmers (120 males/female farmers and 30 female producers) who will be reached through food supplier to provide the project with required fresh food and processed foods. The food parcels will be designed to provide all necessary macronutrients (proteins, carbohydrates, lipids, and fibers) and micronutrients (minerals and vitamins), knowing that the food items will be distributed based on necessity, availability, price and season while maintaining balanced and nutritious food assistance, knowing that each food parcel will contain at least 8 fresh food items and 19 dry/canned food items.

One of the crucial concerns related to COVID19 response is the delivery of food parcels to the targeted HHs. with the maximum safety measures. PARC has developed a food distribution strategy to mitigate the infection and increase the safety as much as possible. The strategy includes the procurement process with the small-scale farmers and dried food suppliers. The process also includes the safe delivery of food to HHs. In addition, that special door to door distribution plan will be developed as follow:1) The project team with close coordination and cooperation with the local partner Community Protection committees CPCs will make sure of safe and correct delivery of baskets to targeted HHs through &#x201C;door-to-door&#x201D; will be formed. 2) PARC will contact a delivery company to deliver the food packages to target HHs. Finally, a guidance brochure will be distributed to target HHs to know how to deal with the plastic bags of foods and how to preserve the food to longer period of time
PARC, in collaboration with PUI and UWAC, has developed standers operative procedures (SOPs) for the programmatic implementation. The SoPs are designed to provide the operational teams with guidance for the safe implementation of activities with a commitment to Infection Prevention and Control measures and an enhanced mitigation approach to risks for both staff and the Bene.
In the last two months, PARC has also used the from-door-to-door modality to reach Hhs Homes to keep people&apos;s safety and social distancing measures. Noteworthy to mention that this from poor farmers to poor families program contributes to local markets stability and sustained agricultural production and production cycle of female producers as well as the stable food security levels to targeted HHs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nida&apos;a Aniss Abu AL Atta</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coordinator of External Relations  Fundraising</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+970599954642</telephone>
   <email>nidaa.atta@pal-arc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tayseer Muhaisen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza branch Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00970599366038</telephone>
   <email>tayseer@pal-arc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">39565.9</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">320483.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-17277">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">360049.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304833608">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">216029.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
