<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="109" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-11T03:07:34.207" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-11T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/16261</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve access to the veterinary services and empowering the veterinary technicians to advance the veterinary sector</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to protect the livestock assets through improving the access to veterinary services and building the capacity of veterinary technicians by targeting the following communities Bales, Hila, Kafrmid, Kniseh, Mhambal, Ora Qabli &#x2013; Edwan, Sararif, Bab Ellah, Berjhab, Thaheriya, Ein Elhamra, Mazuleh, Bsheiriyeh &#x2013; Bello, Bzeit, Aqrabat of Ariha and Jisr-Ash-Shugur districts.
the activities are:

 conducting ten field visits to 1500 breeders during ten months. The IHR veterinarians will check on the animals&#x2019; health situation and provide the required treatment, if needed, against the most common diseases, or consultations.
 holding ten awareness sessions for no less 50 % of the same1500 breeders to raise their awareness about the best veterinary practices. The sessions will be through small groups of breeders to ensure their safety. 

 Conducting six vaccination campaigns at same area by targeting 50.000 sheep and goat at each campaign that owned by beneficiaries and non-beneficiaries against Enterotoxemia (for twice), Sheep Pox, FMD, and Pasteurella diseases. As well targeting 1000 cow against Lumpy Skin Disease. 
 Conducting artificial insemination for 100 cows by using seminal straws high-throughput strains. organizing the pregnancy of 1000 sheep by using vaginal sponge to increase birth rates for sheep. and follow up health situation of those cow and sheep by IHR veterinarians.
 Training 50 veterinary technicians of persons who graduated, students still in the university or out of university, for ten actual days. Distributing 50 veterinary kit consist of main required tools to enable them of launching their special work. Selecting the best ten trainees to benefit from CFW activity by accompanying the field veterinary visits for getting on practical experience and livelihood opportunity. Each trainee will receive 7 USD per work day for ten calendar months. 
 Distributing 360 ton of fodder (pellet) to 2000 sheep and 100 cow for four batches (Sep, Oct, Nov, Dec).
this project aims to continue providing the veterinary services in the same intervention area, that IHR is closing similar project there. Therefore, protecting the animals which is the source of income for the breeders. As the awareness sessions aim to build livestock breeders with strong livestock knowledge background. 
Also, providing insemination will contribute to improving cow breeds and raising animal productivity. furthermore, using the vaginal sponge will enhance the breeder&apos;s culture towards the importance of regulating pregnancy for getting on two births per year from the healthy sheep.
Meanwhile, Raising the scientific and practical competence of veterinary technicians through theoretical training and the opportunity to participate in field visits. It aims to build their capacity and provide a suitable livelihood. as well, promote the presence of qualified veterinary technicians in the region in order to meet the livestock needs. 
Regarding COVID-19, the field visits for treatment, vaccination are fodder distribution going to be door to door, with keeping distance between staff and breeders and taking consideration of the health measures to stay safe. While the training will be in a clean and big place, consider keeping a distance between trainees to avoid infection. With planning to be online through appropriate training platforms, in case the situation did not allow the training physically.
The vaccines kinds ampschedule selected according to allocation paper&#x2019;s LTWG recommendations(attached BoQ</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-163973-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-29">197023.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-29">194869.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16261">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-29">391893.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304666101">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-09">235135.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304913933">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">156757.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
