<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="41" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-17T02:06:31.447" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-25T16:29:46.797" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-20/DDA-3558/SA1/E/NGO/17070</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative education services to children in Rural Damascus</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this project AlTamayoz will support the most vulnerable children in Rural Damascus with comprehensive qualitative education services as a response to the urgent education needs of boys and girls from different communities (IDPs, returnees and host community) in this area.  
Project specific locations will be: Duma, Harasta, and Ein Tarma where AlTamayoz has existing operational presence and considered as a trustworthy NGO in Rural Damascus because of the several qualitative services it provides to people.

AlTamayoz is now running an education project under SHF 2019 in 4 locations, the actual work on the ground showed the huge need for education services which exceeded our expectations, therefore, part of this project will be as a continuation of the activities in 2 locations (Duma and Harasta &#x2013; severity scale:4) to enable more children benefit from the essential services. A new center will be in Ein Tarma where the severity scale is 5. 
This project is planned to start in November 2020 due to the time needed to get the necessary approvals, and this will make part of this project run in parallel with the currently running project, during this period the activities will be implemented in 2 shifts and will target different students to avoid duplication. Implementing the new activities in facilities already operational will help benefiting from the already existing furniture and equipment and will support sustainability. during the period where the 2 projects are implemented at the same time, the activities will be conducted in a manner that prevent overlapping or duplication, activities will be implemented in the same place but at different time, they will be as a second shift and will target new students and parents who are not supported by the ongoing project, this will be monitored through data cross checking and data exchange.

Activities will include:
Providing children under 5 years with early childhood education, and recreational activities.
Support children (5-17) years with non-formal education (remedial classes, catch-up classes, accelerating learning program), school supplies, psychosocial support, life skills and citizenship education program, and recreational activities.
Provide teachers and education staff with capacity building training.
Conduct awareness raising sessions to parents and children about the importance of education, and about COVID-19
Conduct back to learn campaigns in 3 locations.
Through this project, AlTamayoz will target  27560  beneficiaries (Students, parents, and education actors) 
Project activities will target boys and girls in addition to their parents, this will enhance the effectiveness of education activities and increase parents awareness about the importance of their children education. 
Project activities will be implemented in a free of violence atmosphere, Do No Harm will be one the most principles applied during implementation. Most teachers will be female to avoid any risk of GBV during implementation, in addition, a well trained PSS provider will be in each center to provide the needed psychosocial support and to observe any cases related to GBV and refer them to the specialist.
Project will assure active participation of students with disability, a special person will be available to support them in each center, assisstive devices (crutches, walker,..) will be available to the most vulnerable, a good coordinate with other actors in the area will be in place to support them with other special services (hearing aids, enunciation sessions,...)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-EDU-164684-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nariman Alhamwi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0968886022</telephone>
   <email>nariman@t-tamayoz.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kinana Santeer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial focal point</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>963944278949</telephone>
   <email>kinaasanteer@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Damascus</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.32451400 36.21611100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-25">410843.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-25">79474.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-17070">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-25">490317.87</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
