<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="190" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-27T02:06:01.96" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-28T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA2/H/NGO/17651</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continuous Support for COVID-19 Community Treatment Centers CCTCs (SDH Centers)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SDH&apos;s strategy is to reinforce the continued support of the CCTCs to ensure adequate intervention for providing health services for the new suspected/probable/confirmed cases.
Through this call opportunity, SDH is advocating to ensure the continuity of the ongoing intervention funded by SCHF in (CCTC_5 &quot;Al-Seeraj Center in Hazano&quot; amp CCTC_7 &quot;Al-Seeraj Center in Daret Azza&quot;) which is ended by 14/11/2020. in addition adding another center (CCTC_3 &quot; Al-Seeraj Center in Atareb&quot;) for supporting as high priority location. where the Covid-19 outbreak Disease, is still affecting all the world, including the NWS, there is a high need for humanitarian relief, considering the health system in NWS is still fragile with an urgent need for continuous support and increases the capacity of the response to contain the sharp increase of infected cases.

Currently, SHD&#x2019;s through SCHF support is running two CCTCs located in Hazano amp Daret Ezza communities. Each CCTC will be run by 8 health professional staff (out of 32) to provide medical assessment, monitoring, and supportive therapy for the confirmed COVID-19 infection with mild symptoms and without underlying chronic condition (lung, heart, renal failure, or an immunocompromising condition. The CCTC aims to reduce the burden of the caseload at the overwhelming hospital care services and provide immediate support for the suspected cases referred to the centers including testing and diagnosis while providing supportive therapy for confirmed COVID-19 patients. Moreover, CCTCs will offer separate accommodation and restrict the movement of the suspected/confirmed COVID-19 cases and providing PSS services as well. The CCTCs will be led by the Health Program management as it&apos;s already a focal point for continuous coordination with HC amp COVID-19 TF, at field level by already trained amp working healthcare workers and IPC workers and other support staff.
These CCTCs are already equipped with all needed equipment to be fully functional, while SDH with this fund opportunity will support the running cost of 3 CCTCs for eight months as the second stage of the COVID-19 response plan which includes 5 fully functional CCTCs in 2021.

the modality intervention will depend on the developed COVID-19 Taskforce operational guideline with 50-bed capacity per-center and distributed as follows:
1. observation areas with a capacity of 10 beds defined for highly suspected cases/contact developed symptoms and undergoing laboratory confirmation testing.
2. Isolation and case management areas with a capacity of 40 beds, run by medical staff to provide medical supportive therapy for confirming COVID-19 infection.
this proposal aims to cover all the approximately 480,000 population of the Aleppo amp Idlib targeted areas, by improving access to community isolation services for the most vulnerable group as following: (1) children lt18, (2) the elderly, (3) women of reproductive age, (4) IDPs and host communities(5) and people with disabilities, Through our proposed intervention. the estimated direct beneficiaries are 2400 Ind, with the indirect effect of maintaining the health safety of the rest of the targeted populations. 
this intervention of the SDH organization is well designed to fill the gaps in the current healthcare services in the targeted areas, in coordination with local authorities and Idlib amp Aleppo health directorates.
the project has a great advantage as all mentioned CCTCs are already functional, the staff is trained on IPC matter and the supply chain for PPE amp IPC is set with no need for a preparation period for operational processes, contracting, coordination with other partners. as all of these steps have finalized with the full functionality of these CCTCs and with the possibility to extend our current agreement and contracts. Overall the SHD&#x2019;s through this fund will maintain the current operational cost HR, logistics,s and provision of complementary medicines, consumable medical, PPE/IPC supplies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-20" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-21">27184.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-21">630690.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-17651">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-21">657875.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304856264">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">263150.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
