<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="57" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-21T03:05:39.713" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-10-21T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA5/ESNFI-FSAC/INGO/17217</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Winterisation, Food, and Protection Assistance for Acutely Vulnerable Host Populations of Badakhshan Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the wake of the COVID-19 crisis, an estimated 90 percent of the Afghan population is now living below the poverty line (MoE). Given the severe economic impact of the virus, combined with protracted conflict, widespread food insecurity, and a multitude of pre-existing needs, households remain unprotected and unprepared for the upcoming winter season. Accordingly, Concern Worldwide is proposing an integrated cluster response entailing joint winterisation and food assistance, shelter insulation, and protection support for the most at risk host populations of Badakhshan Province in preparation for the harsh winter season. The project&#x2019;s target districts&#x2015;Yawan, Kohistan, Raghistan, Jorm, Warduj and Shahr-e-Buzurg of Badakhshan Province&#x2015;were identified based on severe winterisation needs attributed to critical climatic conditions (altitude, temperature, and weather), prevalent IPC 4 levels of food insecurity, remoteness and associated lack of humanitarian assistance, and susceptibility to shocks.  The action promotes inter-cluster linkages with the aim of improving the quality and efficiency of assistance by breaking down sectoral barriers and applying a more holistic approach to winterisation assistance.  

Specifically, Concern will respond to the critical seasonal needs of 1,000 acutely vulnerable families in Yawan, Raghistan, Kohistan, and Shahr-e-Buzurg districts with an integrated package of i) 3-month heating/fuel cash assistance ($200) ii) blankets and quilts (in-kind, $40 value) and iii) 2-month food support (in-kind, $180 value). This combined package draws on lessons learnt from the 2019 Afghanistan Winterisation Strategy and recent PDM findings, with the aim of reducing the incentive to sell-off winterisation assistance to purchase food by jointly addressing the prioritised winterisation needs reported by affected populations last year. While this support is intended to be distributed jointly, households that do not meet the criteria for all three packages will only receive the relevant assistance. Concern will scale-up its current shelter project under the AHF First Standard Allocation of 2020 and respond to the urgent shelter and protection needs of 107 conflict-affected households residing in partially damaged shelters in Jorm and Warduj districts through the provision of in-kind Emergency Shelter Toolkits ($60 value) alongside Shelter Upgrade or Repair support via two conditional cash instalments (totalling $300). On-site technical guidance and monitoring will be integrated throughout project implementation to ensure that repairs are inclusive and implemented according to plan and quality benchmarks. To mitigate or address protection concerns resulting from the winter season and pre-existing needs, Concern will provide dignity kits (in-kind, $28 value) consisting of female hygiene and sanitary items to 210 female-headed households receiving ESNFI and/or food support. 

Throughout project implementation, Concern will mainstream COVID-19 risk communication and awareness campaigns&#x2015;including hygiene promotion within winter sectorial response&#x2015;as well as gender-sensitive behavioural change messaging to positively influence expenditure choices, food practices, and coping strategies. Gender, age, and disability considerations will be carefully integrated to ensure the response is inclusive to all segments of a community, particularly People with Specific Needs (PSNs). As women are significantly less likely to report problems with their assistance, Concern will conduct sensitisation tailored to female beneficiary groups to encourage feedback into meaningful access and appropriate modalities for support. With over two decades of operational presence in Badakhshan, Concern is incredibly well positioned to provide trusted, rapid humanitarian assistance informed by last year&#x2019;s winter response that will enable acutely vulnerable families to prepare and recover from the winter season with greater resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Martha Medhanie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93796797655</telephone>
   <email>martha.medhanie@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gregoire Borgoltz</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interim Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799489507</telephone>
   <email>gregoire.borgoltz@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badakhshan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.73477250 70.81199530</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="39" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="61" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-15">300455.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-15">370932.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-17217">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-15">671387.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304770674">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-21">537110.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
