<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="63" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-10T02:05:34.257" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/E/INGO/17560</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education in Emergency - Provide  education service for host community and IDP girls and boys through class room instruction in safe school operation.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The COVID-19 pandemic is an unprecedented public health emergency affecting all countries worldwide. Although in months of the outbreak very few cases have been reported in Ethiopia, this situation has become change very quickly. The report of the government shows that as of October 3, Ethiopia reported 76 988 confirmed COVID-19 cases and 1208 confirmed deaths. This made Ethiopia the fourth country in Africa with the highest caseload, overtaking Nigeria.  In addition to COVID-19 flooding, armed attacks and political tension forced Ethiopia challenged with a multifaceted crisis in different parts of the country. Afar and Benishangul Gumuze regions are prone to such complexities of crisis. 


Ethiopia experienced prolonged political unrest and prone to natural disaster as a result the humanitarian landscape continued to be Protracted, complex and dominated by conflict displacements and related humanitarian needs. As a result, children in Afar and Benishangul gumuze regions exposed with protection risks and disrupt the school reopening effort amp affect the students going back to school. 


Girl in crisis are will also be at heightened risk of immediate and longer-term effects of the pandemic, as their social support networks are often fragmented and coping mechanisms already stretched. They difficulties in access to care and medical services, including testing for covid-19, due to lack of transportation, lack of service availability in remote informal settlements, and unsafe and roads unable to serve because of flooding   which affect   travel conditions to health services. 

There are major challenges around equitable access to learning for all children during the COVID-19, flooding and other social crisis. The COVID-19 pandemic and temporary school closures have left 26 million Ethiopian students out of school, which may have long-term impacts on their health, development, and future earning potential. Temporary school closures may also lead some children from vulnerable households, especially girls and students in rural areas, to permanently drop-out of school, presenting an urgent need to support and encourage re-enrollment once schools reopen.  
Benishangul Gumuz and Afar  regions is experienced  increasingly with ethnically motivated and politicized tensions , flooding , invading by desert locust thereby  leading to widespread violence and massive displacement. . 

According to the recent rapid assessment has been conducted in Afar region 110,034 people are displaced from six woredas and settled with their relatives, in schools and temporary shelters.  The scale of violence and displacement is unprecedented and puts more than these people are displaced which are not reached by the assessment team. The flooding has been damaged a total of 162 schools-of which 59 completely damaged,84 partially damaged and 19 schools are occupied by displaced people.   

PIE will integrate this project with the existing projects implemented in the regions under like child protection program to ensure the complementary amp leverage with the ongoing response, mainly mainstream protection and education service. The project aims to ensure the continuity of education and improve the psycho social well being of girls , boys and schoolchildren. 
strategies 
&#xF0FE;	Support school  reopening process  that every child girls,boys and children with disability. 
&#xF0FE;	Support disinfecting of schools, provide adequate hygiene kits to schools and support safe schools  operation during reopening
&#xF0FE;	Provision of capacity building to  teachers, directors and PTSAs on the prevention and control of COVID-19 in schools and  avoid stigmatization
&#xF0FE;	Back to school campaign &#x2013; advocacy, mobilization and communication. Support teachers to engage with parents and children to understand key elements of children&#x2019;s 
&#xF0FE;	Well being of children support it in the crisis through Psycho social First Aid (PFA)  and Mental Health</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiwotie Simachew</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 911 591825</telephone>
   <email>Hiwotie.Simachew@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tilahun Wolie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education in Emergency specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>251-0911760991</telephone>
   <email>Tilahun.wolie@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zufan Membere</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BDD manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>251-0920746672</telephone>
   <email>Zufan.Membere@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.77273098 12.03628232</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benishangul Gumuz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.44030741 10.50292407</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-12">497323.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17560">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-12">497323.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304876506">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-14">298394.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
