<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="85" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-09T02:06:25.127" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-18T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA6/FSAC/INGO/17741</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food assistance to the vulnerable population in Kamdish district of Nuristan Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Information provided by REACH and the Afghanistan Food Security Outlook Update August 2020 (based on data from FEWS network) shows that as a result of overall insufficient income due to prolonged impacts of conflict on livelihood activities, the majority of poor rural households are expected to be unable to meet all essential food needs. The overall needs assessment shows a prediction of 40% of the population living in IPC 3 or IPC 4 food security situation during coming winter. 


In line with the AHF and adapted HRP 2020, ZOA-SHPOUL will provide food assistance through the implementation of cash for food project in Kamdesh district of Nuristan. The intervention will be through restricted and unconditional cash distribution. Cash will be distributed in 2 installments of USD 90 to cover 50% of the minimum food basket for 4 months. This modality is chosen as it empowers beneficiaries to have more control over their own resources which will maintain their dignity as they have a choice. 


1072 HHs with a total of 7500 beneficiaries in Kamdesh will receive four half food package distribution through cash for food package. The provision will be in two installments in order to be most cost effective and to avoid the distributions being hindered by heavy snowfall. A proven Hawala will facilitate the distribution at Barikot,a village belonging to the Narai district. It has been the usual distribution point in the past and has proven to work well, beneficiaries are able to travel to that point. The distribution will be done based on the signed lists and/or tokens issued to the selected beneficiaries by the Beneficiary Selection Committee (BSC) through the Hawala system. In Kamdesh the network coverage is less than 20% hence more than 80% of the beneficiaries will not be able to make use of the phone. Representatives of the Community Development Committee (CDC) consisting of 10 &#x2018;senior&#x2019; community members (F/M) will be involved in contacting beneficiaries if needed and NIDs will be checked. The cash distribution covers 50% of the accepted monthly MEB for an average Afghan family, it is expected that families will be able to cover the remaining needs. Information will be shared regarding the required food items to be purchased.

Besides the cash distribution, community mobilizers conduct awareness training on COVID-19, and how to potentially mitigate Sexual Gender-Based Violence (SGBV), and Domestic Violence (DV) in the families, including a focus on child rights. Awareness raising will take place in all villages in separate male/female groups, female beneficiaries receive the hygiene kit. Information leaflets will be distributed to ensure ongoing access to information. 

Covid-19 and Protection awareness-raising sessions also take place at the distribution site. Key people of each village participate in community dialogues in order to discuss protection issues and information will be shared about other services available within the area to enable women to potentially get in touch with support services. This will however continue to be a challenge due to the remoteness and small number of health facilities available.

Kamdesh has small shops in some of the villages, these shops cannot fulfill the demand for the required food items. The market assessment done by SHPOUL local staff was focused on the market of Narai, a district in Kunar Province which touches Kamdesh. The market in Narai is able to deal with the demand for food items, the population of Kamdesh usually purchases their food items there. The market is accessible on foot, donkey, and the occasional car. The communities are stable hence social cohesion is reasonably strong through which community members support each other, in particular the elderly, people with disabilities, and female-headed households. For Female/children/elderly/PWD headed households the distribution will take place at Kamdesh centre to ensure a safe and secure distribution accessible to all.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sound Humanitarian Participatory amp; Organizational Uplift (SHPOUL)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerhard B&#xE4;rtschi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director Afghanistan</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93795101064</telephone>
   <email>g.bartschi@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haider Ahmadyar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Operations</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 798996237</telephone>
   <email>h.ahmadyar@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mir Afzal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799329337</telephone>
   <email>m.afzal@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuristan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.32502230 70.90712360</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">55991.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">243961.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-17741">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">299952.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304835617">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-18">239961.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
