<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="8" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-30T03:05:57.803" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-29T19:32:04.91" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/Shelter/NGO/18142</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency Shelter and NFIs in Belet Xaawo District, Gedo Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will provide  life-saving shelter and NFI kits to IDPs who have not accessed similar support for the last two years in Ajuaran, Jaron, Odaa, Gawido, Malkarie, Idan and Bula Amin camps in Belet Hawa district. The camps have been selected on the basis of need, high proportion of the newly arrived, lack of similar support and accessibility. The needs of the beneficiaries have been identified through a joint rapid needs assessment conducted by HAPEN and DRC in March 2021.

The target population (women, girls, men, boys, elderly and people with disabilities) are living in small makeshift structures made of sub-standard materials that compromise their privacy, physical security and protection from weather extremes. The families lack adequate access to NFIs, having lost them during displacement.

HAPEN will distribute Emergency Shelter Kits (ESKs) and non-food items (NFI) kits to 2333 households, including 230 host households who are equally vulnerable in the interest of Do-No Harm principle and in support of reintegration. An owner-driven approach in the construction of shelters where beneficiaries are assisted and capacitated to undertake the construction. The process will enable them to undertake basic repairs using local materials or rebuild their shelters in future, thus contributing to sustainability of the benefits beyond the project period. On monitoring, Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) and Post Construction Monitoring (PCM) will be conducted after distribution of NFIs and ESKs respectively. The exercises will provide beneficiary feedback on project effectiveness and will target 90% of the beneficiaries to ensure proper representation and accuracy.

To ensure accountability, HAPEN will establish community response and feedback mechanisms (CRFM) in the targeted sites. This will be comprised of a CRFM desk and a hotline to offer a channel for beneficiaries to register concerns. 

HAPEN will work closely with local administration to plan distribution points, schedules and instill order during the exercises to minimize protection risks. The timing and locations of all distributions will put the safety of women, girls, boys, elderly, disabled and those with limited mobility into consideration. Distribution exercises will be done within reasonable daylight hours. Distances to distribution sites and facilities provided by the project will be minimal and safe. It will be made clear that support provided by the project will be at no cost to the beneficiaries, hence no favours should be solicited from beneficiaries. COVID-19 prevention measures will be observed at all points where project requires beneficiaries, leaders or partners to gather. In general, the project will address protection risks and inclusion of women, disabled and minorities at all stages.

Community structures including project community committees will play key roles in decision making, implementation and monitoring of activities and will be comprised of men, women and representatives of the disabled and the minority. 

In particular, this project will closely coordinate and harmonize with Protection, WASH, CCCM and Housing, Land amp Property (HLP)  interventions to be implemented by other partners (DRC, SEDHURO and  NOFYL)  in the same district or camps and in general all other initiatives in the district to ensure complementarity. Under the coordination arrangements, organizations implementing different projects will plan together and share information during the selection of beneficiaries to avoid duplication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa Peace Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa Peace Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibrahim Abdi Dubat</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252617560138 / +254791371159</telephone>
   <email>ibrahim@hapen.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Kabogo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722719776</telephone>
   <email>info@hapen.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-29">860531.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-29">109329.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18142">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-29">969860.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa Peace Network</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
