<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="94" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-23T02:05:20.323" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-28T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/WASH-H-P/INGO/17490</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saving lives of Conflict affected IDPs and Disaster affected host communities through integrated response on WASH, Health and Protection intervention covering 7 IDP sites in Moyale Woreda of Dawa Zone, Somali Regional State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Per NCA/OWDA&#x2019;s August 2020 assessment report, WASH, Health amp Protection needs of Moyale woreda is very high. Reports from secondary data shows that, WASH, health, protection amp nutrition severity are all high. People are using water from unsafe sources like ponds amp Birkas.  IDPs in Moyale have limited access to latrine facilities. Communal latrines in camps are inadequate, not gender segregated amp have no proper doors and locks.  Women face GBV while accessing the limited latrine at night. Inadequate latrines resulted open defecation in IDP camps amp in host community with contamination of surface water sources which in turn posing the risk of water-borne diseases including AWD. Sanitation of latrines amp personal hygiene of IDPs is poor due to shortage of water. IDPs have no sanitation materials including dignity kits for girls amp women at reproductive age. Moyale as business corridor bordering Kenya is highly vulnerable to COVID-19 where prevention and Control measures encountered difficulties due to lack of water amp absence of frequent handwashing. 
Moyale Health Office report indicated that IDP sites have shortage of routine essential medical supplies including emergency drugs. IDPs don&#x2019;t have HPs inside the camp and there is no designated ambulance for referral of critical emergency medical and surgical cases. IDPs have poor health service delivery in all health facilities with poor community engagements amp risk communications, weak surveillance system, shortage of health personnel in the health facility amp lack of community awareness for health promotion and disease prevention mechanisms. High need of Emergency care encompasses urgent stabilization, diagnosis, and treatment of acute medical, surgical, and obstetrical conditions. These striking gaps stress the importance of expanding physical access to health emergency care services as part of a strategy of universal health coverage. In Moyale there is no mental health and psychosocial support intervention. FGD discussants indicated that, there is high prevalence of GBV and different forms of abuse in the IDPs and host communities.

In response to the current identified needs, NCA in consortium with OWDA will implement the following major activities. 
	Drilling 2 new shallow wells Construct 20 gender segregated and disability friendly semi-permanent latrines each with 4 stances in 5 IDP sites, Sanitation amp hygiene promotion, WASH NFIs distributions. 

	Conduct minimum initial service package through training of health staff, Conduct community amp health facility-based surveillance training for HWs, HEWs amp CHVs, Provision of family planning counselling amp use of contraceptive for reproductive age groups, Provision of Integrated Management of Neonatal amp Childhood Illness, Immunization mainstreaming through major religious systems, 
	Provide GBV, mental health amp psychosocial training to community Members, Strengthen community-based protection mechanism and structures, Provide awareness raising on protection risk, capacity building on protection principals to local authorities, Identification amp case management support for children at risk, Sensitization amp parenting support for caregivers, Response service mapping amp develop/update referral pathways, Provide psychosocial sensitization to IDPs amp Host communities, Support GBV survivors including sexual exploitation amp abuse through case management amp referral support, Provide dignity kits for women amp girls at reproductive age. 
	Awareness on COVID-19 prevention and response though dissemination of key messages translated into local language, Release audio message of Covid-19 using car mounted loudspeakers, Provide support to highly vulnerable groups amp install foot operated hand washing stations in mass gathering places. In total, the project intends to reach 60,000 direct beneficiaries (31,800 female).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organisation for Welfare and Development in Action (OWDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eivind Aalborg</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 911 200 728</telephone>
   <email>Eivind.Aalborg@nca.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>43.32903576 6.92946999</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="29" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="21" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-23">502852.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17490">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-23">502852.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304856272">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">402281.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
