<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="16" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/H/INGO/18247</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Quality Life Saving Emergency Primary Health Services for Crisis affected populations living in  Hobyo District of Mudug Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will deliver lifesaving emergency health services including maternal, neonatal and child health through 2 static Health facilities (Galbarwaako and Elgula) and 1 mobile health clinic serving far flung villages without static health facilities in close proximity in Hobyo District. This action will complement and strengthen CESVIs health care provision activities in the above stated locations with funding from AICS and DFID (currently known as FCDO). Within Hobyo district, this action will provide quality lifesaving health services to the following 11 villages Galbarwaako, Elgula Herodhagaxley, Haaro, Afgaduudle, Garday, Qalqaloocan, Biriqoday, Boorweyne, Meygaag dheere, Laasa Hawiye. One Mobile clinic will provide health outreach services in 9 villages hosting a total of 2,790 HHs. The health facilities will be equipped with essential medicines and equipment and staff will be trained to provide quality services. Emphasis will be laid on Maternal and Child Health, including Basic Emergency Obstetric and Newborn Care (BEmONC) and Expanded Programme on Immunization to IDPs and most vulnerable communities. This project will focus on provision of both curative and preventive health services at primary level integrated with activities addressing GBV and protection needs. Emphasis will be laid on application of standard treatment guidelines as per EPHS at PHC. Building the capacity of health workers through training on Covid-19 case management and infection control, Integrated Management of childhood illness (IMCI), BEmONC will be done to equip health workers with pertinent skills to deliver quality health care services to the affected population. Selected staff will be trained on surveillance for epidemic diseases to allow monitoring of alert thresholds for prompt initiation of response. This will be achieved in collaboration with the MoH at subnational health cluster level. This action will deliver comprehensive reproductive health care to women of reproductive age among the target beneficiaries and promotion of health seeking behaviour including adoption of preventive practices through campaigns, health and hygiene education sessions. Health and hygiene promotions will mostly be done by trained 11 CHWS and 2 hygiene promoters. Cesvi will also integrate surveillance and emergency preparedness ensuring adequate stocks for epidemic outbreaks of AWD/Cholera and measles are prepositioned. Moreover, Personal Protective Equipment (PPEs) will be purchased for frontline Health workers as a measure for infection prevention and control (IPC) at service provision points. The project will also contribute to strengthening early warning disease surveillance through weekly submission of CSR reports from all the functional supported health facilities. To this end, the project will establish 2 Rapid Response Teams which will be dispatched to investigate and undertake prompt response in case of emergency and epidemic outbreaks. Referral system for patients seeking secondary healthcare services will be done to Galkayo hospital and will be strengthened with focus on pregnant women requiring emergency services, victims of gun shots, casualties from accidents, trauma cases among others. The project will also undertake confidential identification of GBV survivors for provision of comprehensive care and psychosocial support in-line with IASC MHPSS standard. Clinical management of rape (CMR) will also be provided in the 2 Health facilities. Children aged below 5 years and PLWs with acute malnutrition will be referred to nutrition centers for nutrition care and rehabilitation. Finally, CESVI will coordinate with Health and Nutrition, WASH and FSL clusters to coordinate response activities for maximum impact to beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione E Sviluppo - CESVI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione E Sviluppo - CESVI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSOM21-HEA-171449-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Isabella Garino</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254714517381</telephone>
   <email>isbellagarino@cesvioverseas.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lisa Vaglica</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254701221299</telephone>
   <email>lisavaglica@cesvioverseas.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Silas Okumu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254724155015</telephone>
   <email>rhop@cesvioverseas.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9672">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mudug</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.49100000 48.01000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSOM21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">235032.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">115589.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18247">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">350621.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione E Sviluppo - CESVI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305023292">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-19">210373.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione E Sviluppo - CESVI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
