<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="73" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-18T03:06:03.98" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-10T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-20/DDA-3558/SA1/P/INGO/17061</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting the Alternative Care services for most vulnerable children affected by on-going emergencies in Damascus city and its rural surrounding.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this project is to promote and increase awareness about the Alternative Care services for children in Child and Youth Friendly Language among 20,100 children, caregivers in addition to humanitarian workers in Damascus city and it&#x2019;s rural. 
Children and adolescents in alternative care or may become separated from their families face the risk of abuse, neglect, and child rights violations. They often think they do not have the same rights as others.
The project aims at raising their awareness about their right to live in a supportive family environment. It explains what needs to happen to children who cannot live with their parents or are at risk of being separated from them.
The project focus on highlighting the Guidelines for the Alternative Care of Children, which outline standards of care and protection for our target group which was adopted by the United Nations General Assembly in 2009.
The awareness session will focus on speaking directly to the children and youth through the following content:
Children&#x2019;s right to care and protection- children&#x2019;s rights when parents face difficulties, when children cannot live with your parents and when there is an emergency in child&#x2019;s country
The project will also target children with special needs who have challenges to read and understand the booklet. The project team will explain the contents of the booklet through real-life examples or simple games. 
Target groups: Children and youth benefiting from SOS children&apos;s villages&apos; programs and local NGO partners including children who need special care. Children who live in alternative care programs run by local charities, Children, and families who face the risk of family separation, Care providers and humanitarian workers, Children in public school, and Community committees (10 communities).
The project also aims at providing group psychological support to 5000 of the project beneficiaries. The intervention will help discharge beneficiaries&#x2019; emotions and promote the psychosocial well-being of children and their psychosocial safety.
The project will include also risk education sessions for all the project beneficiaries. The goal is to educate them about the danger of mines and remnants of war that could endanger their lives. Using officially approved brochure provided by UNMAS, this awareness will help them remain safe in the areas in which they live or upon their return to their cities and areas from which they were displaced during the crisis.
Moreover, the project aims at supporting most vulnerable children from the project beneficiaries in the targeted communities who face the risk of losing their parental care due to risks of their family separation (100 families or 500 beneficiaries). 
These risks are caused by the protection and socio-economic impacts of Covid-19 and knock-on effects on the economy caused by the unstable exchange rate and other factors that have been observed in SOS Children&#x2019;s Villages programs&#x2019; locations in Damascus vicinity,
The project will also focus on preventing family separation and contributing to restore the local economy recovery by providing financial support for families through 7 months of cash assistance to protect families from negative coping mechanisms impacting children which include separating children from the family. These actions will be supported by a group of activities specially designed to increase access for children and families to quality child protection interventions in targeted locations through psycho-social counselling, case management, and awareness sessions related to parental care.
Moreover, the families will be supported through the wide connection channels of SOS Children&#x2019;s Villages Syria with partners. Also, they will be referred to other NGOs that provide support based on their identified needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children &apos;s Villages Association - Syria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children &apos;s Villages Association - Syria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-PRO-CPN-163945-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">fares Samaan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional Partnership Development specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00963-987-884-481</telephone>
   <email>Fares.Samaan@sos-syria.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lur Katt</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundraising Development and Communication director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00963-933-333-285</telephone>
   <email>Lur.Katt@sos-syria.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Damascus</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.51717500 36.27671000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Damascus</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.32451400 36.21611100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-16">55981.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-16">283637.21</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-17061">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-16">339618.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children &apos;s Villages Association - Syria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304785031">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-10">203770.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOS Children &apos;s Villages Association - Syria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
