<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="34" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-17T02:05:26.693" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-08T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/Ed/INGO/15119</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased access to quality education and support services for the wellbeing of boys and girls with a focus on IDPs and host communities in the Galgaduud region of Galmudug state.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, COVID-19 emerged, and the WHO has declared its outbreak as a global pandemic. The COVID-19 pandemic is a global health crisis that has resulted in a great disruption to education worldwide. Education has been hit particularly hard by the COVID-19 pandemic with 1.53 billion learners out of school and 184 country-wide school closures, impacting 87.6% of the world&#x2019;s total enrolled learners. Drop-out rates across the globe are likely to rise as a result of this massive disruption to education access. Thus, the Somali Government took precautionary measures as stopping international flights, closing learning institutions, and banning large public gathers. As the Government continues to monitor the situation, CISP plans to mitigate and minimize the impact of school closure and interrupted student learning, particularly for the most vulnerable. As there is a lack of clarity on how the COVID-19 situation will evolve globally and locally in Somalia, CISP will forecast long-term contingency measures ensuring that the impact of COVID-19 on students will be addressed as schools remain closed. In Somalia, it has affected learning and forced the closure of learning institutions including schools and universities since March 18th, 2020. In responding to this outbreak, CISP adapts the Ministry of Education, Culture, and Higher Education (MoECHE) strategy on COVID-19 preparedness and response. 
The proposed 9-month intervention will target 12 schools with an enrolment of 3462 learners with the provision of food, TLM, and Dignity kit while 19,890 adults and children of school-going age children will be targeted with radio PSA and health messages to provide mitigation measures on the impact of COVID-19 on top of other existing challenges such as conflict, drought and desert locust for learners both school holidays and when schools reopen. The project will improve access to critical WASH inputs, emergency food for students to meet their food and energy needs, payment of emergency teacher incentives to motivate teachers to stay in the schools, provision of teaching and learning materials (TLM). Specific WASH activities will include the distribution of handwashing soaps, liquid detergents, rehabilitation of latrines, provision of storage water tanks, water trucking for schools with no constant water supply, and improving hygiene practices among children through engagement with school hygiene promoters. Following the Federal guideline on social distancing CISP will work with the ministry of health and MoECHE to explore the possibility of having smaller groups of teacher and CEC&#x2019;s to train so as to maintain 1.5-meter distance in order to implement a lifesaving training of hygiene and Sanitation on preparedness, mitigation and response to COVID-19 pandemic and identification of COVID-19 symptoms to prevent the spread of COVID-19 among the school community. CISP proposes this project to improve access to quality education and making schools child-friendly for COVID-19, drought and conflict-affected communities, and host community children Galgaduud region of Galmudug State of Somalia. The project directly addresses the educational needs of both the displaced and host community children. This project will create a protective environment for children through the improvement of hygiene/sanitation in schools thereby making schools learner-friendly and also the provision of quality education through providing learning resources, general community sensitization through radio PSA will be aired through Galmudug radio station on the COVID-19 pandemic awareness and prevention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Musa Dagane</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Education Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252617281929</telephone>
   <email>dagane@cisp-som.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jelena Savic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CISP Country Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722790971</telephone>
   <email>savic@cisp-som.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">313302.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">86783.19</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15119">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">400085.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304664500">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">240051.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
