<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="193" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-16T02:06:54.453" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-30T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA2/H-FS/NGO/17756</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mitigating COVID-19 outbreak in Northwest Syria by operating 2 CCTCs and ensuring food access for those at risk in camps to both reduce the spread of the virus and the economic&apos;s negative effect on their food security (SO1).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the Health and FSL multisector project, Violet aims to implement integrated activities that contribute to lifesaving and  NWS&#x2019;s COVID-19 response by 1) isolation of the suspected/tested positive cases, and 2) provision cooked meals in the existing CCTC in Ariha, but also by alleviating the negative socioeconomic impact of COVID-19 by 3) the provision of cash for food. The project is designed with the following activities:


Health: Violet strives to maintain the existing CCTC capacity in Ariha to isolate the COVID-19 cases to slow down the transmission of the virus. Ultimately, the activities aim to reduce the morbidity and mortality among the community members, as well as to protect the health system from a potential collapse that might be caused by the rapid spread of COVID-19. Therefore, Violet is requesting funds to support the CCTC in Ariha for 11 months as funding from previous sources ends by mid-January 2021. This component will be linked to the COVID-19 response activities to maximize the project impact such as the referral system, provision of PSS, and wellbeing activities to the BNFs in the CCTC, outreach, and hygiene promotion, disinfection of the public places, and masks production and distribution. Further, it&apos;s coordinated with Violet&apos;s other projects and acts complementary e.g. through referrals.


Food security: Violet seeks to a) provide cooked meals and fresh vegetables and fruits for the patients admitted in Ariha CCTC based on FSL recommendations of at least 2100 Kcal for a person/per day. Moreover, the cooked meals are designed to include nutritious vitamins through fresh vegetables, fruits, pickles, and fresh yogurt to support the quick recovery of isolated cases.

Food security b) Violet plans to respond with lifesaving activities by providing Cash for food (50 USD per HHs) for the most vulnerable and at-risk HHs for 8 rounds. this intervention will also contribute to the COVID-19 response by reducing the negative socio-economic impact due to the COVID-19 outbreak Moreover, the targeted BNFs will also receive soap kits (750 gram/ HH) to improve their access to Hygiene means according to WASH cluster recommendation. the Target locations are the camps surrounding the proposed CCTC, and other CCTC supported by Violet in Idleb to improve the beneficiaries&apos; food consumption of fresh food and vegetables in the COVID-19 pandemic. The cash distribution modality was selected to provide more flexibility for the BNFs to buy their needs, but also to and provide assistance in a dignified way. Prior to cash distribution, Violet will conduct rapid needs assessments to ensure the beneficiaries&#x2019; accessibility to functioning markets to avoid the potential harm of cash inputs. Moreover, the cash will be distributed in USD to improve the purchasing power of the targeted HHs without being affected by the devaluation of the local currency

The project was designed complementary between both sectors by the provision of cooked meals and fresh vegetables to the admitted patients in the CCTC in Ariha, which will contribute to improving their immunity and quick recovery. But also through cash for food for the most vulnerable groups inhabiting the camps in the CCTC areas to alleviate the negative socioeconomic impacts due to COVID-19 and also improve their nutrition status when at risk of contracting COVID-19. 

During all project phases, Violet will ensure the field teams apply COVID-19 preventive measures according to Violet&#x2019;s SOPs. This includes applying social distancing, regular sanitization of the CCTC, and wearing face masks. Moreover, Violet ensures the preventive measures during distribution by minimizing the number of cash beneficiaries in each distribution round, carry out the cash distribution in the well-ventilated areas, as well as supplying the distribution points with sufficient hand sanitizers and cleaning materials.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-164398-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="63.39" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="36.61" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-23">778885.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-17756">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-23">778885.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304859968">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-30">467331.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
