<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="98" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-19T02:07:06.777" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-07T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/ER-FS/NGO/16327</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support and strengthen access to livelihoods by creating  income-generating opportunities through CFW and participatory irrigation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Violet is proposing an integrated 7-months project to 1) strengthen access for vulnerable groups to livelihood opportunities, and 2) improve access to basic services and infrastructure. For a sustainable approach, Violet also 3) supports participatory irrigation via solar-powered systems. 


FSC activities
1. 1738 households have improved access to income-generating activities through CFW activities (100% female) through olive harvesting activities for 1months in Albab and Jarablus (1.580 unskilled and 158 skilled labor), the planned number of trees to be harvested is 79.000 trees where the productivity of each worker is around 2.4 trees per day in Northern Aleppo. The expected number of farmers is 265 by considering the average landholding is 300 trees. To ensure sustainability, 50% of the CFW workers&apos; transportation costs will be covered from the contribution of farmers benefitting from olive harvesting. Additionally, they will provide the necessary harvesting tools.

2. 265 BNF farmers (benefitting from olives harvesting) will have improved access to cultivation skills and knowledge through provision online training on GAP. 
3. Installing 15 solar-powered irrigation systems targeting at least 120 households in Jarablus are installed to provide water for vegetable, crops, and olive trees production. The mobile irrigation systems cover an area of approximately 3.5 hectares each. Targeting the lands that are far away up to 5 km from the riverside and have seepage water. BNFs will be trained on how to operate and maintain the irrigation system to ensure sustainability.
Violet will ensure the integration by targeting the same BNFs with the above-mentioned activities whenever applicable. So, olive farmers having land far from Euphrates river (up to 5 KM) in Jarablus will receive harvesting and irrigation services and GAP training. Moreover, Violet will link the participatory irrigation BNFs with the previously trained BNFs on solar irrigation maintenance in the same location to be able to support each other. Solar irrigation systems will support BNF farmers with sustainable, clean and free energy to reduce production and irrigation costs, and thus, improve their income.

ERL activities 
3.  440 households have strengthened access to livelihoods through CFW opportunities for 3 months/ rounds (400 unskilled and 40 skilled workers) and improving access to public infrastructure by conducting minor rehabilitation to roads, sewage systems, sidewalk, and gardens. through this activity, Violet will ensure the active community participation in all phases. Activities will be identified based on the needs, community priorities, the number of target BNFs and budget limitation. Moreover, the CFW activities under ERL will effectively contribute to the COVID-19 response through cleaning and disinfecting public facilities, garbage collection, rehabilitating of the sewage systems, and water networks. 
While the solar irrigation system was selected to ensure the suitability, CFW modality was selected to improve the community&apos;s resilience,  allow BNFs to participate in their communities&apos; development, and secure their needs in a dignified and flexible way, but also to reduce the reliance on humanitarian assistance through creating short term job opportunities. it also contributes to market recovery through disposing of cash in the BNFs hands
As active member in the different clusters, Violet coordinates with the other actors and systematic reporting to the relevant cluster. E.g. garbage collection will be coordinated and reported to the WASH cluster.
Beside cash distribution, each CFW BNF will receive 750 G of soap sufficient for 1 month to contribute to COVID-19 response based on WASH cluster recommendations.
Violet is ready to immediately start the implementation since it has active FWA for MTA service for CFW payments.

Violet commits to apply COVID-19 preventive measures, accountability and SEA mitigation measures in all activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-ERY-164088-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-164398-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="36.84" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="63.16" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">602139.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">105292.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16327">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">707431.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304666953">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">424459.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
