<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-pakistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="4" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-30T02:03:17.043" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-10-08T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/FS/NGO/17119</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livelihood Inclusion of Vulnerable-COVID-19-affected-Communities with Emphasis upon Women Engagement (LIVE) in Chaghai</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The people of Balochistan are faced with multiple crisis in the recent past. The level of vulnerabilities exacerbated with recurrent drought spells, specifically the last spell between 2007-2019 (1.79 Million Affectees) added serious and irreversible damages to the livelihood patterns of inhabitants. Moreover, above normal rainfall and snowfall throughout 2019-20 turned into flash flooding and snow emergency (1.1 Million Affectees) resultantly marked 48% rural population in IPC phase 3 (crisis) and 4 (emergency). The district of Chaghai is among the worst affected list where around 65% of district population were labelled in phase 3 or above of IPC exercise in 2019. The situation should have compounded with COVID outbreak and Locust attack. The socio-economic impact of COVID-19 are much more significant than its health adversaries COVID will push additional 2.5 million people food insecure in the country by the end of this year. 
District Chaghai is the largest and most sparsely populated district of Pakistan, the level of vulnerabilities for the district are even the highest among the districts of Balochistan. Chaghai became the limelight of COVID-19 pandemic in Pakistan right from the beginning since religious pilgrims from Iran were suspected to be the first victims and/or carriers of Corona in Pakistan. The restrictions imposed during the pandemic have not only increased the cost of living, as well as travelling restrictions aggravate the hardships of the working community with restricted work opportunities. 

IR has conducted a remotely monitored rapid need assessment exercise within its targeted communities during the Pandemic (July 2020. The finding of the exercise in district Chaghai did validate that the menace of the pandemic and its consequences on socio-economic sectors are as harsh as that of the country. The income level have been reduced more than 50% while the efficacy of service delivery has been curtailed to a large extent. Two third of the respondents (71%) share that their livelihood sources have been severely impaired due to the lockdown. 10% respondents that their resources for 50 to 100% have been affected and now that are out of options to earn a living a spend a life upright
IR is targeting Rabi planting season in district Chaghai as well as emphasizing on the protection of livelihood assets. The proposed module is more align with the strategic priorities of Agriculture and Food Security Working group, formally endorsed from the Agriculture line Departments and more importantly in line with the Response Strategy of Islamic Relief against COVID-19. The proposed interventions within the agriculture and livestock sectors (crops support, capacity building session in both agriculture and livestock sectors, restocking of poultry birds and ruminants, veterinary services, and cash grants for service providers in value chain) are estimated to reach 16,925 individuals in district Chaghai, including 5585 men, 5247 women, 3050 boys, 3043 girls and 677 disable persons as targeted direct beneficiaries. The need identification survey and consultation with line departments confirm 5 Union Councils (Barabcha, Chilghazi, Pat Gwanako, Ziarat Balnosh, and Amuri) for effective targeting. Within these Union Councils, population residing along border areas have peculiar needs and vulnerabilities owing to intensified restrictions in terms of livelihood opportunities due to border closures and security concerns. Though the specific outputs of the project are humanitarian in nature  , the outcome drawn are convincingly provide an enabling environment for long lasting impacts. The interventions proposed are evolving around sustainable livelihood options keeping in mind &#x2018;do no harm&#x2019; principles and SPHERE standards. Moreover, 2080 afghan refugees will be targeted for necessary agriculture and livestock interventions to complement their food security needs from household sources and augment their nutritional needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Pakistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Pakistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raza Narejo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00923455009534</telephone>
   <email>Raza.narejo@irp.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Umair Hasan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0092512114212</telephone>
   <email>cd@irp.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rashid Mehmood</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0092512114212</telephone>
   <email>Rashid.Mehmood@irp.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.32720000 65.89310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-05">239817.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-05">237182.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-17119">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-05">477000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Pakistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304757694">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-08">381600</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Pakistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
