<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="18" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-27T02:06:07.86" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-17T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA1/H-P-WASH/INGO/16799</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meeting the multi-sectoral needs of displaced and conflict-affected communities in central and northern Rakhine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In partnership with the Rakhine Community Health Workers Association (RCHWA) and Rakhine Ethnic Congress (REC), the International Rescue Committee (IRC) will implement a 12-month project to provide life-saving and essential health, GBV, mental health and psychosocial support (MHPSS), protection monitoring and, emergency WASH interventions to IDPs and conflict-affected host communities across 7 townships in central and northern Rakhine. A total of 76,752 vulnerable individuals (M 22,928 F 53,824) will be reached including 45,179 through primary health care services, 500 through protection monitoring outcomes, 35,615 through GBV response and risk mitigation activities and 2,756 through WASH services. This includes an estimated 3,530 persons with disabilities (PWDs).


The specific geographies targeted for these activities &#x2013; Rathedaung, Minbya, Mrauk-U, Myebon, Ponnagyun and Kyauktaw - align directly with the Allocation Strategy Paper and reflect locations where IRC and its partners have existing programming and access.


 

Building on the existing integrated programming, as well as wide ranging COVID 19 mitigation measures instituted by IRC internally, this project will respond to the critical unmet humanitarian needs of displaced people and host communities resulting from the ongoing protracted crises across Rakhine. Taking an integrated and complementary approach, with a focus on leveraging local structures and supporting local organizations, this project will promote front-line responders and expand essential service provision for conflict affected populations.

 
The project also aims to improve the health status of displaced and conflict-affected communities, through integrated primary health care provided in 55 IDP camps and villages in Sittwe, Rathedaung, Mruak-U and Kyauktaw townships through 1 IRC mobile team and 3 RCHWA Back Pack Health Worker Teams (BPHWT). This includes integrated primary, and sexual reproductive health (SRH) care services, cash assistance for life-saving emergency referrals community health education including COVID-19 risk communication nutrition screening and services and GBV clinical care. Services will be available for patients regardless of ethnicity, religion or individual disparities, prioritizing groups like pregnant and lactating women, children, adolescent girls, elderly people and PWDs. This is aligned to the health cluster SRP for Rakhine under the COVID-19 crisis and leverages existing funded activities. In response to COVID-19 in Rakhine, IRC will ensure the continuity of life-saving PHC services across IDP camps and conflict affected villages, ensuring appropriate adaptation of infection, prevention, and control measures.
 
IRC, with Rakhine Ethnics Congress (REC), will implement protection monitoring across 5 targeted townships &#x2013; Kyauktaw, Minbya, Mrauk-U, Myebon and Ponnagyun - focused on the identification of at risk PWDs, facilitating their access to appropriate follow up support. IRC will provide technical leadership, systematizing data collection and building capacity around identification of PWDs, aligned to protection sector priorities. Protection monitoring will also gather information on the overall environment and needs of populations in different locations for further tailored response.  
 
WASH activities will meet the water, sanitation and hygiene needs of newly displaced IDPs in Myebon, particularly in communities with very few response actors. IRC will leverage localized networks of volunteers and will promote positive hygiene and sanitation among IDPs. Hygiene materials and sanitation facilities will be constructed and rehabilitated to ensure safe access for displaced populations, including women, girls, and PWDs. Where possible, IRC will promote a cash based response where possible.. WASH activities will target locations where IRC has been working for more than 7 years, and builds on existing capacity and networks in hard to reach locations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine Community Health Workers Association (RCHWA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine Ethnic Congress</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Naomi Rennard</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director - Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 (0) 9892272908</telephone>
   <email>Naomi.Rennard@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zaw Zw Htun</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator - REC</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+9509421741255</telephone>
   <email>khaingkyawmrat@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khaing Myo San</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager &#x2013; RCHWA</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09772628868</telephone>
   <email>Myonada04@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR012">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.50000000 94.00000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="35" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-14">232692.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-14">467307.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-16799">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-14">700000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304739199">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-17">280000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
