<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-nigeria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="21" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-15T03:05:40.137" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-03T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-20/NIG_ERF/SA1/N/INGO/16551</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce mortality associated with acute malnutrition among children, Pregnant and Lactating Women in the context of Covid19 in Magumeri and Bama LGAs, Borno State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS is a non-profit humanitarian organization that is committed to working at the frontline to bring humanitarian assistance to people in danger, victims of natural disasters and armed conflicts. INTERSOS has been implementing integrated multi-sector lifesaving and protection interventions in the proposed project sites since July 2017.

Within Magumeri LGA, INTERSOS is proposing to continue the existing mutual collaborations with the State Ministry of Health (SMoH) and the nutrition sector by prioritizing and strengthening the scale-up of SC treatment of SAM with complications among U5 children. INTERSOS will continue to provide SC operational and technical support, as well as the procurement of therapeutic formulae milk, drugs, and equipment required for timely and effective management of U5 SAM with complications at the SC hosted within Magumeri general hospital. In addition, through the already established outreach OTP sites, INTERSOS will continue to cover 7 accessible wards within the H2R remote areas in Magumeri and Gajiganna. In particular, Kashia/Ardoram (810 HHs), Malanari (550 HHs) and Talwari-Gajiganna (1,075 HHs) are currently covered with NHF funding support to INTERSOS. INTERSOS will continue to provide operational and technical support to these OTP sites, including the provision of RUTF, drugs and equipment for timely and effective management of SAM without complication. 

In Bama, INTERSOS will partner with UNICEF to continue providing operational and technical support 1 OTP site in the GSSSC IDP camp, including the RUTF, drugs and equipment for timely and effective management of SAM without complication. INTERSOS has signed a new Partnership Commitment Agreement (PCA) with UNICEF on June 03 2020 to benefit from the UNICEF&#x2019;s supply RUFT. INTERSOS will continue to refer SAM with complications to the IRC supported SC in Bama host community. INTERSOS operates a PHC facility within the IDP camp, and remains the main health actor in this camp.

Through the adapted family MUAC approach and the robust network of INTERSOS&#x2019; supported CNMs, Mother-to-Mother Support Groups (MtMSGs) and Father-to-Father Support Groups (FtFSGs), INTERSOS will reinforce timely screening and referral of cases from the communities to service provision facilities. All activities will be undertaken in line with the nutrition sector guidelines for management of child acute malnutrition in the context of COVID-19, including mainstreaming social distancing, risk communication, hygiene promotion, screening and referral to testing and treatment centers. In addition, GBV risk mitigation, and child protection will be harnessed by ensuring indiscriminate service provision and continuous engagements of primary care givers and the community participatory Infant and Young Child Feeding (IYCF) best practices and approaches. 

The proposed interventions adopt a community centered rights-based approach that will strengthen the existing collaborations, and foster accountability and ownership at all levels, right from the target beneficiaries, local leaders, State level leaders, INGOs and UN agencies operating within the same sectors in the framework of the 2020 Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) and the overarching 2019-2021 Humanitarian Response Strategy (HRS) as was agreed with the Government of Nigeria. To this end, INTERSOS will continue to strengthen community-based complaints and feedback mechanism that will allow women, girls, men, and boys to safely report concerns of the emergency nutrition response in the NHF supported health facilities. 

These interventions will not be implemented standalone, but rather to complement, supplement, and foster synergies with other humanitarian efforts by INTERSOS, INGOs, government, and UN agencies operating in the areas. INTERSOS is implementing multisectoral project funded by OFDA in both Magumeri and Bama.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ali Hussain Syed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234 (0) 7019528888</telephone>
   <email>nigeria@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stanley Asaku</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Programmes Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234 (0) 9011950781</telephone>
   <email>programco.nigeria@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Africa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>andrea.dominici@intersos.org</telephone>
   <email>Andrea Dominici</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Dauda Lamin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Finance Coordinator (CFC)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(234) 9016212166</telephone>
   <email>admin.nigeria@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-01">179720.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-01">224279.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-16551">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-01">404000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304722842">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-03">242400</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
