<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="16" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-11T03:07:04.253" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/FSAC/NGO/17888</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YHF 1st  SA Priority 2: Emergency Life-Saving Food Assistance to 700 HHs of the Most Vulnerable Acutely Food Insecure IDPs in Al-Mina District of Al-Hudayda Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a 12-month project to assist 700 HHs 4900 individual (960 men, 1000 women, 1440 boys,1500 girls) of the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs living with host families. The intervention aims to increase access to immediate life-saving emergency food assistance to IDPs in the targeted district, to meet their basic food needs, adhering to FSAC minimum standards through form of cash or value vouchers. It contributes to:
- Response to the YHF 1st SA and aligned with 2020 HRP SO: Priority 2: Covering gaps in clusters&#x2019; ongoing emergency response for people in acute need.

- Cluster SO 1 Increase access to food for highly vulnerable families in Al Mina District of Al-Hudaydah. 
It is designed in line with AAP, gender mainstreaming and protection commitments endorsed by FSAC. The district is chosen due to the gap of humanitarian assistance of food security targeting the most vulnerable acutely food insecure IDPs living with host families. They are newly displaced people during the past 3 months. The activities achieve the overall goal will include:

- Coordination with concerned authorities, more specifically SCMCHA at different levels in addition to other local authorities like the Governor and local council to approve and facilitate the implementation.
The team will coordinate with FSAC Al Hudaydah Hub regularly and FSAC partners to know the presence of other partners and avoid any duplication.
- Establish Food Management Community Committee to ensure meaningful participation of beneficiaries and targeted communities. It will include representative from beneficiaries, men, women, acceptable by beneficiaries, disabilities and they all volunteers. 
- Transparence process of beneficiaries Registration and Verification applying FSAC endorsed household vulnerability and targeting criteria taking COVID-19 measurement procedures to avoid transmission of COVID-19. It will be 100% verification door to door process considering exclusion errors.
- Conduct Market Assessment to ensure strong engagement of targeted communities/beneficiaries. # IDPs men, women, boys, girls, the elderly, and disabilities will be consulted to understand their needs and preferences for location and assistance modality cash or value voucher. 
- Baseline survey will also be conducted to assess the food insecurity status before the intervention for the targeted beneficiaries and endline to assess the level of improvement after the intervention.
- Beneficiaries complaints feedback mechanism is in place to improving programming, assisting in understanding beneficiary and community perceptions, promoting beneficiary empowerment and assisting in the early detection of problems such as targeting, misconduct. During execution, regular progress updates on project indicators to be achieved challenges/how the challenges are dealt with, result of BCFM and how they were handled.
- The targeted beneficiaries will receive 6 rounds of cash or value voucher assistance that allow them to meet their basic food needs confirming FSAC minimum standard.
YLDF team has assess the risks and develop mitigation plan will be as follow 
-The security situation and late issuing of the project permits, will be mitigated through recruiting team from Al-Hudayda and close coordination with the authorities on ground.
-Conflict between host communities and IDPs because of targeting IDPs in the targeted district. This will be discussed and coordinated with Food Management Community Committee and local concerned authorities.
-Exponential transmission of COVID-19. This will be mitigated through following applying COVID-19 measurement to avoid.
- Inflation costs and exchange rate will make procurement difficult and budget management will be a challenge. This will be mitigated through monthly market monitoring.
YLDF has strong access to AlHudayda and currently is implementing Cash for Work and Child Protection projects. YLDF is implementing Cash and Voucher projects in many diff</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nawal Dubais</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>735790177</telephone>
   <email>ndobais@yldf.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ali Al-Maznai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sr. FSL Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>777962089</telephone>
   <email>aalmaznai@yldf.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-21">464424.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-21">18576.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17888">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-21">483001.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="304915006-5007">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">193200.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
