<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-sudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="5" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-30T03:07:15.387" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-12T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/ RA5/WASH/INGO/17952</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life-saving humanitarian assistance in Water, Sanitation and Hygiene for Ethiopian Refugees and hosting communities at Hamdayet Border Reception Centre and Hamdayet Village in Kassala State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the leadership of and in coordination with UNHCR RCF, COOPI intends to scale up the ongoing emergency response in WASH in Hamdayet Border Reception Centre as well as within the hosting community of Hamdayet Village. According to UNHCR Situation Update, at 11.12.2020, an estimated 22,559 refugees are still stationed in Hamdayet waiting to be transferred to Um Rakouba Camp and other designated Camps by UNHCR. A field visit was conducted on 15/12/20 and COOPI team reports that no more than 15,000 refugees are stable settled in Hamdayet while the balance moved around to neighboring villages. Although in December the average number of new refugees reaching Hamdayet Border Post dropped from almost 2,000 daily of November to 434 of December (source: UNHCR), the slow progress of the refugees&apos; transfers from the Reception Centre to Um Rakouba Camp (an average of 658 refugees per trip since the beginning of the crisis) has created a significant backlog of refugees still stationed in Hamdayet. Furthermore, the decision by the Government of Sudan to move all the refugees previously scattered between the river, Hamdayet Village and the Reception Centre, and concentrate the refugees&apos; population at the Reception Centre only has created a crisis by overstretching existing WASH services, highlighting an emergency need for additional shelters and shading areas.The first emergency response provided by COOPI since the onset of the crisis was designed to address the contingent needs of a smaller population of refugees. 
Given the current situation, it is urgent to scale up the response and ensure that life-saving WASH services - with particular focus on the supply of clean and drinkable water and other sanitation services - are scaled up to meet this significantly increased demand. As such, in agreement with UNHCR, the intervention will involve the following activities: 

(1.) Scale up the daily water supply provided by COOPI through water trucking, by increasing the daily number of trips of the water tankers and by adding an additional tractor to the service, including water filtering (to reduce the turbidity level), chlorination and regular water testing and quality control. This will ensure the supply of 75k liters of drinkable water for the current demand to an estimation of 10.000 refugees stationed in the Reception Centre (7.5 liters of drinkable water per refugee per day).
The proposal includes the installation of an emergency filter station as pre-treatment for the water pumped from the river, the increase of water storage capacity and water distribution points and the upgrade of the existing ones. COOPI will conduct among the communities of refugees who will transit in the Reception Centre hygiene promotion and community mobilization activities to promote safe hygiene and health-seeking behaviors during their staying. The service of Water trucking will continue up to the completion of the rehabilitation of the Water Station in Hamdayet by COOPI and the construction of the new Water Station by UNICEF. 


(2) Build 2 blocks of VIP latrines (following WASH cluster design and recommendation) in critical infrastructures like schools, health centers, etc. 
(3) Construction and installation of 20 Hand Washing Facilities (HWFs) at the capacity of 500 liters each &quot;hands-free model&quot; placed strategically in critical Reception Centre as well as Village infrastructures to enhance Covid-19 prevention 
(4) Provision of 2000 laundry basins and essential washing supplies 
(5) Set-up a solid waste management and disposal system comprising of 15 collection points, tractors for the waste removal, and disposal/incineration in dedicated pits. Conduct community sensitization to raise awareness about garbage disposal.
(6) Build 3 additional emergency communal shelters and construct 5 shading areas for refugees stationing at the Reception Centre and Dist</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione Internazionale - COOPI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione Internazionale - COOPI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andrea Lorenzetti</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249900910603</telephone>
   <email>programs.sudan@coopi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Michele Angeletti</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249900910600</telephone>
   <email>hom.sudan@coopi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kassala</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.45000000 36.40000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">10385.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-26"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">617914.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-17952">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">628299.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione Internazionale - COOPI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304869849">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-12">376979.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione Internazionale - COOPI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
