<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="28" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-27T03:06:34.167" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-18T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/WASH/NGO/17327</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency lifesaving and sustainable WASH services to the flood-affected most vulnerable and underserved communities living in Belet Weyne district of Hiran Region, Hirshabelle State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The impact of the ongoing flooding compounded by economic and social impacts of COVID-19 escalated conflict, and forecast of below-average Gu rainfall from October to December 2020 may result in further deterioration of humanitarian outcomes for affected communities through 2021. The floods have been triggered by heavy, above-average rainfall locally and in upstream areas in the Ethiopian highlands and have affected Gedo, Hiraan, Middle Juba, and Middle and Lower Shabelle regions. The floods have been triggered by heavy, above-average rainfall locally and in upstream areas in the Ethiopian highlands and have affected Gedo, Hiraan, Middle Juba, and Middle and Lower Shabelle regions. The floods temporarily displaced households to higher grounds in several prone areas including Belet Weyne. The recurrent floods have inundated the roads, WASH infrastructures, crops, houses and etc. A cholera outbreak fueled by limited access to safe drinking water, poor sanitation, and displacement has already been reported in some of the flood-affected districts, underscoring the need for urgent repair and rehabilitation to damaged WASH infrastructure and the provision of clean water. More cases of acute watery diarrhea (AWD) are being reported in children under five years old, who are particularly vulnerable to disease, especially if their immune systems are compromised by malnutrition. Thus, in this project, AADSOM will improve access to safe water, sanitation facilities and promote good hygiene practices to reduce the negative impacts of the flood in the Belet Weyne town and 9 villages in Belet Weyne district to 19,000 women, men, boys, and girls including people with disabilities, minorities and most vulnerable underserved communities. Key activities AADSOM would like to undertake within this project the following WASH services:
Water:
- Provision of safe water to 1,000 households representing 6,000 men, women and children affected population through water vendors (water trucking) by using Water Voucher (WV) 
- Rehabilitation/construction of 29 flood-damaged shallow wells with hand pumps.
- Establishment and capacity building training to gender-balanced 29 WASH committees and 58 Well Operators shared equally by men and women, to ensure continuity of service, operation, and maintenance, coupled training on DDR and conflict resolution mechanisms as cross-cutting

Hygiene and Sanitation:
Lack of access to adequate and appropriate sanitation and hygiene poses a serious threat to public health. The practice of open defecation is a leading cause of fecal-oral transmission of diseases with children being the most vulnerable. A safe and appropriate latrine accompanied by handwashing with soap provides an effective barrier to the transmission of diseases. The provision of appropriate facilities for defecation is also an essential response for people&#x2019;s dignity, safety, health, and well-being. To improve safe access to sanitation it is necessary to meet standards of privacy and safety of women and girls against GBV using sanitation structures that are locally or culturally acceptable. never the less, the disabilities will be given a special design that is appropriate and acceptable for use. in this project, AADSOM will: 

- Conduct comprehensive hygiene promotion campaigns to reach 19,000 men, women, boys, and girls through visiting house to house, schools, health centers, and feeding centers 
-Train 10 community hygiene promoters (5 men and 5 women), who will carry out hygiene promotion activities during and after the project is faced out 
-Distribute of 1,000 HP kits to 1,000 households with vulnerable men, women, and children, and
- Construct 263 gender-sensitive and flood-proof latrines for the most affected community including latrines for disabled people in ensuring the sustainability of the latrines during floods.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulet Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722800129</telephone>
   <email>info@aadsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-05">212707.83</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-05">287293.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17327">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-05">500001.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304788131">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-16">300000.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304914659">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-18">200000.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
