<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="17" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-11T02:04:43.823" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-19T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-20/DDA-3558/COVID 19 RA/COVID-19/NGO/15814</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support preparedness and response to COVID19 in Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at supporting preparedness and response to COVID19 in Syria, especially in Damascus and Rural Damascus, 
Activities will include:

- Procure medical supplies and PPEs to support Altamayoz&#x2019;s health workers at Almidan center and harasta for 5months as a continuation of work beyond June 2020. and to support another center for AlTamayoz in Rural Damascus and 7 NGOs who provide health services and lack the needed support to maintain safe environment while providing service during COVID-19 . 5 out of those centers are in Rural Damascus and 5 are in Damascus. health workers, and awareness raising facilitators  will also be provided with PPEs, the total number of those who will be provided with PPEs is 400 person The facilities that will be supported with disinfectants are the those of the 7 NGOs in addition to 3 facilities for AlTamayoz which  provide health services. This activity will be according to pillar No. 6 of health sector response plan which is infection prevention and control.
- Awareness raising on protection issues (GBV and CP) and on health issues (prevention of COVID-19) through outreach Volunteers as well as at AlTamayoz centers in Damascus and Rural Damascus (Harasta and Saqbq). Awareness will be done by using remote methods (Whats App groups, SMS, Facebook,.), or by one person to one person approach, it will also target pregnant and lactating women. During this activity, women who are observed to have protection risks will be provided with dignity kits and pregnant and lactating women kits. awareness raising providers of one to one will follow prevention measures and will be supported with PPEs. Volunteers will receive trainings on COVID19 awareness

- Provide cash assistance to the most vulnerable population to alleviate negative socio-economic impacts of COVID-19 on them. the exact outcome of cash distribution is to support women who are most at risk of GBV and exploitation (women households, GBV survivors, the victim of early marriage or domestic violence, or have family member with disabilities or elderly, or she or her children has critical or  chronic disease) and protect them from exploitation and abuse and reduce the amplification of violence risks they are exposed to due to the current situation. Most women who are the households and not able to work during the current curfew are exposed to domestic violence, and many of them are at risk of engaging in harmful coping mechanism, this was observed during our remote contact with women who were approaching women and girls&#x2019; safe spaces (WGSS) supported by UNFPA. 
Cash money distribution follows the following steps:
1-choose the most vulnerable families according to vulnerability criteria (Women headed households, GBV survivor, families with one or more persons with disability or specific needs, women who or her children have health or psychological problems (domestic violence,..), families who have one or more elderly persons, girls households (early marriage))
2-A printed list will be prepared for the chosen families, it will contain the name, and the amount each family will receive in addition to a special space for fingerprint to prove money receive. Another validation method is an electronic fingerprint.
3- the fixed amount of money is prepared in the financial department and under supervision of the treasurer and the financial manager, each amount is put in a closed envelop. The financial process is also well organized and under control of internal policies
4- cash distribution will be done in AlTamayoz center,  and could be done in Women and girls safe spaces supported by UNFPA in AlMidan,Dummar and Harasta  to support 200 women with the amount equal to 75 $ per month. the distribution will be done along with maintaining the physical distance between beneficiaries.
5- In case the women couldn&apos;t reach any of  AlTamayoz facilitoes, then AlTamayoz will manage to do distribution via mobile team with maintaining the needed documentation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-11" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nariman Alhamoui</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prpject Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0968886022</telephone>
   <email>nariman@t-tamayoz.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kinana Santeer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accountant</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0944278949</telephone>
   <email>Kinana@t-tamayoz.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY01">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Damascus</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.51717500 36.27671000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Damascus</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.32451400 36.21611100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-13">385352.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-13">24644.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-15814">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-13">409997.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304683162">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-30">327997.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304915982">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-19">81999.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
