<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="124" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-09T02:06:15.977" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-08T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/H/NGO/16197</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing essential life saving health services for most vulnerable people in NW Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to continue and sustain the accessibility to essential life-saving health services to address the dire and immediate increasing needs of health services for all age and sex groups boys, girls, women, and men, with attention to people with special needs physical disability, elderly, people with chronic diseases and psychosocial problems without any sexual discrimination, among IDPs and host communities, in NW Syria, Where the project will provide health services for 36325 beneficiaries (19979 IDPs and 16346 HCs) (12950 men, 12680 women, 5270 boys, 5425 girls) (1090 PWDs) including all age groups children, adolescences, young adults, middle-aged adults, and older adults.
These objectives will be achieved by continue supporting the already existed and functioning Harim General hospital (HeRAMS code G0703149) managed by SDI, located in Harim city in Harim subdistrict which overwhelmed and crowded with new arrivals, this hospital is already funded by SCHF and this project aims to continue this support to continue providing essential health care services involving the following services: 

Providing surgical, trauma, injury care, minor and major surgeries resulting from war and non-war injuries with attention to acute medical emergencies requiring immediate surgical intervention.
Providing outpatient consultations services involving internal and surgical medicine.

Providing hospitalizing and inpatients services involving internal and surgical medicine.
Providing intensive health care services through support ICU. 
Providing prevention and control of NCDs, provide an adaptive response that is required to account for the needs of people with NCDs according to NCD- COVID 19 guideline. 
Management of communicable diseases (CD).
provision of essential medicines, medical supplies, and equipment for direct bene&#xFB01;ciaries.
Integrate WASH services, particularly medical waste management, save water provision, hand hygiene resources, etc.
Integrate PSS services through conduct awareness sessions about mental health issues and aspects related to COVID 19 response.
Ensure referral pathways for cases that need further management.

SDI will continue providing the hospital with running costs, the essential salaries for hospital staff, and emergency maintenance costs, SDI will ensure that the hospital will continue to operate, staff will be retained, referrals will be followed and health services will continue to be provided to people in need.

In addition, this project aims to continue supporting Afrin blood bank (HeRAMS Code B0203082) located in Afrin city. 
The only blood bank that covers Afrin district in Aleppo governorate, monthly it provides blood components involving (complete blood units, concentrated red blood cells, blood plasma, and platelets) for 350 patients including women, men, boys, and girls. These blood components are provided to the health facilities located in the Afrin district then will be transfusion to the patients under health providers monitoring.
The cases supported include major surgeries, acute hemolytic anemia, acute hemorrhages, chronic anemia, thalassemia, as well as normal and C-section delivery, among others.
SDI will continue providing the blood bank with running costs and medical and laboratory supplies. 

Regarding responding to COVID 19 pandemic, the project will contribute in the response to prevent or limit transmissions of COVID 19 in NW Syria through capacity building of health workers to strengthen their skill in IPC and triage procedures, providing extra personal protective equipment and applying precautions measures to protect the staff and patients in accordance to triage and IPC- COVID-19 guideline and standard operating procedures, also raising awareness of the beneficiaries and their caregivers to applying precautions measures at the community and facility levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-HEA-163933-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">514939.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">509311.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16197">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">1024250.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304667984">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">614550.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
