<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="10" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-16T02:07:36.583" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-18T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA1/H/INGO/15926</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribute to address the increased need of primary Health care services among girls, boys, women including Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW) and men who are identified as the most vulnerable communities in six districts of Afar and Amhara Region, Ethiopia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Owing to the current worsening situation in some pocket areas of Amhara like Waghemra Zone and Afar Zone one and Zone two which is resulted from extended dry spell induced drought with previously unresolved humanitarian gap coupled with the current COVID-19 pandemic related issues and limited capacity of the local health system to respond to the increased primary health care services need Plan International proposed this immediate lifesaving response project to address the immediate Health amp Nutrition needs of girls, boys, women and men among the targeted communities in Sekota, Dehana and Zequala districts of Wag-hemra Zoen, Amhara Region and Dubti town, Afdera and Berhale districts of Afar Region. This proposed project aims to contribute to the reduction of mortality and morbidity among targeted communities through maximizing and expanding geographic coverage and accesses to primary Health care amp Nutrition services. 


This intervention will focus on improving the health status of boys and girls under 5 and Pregnant and Lactating Mothers (PLWs) affected by the impacts of the drought. IYCF, WASH, child protection and disability inclusion activities will be integrated through mainstreaming approach to further enable mothers, fathers and care givers to better care for the nutritional status of boys and girls while also supporting the greater protection of children against increased risks created by the drought emergency. As the WaSH situation is also critical in light of COVID-19, Plan International Ethiopia will support the local government to maximize access to key messages on COVID-19 and Hygiene and sanitation through regular community engagement and promotion activities with focusing on Infection Prevention Control (IPC), hygiene and sanitation at critical times.


Therefore, Plan International Ethiopia will support 50 health facilities to identify, refer and treat the top five diseases. One team/woreda is planned and they will be responsible to capacitate 8-10 HF. Health Centers will be provided with technical and logistical support, including transport of essential medical and none medical supplies from Zone to district health offices as well as to lower health facilities to successfully equip primary health care services and provide necessary follow up. Health Workers and Health Extension Workers will receive in-service technical supports by Plan Int`l field team and district health offices experts. Also the primary health care system will be strengthened through provision of emergency drugs and establishment of Oral Rehydration Therapy (ORT) corners. Also, disease outbreak prevention related to COVID-19 including hygiene and sanitation promotion will be tailored with other ongoing efforts by the local government and other actors. Moreover, Plan Int`l will support district health office on COVID-19 prevention measures including ensuring availability of clean water through trucking water particularly in water scarce areas like Afdera and Berhale districts. 
Moreover, Plan Int`l will facilitate joint supportive supervisions to provide on the job coaching to the Health Workers and Health Extension Workers for strengthening their ability to implement the skills learned on primary health care services and provide enhanced services to boys and girls of under-five age children and PLWs. Mothers, fathers and care givers will further be given orientation on Infant and Young Child Feeding (IYCF) and positive parenting to increase their knowledge and ability to follow best feeding practices using the opportunities of supplementary food distribution program and Out-Patient Therapeutic Feeding Programmes (OTP) days. . To support this, IYCF demonstration kits will also be supplied to the Health Centers to aid the orientation of parents and care givers. Besides, IYCF will be strongly linked with other health and Nutrition activities through building the capacities of HWs and HEWs on IYCF during in-service coaching,</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geraldine Breukers</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-115571916</telephone>
   <email>Geraldine.Breukers@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamirat Ketema</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition in Emergency Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251912108999</telephone>
   <email>tamirat.ketema@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zufan Menbere</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BDD Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251920746672</telephone>
   <email>Zufan.Menbere@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.77273098 12.03628232</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amhara</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.04353749 11.56495271</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-11">112563.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-11">37521.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-15926">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-11">150085.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304644712">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-18">150085.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
