<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="69" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-03T02:05:55.933" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-25T16:26:01.157" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-20/DDA-3558/SA1/P/NGO/17091</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance protection services to affected population in Rural Damascus</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims at supporting the affected populations in Rural Damascus with a comprehensive protection assistance through an integrated and community-based approach.
AlTamayoz has existing operational presence and considered as a trustworthy NGO in Rural Damascus because of the several qualitative services it provides to people in need.

AlTamayoz in now running a project under SHF 2019 in 4 locations, the actual work on the ground showed the huge need for protection services which exceeded our expectations, therefore, part of this project will be as a continuation of the activities in 2 locations (Duma and Harasta &#x2013; severity scale:4) to enable more people benefit from the essential services. 
This project is planned to start in November 2020 due to the time needed to get the necessary approvals, and this will make part of this project run in parallel with the currently running project for 2 months, during this period the activities will be implemented in 2 shifts and will target different population to avoid duplication. Implementing the new activities in facilities already operational will help benefiting from the already existing furniture and equipment and will support sustainability.

New centers are planned to be in some of the eligible location in Rural Damascus in the allocation strategy which are: Ein Tarma, and Zabadani,.
Centers in all locations will act as a space where affected people especially women and girls will be able to express and exchange concerns and experiences and receive appropriate services. Centers will also be as safe spaces where children can interact with peers and where specific needs of children are met , it will be as a tool to identify children with specific protection concerns and provide them with needed psychosocial support and case management
Planned activities will be under 4 main objectives of protection sector:
1- Improve protection of population affected by the crisis through community-based and individually targeted protection interventions and through advocacy with duty bearers
2- Survivors have access to quality and lifesaving GBV response services and measures are in place to prevent and mitigate risks of GBV
3- Reduce the impact of explosive hazards
4- Increased and more equitable access for boys and girls to quality child protection interventions in targeted locations
Activities will include: 
- Conduct awareness raising sessions regarding general protection issues
- Provide persons with specific protection needs with PSS case management
- Support 12 community led initiatives, 50 beneficiaries will benefit from each initiative including children, women, youth and vulnerable elderly
- Support Women and girls with GBV case management services
- Train 15 GBV actors on GBV
- Conduct awareness raising activities regarding GBV issues
- Support women and girls with empowerment activities (Vocational training)
- conduct PSS activities for women and girls at risk with focus on women and gilrs with disabilities and adolescent girls
- Conduct risk education sessions
- Train 10 actors to conduct risk education
- Support affected children (boys and girls) with child protection case management
- Establish adults and child committees
- Conduct awareness raising sessions on topics related to child protection
- Engage parents in parenting program
- Support affected children with psychosocial support
Activities will be implemented in all locations with a note that GBV services will not be included in Harasta to avoid duplication in services provision.
All activities in all centers will be conducted while taking into consideration COVID-19 preventive measures to maintain the safety of staff and hygiene of the centers.
Through this project, AlTamayoz will target 19330 beneficiaries (men. Women, boys and girls) in 4 locations</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-PRO;PRO-CPN;PRO-GBV;PRO-MIN-164548-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nariman Alhamoui</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0968886022</telephone>
   <email>nariman@t-tamayoz.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Damascus</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.32451400 36.21611100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-25">418937.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-25">81040.36</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-17091">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-25">499977.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Altamayoz Project for Orphan Sponsorship / Social Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
