<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="35" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-15T03:06:27.19" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/Health-SHNFI/NGO/17899</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Parameter 2: Provision of Integrated essential lifesaving Health services and Shelter assistance to IDPs and most vulnerable groups in hosting communities at Ma&#x2019;arib and Al-Dhale&#x2019;e Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In line with the priority two of 2020 1st SA Strategy paper and clusters objectives, YFCA over the project duration of ten months is planning to implement this integrated comprehensive Health and Shelter interventions to cover the gaps in accessing and utilization of the Minimum Service Package (MSP) and Shelter assistance for people in acute need in areas of high displacement to estimated 69,000 individuals (Both IDPs and host communities). 19,014 are IDPs (3,727 men,3,879 women, 5,590 boys, and 5,818 girls) at the targeted three districts ( Qa&apos;atabah district of Al Dhale&apos;e Governorate, Ma&#x2019;arib city and Ma&apos;arib district of Ma&apos;arib Governorate) and 46,760 are most vulnerable affected communities hosting IDPs ( 9,165 men, 9,539 women, 13,747 boys, and 14,308 girls) plus 3,227 PWDs ( 645 men, 640 women, 937 boys and 1005 girls ) to whom some specific health services will be addressing children such as IMCI and immunization services while RH services will be addressing women in reproductive ages and the rest elements of MSP services such as emergency and trauma care, CDs and NCDs cases management will be cross cutting covering the different age and gender groups. 

For the Health sector, two modalities will be used to address both the IDPs amp host community&#x2019;s priority needs during the COVID-19 outbreak by maintaining and enhancing HFs functionality and their role in the provision of life-saving health services in the context of Covid-19 , enhancing people accessibility and healthcare services utilization as well as for better sustainability. The first modality is the provision of essential and emergency lifesaving health care services in fixed two HFs ( two hospitals).The targeted hospitals are (Al Shaheed Mohammed hail in Marib city and Al Salam hospital in Qa&#x2019;atabah district of Al-Dhale&#x2019;e Governorate). This kind of services will serve the beneficiaries at the first level of HF catchment area, whereas the second and third levels will be covered via the second modality which is two  emergency mobile medical teams (EMMTs) outreach activities to serve the existing IDPs sites and to cover any gaps in the IDPs response. The targeted 2 EMMTs and 2 HFs will be provided with the suitable needed medicines, medical supplies, necessary equipment and laboratory solutions, while the capacity building of health workers is still one of the main pillar of this project towards serve sustainable services in health sector after project end. 

Shelter activities will be provided to IDPs at collective centers and among host communities in Ma&apos;arib district through the implementation of lifesaving and life-sustaining activities: provision of core NFI kits, NFI bedding kits, Emergency Shelter kits amp the provision of flood mitigation solutions in the shape of sand bags giving priority in providing assistance to the disabled people, female amp child headed households, GBV survivors, children, elderly persons and PWSNs. 
Coordination with health cluster, Shelter cluster, Local authorities, GHOs and DHOs has already done to support and facilitate the assessment and the planned interventions and to avoid any duplication with other partners. All stakeholders will be coordinated during the implementation of activities with focus on strengthening the stewardship of local authorities to enable them performing in more effective and efficient ways.

The designed approach in this project is guided by clear findings of multiple RNA assessment that had been conducted at the targeted districts. 

Qa&apos;atabah district is located at areas belongs to Aden hub where YFCA has the second biggest office and also a program implementation unit in Al-Dhalea governorate while the rest 2 districts in Ma&apos;arib will be followed up by Marib focal points, Sana&#x2019;a office, and Hadhramout office as backstopping if needed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nabil Al Ammari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>774090200</telephone>
   <email>n.alammari@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr.Nadeem Al-Aizari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health and Nutrition Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>776511525</telephone>
   <email>n.aizari@yfca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Dhale&apos;e</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.85996808 44.67423913</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marib</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.56841151 45.76081505</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="65" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="35" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-08">1244079.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17899">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-08">1244079.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304914995-4996">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">497631.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Family Care Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
