<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="51" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-08T02:07:19.76" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA2FT/WASH/INGO/17274</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency support to public WASH service providers in Gaza to reduce public health risks related to Covid-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is directly contributing to the WASH Cluster&#x2019;s 1st objective: &#x201C;Support the local institutions, vulnerable communities and families to apply the required WASH protection and responsive measures against COVID 19 outbreak, to decrease the morbidity and mortality associated to the epidemic&#x201D;. It  is linked to the HRP SO 2 &#x201C;The basic needs of vulnerable Palestinians living under occupation are met through the provision of quality basic services and improved access to resources, in accordance with the rights of protected persons under IHL.&#x201C; Furthermore, the 2nd objective of this allocation strategy is to &#x201C;support the implementation of the COVID-19 Response Plan&#x201D;. The project will also respond to the different appeals received from the Gaza Strip Municipalities, the Coastal Municipal Water Utility (CMWU), and the Ministry of Local government (MoLG) to support their capacity to mitigate against the health risks related to the COVID 19 epidemic, and to ensure that WASH facilities will continue to  function in case of further deterioration of the situation. This project will mainly support  WASH service providers in the communities most affected by the virus, which were recently announced as red-zone areas (Gaza and North Gaza governorates). Nevertheless, the project will be flexible to respond to the needs of other communities  across the Gaza Strip in case of further spreading of the virus. This project will support public WASH facilities, already stressed by the increased water consumption, in maintaining safe and sufficient drinking water to reduce public health risks, and will equip the water, wastewater, and solid waste management staff by hygiene, disinfection, and protective materials and tools to ensure the sustainability of essential pubic services by:   


1) providing sodium hypochlorite solution and chemicals for the disinfection of the water produced by 132 water wells, and for the water treatment in 17 public desalination plants (DSs) to improve  water quality 


2) providing basic disinfection, hygiene, protective materials and tools to 1,114 staff working at 272 water, wastewater, and solid waste management facilities in 8 municipalities across Gaza and North Gaza governorates to ensure that emergency workers are safe and well equipped to respond to the C-19 outbreak.  

This project will address the most urgent and acute needs of public WASH service providers based on two detailed assessments, prepared by NRC between July and September 2020 in coordination with the WASH Cluster, CMWU and municipalities. These assessments were based on the WASH responders&#x2019; reported needs and priorities, and were validated by the WASH actors and Palestinian Water Authority (PWA). The first assessment was conducted from April 2nd to July 29th, 2020. It aimed to identify the most urgent needs related to sufficient and safe drinking water, and protective measures related to the outbreak of COVID-19 in 112 CMWU and municipalities&#x2019; desalination plant (DPs) facilities in the whole of the Gaza Strip.&#x202F;The most recent assessment was conducted in September 2020 to identify the WASH service providers&#x2019; needs and gaps related to disinfection and hygiene items, protective clothing and tools. The assessment covered water, wastewater, and solid waste management facilities across all of Gaza.  

During the implementation of this project,  communities&#x2019; needs and concerns will be acknowledged and reflected with the support of NRC&#x2019;s local partner &#x201C;Improvement and Development for Communities&#x201D; (IDCO). This collaboration will ensure active community engagement by sharing information, involving key stakeholders in the design, implementation, and monitoring of the project and supporting active communication channels with the WASH service providers. This project will complement ongoing NRC projects related to the COVID-19 response targeting both the WASH service providers and vulnerable households in the whole of the Gaza Strip.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improvement and Development for Communities Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caroline Ort</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0547360786</telephone>
   <email>caroline.ort@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juan Gabriel Wells</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme Operations</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0549930429</telephone>
   <email>juan.wells@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-02">87136.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-02">262863.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-17274">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-02">349999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304795963">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-16">209999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
