<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-pakistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="13" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-20T02:05:16.587" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-21T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/H/NGO/16170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Responding to the critical  live saving health care needs of women, men, girls and boys by inclusive health care interventions in pandemic COVID-19 situation in districts of KP province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In proposed critical amp live saving primary health care project, the immediate health care needs amp concerns of women, men girls, boys and vulnerable groups, in wake of COVID-19 Pandemic situation, were identified through exploring gaps in need and resources available in communities, Districts health departments current capacity for infection prevention amp control for safe access to primary health care services and their need requests(attached), prior assessments done by other stake holders in KP Province, and on the basis of organization practical experience (managing own hospitals in current pandemic situation in target districts with the consent of health authorities in provision of services under the SOPs, guidelines and protocols for COVID-19 ensuring infection  prevention amp control protocols and maintaining social distancing and identification of patient through diagnostic kits and there referral), project intervention were designed to cater the needs of most vulnerable populations, especially women, adolescent girls and children and person with disabilities, with improved and sustained access to quality and timely Primary health care services in 60 BHU&#x2019;s of 3 districts (Mardan, Charssada, Bunner) of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa. The proposed project interventions will enhanced the capacity of targeted health facilities in  treatment of the patients in safe amp infection prevention amp control (IPC) environment on prevailing health conditions such as communicable and non-communicable diseases, diarrhea, dysentery, fever, cough and cold (air borne and water borne diseases), provision of Antenatal and postnatal care, safe delivery, immunization and health and hygiene awareness and education. In each Health facility COVID related 1,000 PPE kits for health staff protection and 3,000 COVID-19 diagnostic testing kits along with Disinfection materials for health facilities General Medicines, MNCH and reproductive health relevant medicines will be provided to support the continuation of health services.. To support the women and girls of the target population, a helpline will be provided for psycho-social support and MNCH support for expecting mothers. The GBV will also be managed through the helpline by providing them psychological support as well as refer them to the relevant authorities if needed.  Strong referral mechanism will be established from community to first level care facility (FLCF) amp from FLCF to secondary or tertiary level care facility by ensuring dedicated ambulance service in target communities specifically suspected maternal amp child patient. Trainings and capacity building activities will target 600 medical health workers including doctors, paramedics, LHWs, LHVs, disease surveillance officers, vaccinator amp psychologists to prevent, identify and refer the COVID patients to designated COVID treatment centers. Further 600 LHV&#x2019;s amp LHWS will receive training on Birth preparedness and prevention of complications in COVID pandemic situation. The staff will be trained amp training material will be provided on antenatal and postnatal care, safe delivery, immunization, use of modern methods of contraceptives, early detection amp prevention of childhood disabilities, efficient referral mechanism.. Moreover, in culturally appropriate manner, trained Social mobilizers/Hygiene Promoter will provide 60 awareness sessions by engagement of 300 community  stake holders and influential like religious leaders, men amp women amp elderly and person with disability representatives and CBO&apos;s amp LSO&apos;s and will be oriented to spread the COVID-19 prevention messages on IPC amp social distances in general public. The masses awareness campaign on the COVID-19  will be initiated in the targeted communities  through dissemination of IEC materials, radio messages and cable TV adverts for reduction of virus transmission and panic, improve care seeking for fever and respiratory symptoms and importance of social distancing amp protection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sameer Hussain</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03218586765</telephone>
   <email>sameer@chef.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sohail Ayaz Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03038886666</telephone>
   <email>sohail@chef.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK2">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khyber Pakhtunkhwa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.48100000 72.09020000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-01">504095.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-16170">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-01">504095.13</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304627848">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-01">403276.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304741896">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-21">100819.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comprehensive Health and Education Forum International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
