<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-sudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="8" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-27T02:06:53.893" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-01-12T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/ RA5/WASH-P/INGO/17954</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of the lifesaving emergency WASH and Child Protection services to Ethiopian refugees and host community in Um Raquba and Village 8 in Gedaref State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will provide life-saving assistance to newly arrived refugees in areas of child protection and WASH with focus on prevention and response to COVID-19. The child protection will be focusing to responding children ( (boys and girls )including adolescent affected by psychological distress through establishment of 03 Child Friendly Space (CFS) based on the CPMS in Um-Raquba and Village-8 and equip them  with play/art, stationery, furniture and engage refugees to identify capacities in their communities to support the vulnerable children and those at risk and help on functionality of the space handwashing facilities, water tanks and other working tools like megaphones will be provided to be used in CFS activities and awareness rising activities . case management including FTR and alternative care for the UASC , referrals will be provided to affected children in structural activities. Moreover,  adolescent prevision and response services  and response competitive adolescent sport teams for boys and girls will be formed and equipped with sport supplies, equipment and materials help thee in sports for peace and fair play championships. 2 women groups will be created to support on prevention and response to SGBV risks support SGBV survivors to access to appropriate services in dignified manner. Girls, women, men and boys will be reached through awareness raising on GBV prevention including early reporting and referral to available services the project will provide clear and accessible information on available complaint mechanisms to communities of concern and establish communal shelter prioritizing refugee women, girls and children in partnership with host community to identify risk areas and safer locations engage the community to explore community-based safety strategies, and enhance physical security.
About 525 Unaccompanied and Separated Children (UASC) will be supported through provision of Family Tracing and Reunification (FTR) services and alternative care support to minors placed care arrangements the support will focus on identification, registration, tracing and re-unification and part of case management to the individual cases identified in coordination with other stakeholders. 30 volunteers will support foster families on alternative arrangement, referral, and response to protection concerns. Five Community-Based Child Protection Networks will be established to monitor and risks associated to children within their communities in coordination other stakeholders. 

Capacities of staff, partner, stakeholders, volunteers and CBCPN will be strengthened to ensure they are capable to undertake their roles and responsibilities, where 30 CFS animators amp volunteers will be trained on case management, Psychological First Aid, PSS and FTR along with provision of monthly incentive to run PSS and mange UASC cases, 30 service providers will be trained on child right, protection and GBV, 20 awareness session will be conducted on child rights and protection against violence facing children, and 50 adolescents (25 male and 25 female) will be trained on life skills, peace building and gender equality staff, partner, community volunteers will be training prevention of Sexual Exploitation and Abuse (PSEA) and methods of strengthening community Engagements and Accountability (CEA) during their contact with communities.
WASH intervention will focus on the provision of re-useable face masks will be procured to the children and volunteers in CFS, 12 awareness campaign for Covid-19 prevention and reporting will be conducted using audio campaign with translation in common local Tigrinya language, distribution of IEC materials about COVID-19 prevention and protocols in Tigrinya, provision of sport supplies, equipment and materials for organization competition on COVID prevention protocol , and distribution of soaps to 3000 HHs (5 pieces of soap per HHs) to support families&#x2019; hand washing in regular bases as prevention measure.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Misgana Amanuel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BDM</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249123508852</telephone>
   <email>misgana.amanuel@plan-interntional.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedaref</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.03333300 35.38333300</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">20247.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">679751.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-17954">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-07">699999.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304869850">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-12">419999.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
