<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="113" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-02T03:06:30.933" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-10T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/16358</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">lifesaving and life-sustaining food assistance for 7679 IDPs HHs in Harim and Salqin subdistricts /Idlib for 8 months through free of charge daily bread distribution, with special attention to COVID-19 prevention and mitigation measures.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will work to serve 7679 IDPs HHs in Harim and Salqin/ Idlib accommodating in 37 locations as camps, random settlements, and collective centers. 
These BNFs will be served through the distribution of daily free-of charged 700GR bread (23 distribution day per month, 1 bread bundle per 5 family members and less, 2 bread bundle per family members 6 and more, 9214 bread bundles per day for 8 months in 11 distribution points). 


The proposed action seeks to target an estimated total of 36005 beneficiaries, of which 

10129 Boys
10166 Girls
7344 Men
8366 Women

After coordination with FSL cluster, and in aligning with FSL 4Ws reports, and gap analysis, SKT target locations are
 Idlib governorate, Harim district- Harim and Salqin sub-district in the following random settlements where the severity rate is 4
Please find the location list in the attachments. 

129 Ton of flour per month, 1643 bread bundles per ton (700 GR weigh), 211929 bundles per month baked, 9214 bundles distributed per day for 23 days per month for 36005 BNFs (7679 IDPs HH).

Project executive summary will be as follow 

1- SKT will start by announcing a tender/quotations to select the best bakery in the target area. 
2- Printing bread distribution cards with a serial number matches the SKT database.
3- Delivery the cards by hand for each HHs on a monthly basis, 
4- Complete the procurement process of needed flour from Turkey, and transfer it in collaboration with the Turkish Red Cresent. 
5- Re-handover the flour in the Zero point in Bab Alhawa gate, by SKT team to be transferred to the bakery, 
6- SKT will provide the operational cost for the bakery and the needed to provide the nylon bags.
7- Complete the distribution of bread for 23 days per month in the targeted locations for 8 months.

Quality Monitoring Activities 
SKT will monitor transferring the bread from the bakery to the distribution points (11 distribution points), through special cars prepared for bread transferring to save the quality of the bread. The distance between the bakery and the distribution points will not be more than 7 km maximum and the distance between each distribution point and the targeted beneficiaries will not be more than 1 km maximum.
The contracted volunteers will monitor and supervise the distribution process, a monitoring process will be conducted for the number of bread bundles baked-on a daily basis.

SKT MampE plan for the weight and quality of the bread bundles, and COVID-19 friendly distribution points will be followed and applied on 3 levels 

1: Bakery level by bakery officer, 
2: Distribution points by the project officer, the project assistant, and the volunteers on a daily basis,
3: All the processes by an external monitor from each camp will attend the distribution process and s/he will monitor the quality, and quantity of the bread distributed. 
Each level of the monitoring process including the external monitor will be reported on a daily basis contained signed paper will be reported to the project manager in Turkey and it will be matched all together.

 SKT will follow WFP and cluster SOP for bread distribution and update this to meet with the recommended COVID-19 prevention measures.

As prevention and mitigation measures related to COVID- 19, SKT will ensure to follow cluster&#x2019;s/ Clusters&#x2019; partner recommendations. 
1-Additional support to self-isolated beneficiaries, elderly,..etc will be provided.
2-Printing 31200 awareness leaflets and distribute it to beneficiaries and setting posters in project sites and vendor points.
3-1 hand sanitizers will be established per distribution point.
4- Masks is obligatory for all field team and vendors.

SKT field team will get access to masks, gloves, and other needed personal protection materials. SKT team will get a 2-day refreshment training session on service provision with COVID-19 prevention measures.
The project duration is 9 months (8 months distribution</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-164265-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">402183.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">197795.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16358">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">599979.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304669127">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-10">239991.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
