<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-pakistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="10" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-25T03:05:22.527" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-22T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/FS/NGO/17157</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Food Insecurity and Preserve the ability of the most vulnerable and affected peoples through Sustainable Livelihood Sources and Cash Distribution in District Jhal Magsi Tehsil Jhal Magsi UCs (Akbarabad, Kot Magsi, Safrani and Barija).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization conducted a comprehensive need assessment survey within 04 most affected union councils of District Jhall Magsi namely, Akbarabad, Kot Magsi, Safrani and Barija of Tehsil Jhall Magsi, in which we found that the selected population of the proposed intervention area is badly affected from the current pandemic disaster. The selection criteria for the aforesaid union councils was worst impact of the COVID-19 pandemic outbreak where COVID-19 cases were recorded hence, we consulted with the concerned stakeholders who further described that the selection union council residents are completely depended on livestock, agriculture and small businesses and the recent disaster have badly affected their wellbeing. Based on the findings youth organization&#x2019;s management has designed project to respond the current pandemic crises. The rapid need assessment practices conducted by Youth Organization dated on August 15-16 2020, which summaries the current situation of COVID-19 affected tehsil Jhall Magsi of District Jhall Magsi, which identifies the current and urgent needs of the affected population in Agriculture, food security, WASH, Livelihood/ERS, Nutrition and health sectors. As per instructions given by PDMA and DDMA strategy for COVID-19 response, the objective of the Assessment was to identify needs of local community needs. The project interventions will help the affected families to restore and improve their Food status, Enhance their livelihood sources, through a sustainable and more realistic approach.
Cash for land cultivation, and capacity building sessions on modern techniques of agriculture and improved agricultural based interventions while ensuring the manipulated income being generated opportunities from the livelihood interventions in the form of livestock and agriculture support, distribution of seeds and agriculture machinery for restoration of their assets and involvement of vulnerable families members for further provision of conditional food by conducting community development provision of conditional/unconditional cash assistance. Capacity building of women beneficiaries on nutrition and livelihood enhancement trainings and poultry support for both vulnerable male and female beneficiaries of the area. 
As per assessment finding conducted by YO and recommendations of Food and Agriculture cluster following activities will be conducted 
1.1. 750 Households (Male) will receive Conditional cash grant (up to Rs. 8,450/+= as per WFP Cash modality) in exchange for participating in livelihoods-enhancing activities, These cash transfers will help households meet their immediate food needs, while the livelihoods activities will support them to recover and build resilience to future shocks on the medium/ long term.
1.2. 750 Female HH will receive Food package including (92.75Kg / Household as per WFP Food Transfer modality) Containing (80Kg Wheat Flour, 4.5 liters cooking oil, 08 Pulses, 2kg Salt) in exchange for participating in livelihoods-enhancing activities, These Food transfers will help households meet their immediate food needs, while the livelihoods activities will support them to recover and build resilience to future shocks on the medium/ long term.
1.3. 1200 HH Provision of Poultry Packages including (Poultry birds 1 Cock+ 9 Hen, Poultry Feed, Poultry Kits, and Trainings on Poultry Management, Poultry production, and breeding to  increase household protein production
1.4.  Provision of 1000 Goats  Packages including (two Female Goats to 500 beneficiaries including 50kg Livestock Fodder,  Livestock management  Training to affected people to enhance their knowledge for food security and livelihood enhancement. 
1.5. Provision of Kitchen Gardening Package to 50 Female Household headed including Seasonal seeds, Fertilizers ( DAP, Urea, ) Kitchen Gardening Tool Kit, and Kitchen gardening management training of affected people to enhance their knowledge for food security and livelihood enhancement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syed Jaffer Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03130185190</telephone>
   <email>jaffar@youth.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Nomi Kaiser</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03418007884</telephone>
   <email>nomi@youth.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.32720000 65.89310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-22">263889.34</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-22">211111.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-17157">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-22">475000.82</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304748860">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">380000.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304848292">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-22">95000.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
