<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="36" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-27T02:05:44.61" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-15T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/Ed/NGO/15138</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Response  Towards Sustainable Delivery Of Equitable, Quality And Protective Education Services For Children In  Rural Baidoa, Berdale and Xudur.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The recent floods in Most parts of Bay and Bakool has resulted in massive displacements compounding the already worsened crisis brought about by the protracted effects of drought,  as well as increased fighting in certain areas of Somalia and the most recent Covid-19 pandemic which started in Wuhan in China sometime in December 2019 and has spread globally infecting more than 1.6 million people and killing over 170,000 with Somalia ,registering 274 infection and 8 deaths as at 22nd April 2020 (WHO)  has leftleaving residents of Bay and Bakool increasingly vulnerable. Destruction of school infrastructure was largely reported by the Joint Xudur Mission that included the cluster and regional parters (Inter-Agency Rapid Needs Assessment Report for IDPs and Vulnerable Host Community in Xudur town, Bakool region-Somalia 4-6 February 2019). The floods displaced learners and teachers, destroyed infrastructure and learning materials and left the residents with the risk of cholera/AWD. Abuses such as recruitment of children into militias have been reported by a number of agencies all of which gravely affect learning processes.
This project is designed to reach IDP children of school going ages in Holwadag Primary School, Misnagato IDP school, Wariri IDP School, Bakaro Yarey IDP School, Madhayto IDP school, Awdinle Primary School in Baidoa Mama Gedia, Bulow primary, Shodog primary school in Xudur and Bardaale primary school, Abubakar, Aldarein primary school, Abuhureyra, Al-Ahli and Sheikh Hamud school in Berdale all of which are in Bay and Bakool to

1) Provide immediate education and hygiene response services integrated with activities and services in response to covid-19 prevention for the most vulnerable children through provision of basic school supplies while focusing on rehabilitation of infrastructure for school damaged by floods in Xudur.
2) Increase resilience through the provision of basic education and hygiene trainings in INEE/TiCC for teachers and school management for CECs to support school-based resilience mechanisms that will contribute to the sustainability of education programs

3) Build the capacities of teachers and CECs to better respond to child protection issues and Covid-19 prevention issues as per Integrated Education and Child Protection response framework and in line with WHO guidelines on Covid-19 response.
The project targets 15 primary schools in Bay and Bakool region affected by the protracted crisis and floods in South West State. READO in response to emergency-affected learners has proposed this project to mainly retain 4684 learners (2096 girls) and 35 teachers (11 female) and 24 CECs (12 female) at school in mitigating the case of high school dropout rate following effects of prolonged drought and floods. The project will focus on the provision of quality learning opportunities through
 Provision of quality Teaching, g and Learning and Hygiene Materials in 15 public primary schools
 Water provision to 15 schools and complimentary food provision in 5 public primary schools in rural Baidoa aimed at improving the quality of learning by contributing to physical and mental growth of learners.
 Providing teacher incentives to 35 teachers and head teachers spread over the 6 targeted schools in Baidoa aimed at improving the quality of life giving an average of 49 students per teacher.
Providing protective learning environments amidst the Corona pandemic for most vulnerable learners through
 Training of 35 teachers in INEEE, Covid-19 prevention and management and TiCC package and 24 CECs on child protection issues including PSS, DRR, child safety and hygiene in accordance with the education/child protection framework and WHO guidelines on Covid-19 response spread over the 15 targeted schools.
 Organize and facilitate National retreat for 17 Somalia Regional Education cluster partners to improve coordination of humanitarian services in Somalia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdullahi Abdurahman Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722375957</telephone>
   <email>info@readosom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dennis Owano</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254728838852</telephone>
   <email>dennis.owano@readosom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9661">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bakool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.28000000 43.80700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-09">234066.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-09">165934.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15138">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-09">400000.78</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304639926">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-15">240000.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304828157">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-15">160000.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
