<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-yemen-allocation-2020" dstore:index="27" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-09T02:07:22.637" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-20/3420/SA1/Health-Nutrition/INGO/17915</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priority 2: Provide integrated emergency health  nutrition services - by running a mobile clinic, support a network of Community Health Volunteers and support for Operational Theater for referral hospital - for conflict affected people in Ku&#x2019;aydina district, Hajja governorate, Yemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will provide integrated emergency health and nutrition services by running a mobile clinic, support a network of Community Health Volunteers (CHVs) and support for the referral hospital for conflict affected people in Ku&#x2019;aydina district in Hajja.
At present, INTERSOS supports 2 health facilities (HFs) in Ku&#x2019;aydina: Al-Ku&#x2019;aydina hospital and Sawakh health center, providing support for the cluster defined MSP, with DG ECHO funding. However, this support does not cover the running cost for the newly (Sept 2020) opened Operational Theatre (OT) for the hospital. INTERSOS is covering the running of the OT from own funding till end of December 2020 only. INTERSOS wishes to secure the running of the OT for 6 months, to complement the DG ECHO funded MSP support and to permit the referrals from primary to secondary health care services and dealing with emergency and trauma intervention, both for HC and IDPs. Drugs, consumables and running cost of OT will be fully covered with health hazard allowances of minimum set of staff to run the OT continuously.

Per priority of the Health Cluster, about 5,800 people living in the area of 7 IDP sites in Ku&#x2019;aydina district in Hajja will also be supported by running 1 MCT to serve 7 IDP sites (Al-Gharbi, Tajamo&#x2019; Al-Juma&#x2019;a Al-Thulth, Al-Madaber, Bani Nashr Al-Rabwo&#x2019;, Al-Sawad Bani Nashr and Sawakh). In total the MCT will be serving over 7,000 people (mostly IDPs but also the most vulnerable surrounding host community) that faces challenges accessing the HFs due to the location/distance/cost of transportation. The services provided by the mobile clinic team (MCT) follow the by cluster defined MSP include Reproductive Health/Maternal, Neonatal, Child Health, deliveries and antenatal and postnatal care for mothers newborn care, immunization, deworming, vitamin A supplementation, screening for malnutrition, treatment for acute malnutrition cases, health education, outpatient treatment for common ailments, and nutrition treatment and prevention. The MCT is composed of 1 GP, 1 midwife, 2 nurses and driver. INTERSOS aims to run the MCT for 5 months.
A network of 8 CHVs will ensure acceptance, outreach and identification/referral, with critical importance for health and nutrition awareness and CMAM. The CHVs are not linked to the HF, but to the IDP sites (the CHVs linked to HFs are covered under DG ECHO funding). Community awareness will be tailored per target, age and gender group. Messages about COVID-19 prevention and response will be included in awareness raising activities. 

In order to mitigate the risks for staff and beneficiaries caused by COVID-19 pandemic, INTERSOS will apply COVID-19 protocols. 
The project will be integrated and complemented with protection services, funded under different funding (DG ECHO) in the same area, permitting a more comprehensive response to the needs of most vulnerable patients/cases. All the staff will be trained on protection mainstreaming and able to refer potential protection cases internally to INTERSOS protection team in Ku&#x2019;aydina.
Per request of the health cluster, INTERSOS also includes in the budget space for procurement of drugs, lab and medical consumables and equipment and furniture, and rehabilitation for HFs (only for Ibb)  &#x2013; total amount of 150,570.80 US$ for local partner YDN (for Ibb) and 44,249.37 US$ for TYF (for Taiz).
INTERSOS requested budget is a total of 390.633.74 US$, including the funds for the 2 partner NGOs mentioned above. 
The project runs 6 months (7 months considering project start-up and closure gt 6 months OT and 6 months MCT), for 7.601 direct beneficiaries (without double counting) for 75% IDPs, 25% Host Community, and 12% men, 28% women, 30% boys and 30% girls, at average cost of 23 US$ per beneficiary (not considering the budget for the 2 national partners for procurement).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamdeen Youth Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs &#x2013; YDN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evelyn Lernout</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967 715 555 001 / 736 846 999</telephone>
   <email>yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Miasa Al-Matari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">country finance coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00962 77800408</telephone>
   <email>admin.yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="85" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="15" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-02"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">390633.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-17915">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-10">390633.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304915000">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">390633.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
