<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="61" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-11T02:06:04.37" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA2NT/FSL/NGO/17462</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance Farmers&apos; resilience through Improving food security for most vulnerable Households in area C</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project targets 6 communities in the west bank in area C  suffering  from occupation discrimination measures and negative consequences of COVID-19.  Within area C, Israel retains near exclusive control, including over law enforcement, access and movement, planning and construction preventing people from accessing their natural resources (land and water), destroying agricultural lands amp animal shelters, water cisterns, uprooting planted trees, these actions forced displacing vulnerable families and disrupting their livelihoods which are against IHRL and IHL. The project aims at enhancing the resilience of 379 vulnerable farmers&apos; HH (capita 1817)   including 506 women, 511 men, 400girls and 400 boys by improving the food security of vulnerable farmers taking inconsideration all COVID-19 safety measures during implementation in addition to 60 workers&apos; HH(288 capita80 Women and 81 men,63 boys and 64 girls) . This will be achieved through: Improving the productivity of 1050 dunums of agricultural lands serving 70 farmers&#x2019; HH (94 women, 97 men, 74 boys, 72 girls) by providing them with 17 tons of fodder seeds in Hammamt Al Maleh, khirbet Samra and AL-hadidiya  in Tubas governorate. This activity will serve farmers with livestock fodder and protect the land from settler&#x2019;s attacks and confiscation. Rehabilitation of 4 Km of agricultural roads benefiting 120 Farmers&apos; HH (160 women, 162 men, 127 boys, 127 girls), in Beita and Asirah Ashshamaliya in Nablus governorate. This activity will protect and improve accessibility and utilization of the served agricultural lands. Agricultural Roads rehabilitation includes several sub activities machinery work, base course, culvert, and construction of stony retaining walls. Furthermore, Rehabilitation of 110 Dunums of agricultural land benefiting 28 farmers&#x2019; HH (37 women,37 men, 29 boys, 29 girls) in Asira Ashshamaliya and Beita. Different sub activities will be implemented for each beneficiary depending on the needs: Light machinery work for leveling, rock removal, rehabilitation of the stony retaining walls to protect from soil degradation and to increase water retention capacity, fencing to protect land from wild and livestock animals. In parallel with activity 2amp3, 60 unemployed workers will be provided with 990 working days including insurance, with an average of 16 WD for each worker. In addition to awareness raising in the field of Labour rights (6 Workshops), and distribution of awareness raising publications and safety and hygiene kits for COVID-19. Installing of 3 km of water carriers amp rehabilitation of a 500 m3 of water tank benefiting 75 farmers&apos; HH (100 women, 101 men, 79 boys, 79 girls) in Furush Beit Dajan. This aims at providing agricultural lands with water and enhance the resilience of farmers and livestock breeders in the targeted area. Provision of 8 metallic water tanks (4 cubic meters each) ,benefiting 16 farmers&#x2019; HH (21 women, 22 men, 17boys, 17girls)in Beita amp Asira Ashshamaliya. This activity aims to provide farmers with water and protect them from settlers attacks who has previously destroyed farmer&#x2019;s plastic tanks. Once the project is approved, a series of actions will take place to ensure good governance, participation and ownership, information and accountability: PARC team will announce and formulate Local Committees(LC)  in each location. These LC will have representatives from VC, Municipalities, CBOs, MoA, and they will participate and steer the project in order to ensure participation of local community, accountability in selection and reflect needs of the local community. Tendering and contracting, where PARC and the local committees will ensure the best value of money for different services and quality. All activities implemented will be ensured to abide by protection of COVID-19 SoPs attached. Finally, PARC will implement the project based on a well formulated exit strategy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Izzat Zaidan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programms and projects Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0598904464</telephone>
   <email>izzat@pal-arc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leena Saad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OCHA focal point</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0598120680</telephone>
   <email>lina.saad@pal-arc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">26032.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">273962.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-17462">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">299995.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304837885">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-16">179997.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
