<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="41" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-02T02:07:33.323" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-20T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA1/P/INGO/15977</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance protection for inter-communal conflict  affected communities  of   Babile and Tulo woredas in East and West Hararghe Zones, Oromia Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal is developed in response to the humanitarian crises in East and West Hararghe  zones  of Oromia region, that resulted due to inter-communal conflict. Large number of IDP&#x2019;s as well as returnees are hosted in East Hararghe  amp West Hararghe Zones  without sufficient access to basic social services and protection. In East Hararghe currently there are 130,102 IDP&#x2019;s and 157,219 returnees residing dispersed in to various woredas of the zone. The project will be implemented in two target woredas namely Babile in East hararge, and Tulo in west Hararghe. With the intention of enhancing the protection assistance to the most vulnerable children, WVE would like to consolidate the ongoing GBV prevention and response activities  in Babile woreda and  aspires to include child protection activities to provide a holistic protection assistance to the affected children. Hence, the proposed project intends to complement the ongoing GB. prevention and response project being implemented in in Babile woreda. In Tulo woreda there are 425  IDPs sheltered in Hirna town IDP camp.  WVE has an ongoing E_ Child and Livelihood development projects in Tulo woreda. This program will work in complementary on CP issues.  Moreover, WVE is planning to integrate COVID_19 activities in the day to day activities of the project in order to prevent infection and curb the possible spread of the virus as well as support the children affected by the pandemic. Some of the planned COVID _related activities include: developing IEC materials and messaging relevant to COVID and Child protection, conducting awareness raising activities which address both CP and COVID related issues, providing sanitizers and soap to CPCs, community facilitators for own self-care and to give basic information on COVID 19. Moreover, the project will integrate COVID -19 in all of the training planned for community facilitators and child protection committees to increase their awareness on CP and COVID and thereby reach out to the target community The goal of the project is to contribute to improvement of quality of life of the conflict affected children. Towards this end, World Vison Ethiopia will implement a comprehensive project which focuses on: Strengthening the case management system based on the COVID_19 case management guidance through adapting CP case management interventions to the new COVID 19 pandemic. WVE will ensure the coordination of services through establishing functional referral pathways in both woredas .Moreover continued support will be given for all of the  cases within  the existing case load along with appropriate responses for new CP risks and concerns generated by the pandemic , expedite alternative care arrangement by facilitating foster care options for UASC whom parents are difficult to trace, and facilitating family tracing and reunification of UASC with their families to ensure long term care. . WVE will employ the FTR amp reunification steps in facilitating the reunification process which include : identification of children who have been separated ,tracing the missing family members, verify the relationship and bringing together the child and the family through covering transportation costs and providing reunification kits such as clothes and shoes, provision of individual psycho-social support amp PFA services in line with the national and regional guidance of social distancing and avoiding large group activities ,strengthening the capacity of community based child protection mechanisms and service providers through organizing different relevant capacity building training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eshetu Alemu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager- Protection Unit</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-0911614701</telephone>
   <email>Eshetu_Alemu@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edward Brown</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 966 21 66 25</telephone>
   <email>Edward_Brown@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samuel Tilahun</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of HEA</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-911-715-362</telephone>
   <email>Samuel_Tilahun@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-14">100549.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-14">49450.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-15977">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-14">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304672994">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-20">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
