<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-lebanon-allocation-2020" dstore:index="20" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-17T02:05:18.51" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-17T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-20/DDA-3604/SA1/P-H/NGO/16647</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alleviating the impact of the COVID-19 crisis on vulnerable older persons, persons with disabilities, persons with serious medical conditions, and other persons with specific needs from the refugee and host communities, including Syrians, Palestinians from Lebanon and Syria, migrants, other nationalities, and Lebanese, in Mount Lebanon, North Lebanon, South Lebanon, and Bekaa, through the provision of Protection and Health services, including Emergency Cash Assistance, Protection Cash Assistance, and the financial contribution of patient share hospitalisation fees  Provision of Emergency Cash Assistance as part of a holistic protection approach to the those most vulnerable affected by the Beirut port blast.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since October 2019, Lebanon has faced severe economic and socio-political crisis affecting the country, the impacts of which have been compounded by the lockdown resulting from COVID-19, straining the dire conditions, increasing debts, and reducing purchasing power. 
Explosion of a warehouse on 4 August 2020 with 2,750 tons of ammonium nitrate in immediate vicinity of central Beirut caused widespread damage and loss of life. At least 160 people were killed, and more than 5,000 people were injured. Humanitarian response to Beirut explosions puts protection in the center of response. CL is proposing the Provision of ECA as part of a holistic protection approach to the those most vulnerable affected by the blast (and particularly the elderly and those with physical disabilities) since it has been identified as a key priority by Emergency Operations Cell (EOC).

The project aims to provide a multi-faceted response to support gaps in current protection and health services, with the provision of ECA and PCA, and contributions to the patient&#x2019;s share for life-saving non COVID-19 related hospitalization. The activities will target vulnerable individuals, including people affected by the Beirut Blast, older persons, persons with disabilities and persons with severe medical conditions, living in Akkar, North Lebanon (Tripoli, Minieh-Dannieh, Zgharta, Koura, Bsharre, Batroun and other If need be), Mount Lebanon (Jbeil, Keserwan, Matn, Baabda, Aley, Chouf  and other if need be), South Lebanon (Saida and Sour), and Bekaa (all Bekaa). Overall, the project expects to serve 20% Syrian refugees, 10% other nationalities (Palestine refugees from Lebanon and Syria and migrants) and 70% host communities. (approximately).
Moreover, Caritas Lebanon will work to provide case management utilizing its other portfolio of work.  CL has secured a commitment from UNHCR that the provision of ECA, under this project, can be implemented within the UNHCR grants through CL&#x2019;s current CM activities. This includes 25 case workers in all districts. Additionally, CL has identified complementary funding by its partners, Tr&#xF3;caire, to cover CM cost in the North, filling the gap which was previously implemented by CL funded by LHF. Based on the data collected by CL&#x2019;s BA and CM teams, and as reported by Protection Sector&#x2019;s assessments, such as the VASyR, the needs in North Lebanon remain extremely high, with numerous families unable to meet their basic needs and facing severe protection risks. Tr&#xF3;caire will cover the costs of CM staffing for North Lebanon reaching 568 Syrian refugees, 25 other nationalities, and 408 vulnerable Lebanese and ensuring the ECA and PCA under this grant can address the complex protection environment in North Lebanon.

Under the protection logframe, implementation of Activity 1.1.1 amp Activity 1.1.2 will be in the following regions: 
-	ECA / PCA for Syrian refugees: Akkar, North Lebanon (Tripoli, Minieh-Dannieh, Zgharta, Koura, Bsharre, Batroun) and Bekaa (Central Bekaa) and other areas if need be.
-	ECA/PCA for migrants: Akkar, North Lebanon (Tripoli, Minieh-Dannieh, Zgharta, Koura, Bsharre, Batroun), Mount Lebanon (Jbeil, Keserwan, Matn, Baabda, Aley, Chouf), South Lebanon (Saida and Sour), and Bekaa (all Bekaa) and other areas if need be.
-	ECA/PCA for the Lebanese : Akkar, North Lebanon (Tripoli, Minieh-Dannieh, Zgharta, Koura, Bsharre, Batroun), Mount Lebanon (Jbeil, Keserwan, Matn, Baabda, Aley, Chouf), South Lebanon (Saida and Sour), and Bekaa (all Bekaa) and other areas if need be.
Implementation in Beirut, Mount Lebanon and the south of ECA will be strongly coordinated with PUAMI as well as other Cash and CM actors in the same area of intervention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS LIBAN CENTRE DES MIGRANTS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS LIBAN CENTRE DES MIGRANTS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trocaire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charbel Zeidan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of the Refugee and Emergency Department</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00 961 79 311 198</telephone>
   <email>charbel.zeidan@caritas.org.lb</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sandra Haddad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00961 76 515 490</telephone>
   <email>sandra.mhaddad@caritas.org.lb</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beirut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88690000 35.51310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN2">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bekaa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.00890000 36.14530000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN3">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mount Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.83330000 35.53330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN5">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.43330000 35.85000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.55000000 35.38330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="71" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="29" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-09">845403.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-09">1697794.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-16647">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-09">2543197.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS LIBAN CENTRE DES MIGRANTS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304739203">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-17">2034558.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARITAS LIBAN CENTRE DES MIGRANTS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
