<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-pakistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="17" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-10T02:06:07.04" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-01T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/H/NGO/16247</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To support and complement government efforts for coping the current pandemic of COVID-19 and ensure essential health services, including MNCH, IPC, PPE, psychosocial support and disease surveillance in District Peshawar and Swat of KP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan has witnessed a massive increase in its confirmed cases from the initial two confirmed cases on 26th February 2020. As a country whose economy is highly reliant on manufacturing and service industries, shutdown measures and disruptions in supply chains has negatively impact on the economy and society, particularly the poor. The shutdown measures have already impacted small businesses, small and medium enterprises and daily wagers associated with various sectors of the economy. 
The number of confirmed COVID-19 cases in Pakistan has risen to 40,151 as of 17 May 2020. Increase of 1,352 new cases in the last 24 hours. Test conducted so far is 359,264 out of which 1, 1341 recovered and 873 deaths. The most affected province due to COVID-19 virus in Punjab 14,584, followed by Sindh with 15,590 cases. In Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, the total confirm cases are 5,847 with 305 deaths and 1,699 cases recovered. Active cases in KP is 3,843 which increases on daily basis.There are limited number of laboratories with limited capacity to confirm COVID-19 cases. Substantial progress in Laboratory testing has been made, daily testing capacity has increased from 6700 on April 22, to 13051 on May 13, 2020. This capacity is expected to reach 20,000 per day. Total 330750 tests have been performed as of May 14, i.e. KP 34352.  Given the current positivity rate of 8%, we, therefore, need to conduct 2 million tests to reach the projected 9,049 test per 1,000,000. The average local transmission in the country is around 89%: Sindh 92.69%, Punjab 86.18%, KP 85.49%, and Baluchistan 93.39%. 

The isolation and quarantine facilities are inadequate in number and the infrastructure unsuitable for isolation and quarantine. The standard operating procedures (SoPs) are not being implemented at both the isolation and quarantine facilities the facilities lack human resources, technical expertise, supplies, equipment and proper management. The people being quarantined or isolated are not properly briefed on the importance of social distancing and hygiene. Keeping in view the consistent spread and high ratio of confirmed COVID-19 cases need urgent support to the PDMA, DoH, District Administration in the most affected districts of KP i.e. Peshawar and Swat.  
To provide immediate support in COVID-19 Pandemic and EHSAR strong sectoral experience the following allocation strategic activities have been selected with close consultation of district Administration, PDMA and DoH after proper Need Assessment.


	Training and Capacity Building of government and private health facilities staff (doctors, paramedical, vaccinator, and disease surveillance officer etc) to continue providing essential health services including provision of IPC, MNCH, immunization, antenatal, postnatal care and safe delivery services.  
	Support outreach activities through provision of medicines, medical supplies, maternal lifesaving supplies, modern contraceptives, and availability of basic maternal health equipment
	Provision of appropriate Personal Protective Equipment for government, community and   Public Health  Facilities including  Doctors, paramedics, LHW, CMW, FWW, FWAs, LHV, Dispensers, WMO/MOs and vaccinators.  
	Ensure continuity and effectively operationalized mobile units&#x2019; services in two districts of KP   to strengthen CEmOC referral and onsite SRH, including EmOC and maternal health care services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Health Social Awareness and Rehabilitation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Health Social Awareness and Rehabilitation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kazim Ullah Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+923005834200</telephone>
   <email>kazimullah@ehsar.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mukhtiar Ahmad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+923339805333</telephone>
   <email>mukhtiar@ehsar.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK2">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khyber Pakhtunkhwa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.48100000 72.09020000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-24"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">501061.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-16247">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">501061.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Health Social Awareness and Rehabilitation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304626954">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-01">501061.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Health Social Awareness and Rehabilitation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
