<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="72" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-30T03:05:41.593" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-04T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA2NT/PROT/NGO/17474</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to mental health care and psycho-social support services for the most vulnerable women and girls  and their families in quarantine and remote communities in the Gaza Strip</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project addresses main problem of &quot;Limited access to community based integrated MHPSS services by affected women, girls and their families in quarantine and remote communities.&quot; It responds to time critical needs identified in needs assessment conducted on 22-30/9/2020. Overall objective is &quot;Improved mental health and psychosocial well-being and resilience of most vulnerable women gt18-59 and gt59 years and adolescent girls 14-17 years and their families in quarantine and remote communities based on MHPSS guidelines in emergency settings&quot; It will be achieved &#x201C;only if&#x201D; outcomes are realized: 1. Enhanced capacity building of front-line workers from MHPSS service providers 2. Improved emotional, mental and social well-being and enhanced resilience of most vulnerable women and adolescent girls and their families in quarantine and 3. Increased sensitization and responsiveness of local and national duty bearers towards improved MHPSS support services for most vulnerable women and adolescent and their families in quarantine. The project targets directly 9365 beneficiaries (3695 women, 2140 men, 1775 girls and 1755 boys, out of them 480 with disabilities) identified based on vulnerability criteria: women/ men18-59 and gt59 years amp adolescent girls/ boys 14-17 years including with disabilities, survivors of cancer, GBV survivors, chronically ill (diabetic, hypertensive, with kidney failure), women in reproductive age/ pregnant, internally displaced and female- headed households according to their location, status, protection risks and needs severity. Beneficiaries are selected from COVID-19 hotspots, particularly Gaza North (Jabalia, Beit Hanoun) and Gaza (Gaza City, Mughraga) governorates and remote communities in Deir Balah (Maghazi) KhanYounis (Fukhari) and Rafah (Mawasi) amp ARAs. 
AISHA is well suited to implement the project as it manages a licensed specialized mental health clinic, competent MHPSS specialized staff and experience in working with quarantined women and girls and their families (home amp centers) across Gaza Strip and coordination with related state actors since COVID-19 outbreak. 

The project links to HRP 2020 Strategic Objective 1, Protection Cluster Objective 2, purpose of 2020 2nd Standard Allocation in Gaza Objective 1, eligible actions, and standard activities/ indicators.
Activities are: I) capacity building for MHPSS actors on self-care, remote counselling/ case management IASC guidelines on MHPSS, PSEA, 4Ws to effectivelyamp safely collect, store, analyze and share data to ensure that MHPSS needs met without gaps or duplication amp advance MHPSS programming and advocacy supervision for AISHA staff II) Remote MHPSS services like structured individual PSS and awareness raising to 600 women, 300 girls amp 300 boys group PSS and self-help support to 100 women, specialized mental health to 75 women amp 25 girls/ 20 boys case management services to 120 women, 40 girls amp 40 boys yoga to 50 women amp 15 girls family therapy to 100 women recreational kits to 50 girls/ 50 boys&#x2019; households III) community engagement, accountability amp advocacy like radio announcement, press releases, community meetings, online leaflet, fact sheet, feedback/ complaints mechanism, prevention of SEA, 5 panel hearing sessions amp remote advocacy and lobbying campaign.

AISHA ensures a human rights framework, participatory MampE, staff codes of conduct/ethics, PSEA, feedback/ compliant mechanisms, orientation and training of MHPSS workers, zero problems in mental health and psychosocial well-being among its staff/volunteers, community mobilization amp ownership, dissemination of information to affected people on their rights/ interventions and positive coping mechanisms, safety/security amp full access to services based on humanitarian principles, gender equality, mainstreaming protection ampGBV, COVID-protective measures amp ethical considerations for MHPSS REMOTE WORKING MODALITIES (Informed consent, professionalism, privacy amp confidentiality)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aisha Association for Women and Child Protection.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aisha Association for Women and Child Protection.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reem frainah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972599305585</telephone>
   <email>reemf_1974@hotmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-21">29234.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-21">266031.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-17474">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-21">295265.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aisha Association for Women and Child Protection.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304908861">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-04">177159.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aisha Association for Women and Child Protection.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
