<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syriacrossborder-allocation-2020" dstore:index="173" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-14T02:05:17.787" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-08T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/WASH/NGO/16332</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the resilience of IDPs and host communities through life-saving activities in the WASH sector.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the proposed intervention IYD aims to increase access to sustainable water services in three camps in Harbanoush, Maaret Tamsrin sub-district, the project will support the newly displaced IDPs from Maaret Alnuman to Harbansoh Camps with safe, clean and sustainable drinking water through rehabilitation works which they are proposed in this project including the expansion works for the existing water network to reach the camps around the village who are depending on the water trucking to ensure their daily water need, increase the pumping capacity in the village by equipping the drilled well by the local council with electrical and mechanical equipment such as generator, submersible pump and electrical control panel, also the works includes construction work for generator and pumping rooms in addition to high water tank with capacity of 60 m3 to ensure the proper pressure in the network to let the water reach all the targeted camp, and to ensure the sustainability of the system IYD will form water management committee from the camps residents, and train the committee to establish fees collection system, moreover, IYD will cover the daily need of water by provide the IDP&#x2019;s camp residents with daily safe and clean water through water trucking at least 35 liters per person per day of chlorinated water for drinking, cooking and domestic purposes for 3 months, during this period IYD will rehabilitate the water pumping system in the camp which will replace the water trucking method in the targeted camp, once the rehabilitation works completed, IYD will cover the operational cost for five months to the established water station which will support the water committee to register all HHs who will benefit from the services and built the tariff system. 


And to improve the hygienic conditions in the targeted camps, IYD will provide the IDPs site residents with solid waste collection and 200 locally made waste containers, IYD will address the gap in latrines numbers in the targeted camps by building 30 new latrines blocks (two cells), making them gender sensitive. and address the needs of elderly and disabled beneficiaries, also as complementary with the latrines IYD will provide desludging services and distribute hygiene kits to raise the hygiene awareness for the IDPs as well as prevention for COVID-19, The planned intervention will mainstream protection principles throughout the project cycle by considering the different needs of men, women, boys and girls. Construction of the latrines and the distribution of the water tanks will be consulted with women/men and boys/girls to ensure they serve the communities equitably and consider the specific needs of these groups. 


More specifically, the intervention will provide operational cost for two main water stations in Batbu and Kafr Deryan, the operational cost includes (fuel, spare parts, lubricants oil, and water stations and water networks operators&#x2019; salaries) for five months, by this activity IYD will ensure provide at least 40 liters per person a day for more than 65,000 individuals in both locations, and to ensure that all beneficiaries will have access to the water networks IYD will rehabilitate the existing water networks by replacing the damaged parts, installation for mechanical parts such as valves and expansion of new water line for the neighborhoods that not covered by the water network. The chlorination process will be under the full control from the IYD staff as well, daily samples from providing water and from the point of use will be taken to do the tests, and daily visit to the HHs to check the storage tanks and containers and ensure clean, this will be done through the water safety plan by IYD.

Finally, it is important to note that all the staff working on these interventions will be given the needed information of any other services in the area (protection, education, livelihood etc.). They will also be trained on safe identification and referrals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">519475.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">255479.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16332">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-03">774955.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304667987">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">309982.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
