<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="14" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-07T02:07:03.807" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-06-29T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA3/CPiE/NGO/16075</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection of Vulnerable and at-risk children against COVID-19 through child protection interventions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Afghanistan, children continue to be exposed to violence, abuse, exploitation and neglect. HRP 2020 identified that children are at high risk of psycho-social problems including stress, panic, isolation, nightmares, and other psycho-social problems children are at risk of being separated from their caregivers and in need of temporary shelter while their families are being traced and until reunification is possible. Case management is also identified as a gap to coordinate efforts to ensure that the most vulnerable children are identified and receive appropriate services in a timely manner. There is also a lack of awareness and limited access to knowledge by children and families to protect themselves from different types of violence and exploitation. THE HRP 2020 highlights the need to continue to respond to and enhance activities aimed at mitigating the risk associated with children being separated from their families children being recruited by parties to the ongoing armed conflict and families engaging in negative coping mechanisms such as child marriage, child labor and unsafe, irregular migration due to the crisis. As such, the HRP 2020 has prioritized identification and family tracing and reunification of unaccompanied minors and separated children provision of psychological first aid and community based psycho-social support case management and referral services, provision of lifesaving support such as critical household items to children due to displacement and other natural disasters. Community structures, including community-based child protection mechanisms remain weak capacity building of key actors at the national and sub-national levels is essential. Children remain in need of risk education in and out of school to enhance their protection against Explosive Ordinance (EXO) and ERW. Community awareness raising on general child protection issues and advocacy for implementing the new Child&#x2019;s Rights Protection Law to ensure children are protected from violence, abuse, exploitation and neglect will be critical this year, as will targeted awareness campaigns on how to use the negative coping strategies, such as early and forced marriage and child labor, pose significant protection risks to children. Interventions targeting girls and women, including female headed households, are critical, especially the distribution of dignity kits. While SGBV remains a sensitive topic in Afghanistan, SGBV-focused community dialogues that involve all subsets of each community &#x2013; women, girls, men, boys, community elders, religious and community leaders on how to prevent and respond to SGBV continue to be a critical gap. since in the current situation COVID-19 has largely effected the children in the context in which they live. Quarantine measures such as school closures and restrictions on movements can disrupt children&apos;s routine and social support networks, while also placing new stressors on parents and caregivers who may have to find new childcare options or forgo work. Stigma and discrimination related to COVID-19 may make children more vulnerable to violence and psycho-social distress. Disease control measures that do not consider the gender-specific needs and vulnerabilities of boys and girls may also increase their protection risks and lead to negative coping mechanisms such as child marriage and child labour. Children and families who are already vulnerable due to socio-economic exclusion or those who live in overcrowded settings are particularly at risk.Due to the current pandemic situation the roads and flights are not operating and reunification are required through high cost transportation means. A specific alternative modality of mobile child protection teams are required to support case management, referral, and PSS for the children The proposed project aims to support children well-being through awareness raising, interim care, family tracing, reunification and case management in Kandahar and Nimroz provinces.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social and Humanitarian Assistance Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social and Humanitarian Assistance Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Humayun Razmal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0700304273</telephone>
   <email>pomshao49@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shamsuddin Shams</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director - SHAO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0703859724</telephone>
   <email>director.shao@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="33">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kandahar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.99606790 65.47573600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="34">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nimroz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.02614880 62.45041540</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-20">480083.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-16075">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-20">480083.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social and Humanitarian Assistance Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304662143">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-29">240041.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social and Humanitarian Assistance Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
