<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="23" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-03T02:07:12.01" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-05-21T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA1/FSL/NGO/15466</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance Farmers&apos; resilience through Improving food security for most vulnerable Households in Jordan Valley</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The critical situation that people are living under in OPT including Jordan Valley and area C, and the escalation caused by Israelis increased the vicious acts on the area, In addition to that the annexation of Palestinian lands in the Jordan Valley .This has resulted in worsening the Palestinian living conditions and standards. Continuous demolition of the infrastructure (water pipes, roads, etc), limited accessibility and utilization of natural resources. All these aggression and violation deteriorates life in Tubas governorate and the surrounding villages. The project aims at enhancing the resilience of 182 HH benefiting 834 individuals divided as  (Men 233, women 224, boys 193, girls 184) in 2 locations at Tubas governorates in Jordan Valley. The project activities will also respond to the different humanitarian needs of the most vulnerable farmers (women and men), to improve their living conditions by increasing the productivity of their agriculture lands, where women HH will be given priority. 
The main activities of the project are: 

Activity 1: Installing 2.5 km of water pipelines in Khirbet &apos;Atuf and Al-rasalahmar., benefiting 38 farmers and their families serving 250 dunums.  The installing will Include, main, sub main metallic pipes, valves, wielding.. etc
Activity 2: Rehabilitation of water tank of 800 cubic meter (reservoir) in  Khirbet &apos;Atuf benefiting 80 farmers serving 800 dunums of agricultural lands. This rehabilitation will include replacement of internal balloon, reinforcement of side wall, net etc) 

Activity 3: Rehabilitation of 3.2 Km of Agricultural roads in  Khirbet &apos;Atuf, Khirbet ar Ras al Ahmar benefiting 64 farmers and their families including (base course, culvert, leveling, side protection) this will serve 640 dunums of agricultural land 

The project activities are reconsidered due to the spread of COVID-19 in the Palestinian territories. This has resulted in coordination with the relevant stakeholders in the area OXFAM amp their partners in addition to MoA to avoid duplication of work, accordingly PARC has decided to work in Tubas particularly in Khirbet &apos;Atuf and Khirbet ar Ras al Ahmar. Once the project is approved, there will be inception phase where a series of actions will be made. Firstly, PARC will coordinate with the MoA, FFS, other key stakeholders, then will announce the project to the community and establish local committee (one committee per 2 locations). These committees will consist of a representative from village/municipality council CBOs/cooperatives, and related ministries (MoA).PARC will ensure that the committees are  gender balanced. These Committees will participate and steer the project in order to ensure: Formalize the participation of representatives of the Local Council and local community organizations &#x2013;social accountability and strengthening relations with the community and the targeted population. Secondly, developing a selection criteria drafted by PARC team and approved by the committees, application distribution, then selecting the end beneficiaries based on a scoring system to choose the end beneficiaries, where open competition for men and women based on vulnerability criteria (close to settlement, wall, and subjected to violation by settlers, poor families, affected by recent weather depression...etc) will be approved by the committees. Thirdly, tendering and contracting process according to the defined Bill of Quantities, with open competition. Fourth, implementation through daily follow-up and ensuring quality of works and services, in participation with local committee. Last, the implemented services will be handed over to related beneficiaries and relevant agencies with clear exit strategy to ensure sustainability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-17" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-17" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Izzat Zaidan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Projects and programs department</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0598904464</telephone>
   <email>izzat@pal-arc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">lina Saad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0598120680</telephone>
   <email>lina.saad@pal-arc.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-17"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-19">149995.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-15466">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-19">149995.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304617032">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-21">149995.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural Development Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
