<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-syria-allocation-2020" dstore:index="63" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-15T03:07:06.68" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-03-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-20/DDA-3558/SA1/H/NGO/17060</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support the provision of essential health care services to IDPs and vulnerable groups in Al Hasakeh city</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As Syria enters its tenth year of crisis, the scale, severity, and complexity of needs across Syria remain deep and far-reaching. Over half of the country&#x2019;s population have fled their homes: 5.5 million people have sought refuge in the region and beyond, and 6.1 million people are internally displaced. 13.1 million people remain in need of humanitarian assistance. More than eight in10 people in Syria live below poverty line. Many people&#x2019;s coping mechanisms are depleted, and families face hard choices to put food on the table, a roof over their heads, keeping their children warm or sending them to school
In2020, with conflict still raging in parts of the country, and the COVID-19 pandemic expected to result in severe economic and social impact, humanitarian needs are projected to continue to grow
In the north-east, increased conflict since October2019 has also resulted widespread displacement.. Many of those affected by the recent hostilities have already experienced immense physical and mental stress as a result of years of conflict and repeated displacement
In April 2020, the number of displaced people in Al Hassakeh governorate reached 326,966 IDPs, in addition to 10,975 Spontaneous-IDP-Returnees which makes the total number of population in Al Hassakeh governorate inclusive of the host community 1,031,064 persons ,In addition to 85 Collective shelters distributed In Al Hassakeh city, Tal Tamer and Al Qamishli with a total number of IDPs of 14,752 Most of them are women and children
People in need of essential health care services face challenges related to insecurity and limited access to health care. Already weakened health services in northeast Syria have been severely impacted by the latest security developments
Across northeast Syria, shortages of health workers is widespread as they too have been among those displaced by the ongoing insecurity, aggravating an already critical situation and further depriving underserved populations of access to medical care. According to HeRAMS data of May2020, out of 4 public hospitals in Al Hassakeh governorate , 3 are classified as partially functioning inclusive of Al Hassakeh national hospital , Al Hassakeh Children Hospital and Al Malkyeh public hospital with limited capacity , while Qamishli national hospital is fully functioning
Al-Birr Charity Association For Social Services is a non-profit organization licensed under resolution No. 107/1993 and authorized by the Ministry of social affairs and Labor to partner with UN agencies. And is one of the main partner to WHO and UNICEF in the health sector in Al Hassakeh governate. and  had previous engagement with WHO (6 projects) through which health care services were provided to more than 2000 beneficiaries on monthly basis, Al-Birr Charity Association For Social Services has ongoing project with OCHA which  will provide health services to more than 31000 patients. Al-Birr Charity Association For Social services  had a previous  project with OCHA.through which it provided  health services to more than 21,000beneficiaries
Al-Birr Charity Association For Social Services will provide health service to  IDPs, vulnerable groups in Al Hasakeh city Al-Birr Charity Association For Social Services will continue to assess health needs and scale up their response as needed
The  primare care Services ( consultation, medication ..etc)and health promotion will  be served in our static health clinic in Al Hasakeh city, Our mobile team will provide health Services to more than 7000 people, include new targeting areas more and more in need of these services, which is (the well-sweet and pink countryside and its countryside and the Shadadi and its countryside and the Hasaka region and its countryside to Jabal Abdel Aziz, our mobile team will visit these Target areas on daily basis
The  secondary care and trauma patient ( surgeries, Lab tests..etc) will be referred from  our health clinic,and our mobile team to Private  hospitals in Al Hasakeh</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Bir Association for Social Services in Al Hasakah</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Bir Association for Social Services in Al Hasakah</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Fateh Al Abase</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0096934602298</telephone>
   <email>birralhasaka@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">abd albarko</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0096933584017</telephone>
   <email>alaliiman01@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D. Abd-Alhakem Ale</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0096933462463</telephone>
   <email>d.abdalhakemale@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY08">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Hasakeh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.50537500 40.74289900</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-11">517478.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-17060">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-11">517478.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Bir Association for Social Services in Al Hasakah</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304945652-653">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-16">206991.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Bir Association for Social Services in Al Hasakah</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
