<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="17" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-03-14T02:06:26.663" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-09-16T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA1/H-P-E/INGO/16940</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EHAI (Emergency Humanitarian Assistance for IDPs and Conflict-affected Communities) in Northern Shan State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The &#x201C;EHAI (Emergency Humanitarian Assistance for IDPs and Conflict-affected Communities)&#x201D; project will support primary health care services together with life-saving and emergency referral services under health cluster, protection services and interventions tackling Gender based violence (GBV) and Sexual and reproductive health (SRH) under protection cluster and Education in Emergency (EiE) activities to conflict-affected people from Northern Shan State. Overall objective of the project is to provide quick and time-bound humanitarian assistance to crisis &#x2013; affected people by providing services to fill their health, protection and education needs in emergencies situation. Total 24,475 affected people from 6 townships   and 2,274 internally displaced people (IDP) will be covered under this project. Out of which 7.6% are children and 53.7% are women and girls. Since 1998, CPI has been promoting access to primary health services in conflict-affected areas in Myanmar and believes that empowering local organizations is the most effective way to address the health needs of displaced populations. Starting from 2019, Myanmar Humanitarian Fund provided assistance to CPI&#x2019;s the humanitarian response activities in conflict-affected areas of Northern Shan States, which has been orchestrated in partnerships with Ta&#x2019;ang Health Committee (THC).
THC will continue provision of &#x201C;Integrated Package of Health Services&#x201D; (IPHS) encompassing primary health care, maternal amp newborn child health, sexual amp reproductive health, emergency referral, mental health amp disease surveillance.   In response to the needs at the community level, THC will be extending its services for Protection through community based activities. The services will be community level awareness raising on GBV, Child protection, Mine Risk Reduction and Human trafficking through trained community volunteers and THC health workers. In order to response and manage for GBV survivor, THC will be trained for GBV case management and MHPSS  . Referral networks will be set up for further medical and legal assistance and management. To meet the immediate hygiene needs and to help women and girl to preserve their dignity during time of crisis and emergency, CPI will distribute dignity kits in affected community.   

As women amp youth empowerment and engaging men is the crucial role in the prevention of GBV, THC will form women, men and youth group in the community to advocate community stakeholders about the awareness on GBV, Child Protection amp human trafficking. 
CPI and its partner organization Ta&#x2019;ang Students amp Youth Union (TSYU) will implement Education in Emergencies (EiE) activities in the targeted area. TSYU will provide assistance to community and boarding schools to be able to provide formal and non-formal education for 1359 students   and 70 teachers from 24 schools in 6 townships in Shan State  . School committees will be formed to provide continuous support in align with Child Safeguarding Policy to schools at the community level. 10 community schools will be supported with renovation, furniture and Covid-19 preventive facilities such as hand washing. ToT training on Health education including Covid - 19 prevention will be organized for teachers and school support staff targeting 75 participants in total    . Moreover, CPI and TSYU will provide financial assistance as stipend, hardship allowance and stipend for teachers   assigned to very hard to reach areas. Since CPI has actively engaged with Clusters, and works in close coordination and collaboration with MoH, MoSWRR,, it is auspicious to seek technical assistance from these stakeholders whenever necessary and participate in routine cluster coordination meetings at the state and township level.

Under this project, CPI and THC will do the initial assessment on GBV at the project area. And then 13 community volunteers, 6 mobile team health workers and 5 clinic staff will also be trained for GBV and SRH. (Ref: proposal .doc)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Partners International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Partners International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ta&#x2019;ang Students and Youth Union (TSYU)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taang Health Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Si Thura</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 925 419 3553</telephone>
   <email>sithura@cpintl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Nu Nu Aye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+959 250 526 539</telephone>
   <email>nunuaye@cpintl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shan (North)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>23.50285400 98.14198900</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="3" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-09">91554.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-09">183864.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-16940">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-09">275419.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Partners International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304738307">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-16">165251.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Partners International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
