<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="26" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-01-27T02:05:59.373" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-07-28T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA1/NFI/ES/INGO/15770</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency shelter / NFI and COVID-19 support in  Kumbi and Babile woredas of East Hararghe zone ,Oromia region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Ethiopia the last two years conflict have negatively impacted hundreds of thousand people&#x2019;s lives and livelihoods and their ability to meet their basic needs. As a result, in recent times, according to HRP, 2020, 1.9 millions of peoples will be targeted for Emergency shelter and NFI assistance starting from April 2020. In response, the GOE and its partners have continued to play their role in trying address the problem. As part of this effort, CARE Ethiopia, aiming at saving lives and livelihoods of conflicted affected people is proposing this specific project. 
Hence, the objectives of the current project falls under the two shelter cluster strategic objectives and HRP. Accordingly, the project will target 1838 most vulnerable crises affected IDPs and returnees households through emergency shelter repairing, and ESNFI kit assistance. Besides, we aim to decongest the IDPs in overcrowded sites for the ESNFI assistance. For selecting the beneficiaries, we will conduct a vulnerability assessment and employ targeting criteria. These criteria includes child-headed household, the separated child in need of shelter, Children at risk in need of shelter, Woman of 18 years old or above who is at risk of protection concerns, female headed households, elders, people with underlying chronic illness, polygamous family and large family with more dependence with no alternative livelihoods. Due to the outbreak of the COVID-19 and its possible rapid spread in the country, the targeting will give priority to those who are most vulnerable to the pandemic. The shelter repairing kits and ESNFI, after market assessment, will be delivered in mixed cash and in-kind for the 514 returnee households in Babile woredas and 1324 IDPsHH in Kumbi woredas of East Hararghe zone, respectively. In addition, to maximize the cash utilization on emergency shelter repairing kits, CARE will raise community awareness and sensitize the beneficiaries about the project. In addition, the project will target households who are living under substandard shelter condition, in congested shelter and who doesn&apos;t receive any shelter assistance so far. The project will follow up COVID-19 specific beneficiary&#x2019;s targeting, registration and distribution operation procedure which was shared by the clusters.

After each cash and in-kind distribution, post distribution monitoring assessment will be conducted to understand how the cash has been spent and in-kind support delivered, whether the beneficiaries were able to meet their basic needs, capture beneficiary&#x2019;s satisfactions and document lessons for future cash project. The proposed sampling size will 31 8 samples (+ 5 % Confidence Interval).
CARE will regularly attend federal and zonal level cluster coordination meetings. To minimize the duplication of effort at woreda level, CARE will coordinate with different NGOs who are working at project implementation woredas and communicate as needed.

Besides, in order to support the country&#x2019;s effort to mitigate the spread and reduce the damage of COVID-19 pandemic, CARE is proposing sensitization and community awareness raising campaign in Kumbi and Babile woredas of East Hararghe zone. The campaign will include hand washing, physical distancing, stay at home and other protection measures. In addition, CARE will have poster sessions to demonstrate virus transmission ways to the target communities. To minimize the risks of protection and GBV for the target beneficiaries during beneficiaries targeting and distribution, CARE will provide PSEA and GBV training to financial service providers, government&#x2019;s staff and Targeting committees. To undertake the abovementioned activities, a total of 448,847 USD is proposed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elizabeth Milten</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency programm coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0911164475</telephone>
   <email>Elizabeth.Milten@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Esther Watts</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>251911120731</telephone>
   <email>esther.watts@Care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-17">383801.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-17">65015.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-15770">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-17">448816.7</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304676741">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">359053.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
