<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="AUD" dstore:dataset="oau-pg" dstore:index="10" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>AU-ACNC-18055208636-PNG-0059</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="AU-ACNC-18055208636" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Response 2nd Activation in PNG AHP (PNG-0059)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project&apos;s overarching objective is to enhance the resilience of COVID-19 affected communities in PNG against future shocks such as a further spike in COVID-19. To do so, the consortium partners are focusing on the most pressing needs highlighted through recent assessments which have underlined the secondary impacts of the current crisis, demonstrating the core sectors which become impacted during a response such as COVID-19. This includes enhancing community access to appropriate WASH facilities, improving livelihoods initiatives, strengthening response mechanisms for survivors of gender-based violence (GBV) and other protection concerns, and improving disaster risk reduction (DRR) across provincial, district, and local actors. Given the disproportionate impact a humanitarian crisis has upon them and the limited engagement at decision making moments normally afforded, particular attention will be paid to vulnerable or marginalised community members, including women, girls, boys and those living with disabilities. Each NGO will partner with local implementing agents including disabled people and organisations (DPOs) to ensure that projects are designed, monitoring, and adapted based on the particular needs and perspectives of these groups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="AU-ACNC-18055208636" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Australia</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Unit</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reception Desk</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>61392899444</telephone>
   <email>enquire@oxfam.org.au</email>
   <website>https://www.oxfam.org.au/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">130-138 Leicester Street, Carlton VIC 3053, AUSTRALIA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="AUD" value-date="2020-11-01">108250</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
