<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="ifoam-activities" dstore:index="2" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-BonnVR8726-1.2.2.</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.2. OLC Ghana, Togo, BF, STP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first face-to-face session of the Organic Leadership Course took place in Ghana between 21-29 April 2018. The objective of the course is to form a new generation of organic local leaders who will contribute to developing the local sector. A total number of 21 participants took part to the first residential session. The main training topics revolved around institutional management, communication, organic value chain, organic services and development, but also an in-depth understanding of the fundamentals of the organic sector. The second face-to-face session took place in October 2018. As part of the graduation process, the participants have created development plan in one of the directions that were explored during the course. Following a competitive selection process, the best three development plans have received a mini-grant of 3000 Euros each. The winners of the grants were announced during the graduation ceremony which took place end of October 2018. The selected projects include a public policy development plan, an organic agriculture training initiative and the set up of a demo farm. The OLC Togo and Burkina Faso were also finalised at the end of 2019, and 3 development plans per country were funded with 3000 euros each. The STP OLC has been scheduled for April 2020, but due to the current Covid-19 pandemic, it will be postponed to a later date.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DE-CR-BonnVR8726" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFOAM - Organics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
