<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" dstore:dataset="danida-all_4" dstore:index="1885" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-237227</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IHP efforts in relation to Ebola-crisis in Monrovia, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On September 18, 2014, the World Health Organization (WHO) requested the International Humanitarian Partnership (IHP) for assistance in the Ebola Outbreak in the city of Monrovia in Liberia. The purpose is rapid construction of five large Ebola Treatment Centres (ETC&#xBF;s). ETC&#xBF;s are requested to have a capacity of at minimum 500 beds for Ebola patient care, and will provide a significant support to the Liberian response to Ebola. Due to the urgency of the situation, IHP is working within a timeframe of maximum 4 weeks for the ECTs to be functioning. National and International staff working in the ETCs has to wear Personal Protective Equipment in a hot environment and will need air-conditioned facilities for the prevention of and recovery from a heatstroke. The support consist of 24 pre-fabricated flat packed air-conditioned habitat units, for the use of offices and rest areas at five major ECT-sites in Monrovia. Five to six units in each of the four main tent facility sites are to be set up, and further two units at Island Clinic, an already established Hospital facility. Nine of the units will function as office-facilities at the ETC&#xBF;s. Another nine units will serve as rooms for rest, cooling and recuperation for seated staff at the ETC&#xBF;s. These will be constructed as either single or multi section rooms. The rest of the units will function as rest/sleeping areas for the staff on night shift and on-call. The units will be established by the logistic team from Danish Emergency Management Agency (DEMA) in cooperation with The Swedish Civil Contingencies Agency (MSB). As MSB are engaged in other activities of the overall mission, they took lead of the IHP mission as well. MSB has currently contributed with a total of 25 million SEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2014-19954">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-237227-29171" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
