<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="308" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2014140877</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No Lost Generation: Promoting Multi-dimensional Child Well-being through Integrated Programming</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">No Lost Generation: Lasten hyvinvoinnin edistaminen integroidulla ohjelmoinnilla</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon is hosting around 1.5 million people who have fled the conflict in Syria. In addition there are more than 208000 Palestinian refugees in the country. The crisis in Syria has exacerbated the lack of resources and services in Lebanon. The situation h
as considerably deteriorated during the past year following the downfall spiral of the Lebanese economy made even worse by the COVID-19 pandemic and the Beirut explosion in August 2020. The No Lost Generation (NLG) initiative is a regional strategy to mobi
lise funding to improve the wellbeing of the millions of children who suffer due to the Syrian crisis. An estimated six million children in the region are at risk of being left without education and exposed to violence. The Finnish-funded UNICEF NLG projec
t in Lebanon focuses on the most vulnerable children and youth. The previous NLG implementation has brought an important lesson that the most effective way to increase vulnerable children&apos;s enrolment in basic education and to prevent violence against child
ren is to address their wellbeing in a comprehensive manner. Therefore this additional funding of Finland focuses on children&apos;s wellbeing by addressing their needs comprehensively both through child protection services and social benefits as well as throug
h provision of learning opportunities. Altogether some 5016 out-of-learning children will receive basic learning opportunities child protection services and/or vocational training or life-skills training opportunities. Beneficiaries are over 10-year-old Sy
rian Palestinian and Lebanese children and their families. Finland has been previously funding the UNICEF NLG components in Lebanon (5 M? in 2014 3.7 M? 2019) Turkey (2.5 M? in 2015) Jordan (2.5 M? in 2016) and Syria (2.5 M? in 2016 3 M? 2020). The new fun
ding decision of 4.3 M? for the years 2021-2022 to UNICEF Lebanon&apos;s NLG project continues Finland?s funding to Lebanon?s education sector and child protection provision.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">15 miljoonaa konfliktia paennutta syyrialaista on Libanonissa Libanonin viranomaiset arvioivat. Taman lisaksi maassa on yli 208 000 palestiinalaispakolaista. Syyrian kriisi kuormittaa entisestaan Libanonin jo aiemmin riittamattomia palveluita. Tilanne on h
eikentynyt huomattavasti viimeisen vuoden aikana Libanonin talouden syoksykierteen vuoksi. Kehitysta ovat heikentaneet entisestaan covid-19 ja Beirutin rajahdykset 4. elokuuta 2020. Palveluja on karsittu ja kouluja suljettu.No Lost Generation (NLG) on alue
ellinen aloite rahoituksen mobilisoimiseksi Syyrian konfliktista karsivien lasten hyvinvoinnin edistamiseen Syyriassa ja sen naapurimaissa. Aloitteen piirissa on kuusi miljoonaa lasta joiden koulutusmahdollisuudet ovat heikot ja joilla on korkea riski jout
ua vakivallan uhreiksi. Taman Suomen rahoittaman NLG-aloitteen alaisen hankkeen tavoite on haavoittuvimpien lasten ja nuorten hyvinvoinnin edistaminen kokonaisvaltaisesti. Suoriin hyodynsaajiin kuuluu syyrialaisia libanonilaisia ja palestiinalaisia yli 10-
vuotiaita lapsia ja nuoria. Heidan hyvinvointiaan tarkastellaan kokonaisvaltaisesti lastensuojelun koulutusmahdollisuuksien ja sosiaaliturvan nakokulmasta. Hankkeen avulla tarjotaan opetusta lastensuojelupalveluita ja ammatillista koulutusta yhteensa 5 016
 tytolle ja pojalle jotka eivat kay koulua ja jotka ovat vakivallan uhan alla. Hankkeen toteutus jatkaa Suomen aiempaa NLG-tukea jota Suomi antoi Libanoniin 5 MEUR vuonna 2014 ja 37 MEUR vuonna 2019. Suomi on rahoittanut myos muita UNICEF:n NLG-komponentte
ja Turkissa (25 MEUR v. 2015) Jordaniassa (25 MEUR v. 2016) ja Syyriassa (25 MEUR v. 2016 3 MEUR v. 2020). Nyt tehtava 43 MEUR lisamyonto Libanonin NLG-komponentille vuosille 2021-2022 jatkaa Suomen rahoitusta Libanonin koulutussektorin ja lastensuojelun k
ehittamiseksi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Childrens Fund</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n lastenrahasto</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2014140877" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-05-13" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.5" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2800000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">1500000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">4300000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2800000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2014140877" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
