<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="16" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-02-12T16:05:40" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-02-12T16:05:40" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2015150332</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-Led Accelerated Water Sanitation and Hygiene in Ethiopia phase III</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Vesihuolto- sanitaatio ja hygieniahanke vaihe III</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COWASH (Community-led Accelerated Water Sanitation and Hygiene ProjectI) increases the availability of safe water and sanitation in rural areas of Ethiopia. The aimed long term impact is to improve the health of the population. The project is based on comm
unity led approach: the villages are themselves in charge of the management of the building of the water points. Institutional WASH is targeted to schools and health facilities. The project is in alignment with the Government of Ethiopia?s long term plan (
GTP II) and the One WASH National Program II (OWNP II). Moreover it contributes towards the SDGs 6.1 and 6.2.Due to Covid-19 pandemic the planning of Phase IV is delayed. In order to avoid any gap between the phases the Ethiopian government supports the id
ea to continue the Phase III with an extension from June to December 2020. WASH sector is in addition to health sector the most critical one in fighting the pandemic. Therefore the extension includes elements of emergency and humanitarian aid as well as bu
ilding resilience against the spread of Covid-19 in all of the current five regions: Tigray Amhara SNNPR Benishangul Gumuz and Oromia. These include supporting the functioning of water supply and sanitation facilities in the health units isolation quaranti
ne and treatment centres. The rules and restrictions declared in the Federal State of Emergency as well as additional Regional State of Emergency rules and regulations will be applied throughout. The extension also enables the continuation of the project?s
 usual functions which also contributes to Covid-19 prevention and response. The project has a specific focus on women and girls as well as on people with disabilities; the specific needs of them will be applied in the project and emergency activities.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">COWASH III (Community-led Accelerated Water Sanitation and Hygiene Project) vesihuolto- sanitaatio- ja hygieniahankkeen tavoitteena on puhtaan veden saatavuuden ja sanitaation lisaaminen Etiopian maaseudulla ja sita kautta vaeston terveydentilan parantamin
en. Hankkeessa on kaytossa yhteisojohtoinen toimintamalli CMP (community managed project approach) jossa kylalaiset itse vastaavat vesihankkeen hallinnasta toteutuksesta ja huoltotoiminnasta. COWASH III-hankkeen tavoitteet on asetettu Etiopian kasvu- ja mu
utossuunnitelman (GTP II) ja kansallisen vesiohjelman One Wash National Plan (OWNP II) seka kestavan kehityksen tavoitteiden 6.1 ja 6.2 mukaisesti. Hankkeen IV-vaihe oli tarkoitus alkaa heinakuussa 2020 mutta korona-pandemian alkaessa suunnittelutyo viivas
tyi. Hankkeeseen toivottiin Etiopian puolelta jatkokautta etenkin tilanteessa jossa vesi- sanitaatio- ja hygieniatoiminnalla (WASH) on terveyssektorin ohella kriittisin rooli vaeston suojelemisessa korona-pandemialta. III-vaiheen jatko kesa-joulukuulle 202
0 sisaltaa siten raataloityja aktiviteetteja koronan vastaisiin toimenpiteisiin ml. humanitaarista toimintaa seka kriisinsietokyvyn rakentamista pandemiaa vastaan hankkeen nykyisilla toiminta-alueilla Amharan Tigrayn Oromian Benishangul Gumuzin ja SNNPR:n 
osavaltioissa. Suunnitellut aktiviteetit terveys- karanteeni- ja eristyskeskuksissa ja yhteisoissa vaikuttavat suoraan pandemian torjuntaan. Toiminnassa noudatetaan kansallisen hatatilan saadoksia ja rajoituksia seka osavaltioiden mahdollisesti asettamia s
aadoksia. Jatkokaudella pidettaisiin ylla myos hankkeen ns. perustoimintoja eli vesi- ja sanitaatiopisteita rakennetaan seka yhteisoissa etta instituutioissa ml. kouluissa ja terveysasemilla namakin kontribuoivat pandemian vastaisessa tyossa. Hankkeen kaut
ta parannetaan myos naisten nuorten tyttojen ja vammaisten asemaa ja naiden ryhmien erityistarpeet otetaan huomioon pandemiaan vastatessa seka hankkeen aktiviteettien suunnittelussa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="61009" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ramboll Finland oy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2015150332" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is a secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the main priority area in this act
ivity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="13" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2957800</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2670000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">3228013.6201</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2015150332" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
