<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="finland_mfa-009" dstore:index="317" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020- 2020000344</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP SRF Syria crisis support to resilience agenda</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">UNDP SRF Syyrian kriisi resilienssi-agendan tuki</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Syrian conflict has created a humanitarian catastrophe affecting the lives of millions of people. The resilience of societies is under extreme pressure also in Syria&apos;s neighboring countries that host millions of refugees while facing their own internal
 societal and economic challenges.Finland supports the resilience of Syria&apos;s neighboring countries who carry the highest share of hosting the refugees as outlined in Finland?s Strategy for Development Cooperation and Humanitarian aid in response to the Syr
ian conflict. Finland has supported the work of the UNDP in mainstreaming resilience-thinking into the work of the UN. UNDP is the co-coordinator (with UNHCR) for the Regional Refugee and Resilience Plan (3RP) plans being responsible for coordination of re
silience activities under the plan.The project continues Finland&apos;s support for UNDP?s resilience work. With Finland?s support UNDP&apos;s SRF has previously promoted resilience agenda in the UN Syria crisis response. For example SRF has convened partners in con
ferences meetings and workshops in which crisis response plans have been drafted and monitored. SRF has also produced knowledge products and articles on strengthening societies? resilience as well as advocated for a more resilience-based programming in UN 
response plans. In addition Finland and SRF together with private sector actors have organized Innovation for Crisis workshops (I4C) in which efforts have been taken in order to find new solutions to humanitarian challenges. All the above work will continu
e in the next phase of the project: SRF will continue its coordination role; convenes different actors in conferences workshops and meetings; develops knowledge products on supporting resilience; as well as brings together private sector actors for I4C wor
kshops. Particular emphasis will also be put in fragile societies? ? such as Lebanon and Jordan?s ? capabilities and resilience to cope with the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic as the outbreak is likely to have far-reaching implications for these societies. Furt
hermore in the new phase of the project SRF will put more focus on sensitizing the relevant UNDP country teams for the resilience agenda using its expertise to strengthen the country offices? resilience-based programming.The overall budget of the project i
s 0.9 million euros which will be allocated to UNDP?s sub-regional response facility SRF for 2020?2022.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Syyrian konflikti on aiheuttanut humanitaarisen kriisin vaikuttaen miljoonien ihmisten elamaan. Yhteiskunnallinen ja yhteisojen kantokyky eli resilienssi on koetuksella myos Syyrian naapurimaissa jotka majoittavat miljoonia pakolaisia samalla kun kamppaile
vat omien yhteiskunnallisten ja taloudellisten haasteidensa kanssa. Suomi tukee pakolaistaakkaa kantavien Syyrian naapurimaiden resilienssin vahvistamista Suomen Syyria-apustrategian painopisteiden mukaisesti. Suomi on tukenut etenkin YK:n kehitysjarjeston
 UNDP:n toimintaa resilienssi-ajattelun valtavirtaistamisessa YK:n toimintaan. UNDP:n alainen SRF-keskus koordinoi UNHCR:n kanssa Syyrian kriisiin liittyvia YK:n alueellisia apusuunnitelmia (3RP-suunnitelma) vastaten niiden resilienssi-toimien koordinoinni
sta.Hanke on jatkoa Suomen tukemalle SRF:n resilienssityolle. Suomen tuella SRF on edesauttanut humanitaarisen avun ja kehitysyhteistyon jatkumoajattelun sisallyttamista YK:n toimintaan Syyrian kriisissa. SRF on koonnut yhteen eri toimijoita konferensseihi
n kokouksiin ja tyopajoihin joissa kriisin apusuunnitelmia on laadittu ja niiden toteutumista seurattu tuottanut tutkimusta/artikkeleita yhteiskuntien resilienssin vahvistamisesta seka vaikuttanut konkreettisesti YK:n apusuunnitelmien resilienssi-rahoituks
en tason kasvamiseen nostamalla resilienssi-agendaa eri foorumeilla ml. avunantajien parissa. Suomi on toteuttanut yhteistyossa SRF:n ja yksityisen sektorin toimijoiden kanssa myos I4C-tyopajoja joissa on etsitty uusia ratkaisuja humanitaarisiin haasteisii
n.Hankkeen edellisessa vaiheessa toteutettuja toimintoja jatketaan: SRF jatkaa apusuunnitelmien koordinointiroolia ja resilienssi-toimintojen suunnittelua ja seurantaa; eri toimijoiden yhteen tuomista resilienssi-agendan vahvistamiseksi; tutkimustyotaan li
ittyen yhteiskuntien kantokyvyn vahvistamiseen; seka uusien ratkaisuiden loytamista humanitaarisiin ongelmiin I4C-tyopajoissa. SRF panostaa myos koronavirus-pandemian ja siihen liittyvien rajoitustoimien vaikutusten arviointiin Libanonissa ja Jordaniassa. 
Lisaksi SRF vahvistaa alueen UNDP:n maatoimistoja jotta nama kykenisivat huomioimaan yhteiskuntien resilienssin vahvistamisen paremmin toiminnassaan.Hankkeen 0.9 MEUR rahoitus tulee Afrikan ja Lahi-Idan osaston vuoden 2020 maararahoista seka kuluvan vuoden
 valtuuksista vuodelle 2021. Rahoitus kanavoidaan UNDP:n SRF-keskukselle hankkeen toteutukseen vuosina 2020?2022.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n kehitysohjelma</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-18" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="74020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="11.5" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="8.1" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">450000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">450000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">900000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">450000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
