<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="imc_uk-activities" dstore:index="7" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1093861-XM-DAC-47066</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1093861" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Ministry of Health Preparedness to Respond to COVID-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity 1- International Medical Corps will set up screening room for triage and isolation of patients at the hospitals in Bria, Bambari and Birao. screening and isolation units installed. No patients tested positive during the reporting period. last positive case was in Bria in June 2020. Activity 2: Ensure case management through a 20-bed establishment in the hospitals of Bria, Bambari and Birao. Installation of tents with 20 beds in Bria and 8 beds in Birao. Activity 3: Purchase and supply pharmaceutical products, medical supplies, including PPE, medical equipment and IPC supplies for the three hospitals of Bria, Bambari and Birao and MSF France. international order for drugs, supplies and medical equipment launched in September and in November 2020.This was due to the fact that after the project was approved no cases were recorded in the country therefore IMC was considering modifying the requests according to the situation on the ground. Part of this order will be a donation to MSF-France in Bria. Activity 4: Provide MHPSS services to staff, patients and community members, including telephone counseling, Psychosocial support to frontline workers, patients and their families. MHPSs team were available to offer services to patients who have been screened. Activity 5: Strengthen the installation of additional hand washing stations in the health establishment and waste management (according to the COVID-19 protocol). Each isolation site is equipped with safe environmental hygiene measures. Activity 6: Recruit human resources for the project. IMC launched recruitment of staff for the project, but delayed due to shortage of health care personnel like Medical doctors. Activity 7: Transport of supplies to the field. PPE received in country was transported in September 2020.
Output 2 - Activity 1: International Medical Corps UK will use the existing Community Health Workers (CHWs) to conduct community and household level awareness on COVID-19 such as dispelling myths, and communication on preventive measures, symptoms and what to do if ill. CHWs were trained and provided with masks for door-to-door visits to protect them. IEC materials on COVID-19 messages were distributed to them to raise awareness and emphasize to recognize the symptoms of COVID-19. Activity 2: Involve CHWs to conduct community-based surveillance and patients&#x2019; referral&#x2019;s, Weekly report, is shared during the meeting of the multisectoral prefectural committee responsible for locally coordinating the response to COVID 19 in each site before being sent to the MOH.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-47066" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration (IOM)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1093861" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>4402072530001</telephone>
   <email>info@internationalmedicalcorps.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenses as of September 30 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">37119</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly expenditure - Q1</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-47066" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1093861" ref="International Medical Corps UK" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GB-CHC-1093861-XM-DAC-47066-DP.1207</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <sector code="12220" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Expenses as of November 30 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-30">298929</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly expenditure - Q2</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-47066" ref="IOM  XM-DAC-47066" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1093861" ref="GB-CHC-1093861-XM-DAC-47066-DP.1207" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <sector code="12220" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
