<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-democraticrepublicofcongo" dstore:index="54" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC690</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency assistance for most vulnerable Households affected by the crisis in Eringeti</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the Eringeti IDPs committee, there are 1,300 new displaced households in Eringeti who arrived from October 17 to 20, 2020. It is reported that some families are spending the night in low-income houses abandoned by local populations, others in host families, very unfortunately these families have the same poverty lines as the displaced and others in local churches, but others are completely homeless.
These displaced people are exposed to bad weather and mosquito bites. They are without food, essential household items, toilets, etc. They are exposed to problems of malnutrition, SGBV protection, water-borne diseases, COVID-19, etc.
Local authorities are not equipped to face this emergency and provide support to the affected population. Up to now, most of affected people haven&#x2019;t received any assistance yet and it is highly unlikely they will receive any. Local authorities are not equipped to face this emergency and provide support to the affected population. Up to now, most of affected people haven&#x2019;t received any assistance yet and it is highly unlikely they will receive any.
According to the Preliminary Diagnosis Report carried out by the displaced persons committee, displaced persons need:
- Food security: All displaced households are in need of food, some had spent their first night without eating and others benefited from the generosity of host families to find something to eat, although without being full. Displaced households without everything do not have the resources to obtain food from the local market. The indigenous populations painfully following the lack of access to the fields, the only source of income.
- Shelters / AME. The newly displaced are living in host families, in close proximity, and abandoned houses without essential household items. These families, having traveled several kilometers before reaching Eringeti, are deprived of everything and are exposed to the elements.
- Protection. Some of the displaced were showing signs of trauma, crying and not knowing how to speak with the mission team. There is a need for protection actors to organize an in-depth protection assessment mission, in order to identify the protection problems and risks for these newly displaced persons. Some children are said to be separated from their families, while searching towards Eringeti. 30 unaccompanied children are also reported in this locality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC690" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC690" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9; Coop&#xE9;rative Agricole du Congo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC690" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-11-17">50000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54522">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-11-17">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69022">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-11-17">50000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9; Coop&#xE9;rative Agricole du Congo</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
