<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-southsudan" dstore:index="106" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SSD210</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID &#x2013; 19 Preparedness and Emergency Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMI is implementing the CGF funded Self &#x2013; Reliance and sustainability of peace in conflict affected areas of Aguok South and North in Gogrial (SSD203). Although Gogrial has not yet recorded cases of COVID-19 infections, as a preventive mechanism and to prepare the communities before infections spread,  we propose to undertake emergency preparedness and response to build community awareness among key stakeholders, SDMIC staff team, project beneficiaries through reaching activity locations, public places and target families through outreach sanitization in five rural communities. We would use the ongoing project intervention platforms such as peace and reconciliation communities, women self-help groups, parents and teachers&#x2019; associations and school peace clubs in sensitizing and reaching the larger community on COVID 19.  
Volunteers, SDMIC staff team, women self-help groups leaders and peace and reconciliation committee leaders would make home visits (during home visit, volunteers and leaders would adhere to social distancing) and orient families about the preventive measures and personal hygiene.  
Illiteracy rates are high particularly among women which keeps a large percentage of the community people from important information about the outbreak of the COVID 19 that comes through the regular media and other forms of modern (online) communication. Diverse public awareness activities will focus on distributing pamphlets, displaying banners,  public awareness through megaphone, placing hygiene and sanitation kits in public places like markets, clinics, PRC meeting center, Self Help Group meeting centers, peace dialogues points. Home visit and awareness-raising are important for direct messaging in local language since there is high levels of illiteracy. Radio messages in local languages will also be used to provide information on social distancing, hand washing and emphasis on staying at home. The messaging will also be used to communicate accurate information which has been cleared by UNICEF, WHO and Ministry of Health. This will counter fake information which is being circulated in various platforms such as social media platforms.  The preparedness response would also prevent stigmatization of people perceived to be coming from the virus prone locations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD210" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD210" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Society Of Daughters of Mary Immaculate</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSD210" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-01">15000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54054">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-14">15000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68501">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-14">15000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Society Of Daughters of Mary Immaculate</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
