<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-democraticrepublicofcongo" dstore:index="36" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC669</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Assistance to Vulnerable Families in Kinshasa during the COVID 19 Outbreak</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 is having a significant impact on the global economy, and for cities like Kinshasa, the impact will be more severe, where casual labour and small businesses are a lifeline for many families who are already struggling to survive.The consequence of limiting or even closing businesses in Kinshasa will have an extremely negative effect on people&#x2019;s means of survival, more so than the impact of the virus being contracted, experts have warned of the dire impact this could have on many families. People will be faced with an unenviable choice of staying at home and losing much needed income, or going out to try to secure an income and potentially spread the virus or increase their risk of contracting it.  The economic consequences on vulnerable families will be catastrophic in Kinshasa where many low-income families live in informal settlements and slums which make social distancing impossible. Many will be ill-served by measures that rely on the stockpiling of food, the availability of savings, the ability to work from home and the need to keep distance even from close relatives. In these environments, staying at home will itself be a risk as people live in cramped, poorly ventilated dwellings housing in large numbers, queuing to use shared toilets, drawing water from shared wells and using crowded public transport. Immediate help is needed to support vulnerable groups, particularly those working in the informal sector who can no longer access livelihoods (decreasing purchasing power and leaving them unable to buy food or basic items to help practice good hygiene and not further spread the virus), people living with disabilities, the elderly, the chronically ill, and child headed households. Alongside this immediate need for support, there is also a need for mass education campaigns to dispel myths and rumours spreading about COVID-19 and to inform on best practices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC669" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas DR Congo National Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC669" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC669" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-10">237712.2258</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54120">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-19">237712.2258</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68557">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-19">237712.23</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas DR Congo National Office</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
