<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-jordan" dstore:index="1" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-JOR020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Telemedicine: Supporting Caritas Jordan in response to COVID-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 has been spreading in Jordan since the beginning of March 2020. Restrictions imposed by the Jordanian Government following the COVID-19 outbreak have severely impacted the ability of refugees to access health care services, and at the same time, those services which are available are hugely overstretched. Due to restrictions, Caritas clinics are operating on a reduced capacity, leaving thousands of refugees without access to healthcare and medications. Although Caritas Jordan health clinics are now partially functioning, clinic staff are overloaded and not able to accommodate the full needs of the refugee population. 

This project will fund the installation of a Telemedicine service (calling centre) to provide essential health services for refugees during the pandemic and beyond, and will include the following sub-services: GP and Specialist consultation, Pharmaceutical prescription, Nutrition Advice and  Emergency Referral cases. The Telemedicine service will increase access to CJ&apos;s health services, reaching more people and easing the burden of existing health facilities, while complying with government regulations and ensuring the safety of both Caritas staff and refugee communities. It will also reduce the number of people arriving at the health centres thereby reducing the risk of the virus spreading, and is also a way of ensuring that people living in isolated areas or neighbourhoods that have been blocked off by GoJ can still access essential health services.

Funds will be spent on the following:
 - Setting up the Telemedicine calling centre system 
 - Laptops for operators
 - Antivirus for calling centre server
 - CRM licence</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="JOR020" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Jordan National Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="JOR020" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="JOR020" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-01">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54477">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-11-02">10000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
