<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="mrg-activities" dstore:index="3" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-282305-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004021</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-282305" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minority Rights Group</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;All for All&quot; For the right to be different and the elimination of all forms of discrimination in Tunisia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Tunisian CSOs working in the field of human rights and in the fight against all forms of discrimination, and in particular the associations that are part of the Observatory for the Right to Difference (57 organizations in 14 governorates) and the network of Anti-Discrimination Points (10 organizations in 8 governorates including the ADD) 2. Tunisian lawyers (members of the legal clinic); 3. Tunisian journalists; 4. The Tunisian media ; 5. The Tunisian government and international actors such as the Committee on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination, HRC, and UPR; 6. Associations with a cultural mandate</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Tunisia, many sexual, ethnic, religious, and cultural minorities constantly face deep-rooted discrimination in Tunisian society even though the principle of equality among citizens is enshrined in the 2014 Constitution. This equality remains theoretical insofar as these forms of discrimination are particularly entrenched in Tunisian society, and are reflected in public and media discourse, thus ignoring the existence and rights of these minorities. The LGBTQI+ community rights and freedoms of LGBTQI+ people are seriously threatened by recurring and trivialized acts of torture, arbitrary arrests and degrading practices. Although a law against racial discrimination was finally adopted in October 2018 by the Tunisian Parliament,direct discrimination on the grounds of the colour of their skin (whether Tunisian or of immigrant origin), is still widespread. insofar very few cases are brought to court. The Amazights represent the largest ethnic minority in Tunisia, yet they are struggling to have their language and culture recognized as full citizens, victims of a policy and discourse of invisibility of their people for the benefit of national unity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ultimate objective of this project is to promote and strengthen the right and position of discriminated groups in Tunisia for an egalitarian citizen participation, by fighting against all forms of discrimination, at the legislative and social level, while taking into account the current context of the COVID-19 crisis. The project is based on two main intertwined thrusts a) Supporting civil society in its fight against all forms of discrimination. b) Raising awareness among key actors on the issue of discrimination and to implement and strengthen policies and practices to reduce discriminatory incidents and to support the establishment of a legal framework guaranteeing the rights of discriminated groups. Through the use of effective tools to identify and record discrimination against minorities in Tunisia, this project will allow to furnish material to confront the reality and impact public policies addressing the structural racism, xenophobia, sexism and homophobia at the root of the forms of discrimination. The strategy of the project tends to improve the skills of CSOs, lawyers, media and rights holders, as well as to establish very close links between associations and state structures implicated in the themes related to this project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004021" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association for the Promotion of the Right to Difference</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt; Human rights programming targeting specific groups, e.g. children, persons with disabilities, migrants, ethnic, religious, linguistic and sexual minorities, indigenous people
&gt; Translation of international human rights commitments into national legislation; reporting and follow-up; human rights dialogue. Human rights defenders and human rights NGOs; human rights advocacy, activism, mobilisation; awareness raising and public human rights education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-07-01">345200</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
