<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-sudan" dstore:index="27" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SDN116</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operational costs for COVID-19 Economic Recovery and Emergency Delivery (CovERED) in North Darfur</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">While COVID-19 is principally a public health emergency, the pandemic will have a significant socio-economic impact on the people of Sudan. Modelling by the Centre for Disease Dynamics, Economics and Policy estimates that between 40,000 to 60,000 people will develop a severe infection as a result of COVID-19 in Sudan with much dependent on the movement restriction approaches adopted by the Government.  Pre-COVID-19, Sudan already faced a highly complex socio-political environment. This includes new and protracted displacement of large parts of the population, regional insecurity and high levels of chronic malnutrition and food insecurity nationwide. CAFOD is participating in consortium led by CRS to respond to the COVID-19 in ND with support of funds from FFP
The project Goal is: Vulnerable urban communities in Darfur survive with dignity, restore their lives and communities in the face of COVID-19
Strategic Objectives:
1.Strategic Objective 1: Mitigate health impacts of COVID-19
Intermediate Result 1.1: Communities in Darfur adopt preventative behaviors to protect themselves and others from COVID-19
2.Strategic Objective 2: COVID-19 affected households have met their basic food and hygiene needs.
Intermediate Result 2.1: People living in urban areas of Darfur meet their food and other essential needs throughout the lean season
Cross-cutting priorities:
 Safe and dignified programming approaches: will ensure equitable access, especially for the most vulnerable and at-risk groups; accountability to the people we serve; support of self-protection capacities; and Do No Harm principles.  
 Partnership with local and national actors: will leverage vast, long-standing relationships with government institutions, local organizations and civil society networks to heighten reach and scale.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN116" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN116" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SDN116" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-28">227828.7313</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54380">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-17">227828.7313</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
