<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-sudan" dstore:index="24" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SDN113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Emergency Response in El Fasher, and CoVERED  North Darfur</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">While COVID-19 is principally a public health emergency, the pandemic has engendered significant socio-economic impact on the people of Sudan. Pre-COVID-19 Sudan already faced a highly complex socio-economic and political environment. This includes new and protracted displacement of large parts of the population, regional insecurity, inflation and high levels of chronic malnutrition and food insecurity.  The situation is likely to be worsened by the COVID-19 pandemic. There are fears that COVID-19 would likely further increase the risk of mortality for those populations whose health status is already compromised by acute malnutrition.
The project will provide food security and livelihoods support to at least 250 most vulnerable households (approximately 1500 people) drawn from the 16 villages where CAFOD and SAG are undertaking RISING II project activities. The project will assist households to transition through the lean season by providing them with food basket vouchers, restocking vouchers; and address critical WASH facilities/materials and information on COVID-19 infection and prevention. 
Specific objectives:
At least 250 most vulnerable HHs in El Fasher rural have their basic emergency food and livelihood needs met.
At least 1500 vulnerable and at-risk women, men, boys and girls in El Fasher rural adopt preventative behaviours to protect themselves and others from COVID-19
Outputs.
1.100 HHs provided with vouchers for restocking (each household to receive vouchers worth one goat/sheep) 
2.250 HHs provided for two months with food vouchers (SDG 4500 per month) 
3.16 Hand Washing Facilities (HWF) installed in 16 villages
4.32 awareness campaigns undertaken in the 16 villages on COVID-19 infection prevention and control.
5. 3200 IEC materials on COVID-19 infection prevention and control produced and distributed to during the awareness campaigns.
The other funding stream which is 2nd approval ae  from CoVERED funds under FFP  and linked to Type 2 Project SDN116</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN113" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN113" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Action Group (SAG)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SDN113" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">49232.4224</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54159">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-25">30000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68584">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-25">30000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Action Group (SAG)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
