<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-niger" dstore:index="52" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIG113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting Caritas-development-Niger in the Covid-19 response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the progressive increase of Covid-19 cases since the first case was recorded on 29 March 2020 in Niger, the situation is becoming increasingly worrying because Niger is one of the countries with the weakest health system to cope with this pandemic. In addition to this, there are other factors that make the situation more and more worrying and increase the vulnerability of the population in the face of this pandemic and make the response very complex and the pandemic difficult to manage. Among these factors we can mention: difficult access to water due to the dry season, transhumance movements that favour the spread of the pandemic, the seasonal meningitis that Niger often experiences during this period, the agricultural lean season which increases food insecurity and the low level of knowledge on prevention measures of the population. 
As of 17 April 2020 Niger has registered a total of 627 confirmed cases of Covid-19 of which 110 are warned and 18 are died.
In order to support the efforts and initiatives of prevention and response put in place by the government, the intervention of all actors is very important to face this worrying public health problem. It is in this logic that this project proposal is submitted to enable CADEV-Niger to contribute to the activities planned by the Covid-19 response and coordination committee set up by the government of Niger.   

In line with the goals of our Country Strategy Paper which mandates CAFOD to intervene in emergency situations in support of our partner depending on the availability of resources, this project therefore aims to support our long-term partner CADEV-Niger which has agreed to represent the Caritas country forum in the response to Covid-19.

This project will focus mainly on activities to sensitize the population on measures to prevent the spread of Covid-19 from the 36 health areas where the 36 health centres run by the Catholic Church are located. All activities are planned and will be implemented according to the national response plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG113" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG113" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIG113" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-01">17545.0002</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54003">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-22">17545.0002</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68384">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-22">17545</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
