<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-sudan" dstore:index="22" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SDN111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Risks and Impact Reduction through infection prevention and control in SK and NK</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 15th April, according to WHO, 1,918,138 were the cases confirmed of COVID-19 infection in 213 countries, with 123,126 confirmed deaths. In Sudan, as of 22nd April, confirmed infection cases were 140, with 13 deaths. Sudan state officials have taken a number of steps towards reducing infection risks in the country. Some of the steps taken include declaring the disease a public health emergency, closing of all airports, ports and land crossings, halting inter-state public transportation and imposing a country-wide curfew between 18:00 and 06:00.
WHO has supported the Federal Ministry of Health (FMOH) to elaborate a Countrywide Preparedness and Response Plan (CPRP) which outlines management of arrivals at the points of entry, isolation, patient care, infection prevention and control, supplies, risk communication, surveillance and capacity building.  The CRRP has a three-month preparedness and response plan, outlining key activities and resource requirements anchored on 8 key pillars. 
CAFOD is part and parcel of the response plan under two pillars: Risk communication and community engagement and infection prevention and control. 
The following activities will be delivered under this response.
1.Conduct 3 trainings  each for two-day for 15 community leaders drawn from the three target localities (5 from each locality). 
2.With the support of the trained community leaders, establish 9 COVID-19 Community Support Centres,
3.Design, produce and distribute 4000 IEC materials on COVID-19 infection prevention and control
4.Procure 6235 pieces of soap (250 grams) and distribute them to 1247 HHs. With the support of the community leaders, and in consultation with community members, 
5.By use of megaphone, undertake 20 community awareness campaigns, 14 campaigns in South Kordofan targeted localities and 6 in North Kordofan targeted locality</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN111" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SDN111" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Sahara International Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SDN111" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-26">14520</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54021">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">14520</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68414">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">14520</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Sahara International Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
