<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-brazil" dstore:index="29" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BRA616</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Emergency Response: food and hygiene provision to favela communities in S&#xE3;o Paulo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of July 2020 Brazil had over 2.4 million confirmed Coronavirus cases and near 90,000 deaths, with 0.5 million in S&#xE3;o Paulo (SP) alone and 21,000 deaths. Cases continued to rise as the country reopens. Health services were reportedly near to collapse and 58% of recorded deaths occurring at home. The 2 million people living in favelas and poor peri-urban communities have been disproportionately affected with research showing that residents of the poorest districts of S&#xE3;o Paulo are 10 times more likely to die of COVID than those in wealthier neighbourhoods. Lack of economic options, crowded conditions, poor ventilation and lack of basic sanitation have made it difficult to follow guidelines. Poorer access to and quality of health care, higher pre-existing risk factors, and lack of reliable information have contributed to poorer outcomes in S&#xE3;o Paulo&apos;s favelas. Low paid workers have lost their jobs, government emergency benefits are half of the minimum wage and many have been unable to access, or had difficulties accessing them. 

This project will benefit 10,528 people in 8 favela communities in eastern S&#xE3;o Paulo with improved access to information about the virus and how to prevent it, signposting to social protection, health, and gender-based violence support services. 2,820 of the most vulnerable people will receive food and hygiene kits for 3 months. 548 people will benefit from increased household income through participation in a recycling project which will also benefit the whole favela with reduced flood and vector borne disease risk. The 8 favela communities targeted by the project will also benefit from advocacy for street cleaning to reduce COVID and other disease risk.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA616" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA616" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Movimento de Defesa do Favelado - Regiao Episcopal Belem</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BRA616" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-01">83413.9551</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54264">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-06">52165.8931</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68691">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-06">52165.89</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Movimento de Defesa do Favelado - Regiao Episcopal Belem</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
