<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-cambodia" dstore:index="18" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-KAM132</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Covid-19 emergency response and recovery for poor communities in Pursat and Banteay Mean Chey</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is to reach out to respond to needs of the affected people, mainly youth and young adults, who had returned to their villages and are unemployed as a result of Covid-19. Over 800,000 Cambodian migrant workers from Thailand alone have had to return home and have lost their incomes since March 2020. The main Covid impact on Cambodia is economic as it is heavily dependent on garment industry which has been hit hard by cancellations/non-payment of orders. Many former garment workers mostly young people have also returned to their hometowns increasing burdens on farmer families to find food to feed all their members.

Partner has conducted impact survey in target communities to understand real issues and needs of community people. Interviews and meetings were conducted with all groups of people, local authorities, youth and young adults migrants who have returned home, poor farmers, school directors, and students, for providing them the opportunity to discuss about challenges, to find a solution and to seek any alternative way to support each other.

The project objectives are:
- To support farmers for creation Self-Help Group&apos;s fund and loans that can give to these affected people who are willing to get back into small and sustainable agriculture. 
- To provide support to farmers for setting up the SRI cultivation, chicken rearing and home gardening on their land or on hired land for youth in the communities as necessary. Instead of hiring machines, the work will have to be done manually by these affected people for which they will be paid.

This project is specifically targeting group of people those who need immediate jobs to get food and income to survive. The project will support farmers on chicken rearing, vegetable growing, hiring land for the poor to grow rice,  providing some for emergency food for the poorest farmer who face food shortage, and raising people awareness on hygiene and sanitation related behavior changes to prevent Covid-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KAM132" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KAM132" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Battambang Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="KAM132" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">15000.01</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54149">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-24">15000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68551">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-24">15000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Battambang Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
