<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="wvuk-activities" dstore:index="85" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285908-216826</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Fund Zimbabwe Storm Chalane 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will focus on 10,000 most vulnerable people or 2,000 Households (out of an estimated 100,000 people) that are expected to be in need of emergency wash assistance and protection support. These are selected as the anticipated priority interventions, based on the initial assessment work and key informant interviews World Vision has carried out. The activities are flexible, and World Vision could adjust the proposed interventions should the actual needs differ from those anticipated. 
 
 Chimanimani&apos;s District Civil Protection Unit and the associated Committees (DCPC) have set up 25 evacuation centers in Chimanimani. Sheltering is expected to last for at least 1-2 weeks, during which WASH and protection needs of the most vulnerable will be critical. The project will supply 60 handwashing stations to the evacuation centers in Chimanimani. These will be supplied with clean water for a period of 1-2 weeks, as long as it is required, inline with government estimates for how long the evacuation centres will be operational. Supplies of PPE (cloth facemasks and sanitisers) will be made available to the vulnerable groups inside evacuation centres, so that those most at-risk have reduced exposure to the spread of diseases, including COVID-19. Menstrual hygiene kits will be supplied to ensure that the dignity of women and girls during displacement is protected, as a key component of the project&apos;s protection strategy. 
 
 As it becomes increasingly safe for families to return to their homes, they can expect that water sources may be contaminated due to the anticipated levels of flooding in the district. The project will therefore focus on addressing these challenges by providing water purification aquatabs to 2,000 households - targeting child-headed households, under 5s and pregnant/lactation women, the elderly, people living with chronic illness, and people living with disabilities. The Civil Protection Committee has requested the provision of mosquito nets as they are severely lacking. These are important to protect people from maleria which is already high in the area.
 
 In addition to the WASH needs of HHs evacuated and of those sheltering in place, the psychosocial support and protection will be needed in order to avoid deterioration of the well-being of young women and girls during the period where they are exposed to the shocks and most vulnerable. The project will seek to improve access to emergency GBV and child protection services both during displacement and during the early phase of communities returning to their homes, by working with Musasa, a nationwide provider of GBV services as well as Child Protection Society who provide child protection services at a grassroots level. Through support from the Start Fund project, these two organisations (among others) will work with World Vision to develop key messaging to support a public awareness protection campaign among households most affected by Tropical Storm Chalane in Chimanimani. Messaging will tackle the topics of child marriage, child exploitation and harmful child migration/labor which are rife in the region. World Vision , working with these protection expert organisations will carry out rapid protection assessments focusing on Evacuation Centers, displaced communities, and those communities within their original place of residents but who will have been severely affected. These rapid assessments will be used to refine key messaging. Awareness raising will be conducted through radio, mobile vans, and social media platforms. Through this campaign, the project will seek to increase the uptake of protection and GBV services at the time where the normal community-based protection structures are disrupted, and before events and decisions cause long-term harmful effects. As an adaptation to Covid-19, case management and psychosocial support will be provided through GBV emergency hotlines by service providers. The role of the project will be to make communities affected by Chalane aware of the services and encourage them to reach out for support during the disruption caused by the Tropical Storm.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="US-EIN-95-3202116-ZW" ref="US-EIN-95-3202116" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="US-EIN-95-3202116-ZW" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.worldvision.org.uk</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="P25" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water and sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-07">124995</value>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Network</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-08">151753.27</value>
   <provider-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="US-EIN-95-3202116-ZW" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Zimbabwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-31">18402</value>
   <provider-org ref="GB-CHC-285908" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision United Kingdom</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="US-EIN-95-3202116-ZW" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Zimbabwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
