<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-niger" dstore:index="57" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIG120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to people living with disabilities impacted by the Covid-19 pandemic in Niger</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Having registered its first case on March 29, 2020, Niger has accumulated by January 30, 2021, 4433 positive cases out of 72624 tests performed. Out of the 4433 positive cases, 3583 cases have been declared cured, 153 people have died and 697 active cases are being treated.
This pandemic context aggravates an already unstable and poor health situation characterised by persistent seasonal epidemics (meningitis, measles), a high mortality rate (Maternal mortality rate: 509 per 100,000 live births, Deaths under five: 85 per 1,000 live births) against the backdrop of a very weak health system and factors that increase the vulnerability of the population or facilitate the spread of the virus (drought, food insecurity, transhumance, difficulty of access to water).
The negative impact of this pandemic is not only health-related, but also economic, especially in a country where human development indicators are very low, making Niger one of the poorest countries in the world, chronically affecting more than a quarter of the population (26.8%). 
This impact is much more pronounced among the disabled population than among the rest of the population. People with disabilities are particularly disadvantaged by the socio-economic consequences of COVID-19 and the measures taken to control the pandemic. 
The risk of contracting COVID-19 is higher among people with disabilities and the risk of medical complications and death related to COVID-19 is higher among people with disabilities.
With an estimated population of 22.8 million, Niger is one of the countries with one of the highest natural population growth rates in the world (3.9% per year)1 and the disabled population is estimated at 4.2% (2.11% women and 2.06% men) .

This project therefore aims to support people with disabilities to reduce the considerable economic and health impact that this pandemic has on their daily lives by providing them with food to meet their immediate needs but also by supporting their income-generating activities and ensuring the strengthening of their capacities or by accompanying them in learning the profession in order to strengthen their long-term resilience.
This project will support people with disabilities to become stakeholders in the prevention of Covid-19 by raising their awareness of the barriers against Covid-19, by training and supporting women with disabilities in the sewing of masks in line with government recommendations. Hand washing kits adapted to people with disabilities as well as other pandemic prevention equipment and products will be distributed to the beneficiaries (disinfectant gels).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG120" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niamey</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG120" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIG120" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-15">41459.4269</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54891">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-12">41459.4269</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69410">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-12">41459.43</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niamey</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
