<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="gb-chc-220949-activities" dstore:index="43" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-220949-P8417</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Northern Rakhine project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will address the primary and secondary impact of Covid-19 in Maungdaw and Minbya township in Rakhine, supporting the implementation of preventative measures, increasing awareness and addressing basic needs of vulnerable communities in two townships in Rakhine. In addition, the project aims to enhance the capacity of MRCS&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x2122; township branches and strengthen linkages between the branch and the network of community volunteers, which are critical to the success of the project. &#xC2;&#xA0;
In the short term, 5 villages will be able to successfully form community volunteer groups which fosters sustained linkages with the Township branch. In the long term, it is expected that these linkages will be mobilised to support a community led resilience building, as discussed in the Lessons section above. This approach will be integrated into the Covid-19 recovery phase and addressing the secondary impacts of Covid-19.
The project includes: 1) COVID awareness sessions, through the approach of RCCE, MRCS will conduct COVID-19 awareness sessio in the targeted communities. 2) Community level cloth mask making, community level volunteers will be organised and trained to undertake community level cloth mask making activities in selected villages. Community level tailors will be enaged in the process pf producing mask under tehcnial supervision and guidance of MRCS. 3) Community level hand soap making, the village colunteer groups thorugh active participation of community members will undertake hand wash soap making acvities and the liquid soap will be distributed among village schools and other common community meeting places, including monastaries and community quarantie facilities within villages. 4) Community quarantine facility management support will focus on supporting community quarantine facilities managed by village admistration and committees prioritizing required materials based on the needs identified such as water storage, batteries for electricity and other basic supplies. 5) Cssh for basic needs to the most vulnerable people undergoing community quarantine in targeted communities with one-time cash transfer of MMK 35,000 meeting basic needs of people 6) Training and buioding capacity of MRCS branch and red cross volunteers to support the COVID response
&#xC2;&#xA0;
&#xC2;&#xA0;
&#xC2;&#xA0;
&#xC2;&#xA0;
&#xC2;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-21018" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFRC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Red Cross Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>Performance&amp;Accountability@redcross.org.uko</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Rakhine</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="740" percentage="25" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="720" percentage="25" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="730" percentage="25" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="25" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="GB-CHC-220949-P8417-001-001">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-22">100000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">M2010027 - BRC to pay IFRC for supporting Myanmar Northern Rakhine Project</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-220949-P8417-001" ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-21018">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFRC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="3"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="GB-CHC-220949-P8092" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
