<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-cambodia" dstore:index="17" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-13T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-KAM131</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting communities on improving access to safe drinking water in Pouk district, Siem Reap provin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is to support disadvantaged people in Lvea and Trei Nhor communes, Pouk district, Siem Reap province, to enhance living conditions through better access to safe drinking water and proper hygiene practices. It is a complemented project to target communities whom are being supported by one of CAFOD partners, Srer Khmer (SK). Key lesson learnt from SK&#x2019;s project implementation is that community people are facing immediate needs on accessing safe water for their daily consumption and the limitation knowledge of both local authorities and community people on safe drinking water. In Thveas village, Trei Nhor commune, there is a bottled water purification system 20L handed over from Habitat for Humanity which found with need of supports on the establishment of water management committee and capacity building in business and marketing operation to make it re-function and respond to community needs on accessing safe water. Also, With outbreaking of COVID-19 pandemic, there is a concern about people health which would be inflection of Coronavirus due to limiatation of getting information on Covid-19 implication,  precausion guidance and hygiene practices. All these challenges are critically affected people livelihood conditions.  

To support communities to overcome these issues, the project has been designed by conducting a feasibility study, all different groups of community people have been engaged through number of meetings, focused group discussion, and in-depth interview to discuss on situation analysis, resources mapping, and identify alternative actions to improve the current situation. The project objectives are:
- To increase knowledge of community groups and local authorities on safe drinking water and proper hygiene practices through adoption of water safety plan. 
- To increase communities&#x2019; access to safe drinking water through upgrading water facilities and increased capacity of commune and village focal points to sustainably manage the water purification system 20L (handed over from Habitat for Humanity). 
The project is proposed to work complementarily with targeted villages under Srer Khmer and to contribute to community sustainability after the project of SK would be phased out by 2022, by forming local authorities, commune focal points, village focal points and community leaders to be a water management committee and to involve in all project phases. SK is focusing on farming capacity and livelihood development, and at the meantime, RWC&#x2019;s project is on safe water management and improvement of hygiene practice- It is a key sustainability of project with the strategic approach of integration between livelihood and WASH to increase community quality of life. The project has also supported communities with recent outbreaking of COVID-19 pandemic through conducting people awarenee and knowledges on Covid-19 precaution and hygiene promotion in alignment with the government IEC materials and guideline.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KAM131" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KAM131" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RainWater Cambodia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="KAM131" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-01">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54224">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-24">10000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68722">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-24">5000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RainWater Cambodia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68916">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-24">5000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RainWater Cambodia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
