<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" dstore:dataset="cafod-democraticrepublicofcongo" dstore:index="44" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC683</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisectoral emergency assistance to the most vulnerable people affected by storms in Kalole</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the distribution of unconditional cash, this project will empower the community as we will do a survey prior to the cash distribution to assess the power dynamic within HHs and carry out sensitisation around targeting, especially as it will be largely women who will be receiving the cash on behalf of the HHs. Priority will be given to the most vulnerable households affected by the storms and wind, including widowed women, children heads of households, elderly people, people with disabilities, chronically ill, and / or other people who are unable to buy food and goods of their choice that meet the need of their households. The targeting criteria will be included within the sensitisation to ensure the do no harm principle is adhered to. The targeting criteria will also be informed by a tool developed through a recent Start Fund Learning Grant (see section 2.3 below for more information).
We will organize the mobile banking  through which each household will receive &#xA3;114.50. The head of the household will receive the cash for the HH. This amount has been advised by the NFI cluster group. Throughout the project, we will take into account the COVID-19 prevention measures as stated by the government and include COVID-19 sensitisation activities which will reach 10,932 people. The vulnerabilities of certain groups will be taken into consideration. For example, to avoid pregnant women, the elderly and people living with disabilities standing for too long, beneficiary lists will be categorised in order for them to quickly recognise their names. The cash will be done through mobile money which means people will not have to wait in long queues to receive their cash. Queues will also be socially distanced. 
CAFOD and Caritas Kasongo will target 972 households (5,832 individuals) with unconditional cash, among them: 850 of those affected directly by the storm and 122 of the host families affected by the current crisis, especially in the city of  Penekusu  and Kiloza, Mwamba, Nyalugungu, Nsamba, Wasezya, Ndenge, and Kalole villages in Kalole health zone. This represents respectively 70% of 1215 direct affected HH and 5% of 607 host families to ensure &quot;Do No Harm&quot; is taken into consideration.
Beneficiaries will be selected and targeted by the Caritas Development Kasongo team in collaboration with the disaster committee, the representative of the humanitarian affairs division, local authorities and members of the Basic Humanitarian Committees (CHB) on the basis of the vulnerability criteria mentioned above which will be validated by all stakeholders, including the community, during the evaluation.  In terms of coordination, we have already coordinated with Christian-Aid and we will continue to cooperate with the other local authorities throughout the implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC683" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC683" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Kasongo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC683" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-29">278906</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54345">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-03">139453</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68784">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-03">139453</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Kasongo</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
