<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" dstore:dataset="paradigm-activities" dstore:index="1" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-30547-CSSOFE1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-30547" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARADIGM INITIATIVE</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creating Safe Spaces Online for Freedom of Expression</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implemented Activities Within the Period Under Review 
In order to achieve the stated objectives, we proposed a total of nine unique activities that feed into the desired outcome. The activities proposed were building a Digital Rights violations reporting platform, website upgrade, Strategic Litigation, Capacity Building, Digital Rights Workshops, Digital Rights Media Fellowship, Research, Digital Rights in Africa Report, Media and Communication, Digital Rights and Inclusion Forum (2020 and 2021), and participating in global convenings (RightsCon and FOC). 

Media Fellowship 
The Fellowship program is a 5-month program designed to immerse selected journalists in digital rights and digital inclusion advocacy and intervention efforts in Africa. Selected journalists (4) worked with Paradigm Initiative on various projects and contributed to improving media coverage of relevant issues in the first year. The fellows published stories to support their learning during the fellowship, including topics such as digital platforms and protests, digital footprints in policy, language diversity online, hate speech and fundamental human rights. The fellows produced at least 12 reports published on PIN&#x2019;s website or their affiliated organisation&#x2019;s platform throughout the lifetime of the project.

Digital Rights in Africa Report 
The 2019 Digital Rights in Africa report, covering the period between January and December 2019, was released in March 2020. Building on previous reports published since 2016, the 2019 Digital Rights in Africa report provided in-depth analysis on the state of digital rights in Nigeria and 12 other African countries, and examined violations such as Internet disruptions, illegal surveillance, arrest of bloggers, and the passage of hurtful legislation, amongst others. In addition to this, we worked with a production company to convert the report into a short movie titled Training Day. By the end of the reporting period, the movie grossed over 360,000 views on YouTube and over 1.1 million views on Facebook, and was screened by four television stations including the Nigerian Television Authority, Zambia&#x2019;s Muvi TV, Ghana&#x2019;s Joy Prime and Cameroon&#x2019;s Canal 2. The short film is also available on the popular pan-African video on demand platform, AfroLandTV. Work for the 2020 report, named Londa, started with a call for contributors. Londa, which means to defend or protect, echoes the call for the collective work of different stakeholders to protect the digital rights environment in Africa. The report analyses the state of digital rights and inclusion in 20 African countries and unpacks the use of policy and legislation in Africa making key recommendations for improving the digital rights landscape.

Media and Publicity Engagements 
(a) Media Parleys: We held two media parleys, beginning with a physical media parley in Lagos, Nigeria, in January 2020, where we discussed the elements of the project with the media. The second media parley couldn&apos;t hold physically because of the COVID-19 imposed restrictions so it was hosted virtually.
(b) Online Advertisements: We created audiovisual content that enabled us to run adverts on all our social media platforms (Youtube, Instagram, Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn).
(c) Newspaper Advertisements: We ran newspaper advertisements on the proposed Social Medial bill in Nigeria and also ran advertisements condemning civic restrictions as the government clamped down on citizen rights during the #EndSARS protests. During the implementation of
COVID-19 lockdowns, we continued to advocate for the government to ensure rights-respecting measures and recognise that the virus, not citizens, is the enemy. 
(d) Radio Advertisement: We ran infomercials on 3 radio stations in Abuja for one week and its focus and messaging were towards pushback on the anti-social media bill. We also started a  #SayNoToSocialMediaBill radio tour that featured PIN team members and partners discussing the need for rights-respecting approach to legislative proposals on radio stations in Abia, Adamawa, Akwa Ibom, Anambra, Bayelsa, Benue, Cross River, Ebonyi, Edo, Enugu, FCT, Gombe, Kaduna, Kano, Katsina, Kogi, Kwara, Lagos, Niger, Ogun, Ondo, Osun, Oyo, Plateau, Sokoto and Yobe states.

Digital Rights Violation Reporting Platform RIPOTI
RIPOTI, the web platform for reporting digital rights violations and connecting with partners to seek redress has been completed and was launched on April 30, 2020, during the closing session of the 2021 Digital Rights and Inclusion Forum. The platform is being used to report, document, and process human rights violations online. It serves as a platform for collaborative intervention, research, and a safe place for whistleblowing around state induced clampdowns against freedom of expression.


Digital Rights Toolkit: AYETA
We believe in a world where everyone (young people, parents, educators, policymakers, stakeholders) will gradually become actors in securing a better online experience. The Ayeta toolkit was developed with the overarching aim of addressing the growing need to safeguard digital rights defenders, journalists, whistleblowers, and others working with sensitive information in the global South. Paradigm Initiative (PIN) is dedicated to making the toolkit user friendly and ensuring it remains a living resource by making newer versions available annually.

Capacity Building 
We reached 45 civil society organizations in our 3-day workshop held in Uyo, Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria, in February 2020, before Nigeria announced its lockdown measures against the Covid-19. We had planned 3 workshops in the year 2020 with different focus groups (civil society, the judiciary, and law enforcement agencies). To this end, we rescheduled the rest of the capacity-building engagements proposed for the project to 2021 to enable us to reach
targeted groups such as the judiciary and the Nigerian security agencies. 

Strategic Litigation 
We continue to employ strategic litigation as one of our advocacy tools because when done right, it has proved to be a powerful instrument for the enforcement of rights as well as a reminder to the government that they are accountable to the people. In most cases where we do not make progress at desired paces, we at least achieved the objective of raising the profile of the cases and attracting media coverage. For the period under review, we filed court cases in support of wrongfully accused #EndSARS protesters, we issued a joint statement calling for respect for citizens&#x2019; rights during protests and challenged the violation of citizens&apos; rights. 

Communications
For effective communication of project activities and objectives, we implemented media and communication activities to support the work and facilitate joint/communal action, reaching different stakeholders with relevant messages. We hosted physical and virtual media briefings and produced communication contents such as infographics and audio-visuals and ran online and traditional media advertisements.

Global Convenings (RightsCon and Freedom Online Conference)
Participation in relevant and strategic global convenings was proposed as part of the project. The objective of our participation is to provide a platform to present our research and advocacy work to a global audience, learn from best practices across the world and benefit from diverse expertise available at such meetings. We have participated in two out of four convenings proposed and we have hosted three side sessions dedicated to our work on these platforms. We will be participating at RightsCon in June 2021 and Freedom Online Conference later in the year.

Risks, Challenges and Mitigating Measures
The unprecedented episode of the COVID-19 pandemic caused a major disruption to most organizations&#x2019; calendars and programming and Paradigm Initiative was not spared. Consequently, activities were either suspended, cancelled or postponed causing a low rate of depletion for this project. The financial excesses reported for Year 1 are mostly as a result of activities not yet carried out due to the COVID-19 restrictions but are now set to be implemented in Year 2, as indicated in the annual plan. While some project activities were interrupted by the COVID-19 lockdowns, we have not departed from the theory of change as we continued to ensure that online activities helped drive home our message about the need to create safe spaces online. Noting that learning, work and most other activities moved online because of the global pandemic, we believe that this strongly supports our assertion about the huge importance of online civic spaces, and the need to protect them.

Sustainability Plan

Our sustainability plan is built around developing a community of partners and organisations with shared goals and objectives. We position ourselves for funding and institutional support by demonstrating leadership in our field through our research and advocacy work. We continue to offer value and engage broadly, bringing attention to our work in relevant circles. One of the key post-activities of PIN&#x2019;s events, especially workshops, is to invite participants to join the NetRights coalition which we manage and where we continue to share with, and learn from, coalition members. This helps us to keep the engagement going beyond each project lifetime. In addition to these, sustainability in this project will be guaranteed based on the following:

(a) Paradigm Initiative has been active on the Internet Freedom scene in Africa for over 10 years, and has acquired the reputation of impact in delivering Internet freedom programmatic interventions across the continent, including in work related to this project&#x2019;s activities. During this process, we have also forged partnerships with organizations within Nigeria, such as the Nigerian Network of NGOs, Digital Rights Lawyers Initiative, Citizens&#x2019; Gavel, among others, which has increased the impact of our work. 
(b) Our Internet freedom interventions across Africa over the past 10 years has involved the train-the-trainer model. Our programmatic interventions have involved identifying long-term partners and training in-country civil society organisations so that they can use new knowledge gained and resources to train others. This process continues to produce a ripple effect that effectively multiplies our impact and ensures that our work is sustainable even if particular programs have ended.
(c) Paradigm Initiative has multiple and diverse long-term funding partners that support our work for the foreseeable future. For example, our grant relationship with Ford Foundation is within the framework of the BUILD grant, which provides 5 years of institutional support for our work; we have a 2-year grant, covering 5 countries, with the United States&#x2019; Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor; and we are part of the 3-year Greater Internet Freedom project supported by the United States Agency for International Development.

Pending Activities and Implementation Plan
As part of the contingency plan we submitted in earlier reports, we increased the number of people to be reached in 2021, to be able to achieve the objectives of our capacity building programs of organising workshops for civil society actors, law enforcement officers, and Judiciary officials, in the second and third quarters of 2021. Also, the Digital Rights and Inclusion Forum held in April 2021 with an increased level of involvement to cater for the cancelled 2020 event and we are currently converting the Digital Rights in Africa Report into a short film as we did in 2020. 

Conclusion
We are excited by the level of implementation of this project despite the limitations imposed by the COVID-19 pandemic. We are on course to achieve a 100% implementation of the grant and cannot wait to measure the impact of the project on the landscape for freedom of expression online in Nigeria and beyond. We remain committed to the objectives of this project beyond 2021. We are grateful for the kind support extended to us by the Embassy and we look forward to a long and sustained relationship and sharing our goals and focus in the coming years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Objective 
The objective of this project is to increase awareness and respect for online freedom of expression by carrying out activities that educate, inform, influence, and support the implementation of policies, laws, and practices on the subject matter. The project is addressing the identified problem by constructively engaging relevant stakeholders on the said subject; planning information sessions, discussions, and training for the judiciary and law enforcement agencies; organizing awareness training and workshops for media practitioners and ordinary citizens; employing effective advocacy strategies to ensure that proposed legislation that hurt freedom of expression is not passed; influencing the passage of positive rights legislation; utilizing the Freedom of Information Act to formally seek information regarding actual or potential freedom of expression infringements; instituting lawsuits against violators of online freedom of expression; and creating a systematic way of identifying, reporting and addressing violations of rights to freedom of expression online. The project is expected to significantly change the overall outlook towards digital engagement in Nigeria by reducing the climate of fear around freedom of expression online and creating safer spaces for dissidents, disadvantaged groups and minority groups who face huge discrimination on the basis of their opinion, beliefs, sexuality or gender.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="CSSOFE1" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NG-CAC-30547" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARADIGM INITIATIVE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-01">163210559.36</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-01">-3550494</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 media parleys were held. The first, a physical media parley in Lagos, took place in January 2020 where we discussed the elements of the project with the media. The second parley couldn&apos;t hold physically because of Covid-19 imposed restriction. It was held virtually. We also committed funds of 3,406,494 to radio tour accross states in the country.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">7771931.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Administrative</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">7880000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Audio Visual</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">5040000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Capacity Building</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">13740000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for DRIF2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">19888000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Digital Rights Media Fellowship</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">12520000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Digital Rights Toolkit: AYETA</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">32874000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Digital Rights Workshops</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">16246150</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Digital Rights in Africa Report</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">2176299</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Equipment and Supplies</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">1020423.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Freedom Online Coalition 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">2950000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Media Parley</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">11440000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Online Advertisement</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">12308358</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Personnel</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">6800000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for RIPOTI</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">1107581.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for RightsCon 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">4161000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Strategic Litigation</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-17">5286816</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming funds for Traditional Advertisement</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-01">-3265000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sunk cost incurred  towards hosting DRIF 2020 for the sum of 3,265,000 (Flights - 3,215,000 and Per Diems - 50,000) out of the total budgeted of 13,740,000, giving a variance of 10,475,000</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-01">-17120440</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Digital Rights in Africa Report was released in March 2020. We worked with a media company to convert the report into a short movie titled Training Day. This cost the sum of 16,348,240 as compared to the budgeted sum of 2,500,000 while researchers fees incurred the sum of 772,200, making a total of 17,120,440, thereby giving us a variance of -874,290. This will be covered up in Year 2. The movie has grossed over 360,000 views on YouTube and over 1.1 million views on Facebook, in addition to screening by television stations including the Nigerian Television Authority. We have already started work on the 2020 report.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-06-01">-12938096</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Fellowship program is a 5-month program designed to immerse selected journalists in digital rights and digital inclusion advocacy and intervention efforts in Africa. Selected journalists (4) worked with Paradigm Initiative on various projects and contributed to improving media coverage of relevant issues. The sum of 12,128,096 was expended, including additional sum of 810,000 was committed as stipends, giving a total sum of 12,938,096 as against a budgeted sum of 19,888,000. Hence a variance of 6,949,904</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-01">-5267227.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The actual expenses incurred on bank charges was 5,267,227.05 as compared to budgeted sum of 7,771,931.40, leaving a variance of 2,504,704.35</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-06-01">-144800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of 144,800 was only incurred for per diems for this activity from the total cost of 1,107,581.29, leaving a variance of 962,781.59.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-01">-8140250</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of 440,000 was incurred on scripting, while production and post-production attracted the sum of 1,200,000. We have also committed the sum of 4,947,750 into scripting and 1,552,500 for production and post-production. This commitment was made in November towards the projected cost of screening Training Day on International Human Rights Day.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-01">-940900</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of flights to appear at court hearings was 90,900 and while filing, process and service fees charged by the court all  totalled 940,900, as compared to a budgeted sum of 4,161,000, Hence a variance 3,220,100.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-01">-2279216</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The variance between the actual and budgeted expenses is from the variance from the laptop purchase due to market price flunctuations and we were able to match that with some cost savings from office supplies. Hence, a variance of -102,917</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-05-01">-6800000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The website upgrade project budget was overshot with an excess 110,000. This activity was thoroughly negotiated to match with the excess variance in the website upgrade, thereby giving a total NIL variance for Technical Component.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-09-01">-6698500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">We incurred the costs on Production of Digital Rights Toolkit in Year 1; on Content Creation for 2,730,000, Design for 640,000 and Printing for 252,000. We also had committed funds of 3,076,500 for Printing.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-01">-13203844.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">We ran adverts on all our social media platforms and incurred the sum of 5,396,344.81 on Facebook, Youtube and Instagram. We committed an additional sum of 7,807,500, hence the negative variance of 1,763,844.81</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-01">-5503612.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">We ran newspaper advertisements on the proposed Social Medial Law in Nigeria. We also ran advertisements against civic restrictions as government implemented measures and lockdowns around Covid-19 and the #EndSars protest. We also committed an additional sum of 3,160,882, hence the negative variance of 216,796.25.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-01">-10206000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">We reached 45 Civil Society organisations in our 3-day workshop held in Uyo, Akwa-Ibom State, Nigeria. We made actual expenses of 7,798,500 on flights, hotel accomodation, airport shuttle, per diems and hall. We incurred additional committed funds of 2,407,500, total sum being 10,206,000, leaving a variance of 489,000 for Civil Society Workshops. Workshops for Law Enforcement and Judiciary postponed to 2021 due to COVID-19.</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-01">-1224600.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yearly training for Project Officers was expended with a variance of 755,399.09</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-01">-1020429</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-11-30">-12308358</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
