<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2073" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06445-02:MZ</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NANA - Youth Eng. on prevention  Covid19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The world is currently facing a devastating scenario because of the COVID-19 pandemic, and all countries with confirmed cases are taking measures to react ranging from the lightest to the most severe to contain the transmission of the virus and protect people, especially to the most vulnerable.
The Mozambican government has also expressed its concerns in this regard and have put forward structural measures aimed at reducing the risk of infection by Covid-19. One of the measures taken was the declarationof State Emergency phase 3 as of 1 - 30 of April, then extended to 1 - 31 May 2020. The declaration of a state of emergency was accompanied by other related measures aimed at blocking the chain of contagion by Covid-19, such as the restriction of the number of people in the workplace, limitation of passengers number on public transport, obligation to wear masks in crowded places, closure of entertainment places,schools at all levels, among others.

The closure of schools, and social distance (includingconfinement of people at home), are in fact great measures to prevent the spread of the Covid-19 pandemic. However, in many rural communities in Mozambique, due to factorsassociated with poverty, access to information is limited. TV and the Internet isaccessible to a very limited group of people, which contributes to (i) exposure of communities to Covid-19, by ignoring disease prevention measures; (ii) Limits access to distance education for thousands of boys and (iii) girls and women may be exposed to situations of Gender Based Violence.

Oxfam Mozambique designed its response strategy to COVID-19 and has been looking for potential donors to materialize its activities. The Education Program for Active Citizenship and its partners is responsible  for implementing a part of this response strategy to Covid-19, during theschool closing period, by (i) disseminating Covid-19 prevention messages, (ii) piloting, together with local education authorities,radio-schools, to guarantee the right to education inthe face of Covid-19 and (iii) support youth organizations to prevention and  raise alert for Gender Based Violence  in context of COVID 19, due to women and girls confinement and permanent exposure.

Young women and men are a valuable resource and network during crises and public health emergencies. Through their informal and formal groupsand networks, they can help to break the chain of infection by working closely with their community, including the health authorities. Young people&apos;s involvement inthe COVID-19 response should be encouraged as they are drivers of change and educators in their communities and among their peers. In general, they are highly mobile, fast movers, entrepreneurs, innovators and users of various online communication and social media that can be used to mobilize people in responding to and preventing the COVID-19 pandemic.
Inspired on the above, Oxfam Mozambique intends, through youth engagement, to trigger actions in order to respond to 2 components of response to COVID-19 in two districts of Zambezia province, specifically Mocuba district through our local implementing partner NANA and Nocoadala through aour Local youth implanting partner ARZ (Associa&#xE7;&#xE3;o das Raparigas da Zambezia)

The management of the project on the ground will be under the leadership of NANA, which will ensure the mobilization of young people to engage in community awareness campaigns to prevent Covid-19. NANA will also work in partnership with another youth organization, ARZ, to join efforts to prevent and report potential situations of gender-based violence at the community level. Relevant stakeholders such as community authorities and district services will also be involved in the implementation of this initiative to ensure ownership and continuity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NANA - Ass. for Development Support</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NANA- Association for  Development Support, is a non-profit, private development legal entity with legal personality with administrative, financial and patrimonial autonomy. It gathers 32 young members of both sexes. The organization is of provincial scope, with its soothes in the City of Mocuba, street Robert Mugabe, founded the 14 of February of 1998.

The NANA actions are developed in the Districts of Mocuba, Lugela and Alto Mol&#xF3;cu&#xE8;. NANA began its activities in the City of Mocuba through a nucleus of students from theMocuba Secondary School who were concerned about environmental problems. Over the last few years NANA has expanded its base of intervention, covering, in addition to the environmental area, the areas of Health, HIV / AIDS, Education, child support and protection and Good Governance. In its intervention NANA also prioritizes the interaction and capacity building of other Civil Society Organizations at the local level.

NANA and its partners work to ensure that human rights are respected, protected and held as the primary responsibility of the state. The NANA has a strategic plan (2016-2021) and two statutes, one published in the Bulletin of the Republic, third series: NANA-Nucleus of Friends of Nature and Environment and another thatrepeals the first, which is in the process of itspublication where the NANA appears as a Development Support Organization, approved by the organization&apos;s General Assembly on February 14, 2013.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-18.665 35.52956</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-10">42329</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">42329</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NANA - Ass. for Development Support</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-01">42329</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06445-02:MZ">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000161" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002142"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007302"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Mozambique SAWA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06445"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Youth Engagement on prevention  Covid 19"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="855"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="645"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="641"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to be better prepared and reduce disaster risks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="483"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
