<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="plannlno-ao" dstore:index="147" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41198890-YPI100025</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wired4Work! - Technology for YEE Solutions in Indonesia including prevention &amp; response COVID-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY 
Over 33 million youth in Asia are struggling to find jobs. Gender inequality is slowing down the transition towards inclusive growth due to women&#x2019;s limited access to education and employment. In January 2018 Plan International lndonesia started Wired4Work! (W4W). A 3 year innovative Youth Economic Empowerment (YEE) program that leverages scalable digital solutions to increase the capacity of YEE practitioners in reaching youth in high quality employment. W4W is focused on vulnerable youth (16-29 years old), especially women, in Jakarta, Semarang and Lombok, who acquire vocational and work readiness skills to successfully enter the labour market. Also youth are equipped with life skills. By the end of 2020, 10,000 disadvantaged youth will be trained and 3,000 will have access to decent employment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO estimates that 392 million young people have any form of education, employment and training (NEET). Half of those young people live in South Asia, East Asia, and the Pacific. These numbers continue to rise, underlining the urgent need to address global youth unemployment.

Indonesia needs an average of 3.2 million additional skilled workers per year, while budget allocations for non-formal (vocational) education are limited, leaving a significant number of youth untrained. This is reflected in a youth unemployment rate of 17.8%. Approximately 8.7 million women are unemployed compared to 6.1 million men, while poor women are likely to be unpaid workers (27% of women compared to 6% of men).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wired4Work will focus on the following components: 

1. Private sector engagement: consisted on the creation of shared value implementation approaches and partnerships with private &amp; public sector actors, training institutions and community-based organizations to increase the job opportunities of youth and develop effective market-driven training curricula to fill in the gap between the offer of trainings and the demand needed in the labour market.  

2. Youth skills development and empowerment: Digitally enhanced YEE training solutions are developed, leveraged and scaled to enable vulnerable youth, especially young women, to pursue employment and economic empowerment opportunities. Online modules of the training curricula are developed in the demonstration countries and scaled up to other countries through the YES!ACADEMY (e-learning platform). 

3. Enabling environment for youth employment, by strengthening alliances and networks: Through regional and local influence, advocacy and support, this component will facilitate and lead alliances that favour greater inclusion in the labour market for vulnerable youth, especially young women. This component is focused on engaging multiple actors/alliances to create an enabling environment for effective youth employment programming. Plan will also offer youth themselves a platform to participate and influence both public and private policy development.

4. Program quality and innovation to leverage impact
The improvement and further development of the YES!DIGITAL Ecosystem of Plan International will bring high quality youth employment initiatives to scale, building capacity of Plan International offices to integrate the Digital Ecosystem assets into their YEE programs, and expanding them with additional services to evolve programs into a full circle digitally enhanced approach. New innovations are developed, especially the YES!CNEXT (match platform for job seekers and companies jobs) using a Human Centered Design approach.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wired4Work is built on assets developed by Plan international since 2011 in alliance with one of its  partners from the private sector that has resulted in the training of more than 15,000 youth and the transition of more than 12,000 youth into decent work across Asia and Latin America. These assets include the market scan methodology, YES!ME (direct beneficiary monitoring) system and assessment of high level requirements for e-learning management systems. In multiple strategic partnerships with the Asian Development Bank (ADB) and the World Bank&#x2019;s Solutions for Youth Employment (S4YE) Coalition, Plan International is working together with other parties of the private and public sector to catalyse new public-private sector partnerships and support new innovative programs for youth economic empowerment. 

Plan International Indonesia works in close coordination with the Ministry of Manpower (MoM) and other ministries to replicate the use of the gender-focused life (soft) skills e-learning module across Technical and Vocational Education Training (TVET) institutions. As a result of this strong collaboration with MoM, the life skills modules have been scaled up to 17 vocational training centers (BLKI), sharing resources to improve quality of instructors and management support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan will target almost 10,300 vulnerable youth (age 16-29 years old), in rural and urban areas of the cities of Jakarta, Semarang and Lombok with a 78% participation of young women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The following work plan is considered to lead to the targets and outputs of the project:

Component 1: private sector engagement
o	Conduct a market scan in all implementation areas to determine the labor market trends and opportunities for the target group of vulnerable youth.
o	Establish agreements with private sector partners to ensure commitment towards hiring youth trained by Plan International, develop traineeship and upskilling opportunities, and create robust mechanisms to link vulnerable youth, particularly young women to opportunities for employment.
o	Engage with stakeholders to jointly develop market-based and digitally enhanced curricula and training programs.
o	Create shared value business with companies. 

Component 2: Youth skills development and empowerment
o	Development and scaling up digitally enhanced training modules 
o	Development of a strategy for youth recruitment 
o	Equipping youth with technical and vocational skills
o	Placement of youth in jobs
o	Create mechanism for community support for youth

Component 3: 
o	Engage multiple actors/alliances to create an enabling environment for effective youth employment programming. 
o	Offer youth a platform to participate and influence both public and private policy development.
o	Utilize big data to support and showcase project impact in a reliable, robust and credible way, and to scale up high quality project components and move toward evidence based influence advocacy. 

Component 4: 
o	Enhance Alumni engagement by creating a digital platform (or space) which enables students to scale up the network and Capacity building for alumni associations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan has secured and allotted funding for at least 10 countries for 2018-2020 to roll out different pieces of the Ecosystem to support programming. But as a key component for the implementation of Plan&#x2019;s Global Strategic Framework on Youth Employment, Entrepreneurship and Empowerment (YEE), Plan envisions the global adoption of (pieces of the) Ecosystem, with each country office using at least one component for their programs. This will require a comprehensive analysis of the capacities and resources needed to rollout, manage and sustain the effort. Hence, Plan will be undertaking the development of a growth and governance strategy, which would complement the Global Strategic Framework and include the development of a viable business model (e.g. commercial; social enterprise model, such as the open source cooperative; data as an asset; or others) that will guide the organization in securing the resources that will sustain the YES!DIGITAL Ecosystem&#x2019;s operation and growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unspecified</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IATI contact</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>iati@plannederland.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stadhouderskade</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">60</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1072 AC</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="5">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="5">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11230" percentage="70" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic life skills for youth and adults</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLAN AOGD 2" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEARN - Skills opportunities for youth employment and entrepreneurship (SOYEE)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="PLANNL-B" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Economic Empowerment &amp; Education</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-15">81722</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">1193494</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-29">1193494</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB1372">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-31">139000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB341">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-02-14">84400</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB342">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-31">88000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB343">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">33760</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB785">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-14">150000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UB786">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-24">480000</value>
   <receiver-org ref="ID-NJP-024100158053000" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41198890-W4W" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children, youth or adults are economically active</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth who are economically active</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0117.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30.00"></target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delay in the start of trainings for youth resulted in less number of youth in job as by end 2018 and thus economically active</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="123.00"></target>
     <actual value="79.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not all job positions available matched with the skills and experience of young men participating in the project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400.00"></target>
     <actual value="386.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Less than targets due to COVID-19</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth who are economically active</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0117.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="85.00"></target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delay in the start of trainings for youth resulted in less number of youth in job as by end 2018 and thus economically active</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="129.00"></target>
     <actual value="45.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Less job positions available matched with skills and experience of young women participating in the project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400.00"></target>
     <actual value="423.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills training for Children and Youth or other individuals</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who completed financial literacy trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.4.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="120.00"></target>
     <actual value="326.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1644.00"></target>
     <actual value="1708.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000.00"></target>
     <actual value="1025.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who completed financial literacy trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.4.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="800.00"></target>
     <actual value="846.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="480.00"></target>
     <actual value="416.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1914.00"></target>
     <actual value="2494.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who completed life skills trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.5.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="120.00"></target>
     <actual value="326.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Higher participation than expected  due to the partnership with vocational high schools</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1644.00"></target>
     <actual value="1708.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Involvement of implementation partners allow more participation of young  men</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000.00"></target>
     <actual value="1025.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who completed life skills trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.5.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="480.00"></target>
     <actual value="416.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">More participation of young men than young women at the start of the project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1914.00"></target>
     <actual value="2494.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Better coordination with training centers allow higher participation of young women</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="800.00"></target>
     <actual value="846.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who completed vocational skills trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.6.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="710.00"></target>
     <actual value="710.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="36.00"></target>
     <actual value="36.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="735.00"></target>
     <actual value="735.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who completed vocational skills trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.6.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="437.00"></target>
     <actual value="437.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="29.00"></target>
     <actual value="29.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="875.00"></target>
     <actual value="875.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth provided with job placements by the private sector</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.9" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30.00"></target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delay in the start of trainings for youth resulted in less number of youth in job as by end 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="123.00"></target>
     <actual value="79.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Less job positions available matched with the skills and experience of young men of the project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400.00"></target>
     <actual value="386.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">More young women reached than men</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth provided with job placements by the private sector</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1000.9" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="85.00"></target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delay in the start of trainings for youth resulted in less number of youth in job as by end 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="129.00"></target>
     <actual value="45.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Less job positions matched with the skills and experience of young women in the project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400.00"></target>
     <actual value="423.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender training for children, youth or adults</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who have completed gender trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1100.1.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="120.00"></target>
     <actual value="326.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1644.00"></target>
     <actual value="1708.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000.00"></target>
     <actual value="1025.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children, youth or adults who have completed gender trainings</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1100.1.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="480.00"></target>
     <actual value="416.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1914.00"></target>
     <actual value="2494.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">High interest of young women to participate in the project supported by parents</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="800.00"></target>
     <actual value="846.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge sharing</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of best practices documented</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="7500.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.00"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">End Year 3 internal evaluation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance Plan Nederland as a development organisation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender score of the program design and activities (scale 0-4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.6" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4.00"></target>
     <actual value="3.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young women (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.7" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1369.00"></target>
     <actual value="2012.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">More women reached than men</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="250.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delay in formalisation of partnerships has generated delay in start of trainings</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="230.00"></target>
     <actual value="416.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="669.00"></target>
     <actual value="669.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1245.00"></target>
     <actual value="1825.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">High interest of young women to participate in the project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young men (age 18-24) reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="0000.8" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2105.00"></target>
     <actual value="1549.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="250.00"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delay in formalisation of partnerships has generated delay in start of trainings</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="120.00"></target>
     <actual value="326.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="462.00"></target>
     <actual value="462.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1182.00"></target>
     <actual value="1246.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Involving the private sector in the activity</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of private sector businesses participating in the activity</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="4600.1.2" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10.00"></target>
     <actual value="10.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16.00"></target>
     <actual value="34.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector was involved in market scan, curriculum development and job placement activities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15.00"></target>
     <actual value="18.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 prevention &amp; response</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of soaps, disinfection equipment that has been provided among at risk population</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.1" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of at risk population who are provided with soaps, disinfection equipment</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.2" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
    <baseline value="0.00" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of at risk population who are provided with soaps, disinfection equipment</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people who are benefitting from the constructed improved sanitation facilities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="3.2.2" indicator-uri="none" vocabulary="1"></reference>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people  reached by COVID-19 awareness raising</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="COVID-19.1" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="802.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of hygiene kits provided in response to COVID-19</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="COVID-19.3" indicator-uri="http://www.planinternational.nl/plan-international-netherlands-indicator-code-list.pdf" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="802.00"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
