<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2094" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06459-04:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CECI - COVID Response in Ug (OSF)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Empowerment for creative innovation (CECI) was formed to address the increasingly deteriorating relationship among refugees and with host communities characterized with ethnic divisions and violent conflicts, address the dire youth situation characterized with antisocial behaviours and practices and to respond to the need for resilience activities that increases livelihood. The CECIwas founded in late May, 2017 by a group of visionary South Sudan youths who were granted asylum or refugee in Uganda due to the war in their native country, South Sudan.

The organization first started as a peace advocacy youth group and later on registered as aCBO under Koboko District Local Government. Taking note of gender balance, the organization has at least embraced gender balance throughout it#s in and outdoor activities giving a 37% portion to women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT 4 CREATIVE IN CECI</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Empowerment for creative innovations (CECI) was formed to address the increasingly deteriorating relationship among refugees and with host communities characterized with ethnic divisions and violent conflicts, address the dire youth situation characterized with antisocial behaviours and practices and to respond to the need for resilience activities that increases livelihood. The CECI was founded in late May, 2017 by a group of visionary South Sudan youths who were granted asylum or refugee in Uganda due to the war in their native country, South Sudan.
The organization first started as a peace advocacy youth group and later on registered as aCBO under Koboko District Local Government. Taking note of gender balance, the organization has at least embraced gender balance throughout it#s in and out door activities giving a 37% portion to women.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?
In the past one and half years of our functional existence, besides establishment of a board which plays an oversight, advisory and planning role, and the development and adopting of the supreme constitution of Community Empowerment for Creative Innovation (CECI), the CECI has developed and adopted into laws a significant number of internal policies that include: Finance, Human Resource, Code of Conduct and Anti-fraud and corruption policy manuals that in line with current practices lays down principles, policies and practices on those matters that affect the business of trust, accountability, transparency, inclusivity including the #how we do it# and the #why we do it# as we seek to remain true to our guiding principles of Teamwork, Honesty, Commitment, professionalism, personal development and inclusivity in serving our beneficiaries.
Besidesthe partnerships and collaborations with relevant social actors which improved our capacity, we have in keeping with our peopled-led and participatory approach provided both men and women boys and girls space to freely participate in the identifying of gaps and designing of solutions, through the holding of inclusive Peace intercultural dialogues and training workshops training over 180 (F=37%) Peace Ambassadors who actively engaged in their local communities, schools and on various social media platforms have inspired hundreds of their peers to take on peace and responsible social media use advocacy roles.
3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Mission: What isthe current purpose of the organisation?
To innovatively use recreational activities, education and other innovative approaches to address social problems and transform community-based conflicts into a culture of peace and non-violence; and facilitate youth engagement and empowerment at the grassroots level.

Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?

1. Build peace and improve social cohesion among refugees and with host communities
2. Build skills to support development and peace
3. Promote girl child education and early childhood development
4. Increase community knowledge and understanding of HIV/AIDs care and prevention
5. Eradicate Gender Based Violence
6. Green the environment
7. Foster creativity and innovation among youth in their respective fields of practice

Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?

1) Peace building and Reconciliation: CECI works to promote peaceful resolution of disputes and reconciliation, build and increase peaceful coexistence and social cohesion among refugees and with host communities through dialogues, negotiations, debates, group discussions, trainings/workshops, recreational activities, poems, media programs and community and school outreaches.
2) Livelihood: interventions are aimed at building skills to support development and peace, build resilience and increase employability through vocational or entrepreneurial skill trainings,trauma healing and income generating activities.
3) Education: CECI#s interventions are aimed at promoting girl child education andearly childhood development through advocacy, increasing community understanding and knowledge about HIV/AIDs care and prevention, and eradicating Gender Based Violence (GBV) in all its forms by going beyond awareness creation to capacitating victims to act.
4) Environmental management: CECI works with the community, stakeholders and well-wishers to green the environment through tree plantingand community education on conservation of environment.

The principal geographic areas of operation of Community Empowerment for Creative Innovation mainly are Koboko District and the refugee camp settlements of Bidibidi refugee camp settlement.

The primary beneficiaries of Community Empowerment for Creative Innovation activities can be broadly defined as the South Sudanese refugees and host communities who will benefit either directly or indirectly through project activities that will be offered by Community Empowerment for Creative Innovation activities and its partners in the district and refugee camp settlements.  The specific target groups can be defined broadly as follows:
a) Refugee and host communities Youth, Children, Women and other vulnerable groups of people.
b) Local authorities, community organizations and associations/groups.

4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analyse the environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? #In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?
The environment Community Empowerment for Creative Innovation (CECI) works in is diverse in cultures and ethnicity and is also characterised with some form of fear, ethnic divisions and violent conflicts, intolerance among others, besides being thickly populated by youth who, most suffered adversely armed conflicts, are traumatized,hopeless and idle.

Apart from government and business, other relevant social actors include church, associations/groups, governmental and non-governmental organizations, and institutions. These play roles that range from maintaining law and order, providing relief and humanitarian assistance, educational support, psychosocial and health care to social advocacy.

As the culture of CECI is to work always with the community and other relevant social actors such as earlier identified is in position to influence great positive change, inconsiderate of the closeness of the CECI to the community and the speaking of a common language used by the very diversecommunities we#re committed to serve as well as the diversity of the CECI team and its good relationship with the community, church, CBO/CSOs, and its better understanding of how the community feels.
5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)
How are authority and responsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number of peoplein each position, and if they are men or women.
Kindly find the attached, in PDF, the organizational structure chart of Community Empowerment for Creative Innovation (CECI).
6. CURRENT BALANCE SHEET/FINANCIAL POSITION
Oxfam Novib requires information about what the organisation owns, debts that you must pay and your net financial worth. Therefore, we ask for a balance sheet (available in Microsoft Excel) for your entire organisation as it stands at the end of your two most recent fiscal years.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <humanitarian-scope code="EP-2020-000012-001" type="1" vocabulary="1-2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel Coronavirus Outbreak - Jan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-06">8447</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">8447</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">8447</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT 4 CREATIVE IN CECI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06459-04:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06459"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Refugee-led COVID Response in Ug (OSF)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002154"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="7800"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="7200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="7800"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="7200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
