<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="1493" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-26:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPS CTP Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPs, People Empowering People(PEP) and Vision For Humanity(ViFoH) will implement the CTP project in aconsortium arrangement.
The consortium partners will organize an inception meeting to introduce the project to stakeholders and garner support for speedy implementation. The particiapnts will include; selected target beneficiaries (refugee and host), Local authorities, OPM UNHCR and other agencies implementing CTP such as DRC, NRC, Water Mission, Plan International, selected RWCs and LCs.

PALM Corps consortium willconduct awareness meetings in the areas targeted for the CTP activities. The focus will be on the planned cash transfer options, eligibility criteria, complaints and feedback mechanism that shall be employed by the project team. 60 key stakeholders including target beneficiaries (refugee and host), sector specialists local authorities sub county leaderships, OPM, UNHCR and other agencies implementing CTP will be part of the awareness meeting.The Consortium will obtain and verify listof PSNs/Extremely Vulnerable Individualfrom the OPM/UNHCR databases.  A well-defined eligibility criterion will be developed in consultation with Refugee Welfare Committees (RWC), OPM and UNHCR and communicated to the communities prior to the implementation of CTP. Actual selection of refugee households eligible for CTP will be done in consultation with the Refugee Welfare Committees (RWC), OPM and UNHCR. While for the host communities the consortium will work with LCs, Sector heads/specialists, local government leadership of Rigbo, Uriama and Odupi to select the beneficiaries.

The Consortium partners will conduct monthly partnership coordination meetings. The first meetings will be an in-house induction for consortium staff (both programme and finance staff engaged in this project) on the CTP approach of delivering assistance and CHS. The subsequent meetings will be held to share progress and review plans for subsequent months. In these meetings,partners will discuss budget performance and technicalactivity progress, share experiences, track fund utilization (BVA) and develop outlook for the next month. M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E Officer will present evidence-based performance indicators in the online M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E system (activity tracker). The purpose of end of project meeting is to review the project and decide what the organization can learn from it.It won&#x2019;t be a blame session. The product of the meeting will be lessons learned&#x2014;that will be available to future projects, partnersand stakeholders. During the implementation, short videos will be produced for key activities, these will be shared during the close-out meeting. Twenty-five (25) participants including some key beneficiaries, and other partners will be invited to attend the meeting.

Strengthened access to basic food for selected vulnerable households for the farmers in Yelulu village. Apart from the vulnerability criteria the targeted households will be assessed on the basis of availability of land, proximity to the permanent water source (from R. Enyau and Yeluluriver) for offseason horticulture.
Agro-inputs will be provided to forty (40) selected beneficiaries using vouchers. The Consortium will organize meeting between the selected beneficiaries and Agro-input dealers to clarify procedures and validate preferred Agro-inputs.  PALM Corps and the District Agriculture officer of Terego district shall certify the inputs before they are picked by the farmers. During the market fair a desk will be set at the site for complain handling.The project will trainbeneficiaries in gardening in every household to grow quick maturing and nutritious vegetables to complement diet. The extension support will be home based and in mini groups of 3-5 members to minimize congregating farmers in groups in line with COVID19 controlmeasures.
Using conditional cash transfer, the project will support 35 selected most vulnerable households (PSN) with 5-liter jerricanfor constructing tippy tap. Two - 20-liter jerricans for water storage per household and two bars of soap per month for three months. The 2 jerricans and the five-liter jerricans including soap will be acquired through the identified financial service provider. The construction of tippy tap will be through cash for work by selected youth in consultation with the trained VHTs and Local leaderstrained under HRGF II. The organization will link the suppliers to the beneficiaries to access the items to support the targeted households.

The project will procure and distribute PPE to consortium partner staff and other selectedagencies that will support the project implementation, like the private financial service providers against COVID 19. The key PPE will include standard face masks,hand sanitizers and liquid soap. Each staff will be given 3 masks and hand sanitizers tocarry while implementing project activitiesto protect them and beneficiaries.
Routine awareness campaigns against COVID19 and SGBV will be conducted by the trained VHTs (under HRGF II) in collaboration with sub county Health Assistants and monitored bytheRWCs and LCs. For SGBV, 2 days training will be organized for protection committees (20) to create awareness and follow up cases. Community Development Officers from local government will routinely mentor them. Cases of child protection (involving pupils) will be linked to Child Protection Officer under sister projects of PALM Corps (synergy). The volunteers will be supported under cash for training and humanitarian life-saving sector through direct cash paid by the finance department.

The projectwillsupport 70 PSN with safety nets through unconditional cash grant for a period of three months. The cash transfer value will be based on the MEB. The CTP Standard Operation Procedure for Cash grant will befollowed. For example, selection criteria will beshared with OPM, UNHCR and the local leadership and this will be used to conduct selection of the beneficiaries, more importantly, the 1st tire selection criteria shall be used to identify the beneficiaries. The project will ensure risks are identified and taken care of prior to the cash transfer. Post distribution monitoring will be done to establish and assess value for money and feedback from the beneficiaries.

Restored earning capacities of selected HGRF I beneficiaries whose businesses were affected by COVID-19  through cash for work modality for road rehabilitation.  The work will be done by 60 selected community members identified during transparent community dialogue meetings with the local leaders and other stakeholders. The CTP StandardOperating Procedures (SOPs) will be adhered to during the whole process.31 selected female beneficiaries will access business supplies to rejuvenate their businesses. The cash transfer value will be based on the Minimum Expenditure Basket (MEB) . A Post Distribution Monitoring to check take off of the businesses and provision of ongoing business support shall be undertaken.

Undertake community access road rehabilitation through Cash for Work. A total of 4 km road (Yelulu-Kiridoaku) was selected because the road leads to food distribution point &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; market, and it is literally impassable. Using a clear selection criterion, the CfW will enable the participating households acquire cash to buy food and other basic household goods. The consortium will adopt the Mercy Corps&#x2019; Guidelines to Cash-for-Work Programming and the Oxfam CTP Standard Operating Procedures and steps for CfW will be followed bythe Consortium.  The Cash value paid to beneficiaries will be determined by the general labour market survey conducted by the consortium during inception meetings. The number of days worked shall be recorded on daily basis by the village supervisor. This record will further be verified by the Cash Programme supervisor and the finance staff. Once properly done, the financestaff will prepare payment sheets that will be approved by the project manager and later forwarded to the accredited SACCO to effect payments.  Cash willbe distributed on site via the accredited SACCO. At least there will be 50:50 gender representation in CfW projects. Wage rates from the other agencies i.e. Cash Working Group will be applied . It is expected that each of the two villages (Yelulu and Kiridoaku) will have 30 selected persons and work for 20 days to accomplish the 4km road.

Basedon thestrong recommendation by OPM during needs assessment, the consortium will undertake distribution of 3,000 face masks to the most vulnerable refugee households in collaboration with OPM. The face masks will be produced by the vulnerable refugee andhost youth who were trained in tailoring and garments during the HRGF 1 and they have the capacity to produce standard masks.  The PALM Corps consortium will collaborate with the District Health Office, OPM and UNHCR for quality assurance. They will signagreements with the consortium. Using a clear selection criterion, the preselected 3,000 (1,500 male and 1,500 female) beneficiaries will access the face masks from the mask producers using the vouchersystem distributed prior to the distribution and strictly monitored by the project staff and CTP officer.

The Consortium partners will conduct feedback meetings for two months to keep key stakeholders such as target beneficiaries (refugee and host), Local authorities, OPM UNHCR and other agencies implementing CTP up to date. Additional in order to handle feedback and complaints a help desk will be set at PALM Corps field office desk at Siripi which is more accessible to the beneficiaries. A dedicated telephone will be communicated to groups on stickers shared with all beneficiaries.

Conduct post-distribution monitoring to determine how cash receivedwas   used, amount received, preferences of cash vs. in-kind. The PDM will also help to verify that the households met the selection criteria initially and still qualify for the programme

Two Joint monitoring and field visits will be conducted to assess progressof implementation and also provide feedback to beneficiaries. The visit will involve district leadership both technical and political, OPM andsub county leadership. Targeted field visits to selected beneficiaries&#x2019; households, road rehabilitation sites to monitor progress. The reports will be shared in the relevant sector working group meetings monthly.

The Consortium partners will participate in sector working group meetings that include:  Cash Working Group meetings, COVID 19 response coordination meetings for Rhino camp settlement, Livelihood sector working group. Already the consortium partners have been incorporated into the COVID 19 response coordination meetings for Rhino camp settlement. These meeting will enable the consortium members to share updates, learning (good practices) and participate in decision-making process in the selected sectors.

Produce and distribute visibility materials for project staff and board of Consortium partners: Visibility is a very important tool in activity implementation. The consortium will produce shirts with logos of Oxfam and that of the consortium partners and distribute to project staff and board membersfor visibility

On monthly basis supervisory field visit will be conducted by EDs and M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E to assess implementation progress and beneficiary feedback to guide management decision. The supervision will be conducted before consortium coordination meetingsso that issues found in the field can be discussed during the coordination meetings.

The RTR Lite exercise will be conducted to assess the level of intervention after 6-8 weeks of implementation. The action plan from RTR Lite helped the other consortium members to review strategies and targets in order to optimize results.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPS LTD- GENERAL PCLO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM Corps is a not for profit company that was registered in 2014 arising from the increased demand for local NGOs to contribute and take charge of the development initiatives in the region. The subscribers (Directors) are Anyanzo Thomas Abbey, Albert Azu and Swadik Kasim. See attached article and Memorandum of Association. Before PALM Corps was registered the directors where providing consultancy services in the region under PALM Business Consult and Agric supplies Ltd (for profit company). Since its registration PALM Corps was implementing project in West Nile in the sector of Agriculture, Primary Education, WASH, Nutrition and Environment. In 2017PALM Corps embarked on setting governance system including establishment of board of governance and developing policies. With more solid governance system and policies in place, PALM is one of the rapidly growing local NGOs operating in West Nile.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
PALM Corps in partnership with Horizont3000, Welthungerhilfe, SNV, Eleanor Crook Foundation, ZOA, Volkshilfe secured funds to provide services to the refugees and host communities in West Nile. A total of 1,619 pregnant and Lactating Women and 925 CU2 in Moyo district were directly supported under nutrition project funded by Eleanor Crook Foundation; 2500 pupils in Rhino camp refugee settlement were reached with school feeding and 480 parents of the children supported to improve their knowledge on good farming practices; 180 (75 female) youth are skilled through various trades including saloon, carpentry, building, motorcycle repair, bakery and vegetable growing with support of Welhungerhilfe and Horizont3000; 250acres of teak woodlots established in Rhinocamp and Imvepi refugee settlements in Arua district with funds from BMZ (Germany); access to education is being improved for over 5000 school girls(refugeesand host) in Rhinocamp and finally 50 agribusinesses  including SMEs and farmer groups were linked to market and finance.
3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Mission: To improve the quality of life of the poorest and most vulnerable communities through innovative, sustainable, evidence-based and people-centred programmes that transform their livelihood practices, attitudes and values.

Institutional objectives: PALM desires to see a world wherethe poorest and most vulnerable communities live a dignified, healthy, peaceful and productive life

Field(s) of activity: PALM Corps is permitted/Licenced by NGO Bureau to operate in West Nile, and Northern Uganda. Butcurrently the operations are limited to West Nile.  The sectors are Agriculture and Livelihoods, Primary Education, Nutrition, WASHand Environment.
4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
The influx of refugees in West Nile has attracted a couple of humanitarian and development organizations who areproviding social services to the refugees and the host community to complement on government efforts. With the localization policy of the government of Uganda, this presents opportunities for local organizations to partner with the international organizations to participate in responding to the crisis and development challenges in the region. The demand for social services in huge especially in the refugee settlements where access to and quality of education, health services and food is a problem. WFP provides food or cash for refugees to buy food. The prices of food items increased as result of the influx and unfortunately the local population is not responding adequately to produce food to meet the demand. The region is still net importer of food itemsespecially vegetables, beans and maize from other regions of Uganda and DRC.  PALM has rich experience of value chain development and facilitation of multi-stakeholder processes which makes the organization attractive to several development actors.
5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)
The board is comprised of 5 members, 2 of who are female. The top three positions i.e. ED, Program Manager and FAM are all filled by males;3 Project Coordinator out of 5 are female. And at field level (Project Officer, 40% of the staff are female, 60% male.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-25">24404</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">24404</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALM CORPS LTD- GENERAL PCLO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">24404</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-26:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4310"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3171"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="21977"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3171"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
