<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2320" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06695-03:SO</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting on Borehole Drill  in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The eastern regions in Somaliland and especially Saanag and Sool regions continue to suffer from recurrent drought. This situation has increased the vulnerability of the communities as they have lost most of their livestock which was their main source oflivelihood. The situation is exacerbated by the fact that the two regions also continue to experience occasional inter clan fighting which isoften triggered by competition for available pasture and water resources. Drilling of the a boreholes will not only contribute to providing important water sources that can support the water needs of the communities during drought and harsh climatic conditions, but also contribute to reducing risk factors leading to conflict. It will offer an opportunity to the benefiting communities to have a chance for better access to potable water, reduce the incidents water related diseases and increase access for water for practicing frequent handwashing to prevent COVID-19.
Objectives;
&#x2022; Provide sustainable water source for 5000 people and over 10,000 livestockheads in Sanaag Region.
Groundwater Feasibility Study:
A groundwater feasibility study will be conducted in three selected villagesof Sanaag region. the study will follow three approach method,
1. Remote Sensing: Desk review using latest satellite imageries to selected best possible locations. This phase will focus on finding regional fractures carrying water from highland of Ethiopia to thelowland of Sanaag regions and from Sanaag mountains to low land areas.
2. Geophysical Study: ground truthing work will be conducting using latest start of art geophysical technology at least three locations with spacing of 1000 -1500m. This location are those selected in first phase of the study work. Government and community engagement will be conducted to understand the local geology, possible impact of drilling on environment and stability of the communities.
Drilling of the borehole
Based on the groundwater feasibility study, the drilling work will be advertised through the local media. In order to avoid failures resulted from improper use of drilling equipment and selection of drilling method, the contractor will receive full copy of the study report and will be given a briefing on the drilling technology and technique recommended by the study team. Then, a payment by result approach will be used to contract drilling companies i.e. Oxfam/Taakulo will only pay if the borehole has water with discharge of above 2liter per second. Failureto get a contractor willing to commence drilling with such conduction, further meeting will be help between Oxfam and Taakulo to discuss best possible approach to increase value for money.
Supervision and Monitoring:
In drilling works supervision and monitoring progress is critical step. Oxfam/Taakulo will have a site supervisor equipped with necessary materials for supervision including TDS Sensor to record water quality at each 1 meter, mud funnel to record the drilling mud viscosity and deeper to follow the depth of the drilling. The supervisor will provide daily update to both Oxfam/Taakulo team and will ensure all decision that affect drilling performance is consulted and agreed before action. TDS level will be recorded in monitoring tool provided and the result will be used for deciding the borehole casing arrangement. All materials that will be used for drilling will be inspected by the drilling supervisor and approve. In case a specialized chemical will be used for the drilling; the supervisor will request for all safety related certificate prior use of such chemicals.
Post Drilling Construction:
This action will be decided right after the drilling is completed. Provision of submersible pump with cable and riser pipes, and construction of generator house, water distribution system for both animal and human and storage facilities will be included under this phase. Other grants, including ECHO 2021 and/or other internal grants will be used to finance this critical activity. Incase the borehole salinity is above an acceptable regional level i.e. 2500ppm, provision of desalination unit will be considered.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somali Community Commonly known by the acronym #TASCO#. TASCO is a multifaceted non-governmental, non-profit making, non-political and non-partisan development and humanitarian aid organization established in 2007 and headquartered in Hargeisa, Somaliland. Taakulo is a Somali word meaning #helping/aiding#. Working in partnership with UN, international, and National organizations, TASCO is dedicated to helping the disadvantaged people and communities throughout Somali by engaging in development and related activities and also providing relief support and assistance, facilitating and promoting participatory local community activities and programs that emphasize human dignity and self-reliance.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-15" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-14">86497</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">51898</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-01">25949</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-01">8650</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06695-03:SO">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007052"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Somalia HECA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06695"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Supporting on Borehole Drill  in Somalia"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-15"></period-end>
     <target value="2500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-15"></period-end>
     <target value="2500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-15"></period-end>
     <target value="2500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-15"></period-end>
     <target value="2500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
