<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="761" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05259-09:23</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forging Intersectional Feminist Futures</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IWRAW AP proposes to partner with AIPP, APNSW, APRRN, APTN, APWWDU represented by STEP, ASC, IDPC Asia and ILGA Asia (ILGA will notreceive financial support, but will contribute network resource and professional support) - eight networks and organisations in Asia advocating for the rights of women facing multiple forms of discrimination. The joint project will aim at strengthening intersectional movement building in Asia as the key to developing transformative advocacy strategies that center the voices and lived experiences of diverse groups of marginalised women and challenge multiple systems of oppression to achieve systemic gender equality. Targetcountries for this project will be Cambodia, Indonesia, the Philippines, India and Pakistan, with regional and global spheres of impact. We have updated our focus countries to include Cambodia and Pakistan and to exclude Nepal and Thailand, as multiple consortiumpartners have strong national partnerships in Cambodia and Pakistan and interest from country partners to engage in this project. Additionally, we sought to prioritise Voice focus countries in the final selection. The project addresses the Voice impact theme: space for political participation and citizen engagement. Over the 33-month period, the project partners will organise online and offline activities to: build our collective capacities on intersectionality theory and practice; understand how to engage in CEDAW advocacy and activism from an intersectional perspective;facilitate capacity buildingand intersectional movement building among national partners in all five target countries; reflect on our experiences of seeking to apply intersectionality in advocacy and movement building, and document these practices; engage in strategising and advocacy planning to offer a collective andsystems response to specific manifestations of gender equality;develop an intersectional feminist, cross-movement advocacy roadmap, addressing issues such as bodily rights, health rights, migrant rights, digital rights,decriminalisation and decarceration; network and build cross-movement solidarity at regional level;support national partners to put into practice collective, intersectional advocacy, research or campaignactions; and create and share knowledge with our movements on practical ways to apply intersectionality in advocacy, movement building and organisational practices, through creative communications. The specific results we will deliver include: Strengthened collective understanding of intersectionality and intersectional feminism among nine key networks and organisations working to eradicate gender inequality in Asia Regional and national cross-movement roadmaps for joint advocacy outlining intersectional entry points for collective action towards eliminating gender inequality Documented good practices and strategies for applying an intersectional approach to eliminating gender inequality in Asia Due to COVID-19 and related restrictions, activities taking place over the first 18 months will be organised virtually. We will strengthen our own capacities to organise online by undergoing training on digital advocacy, and digital and holistic security during the inception phase. In order to overcome challenges to wellbeing and inter-personal connection posed byprolonged COVID-19 measures, we will organise quarterly wellness sessions involving activities such as meditation, online workouts, group discussions, etc. Seeking to ensure accessibility for all, we have dedicated a standard amount in all activitybudgets to meet accessibility needs ranging from audiovisual aids to language interpretation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Women&apos;s Rights Action Watch Asia Pacific</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Womens Rights Action Watch Asia Pacific (IWRAW Asia Pacific) was founded in 1993 to work towards the realisation of the human rights of women through the use of the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (the CEDAW Convention) and other international human rights instruments. The founders, a group of Asian women, wanted to link activism takingplace at the local level with that at the global level. By understanding and participating in international activities, women working at the local level would be able to monitor and facilitate the implementation of the CEDAW Convention domestically while contributing to standard-setting at the international level. Thirteen years later, IWRAW Asia Pacific works in 14countries in South and Southeast Asia and over 100 countries globally.
Phase 1: 1993-1996
In the first four years of its existence, IWRAW Asia Pacific worked towards strengthening national womens groups and alliances in Asia that could carry out and sustain CEDAW Convention-related work. The focus of the activities was centred on creating clarity of concepts pertaining to womens rights, especially the key principles of substantive equality and non-discrimination, state obligation and accountability andthe expanded concept of womens rights as human rights. IWRAW Asia Pacific focused on inspiring womens groups to co-ordinate their work within a rights framework. It began looking at developing methodologies for analysing the various sites of discrimination, for developing holistic measures for achieving de facto equality of women and for training womens rights advocates on the CEDAW Convention and on claiming rights inside and outside courtprocedures. Due to its rights focus, IWRAW Asia Pacific was involved in regional and international advocacy, for instance, in the NGO preparations and participation in the International Conference on Population and Development in 1993, and the World Conference onWomen in Beijing in 1995.
Phase 2: 1997-2002
IWRAW AsiaPacific sharpened its approaches in bringing about domestic application of international human rights norms. It continued to prioritise creating and deepening conceptual clarity but now focused also on concretising this conceptual clarity through the development of methodologies for identifying and addressing discrimination against women in its various contexts, i.e. a monitoring tool to assess compliance with the CEDAW Convention, as well as on process and advocacy necessary for holding states accountable for violations.
IWRAW Asia Pacific continued to put strong focus on national-level capacity-building through social investigation visits, two regional trainings of trainers, national-level trainings, and issue-based technical assistance, among others.However, as a parallel indispensable strategy, we also facilitated a process by which national groups were able to build their own capacity through research-based advocacy, which also enabled them to participate in regional and international level advocacy. This move was made in the belief that activities at the national and international levels are interlinked and complementary. It ensures the bridging of the disconnect between the activities at the national and international levels.
Phase 3: 2003-2005
IWRAW Asia Pacific identified new areas of concern for this phase. At this stage, national groups were much more aware of the importance of the Convention and were engaging in activism at the international level as part of the larger strategy of promotingand claiming womens human rights at the national level. As a result, IWRAW Asia Pacific, in addition to continuing its focus on conceptual clarity and testing methodologies, expanded its work to:
- support the international work of its national partnersand constituencies;
- sustain advocacy to further understanding and domestic application of the principles of non-discrimination and equality;
-focus on providing technical assistance to national womens groups, including those in other regions, instead of organising trainings for them. In this way, local groups take ownership over the program by becoming responsible for securing funding for local costs of the training and crafting their own objectives and vision for the event; and
- develop a pool ofresource persons and trainers to assist in our technical assistance and capacity-building work.
As the CEDAW Committee and other human rights bodies progressively interpreted human rights standards in ways that complemented and crosscut their areas ofwork,IWRAW Asia Pacific engaged in advancing and integrating womens concerns into all human rights monitoring bodies. Our engagement here included:
- enhancing IWRAW Asia Pacificsadvocacy with regard to other treaty bodies, the UN Commission on Human Rights(now the Human Rights Council), and the UN Special Rapporteurs;
- integrating information on other major treaties and international and regional mechanisms into our national capacity-building component;
- developing a better understanding of womens economic, social and cultural rights; and
-  strengthening partnerships with mainstream human rights organisations working internationally and regionally.

IWRAW Asia Pacific focuses on women and womens NGOs from the South. We work primarily throughcollaborative projects at the international, national and local levels with women activists and NGOs; human rights advocates; lawyers; governments and international organisations.
As stated above, one reason for IWRAW Asia Pacifics uniqueness lies in its positioning as an international NGO based in the Global South, rather than in Geneva or New York. This positioning and our close contacts with local NGOs allow us to ground our analytical approach in the realities of NGOs and activists in the South sothat we canbetter address the structural causes that permit the violation of rights. Through this informed approach, we examine underlying causes of rights violations and strengths and weaknesses of State efforts and identify factors that are needed to create a culture of compliance with human rights norms and institutional frameworks and legal instruments that are needed for the administration of justice. This allows us to develop programs that aim at developing the capacity of people to claim rights and strengthenthe institutional framework necessary for this.

In addition, the strength of IWRAW Asia Pacifics positioning lies in the fact that we do not take up the causes of national level NGOs, but rather aim to play an enabling and facilitating role tobuild the capacity of local level activists to take up their causes directly and to participate in both their national debates and in international processes. Our programs relating to international human rights norms have brought greater cohesion toactivism at the national level. The presence of national level NGOs at international processes have earned them greater credibility and legitimacywith their own governments.
In addition, IWRAW Asia Pacific has a unique position with regard to the Committeeon the Elimination ofDiscrimination against Women (CEDAW Committee), the treaty body that oversees compliance by States parties to the CEDAW Convention,in that the UN Division for the Advancement of Women has named IWRAW Asia Pacific as the official channelforpassing alternative information from NGOs to the CEDAW Committee when those NGOs governments are reporting. This provides IWRAW Asia Pacific with greater insight into the workings of the Committee and gives local NGOs greater access to the Committee and Committee members because they have an international NGO that is advocating for their participation in the CEDAW reporting process. The alternative information provided by national level NGOs institutes a necessary system of checks and balances, strengtheningpolitical constituencies and increasing the demand for greater transparency and accountability from governments.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Asia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-26">31359</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">31359</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05259-09:23">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05259"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Global Influencing grants"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
