<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="cordaid-41160054-01" dstore:index="210" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-200741</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soutien au Comit&#xE9; multisectoriel en charge de la riposte au COVID-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commission for &#x201C;Risk Communication and Community Engagement&#x201D; of the Multisectoral Committee in charge of the response to COVID-19 in the Democratic Republic of Congo</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the last decade, the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) has experienced the occurrence of several epidemic outbreaks, notably: cholera, Ebola virus disease (EVD), polio and measles. In 2018, the country experienced its 10th epidemic of EVD which, to date, is on track to be controlled thanks to the country&apos;s effort with the support of the international community.
In December 2019, China announced an epidemic caused by a novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2), referred to as Coronavirus disease 2019 or COVID-19, whose epicenter is the city of Wuhan. Since then, several African countries as well as those of the rest of the world have been confronted with this epidemic favored by the intercontinental displacement of humans.
In view of the gravity of the situation and on the advice of the RSI committee (2005), the Director General to follow declared on January 30, 2020 this epidemic &quot;a public health emergency of international concern&quot; (USPPI), then since March 11, 2020 like a pandemic.
Several countries around the world have become at risk because of the large number of COVID19 cases they are recording. The DRC, being in a fragile situation due to the significant flow of trade with affected countries, has unfortunately not been able to escape the importation of COVID-19 cases, despite the prevention measures put in place.
To deal with this situation, the Government of the DRC with the support of partners has published a multisectoral strategic plan against the COVID-19 epidemic. This plan aims to ensure an effective response in the city of Kinshasa and operational preparation in the provinces not yet affected.
The implementation of this plan is based on the Multisectoral Response Committee (CMR-COVID-19), chaired by the Prime Minister, with the Minister of Health providing the secretariat. It gives the political orientations of the government, mobilizes resources and manages funds. To coordinate all response and preparedness interventions, several commissions have been created to monitor the main dimensions of this health crisis: surveillance, medical care, psycho-social care, risk communication and community engagement (CREC ), Infection Prevention and Control (PCI / WASH), Laboratory and research etc. These commissions bring together officials from the Ministry of Health, donors and civil society.
Cordaid DRC participates in several of them, notably the &quot;risk communication and community engagement&quot; commission. This commission launched an appeal to partners to support priority activities to be carried out in the area of &#x200B;&#x200B;communication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Purpose:

Contribute to the response against the pandemic linked to the COVID-19 disease by providing technical and financial support to the Multisectoral Committee of Riposte

Objectives :

1)	Long-term objective : 
       - Fight against the spread of COVID-19
,
       - Support the efforts of the Government of the DRC

2)	Short-term objectives:
 -Strengthen the partnership between Cordaid and the Government of the DRC, by participating physically and financially in the work of the &#x201C;multisectoral response committee&#x201D; (coordination and decision-making   body) and in the &#x201C;Communication and community engagement&#x201D; commission;
- Promote the visibility of Cordaid, targeting communication and media activities;
- Participate in the effort to prevent the spread of COVID-19, by contributing to strategic communication  through the &#x201C;Communication and community engagement&#x201D; commission (communication media, briefing for 
        audiovisual hosts, creation of a website and social media and digital content management)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Mensen in Nood</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid RDC (R&#xE9;publique D&#xE9;mocratique du Congo)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-01">69268</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="100"></capital-spend>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
