<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="2334" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06682-02:SO</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-Rapid Assessment CFM</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam&#x2019;s commitment is to actively centre the voice and experience of people and community in all our work and consider power, privilege and equity in the design of community-based feedback and complaints mechanisms CBFCMS, and to respect the knowledge, wisdom andperspective of others, as there is always scope for Oxfam to grow and learn as an organisation working with communities.
Functionalfeedback and complaints mechanisms that are accessible and safe to use are a demonstration of our organization-wide accountability commitment, to be truly accountable to the people and communities we work with and those affected by our programmes, by ensuring that they understand what is appropriate and inappropriate conduct of our staff and partners, getting their feedback about our programmes and/or complaints about conduct of our staff, agents or partners  and taking appropriate action to address these concerns. Accountability is &#x201C;the process of using power responsibly, taking account of, and being held accountable by different stakeholders, and primarily those who are affected by the exercise of such power&#x201D; . It is the right to be heard, and the duty to respond.

However, anecdotal information indicates that where CBFCMs initiatives and experiences exist in Oxfam, many are still disjointed, some are uncoordinated, and largely undocumented. In many places, they are non-existent, or if they are, not all of them are fully functional. The design of Oxfam&#x2019;s CBFCMs by Affiliates, Country Offices and in part Partners has not always ensured community involvement, in most cases resulting in not fit for purpose mechanisms. Also different affiliates still approach the issue of CBFCMs differently with different emphasis, approaches, tools and resources, therefore lacking a standardised coordinated approach.

Although Oxfam prides itself for encouraging communities we work with to speak out and report PSEA and child protection concerns and incidents concerning them,recent reports in some countries like DRC, Ethiopia, and Uganda not only attests to the limited awareness at community level on SEAand child protection risks and reporting mechanisms, but has also led to an increase in attention to ensure that SEA and child abuse and exploitation by humanitarian and development organisations like Oxfam are addressed through investment in preventive approaches but also responding to reports of abuse and exploitation when these incidents are reported.
Oxfam has two responsibilities for accountability in the programmes it manages, holding a responsibility for mutual accountability with its partners (as do the partners) and also holding a shared or joint accountability (with its partners) to the communities affected by its programmes. There is lack of knowledge how the
In addition to some of the above challenges, COVID-19 has added additional challenges to how effective current CBFCMs are, placing additional barriers to reporting that are currently not fully understood or risks mitigated.
OBJECTIVES OF THE PROJECT:
1. Map out existing CBCM&#x2019;s initiatives in select field/project locations, and document best practices and lessons learnt in implementing CBFCMs across the Oxfam confederation
2. Undertake a rapid assessment of the existing CBFCMs in Oxfam terms of effectiveness, experiences and lessons plus existing gaps.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2004 Oxfam Novib set up a Liaison Office in Nairobi, Kenya in order to support the Strengthening Somali Civil Society Program, at the request of the EU. This request was based on Oxfam Novib&apos;s work in Somalia to date, but intended to be more widely directed atthe entire civil society sector and the specific context in which it is operating in a post-conflict country. The program started with consulting local organisations in Somalia and Somaliland to get a complete picture of the sectors and regions where they are active, the challenges they face and the relationship between civil society, local political structures and the private sector. A program was then developed to strengthen the institutional development of Oxfam Novib&apos;s partners and those of other Oxfams, as well as a range of new NGOs.
In the first year local consultants were trained in Somalia. They were then seconded to civil society organisations to build their capacity in financial and organisational management. Furthermore, workshops were organised on specific themes suchas human rights and the role of civil society in the Somali context. The Liaison Office is now going to support the expansion of the program, focussing on strengthening both organisation and project management, while facilitating more training in the fields of civic education, governance, human rights and women&apos;s rights, HIV and AIDS and child protection.
Over the years, the Somalia Country Office has expanded its intervention on short term humanitarian response as well as development development interventions. In 2015/2016, a decision was reached to move the Country Programme operation, which was largely in Nairobi, from Nairobi to Hargeisa. The country office has a small office in Nairobi , Kenya and large operations office in Hargeisa, Somaliland.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-24">4002</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRA Programme Expenditures Country Offic</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">4000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam International Secretariat</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06682-02:SO">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007052"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Somalia HECA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06682"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Rapid Assessment CFM"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts on inclusion and protection within the security and justice sector.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts on inclusion and protection within the security and justice sector -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts on inclusion and protection within the security and justice sector.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
