<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="onl-activity" dstore:index="1492" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05823-28:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SORUDA CTP Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SORUDA
Beneficiary selection and verification of extremely vulnerable households / persons with special needs. This will be done with UNHCR/OPM/LWF/RWCs for PSN lists and verification.  Cash for work modality support to PSN in land opening and kitchen gardens. Will be done through the Kitgum SACCO. Agricultural input support &#x2013; farm seeds &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; tools through cash (value) Voucher / Coupon andtechnical agricultural extension service support. Emphasis will be working with the Private Business Sector appraised by SORUDA to provide in puts through Voucher / Coupon.
Procure through Service Provider and distribute (in-kind) hand washing tip-taps, soaps andwater purification supplies to the refugees and host-communities. Critical is in adherence to Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)

Through Cash Transfer modality, SORUDA and FOKAPOWA proposes to implement an integrated Food Security and Vulnerable Livelihood intervention that are mindful of environmental considerations, WASH and mainstreams gender and protection issues. It will be complemented by ongoing USAID Uganda Sanitation and Health Activity (USHA) and policy influencing with the appropriate authorities on the basisof issues raised in the course of the humanitarian response. Helping households meet basic food needs and rights enhances survival and choice to live a dignified life. This CCT project will promote food security and livelihood interventions through cash-based transfer modality that is in line with the Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) to ensure some food and income are obtained by vulnerable refugee and host-communities especially youth, women and men. Addressing food security needs and influencing for refugees and host-communities is buttressed by the fact that very few options are available for refugee households as well as host-community members to eke a living within the poor economic and livelihood setting they are in. This integrated approach is important because food security and livelihood outcomes cannot be achieved without an enabling environment; and agricultural dependent livelihoods cannot be sustainable without the management of the natural resources

WASH Intervention: Be aligned to the MoH SOP guidelines and Presidential directives on influencing behavioral practices in hand-washing with soap or sanitizers, wearing masks and social distancing to eliminate COVID-19, Germs, bacteria and water borne diseases. The key priority will ensure creating awareness on safe water chain and hand-washing with soap as well as proper waste disposal, fecal containment and sustaining positive hygiene practices. Overall, issues of public health and COVID-19, institutes personal and respiratory hygiene practices that curtail the virus spread. Limiting often isthe problem of hand washing withsoap, access to PPEs for staff that CCT Project will address by directly procuring and distributing(agreed package) at household levels. Service Providers appraised by SORUDA will provide the items worth the value for payment. TheCOVID-19 response, willbe done through WASH sector coordination together with Lamwo District Task Force and its decentralized sub-structures at Sub-county and Parish levels. The Consortium being members will contribute to quality improvements in service delivery by sharing progress and feedback from the communities being supported with all stakeholder, District COVID-19 Task Force, UNHCR and OPM.

Gender and Protection: Given that the large majority of refugees are women and children; the CCT Project focuses their inclusionto ensure their specific protections needs are addressed while observing the humanitarian response principles. These issues include: 1) the burden on women and girls as providers for their families in an unfamiliar environment, often without the social support of extended family and friends (Situation analysis vis-a-vis gender issues is elaborated). 2) exposure of women and young girls to harm including sexual and gender-based violence in a bid to feed for themselves and their families; 3) the ability ofwomen to access information about basic services, food rights and make decisions about issues affecting them. This Project will deliberately work with women, girls and youth in addressing their food and WASH needs that are preventing refugees and host communities from enjoying their right to a decent livelihood including obtaining food and income and to support appropriate programming to encourage peaceful co-existence. Refugee men and women use resources differently. To be effective, strategies to improve food security using cash-based transfer empowers them to make choices and decisions for their households. Therefore, the Project will pay close attention to the impact of disparities between women and men access to resources and opportunities. This implies women and men will be allies in formulating and pursuing strategies for more equitable development but more in addressing their needs. The integration of the GAL approach in the implementation also recognizes that refugee women and men have differenttypes of vulnerabilities, strategies and responsibilities in environmental change and impact mitigation. There is, therefore, a need to integrate gender issues in food insecure, environmental vulnerability and risk analysis in COVID-19 context.

SORUDAand FOKAPAWA - CCT Project interventions respond to the needs of both refugee and host communities &#x2013; at a 70:30 ratio as per the guidelines of Office of the Prime Minister (OPM) / UNHCR to improve:
&#x2022; Co-existence between the host and refugee communitieswill diffuse potential tensions on land related conflicts and benefits associated with the project.
&#x2022; Cash transfer modality activities will support especially the women and able youth selected by PSN households with income to be able to access food, address WASH and engaging also in small scale agriculture activities.
&#x2022; By avoiding going to search for food and WASH for households, it will ensure protection of women from risks of rights abuse (esp. Sexual and gender-based violence) and sanitation related disease outbreaks.
&#x2022; The Consortium will work with all stakeholders (Local Government, Refugee Welfare Committees, OPM, UNHCR, Oxfam and other partners) to ensure gender analysis is used in influencing policies and programmes that affect refugees and host communities.
&#x2022; Activities that promote energy conservation will support both gender, save time used forlooking for firewood and building materials
&#x2022; The Consortium is cognizant of the current fact that 86% are women and children together, 3% elderly, 44% Male, 56% Female, and 58% are children &lt;(&gt;&lt;&lt;)&gt;18 years of age when targeting

The CCT Project will carry out cash transfer modality for the Persons with Special Needs (PSN) households through community projects such as supporting vulnerable householdsto initiate agriculture with agri-inputs e.g. seeds &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; tools. The households will be provided with vegetable &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; seedlings which will enhance their nutrition intake through horticultural production as well as work positively towards environment protection.

The Project will use cash transfer modality entirely in supporting Persons with Special Needs (PSN) households by contracting Service Provider to supply COVID-19 related items. Appraised Private Service Provider will provide items such as soap, tip-tapsetc. to be distributed to the households. Each household will be provided with a package for prevention of COVID-19. The emphasis will be on building behavioral change among the target communities on COVID-19 pandemic protection, safe and positive sanitation &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;hygiene practices linked to food and water -chain handling and preparation and social distancing.

The CCT Project also proposes to mainstream Gender and Protection issues to address identified protection issues that especially affect women and children. It will do this by linking with actors that handle Protection Issues and referral. While intervening and cases of Sexual and GBV related to access to food and livelihood security, the project will be carried referral support to survivors of violence onspecific cases to the relevant authorities (Sub-county, Camp management and Police) who can handle counseling support and provided psycho-social support.

Overall, the CCT Project will guided by the Core Humanitarian Standards - applying &#x2018;do no harm&#x2019; principle and SOPs in all its interventions at host and refugee communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SORUDA SORUDA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SORUDA formerly Soroti Rural Development Agency, was initiated by a group of volunteers to address aftermath of challenges arising from civil and political conflict. Its focus was to target rural communities who were returning to their homes by addressing their livelihood and food security needs. Legally, it got registered in 2000 with Ministry of internal affairs NGO board registration No. S.5914/2928.
Thereafter, because of the decentralisation policy, the mother Soroti was sub divided to form eight Districts and legally SORUDA had to rebrand to take its acronym as a name and renewed its operation country wide. Increasing SORUDA was able to develop policies among which is the gender policy that guides SORUDA#s delivery of services to target 50% femaleparticipation.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
Program/project coverage has increased and interventions taken closure to communities specifically priorities given to female headed households, girls and Persons with Special Needs (PSN).
Out of the targeting, SORUDA hasbeen able to reach 25,000 (11,000 male and 14,000 Females) participating households covering areas of Teso, Lango, Karamoja and some parts of west Nile (Adjumani).
Developed simple group savings and loan schemes for purposes of improving access to smallfinancial services that do not have collaterals
Introduced disaster preparedness grain storage facilities using improved technologies such as use of super grain bags, plastic and metallic silos
Strengthened production and productivity
Established a community network to address challenges of women and girl child abuses through community surveillance system and District production departments for disasters

3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
To promotesustainable rural development through community driveneradication initiatives, good governance and emancipation initiatives

To carry out capacity building through training in group development, advisory services and research.
# To contribute to reduction of poverty in the rural poor communities
# To empower women and carry out advocacy and sensitization on Child rights
# To promote environment conservation and management
# To promote peace building and conflict resolution in East, North and West Nile regions

SORUDA#s activities and programme competences are organized around four main thematic areas namely;
1) Support Livelihood interventions;
2) Human rights and Good Governance
3) Water, Sanitation and Hygiene promotion
4) Emergency response and Disaster Risk Reduction
5) HIV/AIDS advocacy onprevention
SORUDA has intervened in the rural communities of Teso, Karamoja, Lango, Acholi and West Nile regions in Uganda with interventions targeting farmers, youth in and out of school, children, pregnant mothers, Persons Living with HIV/AIDS and displaced persons
4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
SORUDA has intervened in communities displaces, refugees and has worked in Teso, Karamoja, Lango, Acholi and West Nile. SORUDA has worked in hard to reach areas targeting the rural underserved and poverty strickencommunities.
SORUDA has worked with Local Government structures, religious and Cultural sectors and other CSOs. The named actors supported in community mobilisation, sensitization beneficiary identification, security provision and complementary support

SORUDA has adequate human and logistic resources
Community presence and existence
Ability to quickly respond to emergency situations in the community.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-12">24997</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">24997</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SORUDA SORUDA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-01">24997</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05823-28:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001704"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05823"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="ELNHA Phase II"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="400"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programmes more effective:  # cases where Oxfam Novib/partners implement recommendations derived from learning trajectories.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1107"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5380-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">evidence products (track records, cases, evaluations etc.) produced that assess Oxfam Novib&#x2019;s programmes and projects effectiveness and quality.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5380-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
