<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" dstore:dataset="nl-kvk-41207989-activities14" dstore:index="161" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41207989-P-62601</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Love Alliance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Love Alliance, a new five-year programme (2021-2025), is based on an unwavering commitment to protecting, promoting and fulfilling sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) globally, unifying people who use drugs, sex workers and LGBTQI movements, and amplifying the diversity of voices in these communities.

The alliance brings together national thought leaders GALZ, SANPUD and Sisonke, regional grantmakers UHAI EASHRI, AFE and ISDAO, with the global network of people living with HIV (GNP+) and the Netherlands-based administrative lead Aidsfonds. 

Together, we advocate for adequate levels of funding and for taking truly human rights-based programmes to scale. We take this opportunity to prioritise and invest in challenging the structural barriers of underfunding, criminalisation and exclusion of us in all our diversity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Across Africa, communities are strengthened to come together and build movements to advocate for change by identifying common issues and tackling them together. Community organisations receive funding and support to fight for their rights and promote access to SRHR. The Love Alliance seeks to significantly reduce HIV infections by influencing policies, raising awareness and organising communities in ten African countries. With a specific focus on people who use drugs, sex workers, LGBTIQ+ people and people living with HIV, we aim to achieve the following goals:

1. Capable, inclusive, influential, and mutually supportive key population movements in unrestricted civic space.
2. An end to sexual, gender-based violence, stigma and discrimination against key populations.
3. Equal access to inclusive, people-centred, accountable, integrated HIV and comprehensive sexual and reproductive health services.

Our strategic objectives contribute to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) 3 and 5 and result areas 4 and 1 of the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs&#x2019; SRHR strategy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Love Alliance is based on the premise that to end AIDS, the groups most affected by the epidemic need to be at the centre of the response. We build on existing evidence on the effectiveness of rights-based responses that focus on and meaningfully engage LGBTQI people, sex workers, people who use drugs, with specific attention for people living with HIV, women and young people within these communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The world is far behind in preventing new HIV infections. In 2019, 1.7 million people were newly infected with the virus, more than three times the global target. Also, the response could be set even further back, by a decade or more, if the COVID-19 pandemic results in severe disruptions to HIV services. 

In 2019, people who use drugs, LGBTQI people and sex workers accounted for 62% of new HIV infections worldwide, an increase of 15% compared to 2018. Causes for this increase are stigma and discrimination, together with other social inequalities and exclusion. Despite the urgency and needs, only 2% of current global HIV financing goes to programming for these key populations, and even less goes directly to communities and their organisations. There is an urgent need for securing the sexual and reproductive health and rights of all people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sisonke South Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISDAO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GALZ</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SaNPUD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFE MENA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31(0)206262669</telephone>
   <email>IATI@aidsfonds.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MA" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Love Alliance Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13040" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Love Alliance STD control including HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Love Alliance Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">62903700</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
