<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-mk" dstore:index="84" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12828A0101-MKD-15126</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender mainstreaming advisory (UNW-SEA)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Gender mainstreaming advisory (UNW-SEA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN Women applied to the Embassy of Sweden for funding of about 16,4 MSEK to carry out the &quot;Gender mainstreaming advisory services to the North Macedonian administration at central level&#x201D; in the Republic of North Macedonia during 2020-2022 (shorth project title: Gender Equality Facility in North Macedonia) . The intervention aims at increasing long-term capacities and skills of key Government personnel mandated for European Integration and Gender Equality to mainstream Gender Equality goals into the country&#x2019;s planning and policy processes, so they perform their mandate efficiently and in line with the European Council&#x2019;s decision of 25th March 2020 to open accession negotiations with the country.  
The project aim is to stimulate reform processes and policies and to accomplish development of more sustainable institutions, by focusing the institutions that are directly engaged in the preparation and planning of country&#x2019;s EU accession process.

The intervention is proposed under two complementary strands of engagement:

-In direct partnership with the Secretariat for European Affairs, the project will provide expert support for enhancing the integration of gender perspectives into IPA-supported actions, focusing on sector governance structures such as IPA Units, IPA Coordinators, and Sector Working Groups.
-In direct partnership with the Equal Opportunities Department at the Ministry for Labour and Social Policy, the project will strengthen the capacities of line ministries to mainstream gender into documents and processes of the National Programme for the Adoption of the Community acquis, focusing on staff in line ministries and particularly on the essential role of Equal Opportunity Coordinators.

The Project will also attend:
- Strenghtening knowledge and capacity building for selected CSO actors will to advocate for and to contribute in gender-responsive policy making processes, as well as to effectively engage in IPA-related governance processes and their monitoring through gender-lens.
- Supporting the Government in responding to the significant and gender &#x2013; specific socio- economic challenges which result from the measures to contain the COVID 19 pandemic.

UN Women will implement the intervention in close cooperation with the Secretariat for European Affairs and the Ministry of Labour and Social Policy of the Republic of North Macedonia.

Sida is the only donor invited by UN Women and the Secretariat for European Affairs for support of this intervention.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Women har ans&#xF6;kt till Sveriges ambassad om finansiering p&#xE5; ca 16,4 MSEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &quot; Gender mainstreaming advisory services to the North Macedonian administration at central level&quot; (kortfattad projekttitel: Gender Equality Facility in North Macedonia) i Nordmakedonien under perioden 2020-2022.

Insatsen syftar till att &#xF6;ka l&#xE5;ngsiktig kapacitet och kompetens hos nyckelpersoner i regeringen som har mandat att arbeta med europeisk integration och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet. Detta v&#xE4;ntas bidra till att dessa nyckelpersoner integrerar j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsm&#xE5;l i processer f&#xF6;r planering och policy samt att de utf&#xF6;r sitt mandat effektivt och i linje med Europeiska r&#xE5;dets beslut (25.03.2020) om att inleda anslutningsf&#xF6;rhandlingar med landet.

Projektets m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att stimulera reformprocesser och policys samt att utveckla mer h&#xE5;llbara institutioner med fokus p&#xE5; de institutioner som &#xE4;r direkt engagerade i f&#xF6;rberedelserna och planeringen av landets anslutningsprocess till EU. 

Insatsen f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s fokusera p&#xE5; tv&#xE5; kompletterande delar:

-	Expertst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra integreringen av genusperspektiv i IPA-st&#xF6;dda &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder med fokus p&#xE5; sektorstyrningsstrukturer s&#xE5; som IPA-enheter, IPA-samordnare och sektorarbetsgrupper; i direkt samarbete med Sekretariatet f&#xF6;r europeiska fr&#xE5;gor (Secretariat for European Affairs, SEA).

-	St&#xE4;rka kapaciteten att integrera genusperspektiv i dokument och processer i det nationella programmet f&#xF6;r antagande av EUs regelverk vid Ministeriet f&#xF6;r arbetsmarknad- och socialpolitik. Detta utf&#xF6;rs i direkt samarbete med ministeriets avdelning f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet. Fokus kommer fr&#xE4;mst att ligga p&#xE5; personal i ministerier och specifikt den viktiga rollen som samordnare f&#xF6;r lika m&#xF6;jligheter.

Vidare kommer projektet &#xE4;ven att: 

-	&#xD6;ka kunskapen och kapaciteten hos utvalda civilsamh&#xE4;llesakt&#xF6;rer samt st&#xE4;rka deras vilja att f&#xF6;respr&#xE5;ka och bidra till genus-responsiva beslutsprocesser, samt att effektivt engagera sig i och f&#xF6;lja upp IPA-relaterade styrningsprocesser med genusglas&#xF6;gon.

-	St&#xF6;dja regeringen f&#xF6;r att bem&#xF6;ta de betydande och genusspecifika socioekonomiska utmaningarna som f&#xF6;ljer av &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rderna f&#xF6;r att begr&#xE4;nsa spridningen av Covid-19. 

UN-Women kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med Sekretariatet f&#xF6;r europeiska fr&#xE5;gor och ministeriet f&#xF6;r arbete och socialpolitik i Nordmakedonien.

Sida &#xE4;r den enda givare som har blivit inbjuden av UN-Women och SEA att finansiera denna insats.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project Gender mainstreaming advisory services to the North Macedonian administration at central level (Gender Equality Facility) contributes to administrative capacity building on central and local level and to enabling the public administration to comply with global norms and standards on gender equality and women empowerment. It is about integrating gender equality perspectives at all stages and levels of policies and strategic programmes prepared by the public administration, by focusing on noticing and addressing the existing gender equality gaps and related lack of knowledge in the responsible institutions. Further, the capacity of the relevant central and local institutions will be strengthened in transposition of the EU gender equality acquis and their performance.
The intervention places specific emphases on supporting the Government in responding to the significant and gender-specific socio-economic challenges which result from the measures to cover the COVID-19 pandemic, by implementing the principles of international guidance on gender-responsive recovery, and following the EU&#x2019;s &#x201C;Declaration on human rights in times of the coronavirus pandemic&#x201D;
The overall objective of the project is to further strengthen capacity and skills of key Government personnel in North Macedonia mandated for European Integration and Gender Equality, to perform their mandate efficiently for enhanced transposition of the European Union Gender Equality Acquis and in line with the Gender Equality Strategy 2020-2025.
The expected single Outcome is - Key Government personnel, mandated for European Integration and Gender Equality, are capacitated to implement the EU Gender Equality Acquis
The planned Output 1 is: Secretariat for European Affairs, Sector Working Groups, and IPA units have the knowledge and skills to include gender perspective in programming,&#xA0;implementation, reporting, monitoring and evaluation for IPA programmes
The output related activities, among other, include strengthening capacities and enabling preparation of strategic documents like Country&apos;s Gender Profile , as well as implementation of basic and advanced trainings on &#x201C;Gender Mainstreaming in IPA&#x201D; including provided direct guidance and advice on gender mainstreaming and analysis in priority reform areas and relevant EU chapters (19,22,23,24).
The Output 2 attends: National Gender Mechanisms have the administrative capacities to perform gender mainstreaming of National Program for the Adoption of the Acquis planning processes, and to implement Gender Equality legislation and policy in line with EU regulations and international obligations.
Support to gender mainstreaming in the drafting and revision of sector strategies, programmes, action plans and funds in priority areas, as well as guidance for introducing EU sector specific gender-mainstreaming, shall be introduced to relevant local counterparts for improved gender responsive and national policy dialogue and for implementing the EU Gender Equality acquis.
General public awareness on the support of women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality shall be achieved through increased transparency of work of the public administration and intensive communication and visibility of project activities. &#xA0;
The proposed project responds to Sida&#x2019;s Strategy Plan for 2020-2022 by focusing on administrative reform and institutional strengthening aiming to contribute to increased confidence in the institutions, and by simultaneously building trust in the administration by the means of strengthened communication of activities and transparency in the functioning of the state apparatus, while reducing the risks of corruption. The project is also about strengthening the Secretariat for European Affairs&#x2019; ability to pursue major processes such as EU rapprochement and donor coordination.
The project goal directly contributes to&#xA0;the expected results in the Western Balkans as outlined in the Results Strategy for Sweden&#x2019;s reform cooperation with the Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2020. The Strategy areas attended under the project are WB 2014-2020: B1 - Strengthened democracy, greater respect for human rights and a more fully developed state under the rule of law focusing on strengthened public administration and judicial systems (R3 - A more efficient public management with the administrative capacity to implement reforms for EU integration and R4 - Public services delivered with better quality based on principles of non-discrimination and equal rights and with less corruption) and B2 -Strengthened democracy, greater respect for human rights and a more fully developed state under the rule of law focusing on increased enjoyment of human rights and greater opportunities to exercise democratic influence (R11- To bring partner countries closer to meeting international and national commitments to human rights, gender equality including the EU strategy for gender equality, and non-discrimination). Also, the project is&#xA0;responding to the overall priority of promoting gender equality and gender mainstreaming in all cooperation areas. Further, it directly supports the implementation of Agenda 2030, especially contributing to achieve the SDG 5.
Furthermore, the project supports women&#x2019;s influence in all areas of society which is a direct objective of the Swedish Feminist foreign policy, as well as contributes to the priority areas of the Drive for Democracy by promoting equality and social integration, as well as strengthening women&#x2019;s political participation.
The program is initiated and developed in cooperation with the local institutions and it is adjusted to the national context.
The current 24 months intervention presents the initial phase of a process that will be followed by a subsequent second phase preferably jointly supported with EU/IPA funding.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Macedonia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15126" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other general public services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">503816.6281203514</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">814358.7739014301</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">462901.9403455053</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">503816.6281203517</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">462901.9403455051</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">814358.7739014337</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1781077.342367</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">503816.6281203514</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/vbtla/12828_Decisiononcontribution,GenderMainstreamingAdvisory,UNWomen-SecretariatforEuropeanAffairs(UNW-SEA),2020-2023.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution: Gender mainstreaming advisory services to the North Macedonian administration at central level</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/vbtla/12828_Agreement,GenderMainstreamingAdvisory,UNWomen-SecretariatforEuropeanAffairs(UNW-SEA),2020-2023.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement: Gender mainstreaming advisory services to the North Macedonian administration at central level</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="12828" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
