<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-cd" dstore:index="176" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13720A0101-COD-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 UNFPA - Country Programme Support DRC</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 UNFPA -  landprogram st&#xF6;d DRK</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
This contribution aims at strenthening UNFPA&apos;s capacity to deliver on the results set by the organisation&apos;s country programme for DRC covering the period 2020-2023. 

In DRC, all indicators concerning maternal health, sexual and reproductive services and rights (SRHR), including poor access to contraceptives are alarming. Also, overall policy environment with regards to SRHR and population dynamics is inadapted to country&apos;s challenges. UNFPA is a key actor in DRC whose strong action within the framework of its global mandate is needed to support both decision makers, implementing actors (international and national), and different target groups (professionals as well as services users, such as the youth).

This contribution proposes providing an institutional support to UNFPA in the country to allow them flexibility, freedom and means to position themselves and provide the needed assistance to the multitude of actors on SRHR and related issues in the country.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Denna insats syftar till att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka UNFPA: s kapacitet att leverera de resultat som anges i organisationens landprogram f&#xF6;r Demokratiska Republiken Kongo under perioden 2020-2023.

I DRK &#xE4;r alla indikatorer som r&#xF6;r kvinnors h&#xE4;lsa, sexuella och reproduktiva tj&#xE4;nster och r&#xE4;ttigheter (SRHR), inklusive tillg&#xE5;ng till preventivmedel och ungdomsgraviditeter alarmerande. Dessutom &#xE4;r den &#xF6;vergripande policymilj&#xF6;n n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller SRHR och befolkningsdynamik inte anpassad till landets utmaningar. UNFPA &#xE4;r en nyckelakt&#xF6;r i DRK, vars starka insatser inom ramen f&#xF6;r dess globala mandat beh&#xF6;vs f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja b&#xE5;de beslutsfattare, genomf&#xF6;rande akt&#xF6;rer (internationella och nationella) och olika m&#xE5;lgrupper (kvinnor, ungdomar, v&#xE5;rdgivare och institutioner) .

Detta institutionella st&#xF6;d till UNFPA ger UNFPA flexibilitet, frihet och medel f&#xF6;r att positionera sig och ge st&#xF6;d till akt&#xF6;rer inom SRHR och relaterade fr&#xE5;gor i landet.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This contribution is intended to support the&#xA0;UNFPA DRC country office in contributing to&#xA0;the following objectives: (1) strengthened national capacities to improve financing and develop and implement policies and programmes that address sexual and reproductive health and right&#x2019;s needs; (2) integrated high quality services delivery and information for maternal health, family planning, Sexually Transmitted Infections/HIV,&#xA0;(3) to ensure that young people and adolescents, especially&#xA0;disadvantaged adolescent&#x2019;s girls are empowered to have the capacity to claim their rights and access to sexual and reproductive health services; (4) to strengthened national accountability mechanisms&#xA0;to prevent SGBV&#xA0;and promote gender equality and to provide holistic care to victims of SGBV. These objectives will be pursued in stable as well as in humanitarian context.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.8492676201</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1586311.191954</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yet this is only the first year since this new funding modality was decided upon, UNFPA is very active on all SRHR issues in DRC, comprising provision of PF commodities to selected areas; in supporting the training of humanitarian midwives, in fighting SGBV and assisting the government to prepare next population&apos;s census, etc.&#xA0; Selected results that can be mentioned include: - A study on COVID-19 and pregnancy outcomes is being carried out in collaboration with other stakeholders such as WHO and international NGOs; - 8 health facilities in Ebola high risk areas in the provinces of North Kivu and Ituri benefitted from major rehabilitations within the framework of health system strengthening and the nexus-building back better; and 300 health staff from 20 health facilities benefitted from capacity building in PCI. These 20 health facilities equally benefitted from equipment and medical supplies with additional funds from Paul G Allen Foundation; - Two new pools of &#x201C;humanitarian midwives&#x201D; from Goma (for 31 midwives from North Kivu, South Kivu, Maniema and Ituri provinces) and Kananga (for 32 midwives from Kasai Central, Kasai, Kasai Oriental and Sankuru provinces) were trained on preparedness and response in humanitarian emergency situations during this reporting period; - Much progress has been made in light of obtaining a law regulating the midwifery profession in the country. The bill was placed on the parliamentary agenda during the current session and referred to commission for in depth analysis. In order to promote better understanding of the bill, two sessions have been organized, firstly to sensitize a group of young parliamentarians and secondly to sensitize a group of parliamentarians on the importance and urgency to have a law regulating the profession of midwifery. The bill is under study at the cultural and social commission of the parliament and is expected to be voted into law by the end of the year. UNFPA is supporting the Midwifery Association of Congo and all stake holders in advocacy efforts to obtain this law; -&#xA0; Communication on GBV protection and prevention measures in collaboration with the Ministry of Gender, Family and Children, Association of female leaders, activists on violence against women, One-Stop Centres for the holistic management of rape and HEFORSHE champions; Youth:&#xA0; 25,000 adolescents received comprehensive sex education at school through the KITUMAINI Initiative; 22,000 adolescents received a comprehensive sex education out of school and entrepreneurial skills through KITUMAINI;&#xA0;70,000 reusable masks have been produced by young people as part of the offers to prevent against covid 19; 10,000 adolescent girls use youth-friendly sexual and reproductive health services; 1,100 vulnerable people (women, orphans, people with disabilities, students, etc.) benefited from Covid19 protection kit. - Midwifery:&#xA0;UNFPA, working in partnership&#xA0;with Sanru, equipped the newly rehabilitated skills laboratory of the Institut Sup&#xE9;rieur des Techniques M&#xE9;dicales (ISTM) Kindu/Maniema with training dummies&#xA0;and other training materials. This was also carried out in the ISTM of Tshikapa/Kasai early this year where Sanru rehabilitated&#xA0;the skills lab of this midwifery training&#xA0;institution which UNFPA equipped with training dummies and training materials; UNFPA has rehabilitated the ISTM of Kalima in Maniema and is negotiating with Sanru to complete with water, hygiene and sanitary installations upgrades; UNFPA and partners are working towards celebrating the international year of midwives and nurses in Kinshasa on the 4th of December.&#xA0; The Swedish Embassy is invited as a key player both for UNFPA and the midwifery profession.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="13720" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1225000000.0" strategy-end-date="2019-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <title>DR Congo 2015-2019</title>
    <titleSV>DR Kongo 2015-2019</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
