<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-bd" dstore:index="159" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12966A0101-BGD-12340</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Mental Health Cox&apos;s Bazar</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Psykisk h&#xE4;lsa Cox&apos;s Bazar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
Support to mental health among Rohingya refugees and host population i Cox&apos;s Bazar, Bangladesh.

The Organization for International Migration, IOM, has applied for funding from Sida with SEK 20 million to implement the intervention &quot;Expanding the Protection and Promotion of Mental Health and Psychosocial Support for the Communities Affected by the Refugee Emergency in Cox&apos;s Bazar, Bangladesh&quot; during the period 2019-2021.

The main objective of the intervention is to scale-up Mental Health and Psycho Social Support, MHPSS, to increase outreach capacity and improve service provision towards achieving a more holistic, comprehensive and inclusive mental health and psychosocial response for both refugees and host population.

The programme  will work towards three priority outcomes in order to meet this objective:
1. Strengthen the national system in the provision of MHPSS services through increased coordination and knowledge management
2. Improve MHPSS coverage by adding and expanding outreach services and elements to the host community, as well as addressing the need to strengthen local capacity for adequately detecting and responding to mental health challenges
3. Strengthen the community-based and development approach of the MHPSS response.

The total budget of the contribution is 20 million Swedish kronor. No funds will be sub-granted.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Organisationen f&#xF6;r Internationell Migration, IOM, har ans&#xF6;kt hos Sida om finansiering med 20 miljoner kronor f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen &quot;&#xD6;kat skydd och fr&#xE4;mjande av psykisk h&#xE4;lsa och psykosocialt st&#xF6;d till Rohingya och lokalbefolkning p&#xE5;verkade av flyktingkrisen i Cox&apos;s Bazar, Bangladesh&quot; under perioden 2019-2021.

Insatsen syftar till att st&#xE4;rka Mental h&#xE4;lsa och psykosocialt st&#xF6;d, MHPSS, f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka kapaciteten och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra servicen f&#xF6;r en mer holistisk  och inkluderande psykisk h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd och psykosocial respons f&#xF6;r b&#xE5;de flyktingar och lokalbefolkning.

Programmet  kommer att arbeta mot tre prioriterade resultat f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; detta m&#xE5;l:
1. St&#xE4;rka det nationella systemet f&#xF6;r tillhandah&#xE5;llande av MHPSS genom &#xF6;kad samordning och kunskapsutveckling
2. F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra t&#xE4;ckningen av MHPSS genom att utveckla och n&#xE5; ut med service och st&#xF6;d till v&#xE4;rdsamh&#xE4;llet, samt st&#xE4;rka lokal kapacitet f&#xF6;r att uppt&#xE4;cka och ge st&#xF6;d vid psykisk utsatthet
3. St&#xE4;rka MHPSS-responsen utifr&#xE5;n en lokalsamh&#xE4;llesstrategi och med ett utvecklingsperspektiv.

Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 20 miljoner kronor. Inga medel kommer att vidaref&#xF6;rmedlas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the intervention proposed by IOM is to scale-up MHPSS programming to increase outreach capacity and improve service provision towards achieving a more holistic, comprehensive and inclusive mental health and psychosocial response to Rohingya refugees and host population in Cox&apos;s Bazar.The programme presented by IOM will work towards three priority outcomes in order to meet this objective:1. Strengthen the national system in the provision of MHPSS services through increased coordination and knowledge management2. Improve MHPSS coverage by adding and expanding outreach services and elements to the host community, as well as addressing the need to strengthen local capacity for adequately detecting and responding to mental health challenges3. Strengthen the community-based and development approach of the MHPSS response.Outputs expected are:- Contribution to an implementation plan to address MHPPS gaps identified by the readiness assessment is developed jointly with the Government of Bangladesh (GoB) - MHPSS service delivery offered to beneficiaries at refugee health facilities and points specifically chosen to improve host community access- Strengthened capacity to identify, refer, treat and follow up severe mental disorders amongst affected communities- Promoted a sense of belonging in the Rohingya refugee community to restore social connections and well-beingActivities: Under outcome 1- Conduct a MHPSS services availability and readiness assessment- Provide support to the Government of Bangladesh (GoB) to develop an implementation plan to address MHPPS gapsUnder outcome&#xA0;2- Establish specialized core MHPSS team dedicated to strengthening outreach services for Rohingya and host community members, including recruiting and training mental health professionals, making resources more physically accessible to beneficiaries, and raising awareness around mental health care- Organize comprehensive counselling training/mentoring programme for community health workers- Conduct mental health assessments that will help to identify those in need of specialized services- Conduct resource mapping on existing clinical assessment tools for mental health response, helping to identify gaps in resources for addressing beneficiary mental health conditions- Mental health professional will develop a culturally-validated tool informed by findings of resource mapping and mental health assessment- Mental health professional will train 25 mental health professionals in use and application of tool to provide special mental health services- Core Mental Health Team will train professionals and community-based workers to improve identification of those in need of mental health support, as well as techniques for strengthening referral pathways to assist in their care and improve the mental health response systemUnder outcome&#xA0;3- Establish a Historical Memory Centre that is aimed at promoting community identity and local values; facilitating inter-generational dialogues by engaging children and young people with historical narratives; and finally, vindicating spiritual and cultural rituals that have been historically marginalized or prohibited- Develop a module on psychosocial development skills, targeting non-MHPSS professional community members of both host and refugee communities that are participating in other projects intended to improve livelihood opportunities or full realisation of their social rights.- Conduct 300 community-based activities to promote social-cohesion and integration, coordinating with other humanitarian actors such as UNHCR and UNICEF
The target groups are Rohingya refugees and host population in Cox&apos;s Bazar. The community-based activities will seek to empower women, older persons, youth, boys, and girls, as well as groups especially at-risk in contexts of economic, social, and political hardship.&#xA0; In the districts of Ukhya and Teknaf&#xA0; targeted populations will be children and youth (boys and girls), and older persons (men and women). &#xA0;
The project intervention is expected to lead to that people living in Cox&apos;s Bazar, refugees and host population, will have improved access to mental health, which will hopefully prevent outbreak of more severe mental illness and help them to cope with the daily stressors in their daily life as well as to strengthen their capacity to plan for their future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47066" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organisation for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="12340" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promotion of mental health and well-being</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="123" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-communicable diseases (NCDs)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4 - By 2030, reduce by one third premature mortality from non-communicable diseases through prevention and treatment and promote mental health and well-being.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.4 - Till 2030 genom f&#xF6;rebyggande insatser och behandling minska det antal m&#xE4;nniskor som d&#xF6;r i f&#xF6;rtid av icke smittsamma sjukdomar med en tredjedel samt fr&#xE4;mja psykisk h&#xE4;lsa och v&#xE4;lbefinnande.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">5e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.6985352405</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2115081.589272</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/dc05-iom-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM/International Organisation for Migration</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/dc05-iom-2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mental Health in Cox&apos;s Bazar (IOM)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some of the outputs until May 2020 are:- 9,723 beneficiaries reached of which 22 % in host communities with group activities or individual counselling.- 6,755 (3,366 female, 3,389 male) beneficiaries were reached through 371community-based activities- 100,000 people reached with mass communication on Covid-19 via tom-tom messaging- capacity strengthening of professionals, volunteers and community leaders- guidance to the five subgroups of the MHPSS Working Group:, i) Integration, ii) Child and Adolescents, iii) Emergency Preparedness Response Plan (EPRP), iv) Assessment and research and v) Suicide Prevention - 957 beneficiaries (463 female, 494 male) received direct psychosocial services - hotline service launched during covid-19- a research team of 10 Rohingya &#x201C;Cultural Agents&#x201D; trained- pottery courses held for host community and refugees- 88 skilled Rohingya artisans and artists living in camps engaged to produce works of cultural heritage- five exhibitions in the Cultural Memory Center produced- tri-lingual Visual Dictionary of Rohingya Culture produced and printedAn analysis with revised work plan due to the Covid-19 implications for the project was submitted by IOM. The MHPSS intervention adapt the activities to the covid-19 situation through for example limited group activities, telecounseling and capacity building of front line health workers. It was assessed by Sida to be relevant and corresponding to needs of adaptation of activities and expected results.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="12966" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1040102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1900000000.0" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Bangladesh 2014-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Bangladesh 2014-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
