<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-ke" dstore:index="198" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-05-04T09:32:22" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-05-04T09:32:23" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11331A0102-KEN-15112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Consolidate Gains &amp; Deepen Devolution UNDP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Konsolidera framg&#xE5;ngar och f&#xF6;rdjupa devolution UNDP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
Sweden is supporting the Government of Kenya/UN program Consolidating Gains and Deepening Devolution in Kenya with SEK 75 million. Devolution is a certain kind of decentralization: the statutory delegation of powers from the central government to government at the subnational &#x2013; in this case county &#x2013; level.

The goal of the program is that people in Kenya access high quality services at devolved level that are well coordinated, integrated, transparent, equitably resourced and accountable by 2022, thereby contributing to a democratic political system that is issue-based, results-oriented and accountable to the public. This will be attained by 1) strengthening policy, legal and institutional mechanisms for coordinated, inclusive and effective service delivery; 2) developing public finance management institutions with strengthened processes and systems for equitable, efficient and accountable service delivery; 3) developing county-level institutions&#x2019; capacity for evidence-based planning, budgeting, implementation, monitoring and evaluation for accountable service delivery; and 4) developing the capacity of people in Kenya to engage, deepen accountability and transparency in devolution, especially women, youth and persons with disability.

The program is focused on 14 of the 47 counties, chosen on the basis of criteria such as poverty, aridness, gender inequality, child deprivation, disaster risk, and cross-border issues.

The program will be managed by UNDP and implemented by UNDP, UNICEF, UN Women, the Government of Kenya, and others.

&#x201C;Consolidating Gains and Deepening Devolution in Kenya,&#x201D; Joint Programme Document, final version (Republic of Kenya and United Nations Kenya [25 June 2019])</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Sverige st&#xF6;der den kenyanska regeringens och FN:s program Consolidating Gains and Deepening Devolution in Kenya (Konsolidera framg&#xE5;ngar och f&#xF6;rdjupa devolutionen i Kenya) med SEK 75 miljoner. Devolution &#xE4;r en viss typ av decentralisering: den lagstadgade delegeringen av befogenheter fr&#xE5;n centralregeringen till regeringen p&#xE5; subnationell niv&#xE5; &#x2013; i detta fall l&#xE4;nsniv&#xE5;.

M&#xE5;let med programmet &#xE4;r att m&#xE4;nniskor i Kenya f&#xE5;r tillg&#xE5;ng till h&#xF6;gkvalitativa tj&#xE4;nster p&#xE5; devolverad niv&#xE5; som &#xE4;r v&#xE4;lkoordinerade, integrerade, transparenta, r&#xE4;ttvist finansierade och redovisningsskyldiga fram till 2022, och d&#xE4;rmed bidra till ett demokratiskt politiskt system som &#xE4;r fr&#xE5;gest&#xE4;llningsbaserat, resultatinriktat och redovisningsskyldiga till allm&#xE4;nheten. Detta kommer att uppn&#xE5;s genom att 1) st&#xE4;rka politiska, r&#xE4;ttsliga och institutionella mekanismer f&#xF6;r samordnad, inkluderande och effektiv tj&#xE4;nsteleverans, 2) utveckla institutioner f&#xF6;r offentliga finanser med st&#xE4;rkta processer och system f&#xF6;r r&#xE4;ttvis, effektiv och ansvarsfull leverans av tj&#xE4;nster; 3) utveckla l&#xE4;nsinstitutionernas kapacitet f&#xF6;r evidensbaserad planering, budgetering, genomf&#xF6;rande, &#xF6;vervakning och utv&#xE4;rdering f&#xF6;r ansvarsfull service och 4) utveckla f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan hos m&#xE4;nniskor i Kenya att engagera sig, f&#xF6;rdjupa ansvarsskyldighet och &#xF6;ppenhet i devolution, s&#xE4;rskilt kvinnor, ungdomar och personer med funktionshinder

Programmet &#xE4;r inriktat p&#xE5; 14 av de 47 l&#xE4;nen, valda p&#xE5; grund av kriterier som fattigdom, torrhet, oj&#xE4;mlikhet mellan k&#xF6;n, barnfattigdom, katastrofrisk och problem &#xF6;ver gr&#xE4;nserna.

Programmet kommer att f&#xF6;rvaltas av UNDP och genomf&#xF6;ras av UNDP, UNICEF, UN Women, Kenyas regering och andra.

&#x201C;Consolidating Gains and Deepening Devolution in Kenya,&#x201D; Gemensamt programdokument, slutversion (Republic of Kenya och United Nations Kenya [25 juni 2019])</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goals of the UNDP devolution program are as follows:
*Impact: A democratic political system that is issue-based, results-oriented and accountable to the public. (Government of Kenya Medium Term Plan III Result)
*Outcome 1: By 2022 people in Kenya access high quality services at devolved level that are well coordinated, integrated, transparent, equitably resourced and accountable. (UNDAF outcome 1.2.)
*Output 1.1: Government has strengthened policy, legal and institutional mechanisms for coordinated, inclusive and effective service delivery
*Output 1.2: Public finance management institutions have strengthened processes and systems for equitable, efficient and accountable service delivery
*Output 1.3: County level institutions have strengthened capacity for evidence-based planning, budgeting, implementation, monitoring and evaluation for accountable service delivery
*Output 1.4: People in Kenya have capacity to engage, deepen accountability and transparency in devolution, especially women, youth and persons with disability</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation and support to subnational government</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.3 - Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.3 - Avskaffa alla skadliga sedv&#xE4;njor, s&#xE5;som barn&#xE4;ktenskap, tidiga &#xE4;ktenskap och tv&#xE5;ngs&#xE4;ktenskap samt kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2171623.39707048</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2171623.39707048</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2115081.589272</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/11331_Decision11331KonsolideraFramgangarochFordjupaDevolutionUNDP.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision Konsolidera Framg&#xE5;ngar och F&#xF6;rdjupa Devolution UNDP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Context: County governments in Kenya were established in 2013.&#xA0; Sweden, Denmark and Italy support a program to strengthen the counties, which is implemented by UNDP, UNICEF and UN Women together with government ministries, agencies 14 of the poorer counties&#x2019; governments, the private sector and civil society.&#xA0; The program is broad and diverse.&#xA0; Moreover, in March-September 2020, it was agreed that the program would implement additional measures to deal with the COVID-19 emergency.&#xA0; Generally the program has been implemented close to plan, despite the difficulties caused by the pandemic. &#xA0; Output 1.1: Government has strengthened policy, legal and institutional mechanisms for coordinated, inclusive and effective service delivery *The Inter-Governmental Relations Technical Committee developed key reference material for counties and the national government on the implementation of devolved governance in Kenya. *Four county governments developed plans to implement achieve the Sustainable Development Goals. *The Frontier Counties Development Council Regional Economic Bloc was established. *The draft Model County Gender Policy stimulated review of the current status of gender balance in the counties based on the findings of the gender audit conducted in 2018. *The programme developed and rolled out public finance management frameworks and followed up on policy issues affecting planning and budgeting for children, youth and women. Fourteen child protection working groups (one per programme county) were established to plan and implement various child protection interventions and strategies. *The programme developed county budget briefs with recommendations on the inclusion of women, children and youth priorities in county budget work. All 47 counties included some key recommendations in their 2020/2021 budgets. *The programme developed a guide for county governments on care for children in the streets and residential care. Three counties are using the guide to implement alternative care programmes. *The programme helped finalize the guidelines for County Annual Development Plans and three counties finalized their plans. *The programme helped develop subsidiary legislation on the County Governments Act 2012 and the Intergovernmental Relations Act 2012, which should enhance county service delivery and strengthen intergovernmental relations. &#xA0; Output 1.2: Public finance management institutions have strengthened processes and systems for equitable, efficient and accountable service delivery *All the 47 county governments formed County Budget and Economic Forums, where representatives for civil society and underrepresented groups could discuss county budget issues.&#xA0; These forums were involved in the budgeting process to varying degrees in different counties. *The Controller of Budget commenced the automation of a budget reporting system, which will accelerate the release of funds to spending units and enable more analytical and enhance accountability and public access to finance information. *Counties may generate &#x201C;own source revenue&#x201D; from property rates, entertainment taxes, levies, user fees and other charges. Seven joint programme counties were among the 13 counties nationally that recorded increase in Own Source Revenue in FY 19/20, despite COVID-19 challenges. *The programme supported a new standard chart of accounts for use by county governments in the planning/budgeting process. The standard was finalized and is awaiting approval by the Cabinet and roll-out. *The programme helped undertake a Tax Administration Diagnostic Assessment of three counties, which can improve own source income in these counties. &#xA0; Output 1.3: County level institutions have strengthened capacity for evidence-based planning, budgeting, implementation, monitoring and evaluation for accountable service delivery *At the beginning of the previous devolution programme in 2014/2015, none of the focus counites had a performance management system. During the past year, nine counties signed performance contracts for 2020/21 financial years, and three more are in advanced stage of signing the Performance Contracts. *The programme enhanced adoption of county integrated monitoring and evaluation system in one program county. The programme also worked with Kenya National Bureau of Statistics to produce county inequality and employment reports, to plan initiatives for social inclusion and employment. An analysis of inequality in Kenya is on-going. *The programme supported regular infographics for on-going emergencies (COVID-19, floods, food insecurity and refugee crisis) for 14 arid and semi-arid counties, improving disaster risk management. The programme also supported development of county disaster risk profiles in 11 counties. &#xA0; Output 1.4: People in Kenya have capacity to engage, deepen accountability and transparency in devolution, especially women, youth and persons with disability *The programme improved the publicizing of seven county budget documents. *The programme provided developing the capacity and networking of 89 youth and women agribusiness small and micro enterprises. Thirty-two companies j0ined the Women Empowerment Programmes to support women growing their businesses. &#xA0; Joint Devolution Programme Support to COVID-19 Response *The programme improved public awareness of COVID-19, reaching over 99% of the population. The programme deployed 17 tele-counsellors to provide psychosocial support to vulnerable groups. The programme reached more than 20 million people through TV, 23 million people through local-language radios and 202,050 people through SMS text messages with targeted messaging on COVID-19. Through Hotline 1195, 2,601 survivors of gender-based violence were connected to access essential services. *The programme procured and distributed 9,898 full Personnel Protective Equipment (PPE) kits, 3,038 face masks, 490 bottles of sanitizers and 3,626 packets of gloves to 14 counties. *The programme facilitated cash transfers to 3,000 urban vulnerable households and 5,800 poor households in five counties. *The programme deployed 50 UN volunteers to work in 14 counties as COVID-19 responders. This resulted in mass testing of 214,550 people, COVID-19 surveillance in 70 wards, and care of 3,500 patients in isolation centres, among other things. *The programme provided technical assistance to develop a strategy to help counties to build back better, strengthen their crisis and disaster response, and revitalize economies following the pandemic. *The programme strengthened participation of women, youth, and people with disabilities in County Emergency Response Committees from 14 counties.&#xA0; The programme supported the government in implementing a national COVID-19 recovery framework. &#xA0; Source: The annual report, UNDP, UN Women and UNICEF, &#x201C;Consolidating Gains and Deepening Devolution in Kenya: Programme Annual Progress Report: January 1 &#x2013; December 31, 2020,&#x201D; was submitted on March 30, 2021.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11331" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
