<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-sy" dstore:index="130" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12850A0101-SYR-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Etana Citizens Action Network II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Etana Citizens Action Network II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
St&#xF6;det genom den syriska organisationen Etana syftar till att st&#xE4;rka och f&#xF6;ra samman lokala ledare och civila samh&#xE4;llsaktivister i Syrien och &#xE5;teruppbygga f&#xF6;rtroendet mellan olika grupper i s&#xF6;dra Syrien och Damaskus. Genom dialogen ska ocks&#xE5; samh&#xE4;llsutvecklingen lokalt st&#xE4;rkas och p&#xE5; sikt bidra till en fredlig och demokratisk utveckling. Etanas m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r ocks&#xE5; att arbeta med analys av konfliktens utveckling och h&#xE5;lla internationella och syriska beslutsfattare v&#xE4;linformerade f&#xF6;r att kunna fatta b&#xE4;ttre beslut.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The support through the Syrian organisation Etana aims at supporting local leaders and civil society activists in Syria to connect and to be empowered to maintain some local autonomy in the management of their communities&#x2019; affairs and decision-making. The purpose of Etana&apos;s activities is also to support local leaders and civil society activists in Syria to rebuild confidence between different sectarian communities in their regions. Etana&apos;s goal is also to keep international and Syrian decision-makers well-informed in order to be better decision-makers and pro-actively support the work of Syrian activists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective or Etana&apos;s &quot;Vision for change&quot; as expressed in the Etana&apos;s Strategic Framework is that a peaceful, inclusive future for Syria is possible when citizens, communities, and activists from different backgrounds are connected together and equipped with accurate information to drive positive local-level change that can one day transform into systemic change.
Theory of Change
If networks of Syrian activists, leaders, civil society, and local communities are well-connected and well-informed, they can effectively work towards building peaceful, inclusive communities. If international and Syrian decision-makers are well-informed, they can be better decision-makers and pro-actively support the work of Syrians activists, leaders, civil society, and local communities.
Specific Programming Objectives
Local leaders and civil society activists in Syria are connected and empowered to maintain some local autonomy in the management of their communities&#x2019; affairs and decision-making.
Local leaders and civil society activists in Syria are able rebuild confidence between different sectarian communities in their regions.
International and Syrian decision-makers are well-informed in order to be better decision-makers and pro-actively support the work of Syrian activists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Etana Documentation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syrian Arab Republic</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">713430.9122710116</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">163918.8231686037</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">641280.3891549128</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">434324.679414096</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">713430.9122710116</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">163918.8231686038</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">641280.3891549128</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">434324.679414096</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2031667.126944</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">713430.9122710116</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">163918.8231686037</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-28">-166252.0038654896</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-28">166251.9951789961</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">98374.5398872927</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">217162.339707048</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Peace Network&#x2019;s areas of focus are currently; accountability on the Russian-guaranteed July 2018 Settlement Agreement; the work with community grievances; working for better service provision as delivery of electricity putting pressure on the owners of the electricity companies, working with consensus&#xA0; building in communities; Advocating and acting for a peaceful approach in the demonstrations in Southwest Syria during second half of 2019. During 2019 281 meetings have been held related to local-decision making and community organizing and 51 activities were conducted between members of different sectarian communities. Etana reports on women&#x2019;s participation still being low but approaching target of 10 percent participation. The level was six percent for the community organizing meetings and three percent for the meetings with sectarian communities. The Peace Network regularly meets with communities throughout the south-west to understand the status of provision and service needs throughout the region. Overall, the lack of improvement in services after the regime&#x2019;s takeover was evident, as well as the increasing difficulties communities faced with the plummeting value of the Syrian pound and price inflation of basic commodities.&#xA0;The meetings were often successful in facilitating agreement and consensus between various community stakeholders over how to deal with the regime&#x2019;s aggressions.Representatives from the Peace Network continued efforts in meeting with the Russians and the regime. This may have lead to the redress of specific issues, although far from resulting in any change of the regime&#x2019;s or the Russia&#x2019;s behavior in the South West. The Peace Network also met with INGOs, including the UN and WFP, closer to the latter half of 2019, during their field visits, especially to Busra Al-Sham, to outline the economic conditions and needs in the south-west to an international WFP representative. They also met with Syrian Arab Red Crescent representatives on multiple occasions, as mainly the regime-sanctioned SARC distributed humanitarian aid on occasion following the regime&#x2019;s takeover. The Peace Network has helped organize the emerging protests in South Syria during fall 2019, both messaging and logistics, reiterating throughout that it was of utmost importance that any local civic actions remain peaceful. Peaceful community actions have proved to be what the regime fears the most, whereas any sort of violent escalation makes it easy for the regime to respond in turn with violence and use its tried and true narrative of &#x201C;fighting terrorism.&#x201D; During COVID-19 the peace Network has played a particular role in prevention and planning within communities, while themselves taking the noted public health precautions to take of themselves and prevent transmission as much as possible. Communities are increasingly relying on former opposition local councils to manage the local response to COVID-19 due to the regime&apos;s inability/unwillingness to do so. This demonstrates that Peace Network is playing a crucial role in coordinating the reactivation of the local councils and local committees throughout communities and guiding their emergency response strategies. Challenges for the Peace Network The Peace network&#x2019;s meetings with the INGOs were also often attended by Russian and regime officials, which inevitably created an environment of self-censorship limiting the candidness with which the Peace Network and civilians could candidly speak about the situation and who is responsible for creating it, including deliberate obstacles communities face from the regime when it comes to issues of limiting access or deprivation of services. Moreover, in spite of SARC&#x2019;s agreement to provide medical, environmental and humanitarian aid &#x2013; as committed by the regime during the settlement agreement &#x2013; other than primarily the distribution of food parcels, which dwindled significantly over time, little other assistance was provided to the south-west. As noted already in the low number of women participating in the meeting, a challenge has been considerably diminished space for women to engage in their communities as they had done when the south-west was under opposition control. Instead, concerns about every one&apos;s safety, but especially women while moving around the many regime checkpoints, became a major deterrent to their involvement. Gender focus has shifted to the Peace Network focusing on the specific regime policies targeting women or impacting them. The Peace Network has lobbied the regime to stop its policy of calling women who were residents of south-west Syria to Damascus for interrogation, putting them at greater risk for being arbitrarily arrested by any one of the checkpoints along the way, as well as leaving them vulnerable to detention and torture away from the social protection provided by their communities The work with providing international community advocacy reporting has created a now more widely accepted narrative of what regime rehabilitation of a formerly-opposition controlled areas looks like. Etana&#x2019;s reporting has also drawn particularly attention to the dire situation faced by IDPs in Rukban according to the results framework. There have been overtures of understanding and coming to terms of agreement over IDP communities returning to their homes through mediation and negotiations, some of which the Russians have had an active interest in and thus, helped support. Research has been strengthened during the first phase of the new renewed support and forms the second component. This is a spin-off effect of Etana&#x2019;s network stemming from all parts of Syria, including the Peace Network. Until December 31, 2019 the research department produced almost 50 reports. The reporting period covering fall 2018 through the end of 2019, was formative as it became clearer that false narratives, misassumptions, and misconstrued information were filling the information voids created by the scale back in cross-border humanitarian and stabilization programming when the regime took over in South Syria 2018 and 2019. Detailed understanding of the contexts, actors, relationships and agendas in the different geographies of controls is a mandatory requirement for designing programming in development and humanitarian aid as well as developing and structuring negotiation and mediation processes, and drawing policies for an array of international donors and diplomatic stakeholders. Etana&#x2019;s reporting and analyzing trends and dynamics across the different areas of control in Syria, sought to meet this need in order to drive decision-making based on triangulated facts on-the-ground. In order to ensure that Etana&#x2019;s reporting was engaged with and to help facilitate the information&#x2019;s digestion by generally time-strained diplomats and decision-makers, Etana regularly conducted closed door briefings to focus on the main messages of research outputs, and engage in discussions and advocacy on what could be done, and what these individual components meant for Syria overall.&#xA0; Advocacy is the third component of Etana&apos;s work. Until December 31, 2019 Etana also produced 64 briefings. The briefings and advocacy meetings aims both at facilitating information exchanges between diplomats from different countries who meet together as a group to explicitly counter rumors or false narratives being circulated, as well as to help catch up new diplomats working on Syria on the background and context on the history and actors of an incredibly complex conflict. Perhaps one of the most significant impacts of Etana&#x2019;s reporting on the situation in Syria, is that it helped counter any assertions that it was safe for refugees to return to Bashar al Assad&#x2019;s Syria, a narrative that Russia and right-wing political streams in Europe pushed in late 2018, to the detriment of refugee and human rights. Advocacy work has focused mainly the US, EU, UN and UK as key players in negotiations with Russia and Syria. The Special Envoy&#x2019;s Syria team, both in Geneva and New York, in addition to providing them with remotely conducted briefings have been focus for advocacy work. In addition, Etana&#x2019;s reporting and staff were cited in numerous prominent news media and think tank publications, including the International Crisis Group, the Middle East Institute, European Institute of Peace, Foreign Policy, Reuters, United States Institute of Peace, Financial Times, Foreign Affairs and Asharq Al-Aswat, on an array of issues, such as the threats to refugee return, the dire conditions in East Ghouta, the regime&#x2019;s siege on Rukban, the regime&#x2019;s war profiteers and crony businessmen, and regional complexities around the Druze community in Syria.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="12850" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1110401" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3210000000.0" strategy-end-date="2023-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Syria Crisis 2016-2023</title>
    <titleSV>Syrienkrisstrategin 2016-2023</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
