<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-et" dstore:index="230" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12853A0101-ETH-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 PMU (2018-2022) Peace building and trauma</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 PMU fredsbyggande och trauma, 2018-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
M&#xE5;let med insatsen &#xE4;r att individer, grupper i civilsamh&#xE4;llet, kyrkor och institutioner bidrar till f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad social samexistens genom att p&#xE5; ett fredligt s&#xE4;tt lyfta bekymmer hos gruppen.  
Det huvudsakliga syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r:
&#x2022;	Fr&#xE4;mjande av fredlig samexistens, &#xF6;msesidigt f&#xF6;rtroende, och icke-v&#xE5;ldsamma medel f&#xF6;r konfliktl&#xF6;sning (detta inkluderar f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndrade attityder mot varandra genom att jobba med historiska h&#xE4;ndelser och trauman, och att f&#xE5; f&#xE4;rdigheter f&#xF6;r att l&#xF6;sa konflikter fredligt). 
&#x2022;	Att fr&#xE4;mja fredliga s&#xE4;tt att uttrycka sitt missn&#xF6;je p&#xE5;, och kr&#xE4;va sina r&#xE4;ttigheter genom att uttrycka sina &#xE5;sikter p&#xE5; ett konstruktivt vis.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The goal of the intervention is for individuals, CS groups, churches and institutions to contribute to improved social co-existence and to peacefully raising the social concerns of target groups. 
The main objectives of the intervention are: 
&#x2022; Promoting peaceful co-existence and mutual trust, and promoting nonviolent means for Conflict Resolution (this includes changing the attitudes towards the other, dealing with historical grievances and trauma, and gaining the skills to resolve conflicts peacefully)
&#x2022; Promoting peaceful means for the communities to express their grievance and demand their rights through using their Voice constructively</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the intervention is stated as follows:&#xA0; &quot;Individuals, CS groups, churches and institutions contribute to improved social co-existence and to peacefully raising the social concerns of target groups.
Two objectives are put forward:&#xA0;
Objectives 1: Promoting peaceful co-existence and mutual trust, and promoting nonviolent means for Conflict Resolution (this includes changing the attitudes towards the other, dealing with historical grievances and trauma, and gaining the skills to resolve conflicts peacefully)
Objective 2: Promoting peaceful means for the communities to express their grievance and demand their rights through using their Voice constructively.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PMU Interlife</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">259237.5430252886</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">259237.5430252884</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1022680.19884</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">172604.2529687932</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-28">247360.2120590248</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">11877.3309662638</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/ethiopia/12853_GrantAgreementbetweenSida&amp;PMU.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/ethiopia/12853_12853DecisiononContributionB2018-48(2).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved is presented in the annual report for 2020, which is for the new programme officer to follow up on, but following are examples of achievements, which are also presented in the Conclusion of Performance for 2020.&#xA0; Whereas the first year (2019) of the project focussed on Outcome 1, where all planned activities for that period was implemented, the second year (2020) delivered on all three outcomes.&#xA0; One of the main outputs of 2020 is the Training of Trainers (ToTs) sessions that have taken place in all five project zones, reaching more than 150 change agents in local churches and communities. The ToTs have built on the Peace building manual that was produced during the first project year. Another achievement is the Trauma recovery manual, which have&#xA0;been produced and written tailor-made for training of lay councillors in trauma recovery in a Christian setting. This manual will be utilized for ToTs during the third project year. Examples of achievements under each outcome:&#xA0; Outcome 1: Improved capacities of the evangelical churces to respond to peace needs in their communitites and to address ethnocientrism in churches and society.&#xA0; - National level peace conference conducted in March 2020. Particpants included ECFE regional structures, community gatekeepers, denomination leaders and Ministry of Peace. Exampel of direct result from the conference was f ex an initiative by one participant to organise a training on conflict resolution in Bule Hora, Guji.&#xA0; - A TV production on &quot;role of women in Peace buidling&quot; was realised and aired on Walt TV.&#xA0; - Gate keepers&apos; conferences with 150 participants in 5 zones; Bench Sheko in SNNP, West Guji and Shashamane in West Guji in Oromia. To a large extent, the conferences reach out especially to youth.&#xA0; - Training of Trainers (ToT) of local peace builders. A total of 154 trainers took part in the ToTs that was based on the peace manual developed during year 1 of the project. The trainings include that each trainer develop their own action plan to reach out to their respective communitites. To a large extent, the ToTs reach out especially to youth.&#xA0; - Development of a&#xA0;manual for trauma counseling, which will be the foundation for Training of trainers in trauma recovery during the remaining project years. &#xA0; Outcome 2: Women church leaders and women in communities are active in peace building, conflict resolution and trauma healing.&#xA0; PMU reports that it has been a challenge to involve a larger number of women in the project activities because of traditional structures and misconceptions. Work still remains to raise various stakeholders&#x2019; awareness and to enhance women&apos;s participation, but an encouraging sign of improvement is noted. - The TV production on &quot;role of women in Peace buidling&quot; mentioned above has put the issue on the agenda and triggered discussions on peace and the importance to involve women in peace work. -&#xA0;The most important goal is to include women in the regular work for peace and dialogue and not building parallel structures. However, the a few activities directly addressed women&#x2019;s participation and gender equality in peace building. One of these interventions is the &#x201C;Gender equality and the role of women in peace building&#x201D; seminar that was carried out in each of the project target zones with a total of 151 participants, with the aim to create awareness on gender equality with traditional and religious perspectives. At the end of those seminars 5-7 local female leaders where recruited. &#xA0; Outcome 3: Evangelican churches strengthened to engage with stakeholders to advocate for peace in the communitites. - Three project&#x2019;s advisory committee (AC) meetings have been conducted during 2020.&#xA0;The AC is essential to both firmly establish the project in the ECFE member churches, and to receive advice from the representatives. - Capacity development of implemnenting partners through trainings in&#xA0;peace building and conflict sensitivity;&#xA0;outcome harvesting for reporting; and&#xA0;project management. &#xA0; Some unexpected results include:&#xA0; - A taskforce established following the Gatekeepers&apos; conference in Bench Sheko zone. The taskforce&#xA0;has assessed the prevailing conflicts in the Bench Sheko zone, mapped the conflict zones, and developed an action plan with the budget. The Bench Sheko Zone Administration has accepted the Strategic/action plan with slight modification and promised to fund some of the activities. -&#xA0;A taskforce established following the conference in Shambu, Horo Guduru, with the main aim to periodically gather to discuss peace and security issues in their area and working with government agents to develop solutions. -&#xA0;ECFE was given the opportunity to, in collaboration with Ahadu Radio and Television, organize a panel discussion on the topic of Youth and Peace, which was broadcasted live on radio, with a condensed version aired on Ahadu Television. &#xA0; Challenges and major events during 2020 *&#xA0;The COVID-19 pandemic&#xA0;presented its first case in Ethiopia in March 2020, and in early April the Federal government declared a state of emergency. As for most partners in the country, the effects of the pandemic and the restrictions on such things as travel and meetings, posed major challenges on the programme.PMU, in consultation with the programme officer at the embassy, showed flexibility in adapting activities to ensure continued implementation; meetings and trainings were f ex conducted in larger halls and with relevant C19 prevention.&#xA0;In addition, PMU added COVID-19 mitigation measures like distributing hand-washing kits and information material in the areas of implementaiton, which was positively received and proved to help in creating trust by the communities.&#xA0; *&#xA0;Increasing violence and tensions&#xA0;in most part of Ethiopia has affected the project, mainly by the violence in Oromia region since three of the project implementation areas are found there. The most serious of these events took place in June 29 when a famous Oromo singer activist was assassinated. Following the death of the artist, youth in almost all parts of the Oromia region began to protest, and several hundred people were killed. Another project area where large scale violence has broken out is Guraferda in Bench Sheko zone in SNNP region.Some activities have been slightly postponed due to sudden violent outbreaks in project areas. The vast church network of our implementing partner ECFE has proven to be an asset when navigating in violent areas and for gathering necessary information to take relevant security precautions. * Altough the project is not implemented in Tigray, PMU notes that also&#xA0;the war in Tigray&#xA0;that started early November 2020 pose a risk and potential challenge to the project, due to the growing uncertainty in the country.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="12853" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1440000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Ethiopia 2016-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Etiopien 2016-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
