<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-298" dstore:index="185" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11483A0101-AFR-32182</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Grand Challenges Africa at AESA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Grand Challenges Africa at AESA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
African Academy of Sciences (AAS) har hos Sida ans&#xF6;kt om 98,4 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet Grand Challenges (GC) Africa under perioden 2018-07-01 till 2023-06-30.

GC Africa &#xE4;r ett program som har m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttningen att st&#xF6;dja innovationer som ska bidra till att hitta l&#xF6;sningar f&#xF6;r Afrikas utmaningar med att n&#xE5; de Globala m&#xE5;len f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling. Det grundl&#xE4;ggande konceptet bakom alla GC program &#xE4;r finansiering av innovativa id&#xE9;er riktade mot specifika fr&#xE5;gest&#xE4;llningar utan krav p&#xE5; prelimin&#xE4;ra resultat. GC Africa placerar konceptet i ett afrikanskt sammanhang och definierar fr&#xE5;gest&#xE4;llningar/utmaningar relevanta i den afrikanska kontexten och programmet riktar sig specifikt mot afrikanska forskare verksamma vid universitet och organisationer baserade p&#xE5; den afrikanska kontinenten.

Programmet GC Africa har sin bas p&#xE5; Alliance for Accelerating Excellence in Science in Africa (AESA), ett programinitiativ grundat av AAS och organisationen New Partnership for Africa&#x2019;s Development med syftet att tackla Afrikas utmaningar inom h&#xE4;lsa och utveckling. AESA har etablerat och driver olika program f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja forskare och forskning i Africa samt utveckla akademisk ledarskap och initiativ till innovationer. Sidas avtalspartner kommer att vara AAS, en ny partnerorganisation f&#xF6;r Sida.

Den planerade totala budgeten f&#xF6;r GC Africa programmet &#xE4;r ca. 246,5 miljoner SEK (28 miljoner USD) varav ca 86,5 miljoner SEK (9,85 miljoner USD) &#xE4;r finansierade av Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, Institute Pasteur och South African Medical Research Council. AAS har en p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende satsning att hitta fler givare till programmet, bland annat ska afrikanska regeringar och filantroper f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;s att bidra. Av Sidas st&#xF6;d till GC Africa kommer ca. 65,4 miljoner SEK att vidaref&#xF6;rmedlas till forskningsprojekt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The African Academy of Sciences (AAS) has applied to Sida for funding of 98,4 million SEK to contribute to the Grand Challenges (GC) Africa program during the period 2018-07-01 until 2013-06-30.

The GC Africa program aims at supporting the creation of innovations targeting developmental challenges preventing African countries from attaining the Global Goals for Sustainable Development. The basic concept of all GC programs includes grant support to research projects responding to pre-defined challenges not requiring extensive preliminary data. GC Africa has adapted this concept to the African context and established a program open to African researcher based at African universities and institutions and addresses challenges specific to African development needs.

GC Africa is a program of the Alliance for Accelerating Science in Africa (AESA) that is a programmatic platform founded by the AAS and the organization New Partnership for Africa&apos;s Development with the aim to address Africa&apos;s health and development challenges. AESA has established and drives different programs to support researchers and research projects in Africa and to develop academic leadership and innovations. Sida will enter into agreement with the AAS, a new partner organization for Sida.

The envisaged total budget of the GC Africa program is approximately 246,5 million SEK (28 million USD), out of which 86,5 million SEK (9,85 million USD) have been contributed by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, Institute Pasteur and the South African Medical Research Council. The AAS is in the process of attracting additional funders to the program and is approaching African governments and philanthropists. Of Sida&#x2019;s support to the GC Africa program approximately 65,4 million SEK will be forwarded to research projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the intervention is to promote Africa-led scientific innovations to help countries better achieve the Sustainable Development Goals by awarding seed and full grants to the continent&#x2019;s most impressive solutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AAS/African Academy of Sciences</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technological research and development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="9.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">9.5 - Enhance scientific research, upgrade the technological capabilities of industrial sectors in all countries, in particular developing countries, including, by 2030, encouraging innovation and substantially increasing the number of research and development workers per 1&#xA0;million people and public and private research and development spending.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">9.5 - F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra forskningen och industrisektorernas tekniska kapacitet i alla l&#xE4;nder, i synnerhet utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, bland annat genom att till 2030 uppmuntra innovation och v&#xE4;sentligt &#xF6;ka det antal personer som arbetar med forskning och utveckling per 1 miljon m&#xE4;nniskor liksom de offentliga och privata utgifterna f&#xF6;r forskning och utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">9.b - St&#xF6;dja inhemsk teknikutveckling, forskning och innovation i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, inklusive genom att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla en gynnsam policymilj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r exempelvis industriell diversifiering och f&#xF6;r&#xE4;dling av r&#xE5;varor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">9.b - Support domestic technology development, research and innovation in developing countries, including by ensuring a conducive policy environment for, inter alia, industrial diversification and value addition to commodities.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2256512.933812022</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">36264.6601592656</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">529031.9988707559</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4343246.79414096</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3643100.100980488</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2256512.933812023</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">36264.6601592649</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">529031.9988707593</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4343246.794140961</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3643100.1009804877</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">11320192.396207</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">212878.5786615115</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">2043634.3551505108</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">36264.6601592656</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-28">529031.9988707559</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/forsk/11483_022669-18AvtalmellanSidaochAfricanAcademyofSciences(AAS),GrandChallengesAfrica2287496_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Avtal insats Grand Challenges Africa</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/forsk/11483_020499-18GrandChallengeAfricaatAESA,Beslutominsats2273371_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats Grand Challenges Africa at AESA</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For 2019, Grand Challenges (GC) Africa, a programme of the Alliance for Accelerating Science in Africa (AESA) at the African Academy of Science&#xA0;(AAS),&#xA0;overall&#xA0;reported a total of three new calls for research and innovation grants, progression of work in ongoing&#xA0;grants as well as&#xA0;organization of meetings, workshops and research prioritization exercises. GC Africa has adopted a 3-phase approach supporting Africa-led scientific innovations at proof-of-concept (phase I), transition-to-scale (phase II) and scaling stages (phase III). While projects at the proof-of-concept stage can apply for seed capital to make early, real-world assessments&#xA0;of technical, organisational and financial viability by piloting an innovation in a LMIC context, catalytic capital at the transition-to-scale stage will facilitate business model development and support innovations that have demonstrated success at small scale. At the final scaling stage, growth capital will support widerspread replication and adaptation of an innovation across large geographies and populations for transformational impact. In the GC Africa programme, Sida is supporting calls for proof-of-concept (phase I) and transition-to-scale (phase II) funding. In September 2018,&#xA0;the GC Africa programme had announced its first proof-of-concept call&#xA0;in partnership with Sida.&#xA0;The call Innovation for WASH (water, sanitation and hygiene) in urban settings&#xA0;was part of a global GC call initiative in partnership with Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation (BMGF) and UNICEF&#xA0;seeking for technology-based solutions that promote&#xA0;access to essential resources and services, such as clean water and sanitation, and can make a difference in reducing morbidity and mortality to promote healthy, safe, and productive lives. The WASH call was designed to respond to on-the-ground needs of women, children, and families living in challenging urban environments.&#xA0;The call received a good response from African scientists and research institutions with 166 grant proposals submitted to the GC Africa programme. After initial triage in early 2019, 48&#xA0;proposals were selected for expert review&#xA0;and&#xA0;each proposal was&#xA0;assessed&#xA0;by three independent&#xA0;external reviewers. Finally, seven projects were selected for funding by a decision committee consisting of representatives from all&#xA0;partners involved in the call. Funded projects are based in&#xA0;Botswana, Congo, Ghana, Kenya, South Africa, Uganda and Zimbabwe. A major milestone in 2019 was the announcement of the first round of GC Africa transition-to-scale grants. In this call, GC Africa invited African innovators that had received proof-of-concept grants in previous calls financed&#xA0;by partners&#xA0;in the GC family, including GC Explorations by BMGF, GC Canada, USAID Centre for Development Innovation,&#xA0;GC South Africa and GC Africa,&#xA0;to submit proposals for transition-to-scale support. The call received 106 applications of which 55 went into a review and curation process. Applications were evaluated by an independent panel of scientific and business experts, and applicants invited to refine their innovations, scaling strategies and business plans and to prepare&#xA0;detailed budgets with projections and global access strategies. Nine innovative projects based in Kenya, Nigeria, South Africa and Tanzania were finally selected for grant support by Sida, BMGF, GC Canada and South Africa Medical Research Council (SAMRC). The GC Africa programme has continued its work to build a so-called e-Marketplace for innovators in Africa.&#xA0;The e-Marketplace is thought as a virtual e-based community of practice where innovators, funders, governments, innovation incubators and other partners can have a secluded, safe and confidential space to share ideas, exchange information, support each other and plan for the success of innovations. To realize the idea, the GC Africa innovation Network (GCAiN, http://gcain.africa) was established and an interactive web-app and mobile application&#xA0;developed and recently launched. The app allows innovators and innovation partners to register profiles in the GCAiN&#xA0;and easily connect with&#xA0;each other. Major&#xA0;collaborators and&#xA0;funders&#xA0;of&#xA0;the GC Africa programme include BMGF, GC Canada, Sida, SAMRC, USAID and&#xA0;Wellcome&#xA0;Trust. The AAS&#xA0;is continuing its efforts&#xA0;to broaden the funding base of the programme and has recently partnered with the&#xA0;German Federal Ministry of Education and Research and in 2019 launched a call for proposals focusing&#xA0;on Maternal and Neonatal Health Innovations. Work is ongoing to further engage&#xA0;African governments in&#xA0;innovation efforts and&#xA0;consider the launch of national GC programmes.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="11483" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1140102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <title>Research cooperation 2015-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Forskningssamarbete 2015-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
