<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-zm" dstore:index="128" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11597A0102-ZMB-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
Marie Stopes Zambia has applied to Sida for funding of 40 Million SEK to carry out the Scaling Up Access to Comprehensive SRHR for Women and Girls in Zambia during the period 2018-2021. The contribution aims to increase equitable access and utilization of sexual and reproductive health services. MSZ works in close collaboration with local and central health authorities to provide modern family planning services, information and education about SRHR and with provision of drugs, counselling and access to safe abortion services. A clear focus is to provide quality services to young women and girls in both urban and rural settings, in particular poor women and girls and other disenfranchised and hard to reach populations such as disabled and hiv infected women and adolescents.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Marie Stopes Zambia har inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan om st&#xF6;d om 40 MSEK till att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet Scaling Up Access to Comprehensive SRHR for Women and Girls in Zambia under perioden 2018-2021. Insatsen syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra tillg&#xE5;ngen och utnyttjandet av h&#xE4;lso- och sjukv&#xE5;rdstj&#xE4;nster inom ramen f&#xF6;r sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa. MSZ arbetar brett med att bist&#xE5; de zambiska h&#xE4;lsomyndigheterna med att erbjuda kvinnor och flickor moderna preventivmedel, information och utbildning om sex, samlevnad och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa samt med tillg&#xE5;ng till mediciner, r&#xE5;dgivning och service kring s&#xE4;kra aborter. Ett tydligt fokus &#xE4;r p&#xE5; fattiga kvinnor, ungdomar och unga kvinnor b&#xE5;de p&#xE5; landsbygden och i urbana omr&#xE5;den och samt andra marginaliserade grupper som t ex funktionshindrade och hiv-smittade.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia, MSZ, has a theory of change with an ultimate goal to improve women&apos;s health and reduce maternal mortality in Zambia. This is expected to be achieved through two main results: 1) Increased use of contraception and access to safe abortions among poor and marginalized women and girls; and 2) Enhanced SRHR policies and successful implementation of these. MSZ has formulated three results to be achieved within the framework of this specific intervention: 1. Increased access to modern high-quality contraceptives and safe abortion services, especially for marginalized women and adolescents. 2. Increased awareness of contraception and safe abortion through education and information to decision-makers at community level; to poor and marginalized women and young people. 3. Enhanced advocacy work to create an improved legal and policy environment for contraception and access to safe abortion.
MSZ programme activities thus include direct healthcare services in close collaboration with central and local health authorities, support to MSZ&apos;s health clinics and social marketing in local markets to ensure that medical abortion drugs are available at pharmacies. MSZ will also strengthen its partnership with the government through the establishment of contracts to provide specific services on behalf of the government, to further develop a digital communication model to facilitate the concrete availability of safe abortion, and to cooperate with the Ministry of Health&#x2019;s health clinics to provide youth-friendly SRHR services for young people. MSZ will also participate in advocacy work and conduct dialogue for political change in the area of access to safe abortion and for contraceptives and other reproductive health commodities. MSZ will engage in strategic partnerships for community engagement with local partners. The Sida-funded initiative is expected to ensure that 102,500 women and girls access SRHR services, 14,900 medical abortion pills are distributed and 16,000 safe abortions can be performed. The effort is estimated to prevent 455 maternal deaths, 48,000 unintended pregnancies and 27,700 unsafe abortions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSI Reproductive Choices</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 - By 2030, reduce the global maternal mortality ratio to less than 70 per 100,000 live births.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.1 - Till 2030 minska m&#xF6;drad&#xF6;dligheten i v&#xE4;rlden till mindre &#xE4;n 70 d&#xF6;dsfall per 100 000 f&#xF6;rlossningar med levande barn.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1042379.2305938305</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">912081.8267696016</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">3406057.258584</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/11597-decision.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/11597-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie Stopes Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The year 2019 is the second implementation year of the Sida-funded Marie Stopes programme and it has been a year with good results and positive progress, despite the financial crisis in Zambia resulting in increased costs for service provision, including fuel and transport. MSZ reached out to 59 949 women with contraceptive services across 20 districts and 357 sites in four provinces, against a target of 51 934. Out of the above number, 13 percent of the clients were adolescent clients between the ages of 10 and 19 and 28 percent young women between 20 and 24, hence 41 percent of all clients are below 25 years of age. In total MSZ managed to provide 69 308 services during the year.&#xA0; Key results for the year include: 1) 59 949 women were provided with family planning services through outreach services and static services at the MSZ clinic and youth centre of which 13 percent were teenagers.&#xA0; 2) 79 percent of the family planning services provided by MSZ were long-acting and permanent contraceptive methods, against &quot;only&quot; 21 percent of short-term methods, which are the most popular methods among Zambian women as a whole.&#xA0; 3) 25 percent of the women receiving long acting methods opted for the IUCD, the intra-uterine copper device, which is three times higher than in 2018 and hence a record high rate of this particular contraception. 73 percent of women preferred the implant, and 2 percent the tubal ligation.&#xA0; 4) 19 506 safe abortion services were delivered against a target of 12 000 and compared to 9 473 in 2018. 5) 35 health workers in the public health facilities were trained by MSZ in the National Comprehensive Abortion Care guidelines, in partnership with Ministry of Health, Ipas, CHAI and Zambian Medical Association. The results from the various service models provided by Marie Stopes in 2019 included the following: - Three outreach teams operate in Northern, Eastern and Copperbelt provinces and provide services in rural, hard to reach areas. The teams provided 58 414 FP services for women, adolescents and young women. In 2019, MSZ introduced a new model of service delivery splitting the outreach teams into smaller teams thereby enabling them to spread their services and reach more rural clients. The teams work within the public health facilities automatically transferring skills to health workers. A positive finding is that many rural women, that are traditionally seen to be preferring short term contraceptives, are moving over to long-term methods. This is particularly remarkable as 2019 saw a massive national (global) acute shortage of Jadelle, the most popular implant, and yet the increase in long-term choices was significant. - The two stationary clinics Marie Stopes family centre and the Diva youth centre located in Kabulonga, Lusaka, provided 7 504 services. The Family Centre recruited an obstetrician/gynecology specialist doctor, a pharmacist and expanded on its laboratory capacity. - The MS Ladies operating as community nurses in the high density urban and peri-urban slum areas of Lusaka, Ndola and Kitwe, provided 10 520 services, which is an increase with 54 percent from 2018. The community nurses work closely with the peri-urban highly congested public health facilities. Of the total family planning services provided, 83 percent were long term methods.&#xA0; - The strong focus on attracting youth has also shown positive results and innovative strategies as MSZ worked with the Ministry of Education to provide contraceptive services to tertiary learning institutions through the use of a mobile caravan. The mobile caravans are used to service adolescents in the urban and per-urban slums together with the MS Ladies and services 30 to 40 youth per day. In 2019, the caravan recorded an average of 562 adolescent clients per month compared to 136 compared to the static Diva centre. The stationary clinics are the only MSZ sites where safe abortion can be provided. In 2019, there were 321 abortions recorded and 103 cervical cancer testing and treatment services along with 703 lab tests and 397 hiv tests. Due to its positive results, the caravan model is being replicated also by UNICEF and MOH in other parts of urban settings.&#xA0; - MSZ partnered with Restless Development to expand on the number of staff working on the 5600 Toll-free contact centre and the caravan mobile outreach activities. In 2019, MSZ contact centre answered more than 18 000 calls of which 17 percent were adolescents, many of whom were referred to the nearest youth-friendly health service or safe abortion provider, including the MSZ clinic in Lusaka. About 12 percent of the calls were abortion-related. - Under the commercial sales, a total of 38 912 medical abortion drug units were distributed across pharmacies and private and public clinics in 9 provinces. It should be noted that MSZ captures the number of tablets that have been distributed or sold to pharmacies, and is unable to follow up if the tablets were in fact used.&#xA0; - MSZ conducted capacity-building for 12 public health providers in contraceptive service delivery, infection prevention, medical emergency management and values clarification and attitude training (VCAT) for abortion, to enhance quality of care. Another 15 providers were trained in providing the newly introduced self-injecting short term contraception, and 22 government providers were trained in comprehensive abortion care in Lusaka province. Following this training, six provinces have requested similar trainings to be conducted in 2020. MSZ works with the development of a standardized training curriculum for health providers in Zambia on provision of safe abortion together with Ipas, CHAI, Options and Zambian Medical Association.&#xA0; - MSZ started working more with disabled persons as a particularly marginalized group in Zambia with regards to service access. An internal disability policy was completed with a strong focus on young people as they are often double marginalized. The policy will guide the work of MSZ in the years to come. &#xA0; - Financially, MSZ underspent in 2019 with expenditures amounting to 73 percent of the planned allocation. There were however higher than planned expenditures under budget lines for fuel and transport. The loadshedding during the year was costly for MSZ that had to run generators to maintain the cold chain of vaccines and other supplies.&#xA0; In sum, the year has shown remarkable progress, despite financial crisis in Zambia with increased costs for fuel, transport and maintenance of utilities and services.&#xA0; MSZ has reached good results in increasing the number of women actively choosing a long-term contraceptive method which will reduce the number of unintended and unwanted pregnancies, unsafe abortions and risks related to multiple, frequent pregnancies and deliveries. The conscious ambition to reach out to adolescents is bearing fruit with the use of mobile caravans in the peri-urban slums for the poor and marginalized youth and in the universities for the sexually active at-risk young women.&#xA0; In the slums of Lusaka and Copperbelt, the caravan model attracts 30 to 40 adolescent clients per day compared to the Diva centre that serves 10 per day. In total (going beyond the Sida programme), 15 percent of clients in the peri-urban areas are adolescents and 32 percent are young women between 20 and 24, hence almost half of all clients are below 25. Looking at the overall number of MSZ clients across all services provided in both rural and urban settings, 13 percent being adolescents is still however too modest. The high number of adolescents reached in the urban areas is countered by a low number of youth being reached in the rural areas. The imbalance can be explained by the fact that MSZ has scaled up their outreach into the rural areas giving higher total numbers of rural women reached, but with limited reach to younger rural girls. As the Sida programme has a strong focus on outreach in rural areas, data from the programme shows that out of all the adolescents reached in the programme with contraceptive services, 77,5 percent are in fact rural youth, clearly showing that Sida&apos;s support to MSZ manages to reach these adolescents, albeit in limited real numbers.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="11597" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2250000000.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Zambia 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
