<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-998e" dstore:index="2435" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105050101-GGG-43030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat 2020-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN-Habitat 2020-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a new 4-year cooperation with the United Nations Human Settlement Programme. UN-Habitat was established in 1978 as an outcome of the First UN Conference on Human Settlements and Sustainable Urban Development (Habitat I) in 1976. It is mandated by the United Nations General Assembly to promote socially-, environmentally- and economically- sustainable towns and cities with the goal of providing adequate shelter for all. It is a member of the United Nations Sustainable
Development Group (UNSDG), a consortium of 36 UN funds, programs, specialized
agencies, departments and offices that play a role in development.

The normative-operational mandate of UN-Habitat derives from the Habitat Agenda,
adopted by the United Nations Conference on Human Settlements (Habitat II) in 1996
and renewed in 2016 (Habitat III). The twin goals of the Habitat Agenda are adequate
shelter for all and the development of sustainable human settlements in an urbanizing
world. UN-Habitat&apos;s mission is to advance sustainable urbanization as a driver of
development and peace to improve living conditions for all.

The agency is headquartered in Nairobi, Kenya, with four main regional offices covering
Africa, the Arab States, Asia and the Pacific, and Latin America and the Caribbean. UN-Habitat also has liaison and information offices in New York, Brussels, Beijing, Moscow
and Geneva and project offices in 76 countries across the world. As part of its comparative advantage, UN-Habitat is able to directly engage and sign agreements with
sub-national entities (cities, local and regional governments), not just national
governments which is the usual case for UN entities.

Through this new Program Cooperation Agreement (PCA), Sida will continue to focus its support on UN-Habitat&apos;s core programmatic mandate by aligning to the agency&apos;s 4-year Strategic Plan 2020-2024 and ongoing institutional reform initiatives. This PCA covers the period June 2020*-May 2024, has a total budget of SEK 195 million, and is proposed to be organised into 3 components where funds will be soft-earmarked as follows:

Component 1: Soft-earmarked funding to selected domains of change/subprogrammes
and result areas of the Strategic Plan 2020-2023, and the implementation of UN-Habitat&apos;s organisational reform. (70% of total budget)

These domains of change are:
1. Reduced spatial inequality and poverty in communities across the urban-rural continuum.
2. Enhanced shared prosperity for cities and regions.
3. Strengthened climate action and improved urban environment.
4. Effective urban crisis prevention and response.

Component 2: Funding to the area of land ownership and tenure rights in least-developed
countries, including post-conflict. This allocation to be managed through the Global Land Tool Network (GLTN), a program of UN-Habitat. (20% of total budget)

Component 3: Funding to UN-Habitat&apos;s COVID-response and rehabilitation strategy during June 2020 to May 2021. (10% of total budget)

Components 1 and 3 will be funded through the Swedish strategy for globally sustainable
environment, climate and oceans as well as sustainable use of natural resources, 2018-2022. Component 2 will be funded through the Swedish strategegy for global development cooperation on sustainable economic development, 2018&#x2013;2022.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN-Habitat (United Nations Human Settlements Programme) &#xE4;r FN:s organ f&#xF6;r boende, bebyggelse och h&#xE5;llbar stadsutveckling vars arbete syftar till att fr&#xE4;mja ekonomiskt, socialt och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssigt h&#xE5;llbara bost&#xE4;der, samh&#xE4;llen och st&#xE4;der. UN-Habitats vision &#xE4;r &quot;En b&#xE4;ttre livskvalitet f&#xF6;r alla i en urbaniserad v&#xE4;rld&quot;. Dess uppdrag (mission statement) &#xE4;r &quot;att fr&#xE4;mja transformativa f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar i st&#xE4;der och samh&#xE4;llen genom kunskap, policyr&#xE5;dgivning, teknisk hj&#xE4;lp och samarbete f&#xF6;r att inte l&#xE4;mna n&#xE5;gon och ingen plats utanf&#xF6;r&quot;. 

Det normativa-operativa mandatet f&#xF6;r UN-Habitat h&#xE4;rr&#xF6;r fr&#xE5;n Habitat-agendan, som antogs under FN:s konferens om bost&#xE4;der och h&#xE5;llbara samh&#xE4;llen (Habitat II) 1996 och f&#xF6;rnyades 2016 (Habitat III). I samband med Habitat III antogs ett flertal beslut som ledde till ett f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkt mandat och specialist roll f&#xF6;r UN-Habitat inom FN-systemet. I samma konferens antog medlemsl&#xE4;nderna slutdokumentet New Urban Agenda (NUA), som fokuserar p&#xE5; h&#xE5;llbar stadsutveckling inom ramen f&#xF6;r Agenda 2030, fr&#xE4;mst delm&#xE5;let SDG 11 (H&#xE5;llbara st&#xE4;der och samh&#xE4;llen). UN-Habitat &#xE4;r ansvarig f&#xF6;r stadsfr&#xE5;gor inom FN-systemet, &#xE4;r f&#xF6;rvaltare f&#xF6;r SDG-11 och fokalt organ f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av NUA som syftar till att h&#xE5;llbar stadsutveckling ska bidra till att m&#xF6;ta de utmaningar v&#xE4;rlden st&#xE5;r inf&#xF6;r som klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar, fattigdom, milj&#xF6;f&#xF6;rst&#xF6;ring, v&#xE4;xande slumomr&#xE5;den, flyktingstr&#xF6;mmar, utanf&#xF6;rskap och diskriminering i olika former. 

UN-Habitat arbetar p&#xE5; global, regional, nationell och stadsniv&#xE5;. UN-Habitat har sitt huvudkontor i Nairobi, Kenya, och totalt fyra regionala kontor som t&#xE4;cker Afrika, Arabstaterna, Asien och Latinamerika. UN-Habitat har ocks&#xE5; representantskontor i New York, Bryssel, Peking, Moskva och Gen&#xE8;ve samt projektkontor i 76 l&#xE4;nder runt om i v&#xE4;rlden. UN-Habitat &#xE4;r ett av f&#xE5; FN-organ som kan underteckna avtal med lokala och regionala myndigheter. UN-Habitat arbetar ocks&#xE5; i partnerskap med andra FN- och multilaterala organisationer som exempelvis UNDP (United Nations Development Programme), UNEP (United Nations Environment Program), UN WOMEN, UNODC (United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime), FN:s flyktingorgan UNHCR samt V&#xE4;rldsbanken.

Sida f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;r h&#xE4;rmed att st&#xF6;dja UN-Habitat med 195 MSEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2020-2023 (70 MSEK f&#xF6;r 2020, 60 MSEK f&#xF6;r 2021, 40 MSEK f&#xF6;r 2022 och 25 MSEK f&#xF6;r 2023), en &#xF6;kning med totalt SEK 41 000 000. Den strategiska planen 2020-2023 och den tillh&#xF6;rande f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringsteorin samt resultatramverket &#xE4;r de viktigaste referenserna f&#xF6;r detta Programme Cooperation Agreement (PCA), liksom grunden f&#xF6;r att rikta f&#xF6;rdelningen av Sidas medel till f&#xF6;ljande resultatomr&#xE5;den:

&quot;Sub-programme 1: Reduced spatial inequality and poverty in communities across the urban - rural continuum	
&#x2022; Increased and equal access to basic services, sustainable mobility and public space;
&#x2022; Increased and secure access to land, and adequate and affordable housing;
&#x2022; Effective settlements growth and regeneration.

Sub-programme 2: Enhanced shared prosperity of cities and regions
&#x2022; Improved spatial connectivity and productivity of cities and regions;
&#x2022; Increased and equitably distributed locally generated revenues.

Sub-programme 3: Strengthened climate action and improved urban environment	
&#x2022; Reduced greenhouse emissions and improved air quality;
&#x2022; Improved resource efficiency and protection of ecological assets;
&#x2022; Effective adaptation of communities and infrastructure to climate change.

Sub-programme 4: Effective urban crisis prevention and response	
&#x2022; Enhanced social cohesion and inclusive planning for conflict prevention and recovery;
&#x2022; Enhanced resilience of the built environment and infrastructure.&quot;
 
Denna PCA t&#xE4;cker perioden juni 2020- maj 2024 och f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s organiseras enligt f&#xF6;ljande komponenter:

Komponent 1: Mjukt &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt finansiering till de ovann&#xE4;mnda resultatomr&#xE5;dena i den strategiska planen, och f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av UN-Habitats organisationsreform. (70% av den totala budgeten)

Komponent 2: Finansiering till markfr&#xE5;gor (land ownership and tenure rights) i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nder, inklusive post-konflikt, koordinerad av UN-Habitats Global Land Tool Network (GLTN)-program. (20% av den totala budgeten)

Komponent 3: Finansiering av st&#xF6;d till UN-Habitats COVID-19 respons och rehabiliteringsstrategi under 2020. (10% av den totala budgeten)

Av det totala avtalsbeloppet kommer SEK 155 000 000 ur anslagsposten f&#xF6;r Regeringens strategi f&#xF6;r Sveriges globala utvecklingssamarbete inom h&#xE5;llbar milj&#xF6;, h&#xE5;llbart klimat och hav, samt h&#xE5;llbart nyttjande av naturresurser 2018-2022, f&#xF6;r att finansiera komponent 1 och 3. SEK 40 000 000 kommer ur anslagsposten f&#xF6;r strategin f&#xF6;r globalt utvecklingssamarbete f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar ekonomisk utveckling 2018 - 2022, f&#xF6;r att finansiera komponent 2.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of the intervention is to support the implementation of UN-Habitat&apos;s Strategic Plan for 2020-2023, which&#xA0;was approved and adopted by Member States in May 2019 during the first session of the UN-Habitat Assembly, the organization&apos;s main&#xA0;decision-making body.&#xA0;This document provides a detailed analysis of how sustainable urbanization links directly to, and helps achieve, overall sustainable development. It is also a commitment and strategy for how the agency, using its normative/operational mandate and focal point role, will contribute to Agenda 2030 and SDGs, the Paris Agreement, the Sendai framework and other global development agendas, and will accelerated progress in the implementation of the New Urban Agenda (NUA). It particularly addresses the pledge in the 2030 Agenda &quot;to leave no one behind&quot;.
The overall vision is &quot;A better quality of life for&#xA0;all in an urbanizing world&quot;.
The mission is that &quot;UN-Habitat promotes transformative change in cities and human settlements through knowledge, policy advice, technical assistance and collaborative action to leave no one and no place behind.&quot;
The overall&#xA0;strategic objective is &quot;Sustainable urbanization is advanced&#xA0;as a driver of development and peace , to improve living conditions for all.&quot;
A host of persistent and new development problems have been identified by this intervention, including extreme poverty, socioeconomic inequality, slums, social exclusion and marginalization, gender-based discrimination,&#xA0;humanitarian crises, conflict, air pollution, climate change and high unemployment, all of which are increasingly concentrated in urban areas. At the end of the intervention, UN-Habitat intends to realise the following changes:
1. Reduced spatial inequality and poverty in communities across the urban-rural continuum (Domain of Change 1) through
- Increased and equal access to basic services, sustainable mobility, and public space;&#xA0;
- Increased and secure access to land, and adequate and affordable housing; and
- Effective settlements growth and regeneration.
2. Enhanced shared prosperity for cities and regions (Domain of Change 2) through
- Improved spatial connectivity and productivity of cities and regions;
- Increased and equitably distributed locally generated revenues; and
- Expanded deployment of frontier technologies and innovations for urban development.
3. Strengthened climate action and improved urban environment (Domain of Change 3) through
- Reduced greenhouse emissions and improved air quality;
- Improved resource efficiency and protection of ecological assets; and
- Effective adaptation of communities and infrastructure to climate change.
4. Effective urban crisis prevention and response (Domain of Change 4) through
- Enhanced social cohesion and inclusive planning for conflict prevention and recovery;
- Improved living standards and inclusion of migrants, refugees, internally displaced persons and returnees through effective crisis response and recovery; and
- Enhanced resilience of the built environment and infrastructure.
The cross-cutting thematic areas are:&#xA0;Resilience and&#xA0;Safety. The social inclusion issues&#xA0;are: Human rights;&#xA0;Gender;&#xA0;Children, youth, and older persons; and Disability.
An additional organisational outcome is UN-Habitat as a global Centre of Excellence and Innovation for urbanisation issues. UN-Habitat aspires to increase its presence as a global actor in &quot;setting the global discourse and agenda on&#xA0;sustainable urban development, driving political discussion, generating specialised and cutting-edge&#xA0;knowledge, shaping technical norms, principles and standards, and acting as a multiplier in the&#xA0;exchange of knowledge, experience and best practice in getting cities and other human settlements&#xA0;right&quot;.
Working through the urban spectrum assumes that UN-Habitat will engage with, affect and impact on a very broad range of actors. UN-Habitat has what is known as Habitat Agenda Partners (HAPs) which groups stakeholders around 15 different partner constituency groups and facilitate engagement at policy, strategy, program and project levels. In a sense, all will benefit from the successful implementation of the strategic plan. However, the main stakeholders whose situation will improve for the better if the program outcomes are achieved, and who will benefit from access to norms, tools and increased capacity development are primarily: national governments,&#xA0;local and sub-national authorities, civil society organisations, grassroot organisations (including organised groups of the urban poor), and urban communities, particularly their women, children and youth.
In addition to the support to the Strategic Plan, the Sida PCA will have two more specific components:
Support to land rights and secure tenure issues, implemented through the Global Land Tool Network program
GLTN was formed by UN-Habitat and a network of partners in 2006, with seed and development funding from Sweden and Norway. The objective is to overcome the challenges and&#xA0;obstacles in delivering land tenure security at scale and to fill critical gaps in land governance and&#xA0;administration approaches, tools and systems. Today, GLTN is a UN-Habitat program that provides a dynamic multi-stakeholder alliance&#xA0;of more than 85 land institutions and actors committed to increasing access to land and tenure security for all, with a focus on the poor and women. GLTN uses an inclusive approach to the development of &#x201C;land tools&#x201D;, builds knowledge on land tenure and broader&#xA0;development outcomes, and develops the capacity of land actors to use the tools.
GLTN has a program strategy for 2018-2030 and is implementing its 3rd phase during 2019-2023. The program objective - &quot;improved tenure security&quot; - directly contributes to all domains of change in the UN-Habitat strategic plan, and specifically the outcome area on &quot;Increased and secure access to&#xA0;land and adequate and&#xA0;affordable housing&quot;. Through this PCA, Sida intends to continue to support GLTN core program activities which will help enable scaling up its work at country level. In addition to delivering improved land tenure in countries such as Zambia, Uganda, DRC, Nepal, etc., GLTN has contributed to greater consistency in the use of land tenure concepts and approaches&#xA0;by the international land community. It is contributing to monitoring 12 indicators of the SDGs related to land, land indicators of the NUA, and in pursuance of the guidance note of the UN Secretary-General on land and&#xA0;conflict.
Support to UN-Habitat&apos;s COVID-19 Response Plan
UN-Habitat recently shared its COVID-19 Response Plan with Member States and a range of partners as well as launched its COVID-19 Campaign. The response plan focuses on three main thematic areas of action: i) supporting local governments and community-driven solutions in informal settlements; ii) providing urban data mapping and knowledge for informed, evidence-based, decision-making, and iii) mitigating economic impact and initiating recovery and longer term policy change to build greater resilience. Sida assesses that UN-Habitat&apos;s planning and development approach will complement the humanitarian activities of other actors. At the moment, many humanitarian actors are unable to reach slum settlements or work with slum communities. UN-Habitat, together with its local networks, will facilitate the inclusion of slums in city-level responses.
&#xA0;
The PCA with UN-Habitat is relevant to the Swedish strategy for globally sustainable environment, climate and oceans 2018-2022. It will contribute to the specific outcome areas on &quot;Environmentally sustainable cities and communities&quot; and&#xA0;&quot;Increased access to basic social services and housing for people living in poverty in urban areas&quot;.
The PCA is also relevant to the Swedish strategy for&#xA0;global development cooperation on sustainable economic development 2018 &#x2013; 2022, specifically the outcome areas on &quot;Strengthened ownership and tenure rights for land and natural resources&quot;, &quot;Strengthened women&apos;s economic empowerment&quot;and &quot;More effective domestic resource mobilization, increased financial stability and counteracting corruption&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41120" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat/United Nations Human Settlements Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41120" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Human Settlement Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2 - By 2030, reduce at least by half the proportion of men, women and children of all ages living in poverty in all its dimensions according to national definitions.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.2 - Till 2030 minst halvera den andel m&#xE4;n, kvinnor och barn i alla &#xE5;ldrar som lever i n&#xE5;gon form av fattigdom enligt nationella definitioner.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.1 - By 2030, ensure access for all to adequate, safe and affordable housing and basic services and upgrade slums.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla tillg&#xE5;ng f&#xF6;r alla till fullgoda, s&#xE4;kra och ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomliga bost&#xE4;der och grundl&#xE4;ggande tj&#xE4;nster samt rusta upp slumomr&#xE5;den.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.2 - By 2030, provide access to safe, affordable, accessible and sustainable transport systems for all, improving road safety, notably by expanding public transport, with special attention to the needs of those in vulnerable situations, women, children, persons with disabilities and older persons.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.2 - Senast 2030 tillhandah&#xE5;lla tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kra, ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomliga, tillg&#xE4;ngliga och h&#xE5;llbara transportsystem f&#xF6;r alla. F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra trafiks&#xE4;kerheten, s&#xE4;rskilt genom att bygga ut kollektivtrafiken, med s&#xE4;rskild uppm&#xE4;rksamhet p&#xE5; behoven hos m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer, kvinnor, barn, personer med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning samt &#xE4;ldre personer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.3 - By 2030, enhance inclusive and sustainable urbanization and capacity for participatory, integrated and sustainable human settlement planning and management in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.3 - Till 2030 verka f&#xF6;r en inkluderande och h&#xE5;llbar urbanisering samt f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra kapaciteten f&#xF6;r deltagandebaserad, integrerad och h&#xE5;llbar planering och f&#xF6;rvaltning av bos&#xE4;ttningar i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.5 - By 2030, significantly reduce the number of deaths and the number of people affected and substantially decrease the direct economic losses relative to global gross domestic product caused by disasters, including water-related disasters, with a focus on protecting the poor and people in vulnerable situations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.5 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligt minska antalet d&#xF6;dsfall och antalet m&#xE4;nniskor som drabbas av katastrofer, inklusive vattenrelaterade katastrofer. &#xC4;ven tillse att de direkta ekonomiska f&#xF6;rlusterna till f&#xF6;ljd av s&#xE5;dana katastrofer, i form av l&#xE4;gre global BNP, minskar v&#xE4;sentligt. S&#xE4;rskilt fokus b&#xF6;r ligga p&#xE5; att skydda de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.6 - By 2030, reduce the adverse per capita environmental impact of cities, including by paying special attention to air quality and municipal and other waste management.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.6 - Till 2030 minska st&#xE4;dernas negativa milj&#xF6;p&#xE5;verkan per person, bland annat genom att &#xE4;gna s&#xE4;rskild uppm&#xE4;rksamhet &#xE5;t luftkvalitet samt hantering av kommunalt och annat avfall.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.b - By 2020, substantially increase the number of cities and human settlements adopting and implementing integrated policies and plans towards inclusion, resource efficiency, mitigation and adaptation to climate change, resilience to disasters, and develop and implement, in line with the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction 2015&#x2013;2030, holistic disaster risk management at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.b - Till 2020 v&#xE4;sentligen &#xF6;ka det antal st&#xE4;der och samh&#xE4;llen som antar och genomf&#xF6;r integrerade strategier och planer f&#xF6;r inkludering, resurseffektivitet, begr&#xE4;nsning av och anpassning till klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarna och motst&#xE5;ndskraft mot katastrofer samt utveckla och genomf&#xF6;ra, i linje med Sendai-ramverket f&#xF6;r katastrofriskreducering 2015&#x2013;2030, en samlad katastrofriskhantering p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.c - Support least developed countries, including through financial and technical assistance, in building sustainable and resilient buildings utilizing local materials.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.c - St&#xF6;dja de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, inklusive genom finansiellt och tekniskt bist&#xE5;nd, att bygga h&#xE5;llbara och motst&#xE5;ndskraftiga byggnader av lokala material.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.1 - Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.1 - St&#xE4;rka motst&#xE5;ndskraften mot och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatrelaterade faror och naturkatastrofer i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.2 - Integrate climate change measures into national policies, strategies and planning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.2 - Integrera klimat&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder i politik, strategier och planering p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">4343246.79414096</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">5429058.4926762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3257435.0956057203</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">1628717.5478028602</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-5e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">4343246.794140959</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">1628717.5478028595</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">5429058.4926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">3257435.09560572</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">14658457.930225</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">2443076.32170429</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">1900170.47243667</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/globen/61050501_023012-20ProgrammeCooperationAgreementbetweenSwedenandUNHABITAT2020-2023signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Cooperation Agreement between Sweden and UN-Habitat 2020-2023</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/globen/61050501_023012-20FrameworkAgreementbetweenSwedenandUNHABITA2020-2023signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Framework Agreement between Sweden and UN-Habitat 2020-2023</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/globen/61050501_023223-20Beslutominsats,UN-HABITAT2020-2023,(61050501)2720303_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on support to UN-Habitat 2020-2023</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="61050501" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1180102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="6500000000.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Sustainable environment, climate, oceans and use of natural resources 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>H&#xE5;llbar milj&#xF6;, h&#xE5;llbart klimat och hav samt h&#xE5;llbart nyttj. av naturresurser 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
