<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-jo" dstore:index="77" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11651A0102-JOR-15180</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC Jordan &amp; Lebanon resilience project 2017-2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IRC Jordanien -Libanon resiliens projekt 2017-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
IRC-UK kommer att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet genom att st&#xF6;dja f&#xF6;rdrivna och lokala samh&#xE4;llen, med fokus p&#xE5; utsatta kvinnor och flickor, i Jordanien och Libanon 2017-2020, f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka den sociala och ekonomiska &#xE5;terh&#xE4;mtningsf&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan. Projektet omfattar 54,7 MSEK totalt.
Projektet f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngs till nov 2020 med 51,8 MSEK till&#xE4;gg.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
IRC-UK will promote gender equality by supporting displaced and local communities, with a focus on vulnerable women and girls, in Jordan and Lebanon in 2017-2020, to increase social and economic resilience. The project in total is budgeted 54.7 MSEK.
The project is extended to November 2020 with an additional contribution of 51.8 MSEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21506" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC/International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21506" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3172622.3839084595</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2367069.5028068232</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2823110.416191624</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3172622.3839084595</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">2367069.5028068232</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2823110.416191624</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">9102609.102609</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">3172622.3839084595</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">2367069.5028068232</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/beirut-um/11651_1stAmendmenttotheAgreement-IRC.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC Jordan &amp; Lebanon resilience Project 2017-2020 First  Amendment to the Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/beirut-um/11651_IRCGrantAgreementSupportingSocialandEconomicResilienceofVulnerableWomen&amp;Girls.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC Jordan &amp; Lebanon resilience Project 2017-2020 Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/beirut-um/11651_2ndAmendmenttotheIRCAgreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC Jordan &amp; Lebanon resilience Project 2017-2020 Second Amendment to the Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/beirut-um/11651_IRCDecisiononAmendmentI.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC Jordan &amp; Lebanon resilience Project 2017-2020 Decision on  Amendment of Contribution I</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/beirut-um/11651_IRCDecisiononamendment.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC Jordan &amp; Lebanon resilience Project 2017-2020 Decision on  Amendment of Contribution II</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRC reported the following results, according to agreed objectives:1) Women generate income and assets, and are able to use and control resources,2) Women and girls shape and contribute to their communities and homesand 3) Women and girls are protected from and supported to recover from the consequences of GBV. Achieved progress and challenges of the programme implementation were captured in IRC&apos;s reports, including mitigations of the effects of the social unrest in Lebanon and of the Corona pandemic on the programme through adaptation of the activities and resources. Some undermet objectives were identified by IRC, admitting when a planned target may have been over-ambitious in the initial planning, like the potential profit that was expected to be sustained from creating and supporting micro-businesses in Jordan. The economic situation in Jordan does not leave much room for running businesses successfully. IRC recognizes as well that, in the case of North Lebanon (Wadi Khaled), the planned expected economic opportunities were not matching the reality of this excluded area. In this marginalized territory whose population doubled with the Syrian refugee influx in 2013, IRC has been confronted to the limited capacities of the local civil society, of the markets and existing businesses, to the lack of socioeconomic opportunities and at the same time to a very conservative culture. However, despite limitations of their economic dividends, beneficiaries are acquiring new skills and self-confidence that bring a significant difference to their lives.&#xA0; Our assessment is that IRC provides challenged persons, households and communities with both recovery opportunities and resilience through high quality and &apos;client&apos;-tailored services that are relevant and on high demand, especially in this time of economic crisis. The ongoing crisis in Lebanon (closure of businesses, depressed markets, job destructions, inflation) and the lockdown situations in both countries since March 2020 are however significant obstacles to the empowerment objectives of IRC&apos;s programme. IRC shared with us data on decreasing job opportunities being offered by the market. IRC learnt a lot about factors that were unidentified in the planning phase throughout the implementation phase. IRC could however adapt the programme by recognizing the programme challenges and making possible adjustments at an early stage. IRC is an organization able to reflect on itsself and to adapt with agility. It is noticeable that IRC is generally meetings its result targets, with few exceptions, and that during year 2, it accelerated achievements in order to catch up with delayed results. Results under the target for combined year 1 and 2 may be slightly below expectation due to lower implementation during year 1 and despite reinforced implementation during year 2. In many cases, results are above targets. Interesting and unexpected cooperation experiences with local actors that the programme has generated, were shared by IRC, like the ad hoc training requested by the Jordanian police school from IRC for GBV case management and psychosocial counselling techniques, and like the facilitating role of the municipality of Wadi Khaled in Lebanon in promoting the programme among the population. IRC played there the role of a development actor of proximity, funding with another donor&apos;s resources repairs to the municipal sewage system that made cooperation even more easier afterwards for other interventions. The feedback of beneficiaries about the programme gives indications of positive transformations it brought into their lives: men learning to share decision-making with their spouse, women getting conflict resolution or anger management skills, women and girls acquiring technical skills and increasing their employability, girls negotiating successfully the delay of their too early marriage, etc. A particular character of the programme that defines its success is the way all services and activities are integrated with one another and complementary so that maximum benefit is achieved. Committed trainees may be recruited as volunteers and benefit from a per diem allowance. Mothers may leave their infants at the kindergarten while attending training or counselling sessions. GBV services and empowerment services are integrated, removing the potential stigma of attending a center for case management of GBV. Persons seeking such services are offered as well, like other people and without being identified as GBV survivors, training and socioeconomic opportunities that make the visit to the center casual and unnoticed. The programme benefits to other family members as well who may attend lifeskills sessions, focus group discussions on gender roles, and improve ability to sustain livelihoods and employability. Another particularity of IRC programme is that it is tailored on the beneficiary herself/himself who is more perceived as an agent of the implementation whose opinion is listened to than a recipient. The experience of visiting IRC-run centres, as the embassy has done at several occasions, brings a sense of high spirit and dynamism among both personal and clients, opposite of victimization, and the impression that things have already started to get better for them despite their life situation as refugees. An obstacle for which IRC has found mitigation measures during year 3 is the cost of transport barriers from the community to the centres. IRC has introduced the distribution of taxi vouchers for women and girls living at a too long distance for sustaining their attendance. IRC has also reorganized the services and the curricula in more compact schedules at convenient time of the day so that beneficiaries optimize their time spent at the centre. The overall impression of the programme confirms Sida&apos;s positive assessment of this partnership. It is meeting a priority need in areas of socioeconomic exclusion. It delivers demand-driven and a wide offer of concrete services to the beneficiaries, based on a continuous dialogue with them and reassessement of the progress and relevance of the programme. It addresses GBV and socioeconomic hardship, which are interrelated, in a holistic manner.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11651" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1110401" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3210000000.0" strategy-end-date="2023-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Syria Crisis 2016-2023</title>
    <titleSV>Syrienkrisstrategin 2016-2023</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
