<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-zm" dstore:index="91" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10313A0103-ZMB-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ipas Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ipas Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Ipas Zambia has applied to Sida for funding of 27 million SEK to carry out the &quot;&#x2018;Promoting Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights and Reducing Maternal Mortality in Zambia &quot; in Luapula and Muchinga provinces during the period 2018-2021. The intervention aims at improving awareness of and access to a continuum of quality sexual and reproductive health and rights information and services, including comprehensive abortion care, by women and girls in the two provinces by 2021 through:  1) Health systems strengthening to increase the provision of quality comprehensive abortion care (CAC) services, including post abortion family planning (PAFP)and  2) Community awareness and mobilization to increase knowledge, awareness, access, and social support for CAC services among community members. Ipas Zambia will work with the Ministry of Health at all levels to ensure that implementation is conducted in line within the approved guidelines and legal framework and to ensure complete ownership of the programme by the government. The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 28 million SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Ipas Zambia har ans&#xF6;kt om finansiering fr&#xE5;n Sida till ett v&#xE4;rde av SEK 27 000 000, f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet &quot;Promoting Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights and Reducing Maternal Mortality in Zambia&quot; i Luapula och Muchinga provinserna, under perioden 2018-2021. Insatsens syfte &#xE4;r att bidra till att kvinnor och flickor f&#xE5;r b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else f&#xF6;r, och tillg&#xE5;ng till kvalitativ information och tj&#xE4;nster inom sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter. Ipas Zambia hoppas uppn&#xE5; detta genom att; 1) bidra till f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad tillg&#xE5;ng till kvalitativa h&#xE4;lsotj&#xE4;nster &#x2013; specifikt inom olika former av abortv&#xE5;rd och familjeplanering, 2) bidra till att samh&#xE4;llen f&#xE5;r &#xF6;kad f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else och kunsap om och tillg&#xE5;ng till abortv&#xE5;rd, samt &#xF6;kat socialt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r abortv&#xE5;rd. Ipas Zambia kommer att samarbeta med h&#xE4;lsoministeriet f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att implementering sker i linje med godk&#xE4;nda riktlinjer och bindande ramverk, och f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla nationellt &#xE4;gandeskap. Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r SEK 28 000 000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This three-year project includes the foundational steps to establish the necessary guidelines and health system infrastructure to make comprehensive abortion and contraceptive services accessible to women and especially to girls in Zambia over the long term. Ipas have the opportunity to provide technical assistance and support to the MOH in its RMNCAHN work to prevent injuries and deaths of women especially adolescents from unsafe abortion and, more broadly, to advance the sexual and reproductive health and rights of especially poor women and adolescent girls in two very poor provinces of Zambia.
1.Health systems will be strengthened to increase the provision of quality comprehensive abortion care (CAC) services, including post abortion family planning (PAFP), in Luapula and Muchinga provinces.2. Ipas will raise community awareness and mobilization to increase knowledge, awareness, access, and social support for CAC services among community members in the two provinces.
The intervention intends to minimise the high rate of maternal death due to the problem of unsafe abortion,especially amongst adolescent women,which remains a major problem in Zambia and in particular the two poverty stricken provinces of Luapula and Muchinga. The Zambian MOH has estimated that as many as 30% of pregnancy-related deaths could be attributable to unsafe abortion, while hospital-based studies show that 30% to 50% of acute gynecological admissions are currently caused by abortion complications, a sizable proportion from unsafe abortion. The MOH also estimated that about 23% of incomplete abortions were among women younger than 20 years and that 25% of maternal deaths due to induced abortions were among adolescent girls younger than 18 years. While modern contraceptive uptake is generally low in Zambia, with a national average of 45%, the situation is worse in both Muchinga and Luapula where contraceptive uptake is only 34% and 33% respectively. Muchinga and Luapula provinces have the highest total fertility rate of Zambia&#x2019;s provinces except Northern Province. No safe abortion services exist in the two provinces for women who need them. Post Abortion Care(PAC) is offered only in hospitals that represent 4% of all public health facilities in these provinces, making the service largely inaccessible by vulnerable women and adolescent girls.
Increasing contraceptive use and availing CAC services will reduce both unwanted pregnancies and decrease maternal mortality especially amongst young poor women. Success of the intervention will depend on the interplay of acceptance of the programme,quality service provision by the health facilities and working within the legal framework.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21053" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ipas - Protecting Women&#x2019;s Health, Advancing Women&#x2019;s Reproductive Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21053" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPAS-Protecting Women&apos;s Health, Advancing Women&apos;s Reproductive Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">951786.7151725378</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">977230.5286817161</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">951786.7151725383</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">977230.5286817162</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2301390.039583</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">434324.679414096</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/10313-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ipas Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/10313-decision.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ipas Zambia 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/10313_AgreementAmendmentIPASOctober2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Amendment IPAS Luapula and Muchinga Provinces</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zambia/10313_DecisiononAmendmentofContributionIPASOctober2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment of Contribution IPAS Luapula and Muchinga Provinces</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health systems have been significantly strengthened to increase the provision of quality Comprehensive Abortion Care (CAC) services, including post-abortion family planning (PAFP), in Luapula and Muchinga provinces. &#xA0;A total of 128 facilities are now supported supported from almost zero at the beginning of the project.Ipas Zambia reported that almost 150 providers were trained in CAC services to cover the facilities that were newly introduced on the program in the last year. This resulted in more women including adolescents voluntarily accessing CAC services within the two provinces.The table below shows the number of Uterine evacuations(UE) by age during the reporting period. In the past women below the age of 19 would not access these services because of religious and social norms, service provider bias and misunderstanding of the legal provisions for safe termination of pregnancy which Ipas have now changed through education of service providers,community members,law enforcement agencies and the affected populations. Previously there was more post abortion care (PAC) services for those women who would have engaged in unsafe abortions (previously termed illegal abortions).The communities in Luapula and Muchinga now know that a lot of maternal deaths were due to unsafe abortions and their complications. They are now seeing&#xA0;a significant decline in maternal deaths and more women especially the young adolescents can now access services at nearby facilities without fear of discrimination or retribution.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="10313" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2250000000.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Zambia 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Zambia 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
