<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-ug" dstore:index="620" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-05-04T09:32:22" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-05-04T09:32:23" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118009201-UGA-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joint Advocacy for SRHR in Uganda (JAS programme)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Gemensamt p&#xE5;verkansarbete f&#xF6;r SRHR i Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
This contribution is a program support to the Centre for Health, Human Rights and Development (CEHURD) with focus on joint advocacy for Sexual &amp; Reproductive Health &amp; Rights (SRHR) in Uganda. The support is proposed to work on building a progressive SRHR advocacy movement which is a key pillar of CEHURD&apos;s strategic plan 2020-2024.

CEHURD has applied for 75 000 000 SEK fr&#xE5;n the Embassy of Sweden to implement this program during 2020 - 2023. The program is part of the overall 5-year strategic plan of the organization, which is estimated at 122 371 959 SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Insatsen &#xE4;r ett programst&#xF6;d till en lokal organisation, Centre for Health, Human Rights and Development (CEHURD), med fokus p&#xE5; gemensamt p&#xE5;verkansarbete inom sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa &amp; r&#xE4;ttigheter (SRHR) i Uganda. St&#xF6;det avser att bygga en progressiv gr&#xE4;srotsr&#xF6;relse f&#xF6;r p&#xE5;verkansarbete inom SRHR, vilket &#xE4;r en nyckelpelare i CEHURD:s strategiska plan 2020-2024.

CEHURD har ans&#xF6;kt om SEK 75 000 000 f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra programmet under perioden 2020 - 2023. Programmet utg&#xF6;r en huvuddel av organisationens strategiska plan med en uppskattad total budget p&#xE5; SEK 122 371 959.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the program is to have a progressive social movement boldly challenging the deep structures affecting the realization of SRHR in Uganda.
The proposed goal for this programme is linked to CEHURD&#x2019;s strategic goal of &#x201C;increased participation amongst rights holders, transparency and accountability amongst duty bearers towards the realization of the right to health&#x201D; and is a part of CEHURD&apos;s strategic plan 2020 - 2024.&#xA0;
The programme goal will be achieved through five specific objectives:
- To enhance a sustainable SRHR movement that will collaborate and collectively advocate for SRHR in Uganda&#xA0;
- To nurture and sustain grassroots progressive social movements that engage with deep structures on SRHR at the individual and systemic levels, hold duty bearers accountable; and collectively organize towards the realization of SRHR.&#xA0;
- To strengthen legal rights and enhance access to justice for communities, SRHR advocates and service providers in Uganda. (Strategic Litigation Programme) To generate evidence to inform SRHR advocacy and programming in Uganda.&#xA0;
- To strengthen CEHURD&apos;s institutional capacity and operational efficiency to deliver on its mandate</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHURD/The Center for Health, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.3 - Ensure equal opportunity and reduce inequalities of outcome, including by eliminating discriminatory laws, policies and practices and promoting appropriate legislation, policies and action in this regard.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.3 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika m&#xF6;jligheter och minska f&#xF6;rekomsten av oj&#xE4;mlika utfall, bland annat genom att avskaffa diskriminerande lagstiftning, politik och praxis och fr&#xE4;mja lagstiftning, politik och &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder av l&#xE4;mpligt slag i detta h&#xE4;nseende.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1628717.5478028602</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2171623.39707048</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2171623.39707048</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">2171623.39707048</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2171623.3970704796</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2171623.3970704796</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">2171623.3970704796</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1628717.54780286</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">8143587.739014</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">1248683.453315526</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">380034.094487334</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some results achieved during the inception phase Jan-Jun 2020: During this inception period CEHURD and partners mainly implemented preparatory activities for programme roll-out. This period was disrupted by the Covid-19 pandemic from end of Mar 2020 with strict measurements on movement and public gatherings put in place by the Ugandan government. During the reporting period CEHURD has engaged with School of Law and School of Gender and Women and Women studies &#x2013; Makerere University to establish a formal working relationship for their planned research studies and baseline. While the plan was to conduct research on how masculinities and norms affect the realization of SRHR in Uganda, the outbreak of the pandemic brought to light some more serious issues that continue to affect SRHR in Uganda. CEHURD has therefore decided to adapt the research to also capture emerging SRHR issues arising from Covid-19 and how the pandemic has led to retrogression in the realization of SRHR in Uganda. CEHURD has despite the interruption of the pandemic been able to make progress against the five programme objectives. This has been possible due to adaptations made on programme implementation approaches. Some activities were however postponed to the next reporting period. The pandemic has also created new opportunities for advocacy on SRHR which has informed the changes proposed in the revised year 1 work plan and budget. Collaboration with other partners especially civil society has been proven very important during this pandemic. CEHURD states that is has been clear that sections of the health sector that have an amplified voice have received attention much faster from the government. During the inception period CEHURD has done organisational capacity assessments (OCA) of 6 national partners that they will collaborate with during the implementation of the programme. The partners are Akina Mama wa Afrika (AMwA); Human Rights Awareness and Promotional Forum (HRAPF); Reach a Hand Uganda (RAHU); Coalition for Health Promotion and Social Development (HEPS &#x2013; Uganda); National Forum of People Living with HIV/AIDS in Uganda (NAFOPHANU); and Network of key population service organisations LTD (UNESO). The programme has been introduced to Ministry of Health to get their buy-in and support at both national and district level. The Director of Curative Services in the Ministry, Dr Charles Olaro, has been identified as a champion for the programme. With the country lock down due to the pandemic media interventions has been recognized by CEHURD as one of the most affective approaches for strategic advocacy and communication on issues of SRHR and impact of Covid-19. CEHURD invested quite a lot in media interventions that heighted the plight of SRHR services during the implementation of the national response towards Covid-19, calling for the prioritisation of SRHR as an essential service that could not be closed down during the lockdown. They also conducted several online meetings to discuss Maternal health issues in Uganda in the face of Covid-19 and attended webinars organised by other partners as key note speakers. The media activities including public statements and open letters to policy makers together with partners yielded successes as the President of Uganda and the National Task Force on Covid-19 relaxed the transportation measures for expecting mothers and those who were sick with pre-existing conditions. The JAS advisory committee has been formed with members representing various organisations involved in the different thematic areas of the JAS programme. The programme has been introduced to the district level in five pilot districts where implementation will be done through Community Health Advocates (CHA&#x2019;s). Also these CHA&#x2019;s have gone through a OCA process. CEHURD had not planned to do much of strategic litigation under programme during the inception phase. However, due to the Covid-19 pandemic and the lock down many SRHR and HR violations has taken place. CEHURD has therefore done more strategic litigation during this period than initially planned for and this support has continued as the violations continue to rise. Cases have increased the demand for rapid legal responses which calls for reallocation of resources to facilitate this. They have also strengthened their legal services through establishing a legal aid clinic and pursuing the registration of CEHURD as a legal aid service provider. They have also realised the need to procure a better toll-free line system that can record and handle more than one call at a time. Reallocation for more funds for the toll-free helpline has therefore been suggested in the revised work plan and budget. To strengthen institutional capacity CEHURD staff has been oriented on the new strategic plan as well as the JAS programme. They went through a successful board transition and strengthening of the governance structure. Identification of the JAS team was done as well as seven new staff were brought on board. They also procured 2 new vehicles, 2 big photocopiers, desktop computers, laptops and printers to enhance the delivery of their work with the JAS programme. The Embassy assisted CEHURD during this reporting period with an RBM consultant from NIRAS to revise their result matrix and develop an M&amp;amp;E framework. The consultant also did RBM training for CEHURD and the national partners to together be able to improve the goals, objectives and indicators that an advocacy programme can deliver on.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="51180092" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2400000000.0" strategy-end-date="2023-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Uganda 2018-2023</title>
    <titleSV>Uganda 2018-2023</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
