<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-ve" dstore:index="29" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14395A0101-VEN-72010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NRC&apos;s Humanitarian Programme 2021-2025</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">NRC :s Humanit&#xE4;r Program 2021-2025</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Norwegian Refugee Council (NRC) has applied for a renewed strategic partnership with Sida during 2021-2025. NRC has applied as well to Sida for funding of 364.5 million SEK to carry out &#x201C;the Humanitarian Programme for 2021&#x201D; in 26 humanitarian crisis settings: Afghanistan, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Colombia, Ecuador, Panama, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Eritrea, Ethiopia, Iran, Iraq, Jordan, Kenya, Lebanon, Libya, Mali, Niger, Nigeria, Honduras, El Salvador, Mexico, Palestine,  Somalia, South Sudan, Sudan, Tanzania/Burundi, Uganda, Venezuela, Yemen. The application includes provision of 40 million SEK to replenish the Rapid Response Mechanism funding instrument and 7 individual projects for method, capacity-building and coordination.

The objectives of NRC&#x2019;s intervention is to protect the rights of displaced and vulnerable people during crisis, to provide assistance meeting their immediate humanitarian needs, to prevent further displacement and to contribute to durable solutions, and to provide expertise as a strategic partner to humanitarian systems and actors. NRC&apos;s principled and clear advocacy has the potential to influence positively decision-makers and duty-bearers. NRC is planning to assist around 7,263,000 persons in 2021.

NRC builds its programmes with people in the centre, in particular the displaced persons. As a rights-based organization, it delivers assistance with the aim to protect the most vulnerable from harm and to help them rebuild their lives. NRC always prepares therefore for durable solutions in delivering humanitarian assistance. NRC even integrates humanitarian mediation in its programmes at the community level wherever it can contribute to the peaceful solution to conflicts. NRC&apos;s programming follows obviously the triple humanitarian-development-peace nexus.

NRC will implement the intervention mainly by itself, through its 7,700 staff members and 7,000 volunteers mobilized within the affected communities. 

The intervention&#x2019;s tentative total budget is 4 263 200 000 Norwegian krona (NOK), that the organisation is financing with Sida&#x2019;s funding in a proportion of 8% approximately. Other donors, like the Norwegian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, DG ECHO, UNHCR,  etc. are the largest contributors, besides a dozen of other donors in agreement with NRC. Sida provides NRC with the opportunity to allocate resources flexibly within individual country programmes (Programme-Based Approach &#x2013; PBA).

Humanitarian-Development-Peace Nexus
NRC&apos;s catalytic support for coordination and capacity building contributes greatly to the link between humanitarian aid, development and peace. NRC&apos;s advocacy work and activities enable, at least contribute to, sustainable solutions for refugees and displaced people in a significant way in cooperation with other actors. In the long run, the NRC will reduce humanitarian needs. The NRC prioritizes self-sufficiency in its programs. The NRC&apos;s analysis capability, not least through its Internal Displacement Monitoring Center (IDMC), is an advantage for relevant programming according to the nexus orientations. Among the 26 crises in NRC&apos;s portfolio that Sida prioritizes, there are 15 where Sida implements Sweden&apos;s development strategies in synergy with humanitarian aid.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Norwegian Refugee Council - Norska flyktingr&#xE5;det (NRC) - har ans&#xF6;kt om ett f&#xF6;rnyat partnerskap med Sida 2021-2025. NRC har dessutom ans&#xF6;kt om finansiering p&#xE5; 364,5 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra humanit&#xE4;ra insatser i 26 humanit&#xE4;ra krisomr&#xE5;den under 2021: Afghanistan, Kamerun, Centralafrikanska republiken, Colombia, Ecuador, Panama, Demokratiska Republiken Kongo, Eritrea, Etiopien, Iran, Irak, Jordanien, Kenya, Libanon, Libyen, Mali, Niger, Nigeria, Honduras, El Salvador, Mexiko, Palestina, Somalia, Sydsudan, Sudan, Tanzania / Burundi, Uganda, Venezuela och Jemen. Ans&#xF6;kan inkluderar &#xE4;ven 40 miljoner kronor f&#xF6;r den humanit&#xE4;ra snabbmekanismen (RRM) och 20 miljoner kronor i st&#xF6;d till sju projekt f&#xF6;r metodst&#xF6;d, kapacitetsuppbyggnad och samordning.

NRC:s m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att i krissituationer skydda f&#xF6;rdrivna och utsatta m&#xE4;nniskor, v&#xE4;rna deras r&#xE4;ttigheter och bist&#xE5; med assistans f&#xF6;r att m&#xF6;ta deras omedelbara humanit&#xE4;ra behov, f&#xF6;rhindra ytterligare f&#xF6;rdrivning, samt bidra till h&#xE5;llbara l&#xF6;sningar. Dessutom tillhandah&#xE5;ller NRC expertis som en strategisk partner f&#xF6;r det humanit&#xE4;ra systemet och dess olika akt&#xF6;rer. NRC bedriver ocks&#xE5; principbaserat  och tydligt p&#xE5;verkanarbete f&#xF6;r att ut&#xF6;va  inflytande p&#xE5; beslutsfattare. NRC planerar att under 2021 bist&#xE5; 7,263,000 personer med humanit&#xE4;ra behov.  

NRC bygger sina program med m&#xE4;nniskor i centrum, och med s&#xE4;rskild inriktning p&#xE5; personer som har tvingats p&#xE5; flykt. Det &#xE4;r en r&#xE4;ttighetsbaserad organisation som verkar f&#xF6;r att ge skydd &#xE5;t de mest utsatta och s&#xE5;rbara och hj&#xE4;lpa dem att &#xE5;teruppbygga sina liv. NRC arbetar d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r alltid f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbara l&#xF6;sningar n&#xE4;r de genomf&#xF6;r humanit&#xE4;ra projekt och program. Organisationen integrerar &#xE4;ven humanit&#xE4;r medling och f&#xF6;rhandling mellan olika parter i samh&#xE4;llet i sina program och p&#xE5; s&#xE5; s&#xE4;tt kan organisationen &#xE4;ven bidra till en fredliga l&#xF6;sningar p&#xE5; l&#xE5;nvariga konflikter. NRC:s programmering st&#xE4;var efter att st&#xE4;rka kopplingar mellan humanit&#xE4;rt bist&#xE5;nd, utveckling och fred.

NRC kommer i huvudsak att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen p&#xE5; egen hand, genom organisationens 7 700 anst&#xE4;llda och 7 000 volont&#xE4;rer som mobilisera i de omr&#xE5;dena d&#xE4;r insatsen genomf&#xF6;rs. 

Den aktuella budgeten f&#xF6;r NRC:s hela humanit&#xE4;ra program 2021 uppg&#xE5;r till 4 263 200 000 NOK, varav Sidas del f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande utg&#xF6;r ca 8%. Givare, som det norska utrikesministeriet, GD ECHO, UNHCR, etc. bidrar med st&#xF6;rre volymer och ytterligare ett tiotal andra givare har ing&#xE5;tt avtal med NRC. Sida ger NRC m&#xF6;jligheten att nyttja resurser flexibelt inom varje enskilt landprogram, (enligt  s&#xE5; kallad Programme-Based Approach &#x2013; PBA)

Humanit&#xE4;r-Utveckling-Fred Nexus
NRC bidrar i h&#xF6;g grad till arbetet f&#xF6;r att sammankoppla humanit&#xE4;rt bist&#xE5;nd med freds- och utvecklingsinsatser. Organisationens  str&#xE4;van att effektivisera bist&#xE5;ndet genom katalytiskt st&#xF6;d till samordning och kapacitetsbyggande insatser bidrar till denna ansats. I samarbetet med andra organisationer m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;r och bidrar NRC:s verksamhet och p&#xE5;verkansarbete till att st&#xE4;rka h&#xE5;llbara l&#xF6;sningar f&#xF6;r flyktingar och m&#xE4;nniskor som har blivit tv&#xE5;ngsf&#xF6;rdrivna och bidrar d&#xE4;rmed till att p&#xE5; sikt minska de humanit&#xE4;ra behoven. &#xC4;ven krisdrabbade m&#xE4;nniskors m&#xF6;jligheter till sj&#xE4;lvf&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjning prioriteras. NRC:s analyskapacitet &#xE4;r en styrka som bidrar till att programmeringen anpassas till en nexus-ansats och den analys som genomf&#xF6;rs av NRC:s internationella center f&#xF6;r &#xF6;vervakning av tv&#xE5;ngsf&#xF6;rflyttning (IDMC) &#xE4;r av stor vikt f&#xF6;r dessa analyser. 15 av de 26 kriser i NRC:s portf&#xF6;lj som Sida finansierar avser l&#xE4;nder d&#xE4;r Sverige &#xE4;ven bedriver  utvecklingssamarbete vilket &#xF6;ppnar f&#xF6;r m&#xF6;jligheter till synergier med humanit&#xE4;rt bist&#xE5;nd.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NRC is Norway&#x2019;s largest international humanitarian organisation and widely recognised as a leading field-based displacement agency within the international humanitarian community. NRC is the INGO receiving the largest contribution from Sida&apos;s Humanitarian Unit to INGOs so far, based on experience of successful partnerships, NRC&apos;s capacities to respond at scale and its coverage of crises that Sida is prioritizing through the needs-based allocation approach. NRC receives approximately 8% of Sida&apos;s humanitarian unit&apos;s annual budget appropriation which is substantial.
The objectives of NRC for 2021 can be summarized as follows: &quot;To protect the rights of displaced and vulnerable people during crisis, to provide assistance meeting their immediate humanitarian needs, to prevent further displacement and to contribute to durable solutions, and to provide expertise as a strategic partner to humanitarian systems and actors.&quot; It is expected, for 2021, that NRC will reach out approximately 7.26 million beneficiaries within the proposed country programme portfolio selected by Sida, to which the share of Sida will amount to around 8% according to its contribution in proportion to the total budget. In 2019, NRC reached globally 9.1 million persons in 33 crisis settings.
NRC&#x2019;s work is divided into three pillars: humanitarian assistance, advocacy and expert deployment.&#xA0;Sida&apos;s Humanitarian Unit funding will continue prioritizing mainly the first pillar through funding of the humanitarian country programmes in line with HRPs and the RRPs and through the RRM funding. To some extent, Sida will support as well the second pillar of advocacy which is integrated in the humanitarian country programmes and implemented by NRC&apos;s method, thematic and capacity development projects supported by Sida. Sida will provide NRC with only a punctual support to the third pillar, through funding to CashCap which is deploying experts to the field for invigorating cash assistance working groups (17 in 2020 to 16 countries).
More specifically, NRC will be supported for implementing humanitarian programmes in its respective areas of expertise in the settings that Sida and NRC have agreed upon to prioritize through this contribution: Afghanistan, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Colombia, (plus Ecuador and Panama), Democratic Republic of the Congo, Eritrea, Ethiopia, Iran, Iraq, Jordan, Kenya, Lebanon, Libya, Mali, Niger, Nigeria, Honduras/El Salvador/Mexico, Palestine, Somalia, South Sudan, Sudan, Tanzania/Burundi, Uganda, Venezuela, Yemen and Other. There are the largest refugee and internal displacement crises and cumulate around three quarters of the current global displacement caseload. These programmes will continue to be supported by Sida along the PBA regime of partnership initiated in 2016 and extended since then.
As an indication, NRC distributed its total resources in 2019 within its core competencies as follows:&#xA0;26% for Shelter and settlements,&#xA0;20% for&#xA0; Education,&#xA0;17% for Livelihoods and Food Security,&#xA0;14% for ICLA,&#xA0;9% for WASH,&#xA0;3% for Camp Management and&#xA0;11% for Other. In 2021, NRC foresees to distribute its resources as follows: 21% for Education, 19% for Shelter and settlements, 19% for Livelihoods, 15% for ICLA, 12% for WaSH, 2% for Camp management, 1% for Advocacy. The COVID-19 socioeconomic impacts on displaced populations are partly motivating the increase in Education, Livelihoods, ICLA and WaSH.
The good scores of NRC in ITAD&apos;s evaluation confirms for Sida that NRC is meeting its objectives and delivers quality humanitarian assistance and services, as expected.
Describing NRC&apos;s activities within its core competencies would fill volumes. It is proposed here to provide few examples from field visit observations made between 2014 and 2020 in the Great Lakes and in the Levant that tell about NRC&apos;s work.&#xA0;
SHELTER: NRC may provide cash assistance, construction material, mobilize the community to build shelters for the most vulnerable unable to build them on their own, prevent evictions. In Lebanon, NRC identified very vulnerable and homeless refugee households, or about to be expelled by their landlords for not paying their rent due to poverty. NRC found unfinished housing constructions in the neighbourhood. NRC proposed to the owners to gradually finish the construction work of flats at NRC&apos;s expense but in exchange to accept to accommodate for free the vulnerable families for a year. The family would find shelter and a financial relief beneficial for the whole family as it would not have to pay for the rent, while the landlord would end up with an upgraded building. More interestingly, the refugee household would be identified in the neighborhood as a positive factor upgrading local housing standards, not down-grading the neighborhood socially. NRC documented that the protection of the household was improving ultimately, thanks to local social integration.&#xA0;NRC presents its works in this sector as follows:&#xA0;Facilitating access to shelter during emergency, as well as in&#xA0;protracted displacement situations.
LIVELIHOODS: NRC masters cash assistance, to the point that it is used as an expert for helping other organizations to programme such interventions and for monitoring the outcomes of UN cash assistance systems on behalf of donors (CAMELEON/Lebanon). In Bukavu (DRC), NRC created a vocational school that was handed over to the Governorate for training IDP youth and host community youth in developing different technical skills, including construction, IT, etc. that made them employeable on the labour market and enabled them to generate income. That was a contribution to reduce dependency on aid, prevent criminality and violence, enhance social cohesion and at the same time preparing the way for durable solutions to displacement situation. NRC presents its works in this sector as follows:&#xA0;Provision of food assistance to prevent loss of life&#xA0;and contribution to rehabilitation of local food and market systems to strenghten&#xA0;livelihoods and individuals&apos; and households&apos; abilities to earn a living.
ICLA: NRC is at its best in programmes where it helps refugees and IDPs to recreate the civil documentation that they have lost because of or during displacements. Lost documents may be birth certificates, property documents, certificates of marriage, heritage entitlements, diplomas, etc. Their absence exposes to violations, exploitation and abuse those who are deprived of such documents. Civil documentation, as observed in Jordan, is central for claiming one&apos;s rights, accessing services and preparing for the future. NRC assesses with individuals and families what is missing, advises how to access basic services and provides legal support to get back or replace documents, often across the border, with local lawyers. Syrian refugees would keep the ownership of properties that might have been confiscated if they were not claiming their rights on them timely thanks to NRC with valid property documents. Advising on divorce procedures, supporting women to claim their rights while separating from men they had been married to in early marriage arrangements, was a significant work of NRC&apos;s lawyers.&#xA0;NRC presents its works in this sector as follows:&#xA0;Support to people to claim&#xA0;and exercise their rights through information, counselling, legal assistance, collaborative&#xA0;dispute resolution, capacity building and advocacy to ensure access to legal identity&#xA0;documentation, housing land and property rights, employment rights and knowledge&#xA0;around migration laws. Specific assistance to women and children as they may face&#xA0;particular obstacles in accessing their rights.
EDUCATION: Children and youth lose years of education due to displacement. NRC works for reintegrating students in schools by helping them catching up lost grades faster. NRC has been training teachers and school personnel in Burundi to absorb the additional numbers of returnee youth who were Burundian refugees born in Tanzania that are enrolling in ill-prepared Burundian schools, at the best interest of the students, including protection aspects. Students had to be assisted for shifting overnight from Kiswahili and English-language curriculas to Kirundi and French-language curriculas. By doing that NRC, not only restaures education rights, but contributes to the local social cohesion. NRC is involved in the global Education Cannot Wait through advocacy.&#xA0;NRC presents its works in this sector as follows:&#xA0;Support to children and youth to complete a full cycle of basic education&#xA0;with particular focus on those who are out of school or have had their education&#xA0;interrupted. Provision of technical and vocational training for young adults.
CAMP MANAGEMENT: NRC showed further its protection work to Sida in Azraq and Zaatari refugee camps in Jordan, designed for accommodating social cases, un-documented individuals and alleged security threats, including un-accompanied minors, who could not be left free in the society according to the authorities. NRC would turn the experience of detention, in the middle of nowhere, desertic in fact, less depressing by upgrading shelter conditions, and providing education services, vocational training and psychosocial support, including assisting refugees to negotiate temporary exit permits. NRC presents its works in this sector as follows:&#xA0;Camp management, in and outside of camp settings. Camp&#xA0;management core functions include coordinating and monitoring assistance and&#xA0;protection, setting up and supporting governance and community participation&#xA0;mechanisms, managing and disseminating information, providing multisector feedback&#xA0;mechanisms, and maintaining infrastructure.
WASH: Five year into their displacement situation, Syrian refugees in Lebanon were still provided with 15 L/person/day drinkable water through costly water-trucking deliveries serving around 285,000 people living in thousands of informal tented settlements (ITS) of the Bekaa valley. Central authorities were blocking any improvements, like drilling wells, that would result in permanenting the refugee settlements in the country or giving the refugees the hope that they have a future in Lebanon. NRC managed to negotiate with communal councils, eager to improve their own infrastructures needing maintainance since the Civil War, that certain settlements along main roads would be connected to the local water systems.&#xA0;NRC presents its works in this sector as follows:&#xA0;Provision of infrastructre for&#xA0;water and sanitation, and information dissemination on good hygiene practices.
Sida has evidence that NRC is aligning fully its own response strategies on the HRPs, which is a condition for receiving Sida&apos;s funding. NRC is usually an active stakeholder of the process of elaborating such plans, inter alia through its engagement in participating in or co-leading clusters of the local humanitarian system (potentially in its core competencies sectors) depending on locations, and through hosting NGO coordination forums.&#xA0;
RRM Allocation 2021
Included in this contribution, it is proposed to support NRC&apos;s capacity to address new emerging humanitarian needs in rapid onset crises. Sida&apos;s funding Rapid Response Mechanism (RRM) allocation to NRC will enable NRC to react very fast to new disasters when they strike. It may provide seed funding to larger response programmes and catalyze more resources, complementing as well the resources that the flexibility of PBA provides for re-allocating them in such circumstances, when possible. In 2020, NRC tapped into its 50 MSEK allocation 15 times, replenished once, until it was exhausted, intervening in 13 countries where NRC had presence in the context of sudden displacement situations, floods, droughts and socio-economic consequences of COVID-19 on displaced and vulnerable households. The assistance provided consisted generally in protection services and assistance delivered in form of cash, vouchers, and in-kind life-saving commodities, in the areas of shelter, basic assistance kits, hygiene promotion and psychosocial support. In 2021, NRC will undertake similar interventions with the RRM allocation with an initial 40 MSEK funding from Sida. RRM interventions are considered as projects, implemented over a 3 to 6 month period, with a 3 MSEK budget in average. The ceiling is 5 MSEK, while the bottom budget is 2 MSEK, but exceptions can be justified case by case.
Method- and capacity-building projects
Included in this contribution, NRC has proposed to Sida to support Method- and capacity-building projects that will contribute to improve the global humanitarian system and coordination &amp;amp; advocacy forums at the national level.
- Strengthening global protection policy for displacement communities is a project that Sida is willing to prioritize as it&#xA0;focuses on ensuring effective integration of protection across NRC programming and improvements to global humanitarian protection policy by translating concepts into concrete actionable outcomes. This project aims at ensuring that protection is foundational to all NRC work through the &#x2018;Safe Programming&#x2019; framework defining minimum commitments for NRC&apos;s operations, and at supporting the full realisation of the right of freedom of movement in safety and dignity for displacement-affected persons, in programmes for the protection of civilians, for durable solutions and for migrants in &apos;refugee-like&apos; situations.
- Becoming the leading displacement organization in hard to reach areas (H2R) is a project that will be supported in 2021 by Sida. It addresses the growing complexity of operating environments by investing in in-depth understanding of contexts against the backdrop of shifting international norms and the rise of new tech solutions to ensure timely and appropriate responses. NRC wants to&#xA0;ensure that displacement-affected individuals considered hard-to-reach have better access to assistance and protection, by enhancing NRC&apos;s ability to access multiple geographical and cultural H2R contexts, by delivering high quality and sustained programming in H2R areas and by advocating for the rights of people affected by displacement in H2R areas.
- Sida&apos;s support to NRC&apos;s CashCap will be continued in 2021. The project ensures that humanitarian/development agencies and national actors have sufficient and sustained expertise to design and implement cash and market-based response (CMBR) in an effective and coordinated manner. NRC intends to ensure global rapid deployment capacity for the initial days of a sudden onset emergency and to enable the systematic consideration of cash and voucher assistance as part of the initial response analysis. NRC will facilitate knowledge exchange, provide technical backstop and support to CashCap roster members on deployment, and improve sustainability between CashCap expert and cash community by sharing information, promoting continuity and encouraging to take ownership by the cash community.
-&#xA0;NRC&#x2019;s Internal Displacement Monitoring Centre (IDMC) in Geneva will continue to be co-financed by Sida&apos;s humanitarian unit and Sida&apos;s unit for Global Cooperation on Environment in 2021. IDMC is a global leader in monitoring, reporting on and advocating for people displaced within their own country. It is known for its research publications and advocacy aiming at&#xA0;generating evidence on all situations of internal displacement; building capacity to prevent and respond to the issue; and galvanising political commitment and action to drive positive change. For the second and probably last year, Sida&apos;s Unit for Global Cooperation on Environment will co-finance IDMC in 2021 together with the Humanitarian Unit, as IDMC analyzes displacement situation trends caused by climate change as well. IDMC adds great value to the evidence- and needs-based mobilization of resources for displacement situations. Its analysis and research are major contributions to the global and local advocacy agenda.
- NRC will be supported as well through this contribution for hosting local humanitarian coordination platforms where international and local NGOs cooperate for building up coordinated programmes, common advocacy agendas and for influencing the policy-making of authorities, the UN, donors and other partners. These forums play a key role in localizing the response, offering coordination services, training and partnership opportunities to the local NGO community. They play as well an important role for INGOs in addressing administrative and access obstacles that they may face with authorities for establishing themselves and obtaining visas and work permits. The Jordan INGO Forum and the Libya INGO Forum will be supported through this contribution.&#xA0;NRC&apos;s active engagement in the local NGO forums, sometimes by hosting them with Sida&apos;s support (DRC, Palestine (AIDA), Jordan, Libya, Lebanon until (2019)), demonstrates NRC&apos;s commitment to aid effectiveness and collective action regarding humanitarian coordination and advocacy.
- Furthermore, it is proposed to continue co-financing for a last year the West Bank Protection Consortium (WBPC) with the Swedish General Consulate in Jerusalem and other donors. It is a strategic partnership between DG ECHO, 10 European States and 5 INGOs providing protection and assistance to Palestinians at risk of forcible transfer in the West Bank due to recurrent violations of international law. The project addresses the protection needs of persons and communities of concern through a multi-sector approach that reduces vulnerabilities, builds capacities and responds to threats. The Consulate has established a 3 year partnership 2021-2023 with NRC (#14571, 39 MSEK) for that project. The WBPC project, and the NGO platform AIDA, supported so far by Sida&apos;s humanitarian unit, will be funded by Sweden&apos;s development cooperation strategy for Palestine, integrated in that contribution.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NRC/Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Venezuela (Bolivarian Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">872721.1526976991</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">872721.1526976991</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">872721.152697</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">872721.1526976991</value>
  </transaction>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="14395" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1010104" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0.0" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <title>Humanitarian aid 2021-2025</title>
    <titleSV>Humanit&#xE4;rt bist&#xE5;nd 2021-2025</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
