<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-bd" dstore:index="628" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5217004001-BGD-14031</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Water Safety for the wellbeing of Women and Children in Bangladesh</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Water Safety for the wellbeing of Women and Children in Bangladesh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The intervention is considered to deliver sustainable results that contributes to the Results strategy for Bangladesh has made significant progress in increasing access to improved drinking water in both urban and rural areas, and to all segments of the population. As a result of this, Bangladesh achieved the Millennium Development Goal 7c related to drinking water well before the end date in 2015 and currently 98% of the population enjoys access to a protected drinking water source (JMP, 2015). However, looking past the quality proxy of &#x201C;improved water source&#x201D; reveals that the water supply is undermined by quality issues and unreliable service provision (MICS 2009). According to the most recent Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey, MICS, only 35 % of households consume water which meets the Bangladesh standard for both arsenic and bacteriological contamination. WHO estimate that chronic arsenic exposure leads to 43 000 deaths annually having a significant economic impact on the country. Despite improvements in prevention and treatment of waterborne disease, 15% of post-neonatal deaths all 6% of all U5 deaths are currently due to diarrhea. 

Arsenic contamination of shallow wells has been a recognized problem since the 1990s but, despite large investments by donors and government, the result has only been a decrease in exposure of 1%, which actually translates into an increased number of affected people given the population growth during the same period. Several factors contribute to this limited success and water quality issues in general, but at the core lay weak regulation and accountability, poor information management, and a lack of capacity of government to coordinate and engage with small scale entrepreneurs in the water sector. 

The proposed programme will support the government of Bangladesh to lead, coordinate and facilitate the implementation and management of water safety frameworks and protocols. The long term development goal is universal access to safe and sustainable drinking water and the expected outcomes of the project are:
1. By 2020, roles and responsibilities for regulation, capacity building, service provision and water quality testing are assigned. 
2. By 2020, harmonized systems and procedures are deployed by stakeholders for the delivery of arsenic and bacteriologically safe drinking water.
3. By 2020, evidence-based systems are used by accountable stakeholders in the health and drinking water sub-sectors.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Det f&#xF6;reslagna programmet kommer att st&#xF6;dja Bangladesh regerings arbete med att leda, samordna och fr&#xE4;mja genomf&#xF6;randet och f&#xF6;rvaltningen av ramverk och metoder f&#xF6;r skydd av vatten. Det l&#xE5;ngsiktiga utvecklingsm&#xE5;let &#xE4;r allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kert och h&#xE5;llbart dricksvatten. De f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultaten av projektet &#xE4;r:

1. &#xC5;r 2020 ska roller och ansvar f&#xF6;r reglering, kapacitetsuppbyggnad, tillhandah&#xE5;llande av tj&#xE4;nster och provning av vattenkvalitet vara tilldelade.
2. &#xC5;r 2020 &#xE4;r harmoniserade system och metoder utplacerade av ansvariga akt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r leverans av arseniks&#xE4;kert och bakteriologiskt s&#xE4;kert dricksvatten.
3. &#xC5;r 2020 anv&#xE4;nds evidensbaserade system av ansvariga akt&#xF6;rer inom delsektorerna h&#xE4;lsa och dricksvatten.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The key outcomes and outputs of the project are:
1. By 2020, roles and responsibilities for regulation, capacity building, service provision and water quality testing are assigned
1.1 A government-led platform for adaptation and adoption of sub-sector wide scalable water safety models and protocols is established and functional
1.2 Drinking water safety policies and regulations are complied with and capacity of public/ private personnel developed to deliver safe water at-scale &apos;
2. By 2020, harmonized systems and procedures are deployed by stakeholders for the delivery of arsenic and bacteriologically safe drinking water
2.1 A government-led national performance-based monitoring and surveillance system for urban and rural drinking water safety is established and functional &apos;
2.2 A harmonized National Arsenic Mitigation Protocol and evidence-based model is adopted and implemented securing safe water rights
3. By 2020, evidence-based systems are used by accountable stakeholders in the health and drinking water sub-sectors
3.1 Arsenicosis case detection and management protocol is operationalized &amp;amp; evidence and database of arsenicosis patients established and strengthened
3.2 The integrated WASH National Monitoring and Evaluation System is established, populated and functional
4. By 2020, Rohingya and Host Communities in Ukhiya and Teknaf Upazilas under Cox&#x2019;s Bazar District have sustainable WASH services
4.1 The Behaviour of both host and Rohingya communities have been changed through safe sanitation and hygiene intervention change and safe sanitation
4.2 Rohingya and Host communities are trained on Water Safety Plan (WSP) and able to ensure their own access to safe water
4.3 GoB departments and stakeholders are strengthened to ensure sustainable WASH services for the target communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Childrens&apos; Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.1 - By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.1 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; allm&#xE4;n och r&#xE4;ttvis tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kert och ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomligt dricksvatten f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.2 - By 2030, achieve access to adequate and equitable sanitation and hygiene for all and end open defecation, paying special attention to the needs of women and girls and those in vulnerable situations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.2 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till fullgod och r&#xE4;ttvis sanitet och hygien och att ingen beh&#xF6;ver utr&#xE4;tta sina behov utomhus. S&#xE4;rskild uppm&#xE4;rksamhet b&#xF6;r &#xE4;gnas &#xE5;t behoven hos kvinnor och flickor samt m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1462501.4625014623</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2876737.549479886</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">705777.604047906</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2876737.549479886</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180773</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">705777.6040479064</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1462501.4625014623</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">5733005.733005</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-28">1462501.4625014623</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">575347.5098959771</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">2301390.0395839084</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">705777.604047906</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/52170040-amendment.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/decision1617.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Safety for the wellbeing of Women and Children in Bangladesh</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bangladesh/52170040-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the conclusion on performance of the contribution for the period October 2019 to September 2020. During this period the contribution progress was satisfactory, though during March - May 2020 field activities were disrupted/slowed down due to Covid 19 pandemic.&#xA0; Key achievements during the period: -Strengthening of the Policy Support Branch (PSB), which is now actively implementing a one-year action plan developed as part of the Sida project. Activities that have been initiated by the PSB include the revision of the Sector Development Plan (SDP) 2011-2025 and the National Policy for Water Supply and Sanitation 1998 as well as the development of the National Operation and Maintenance Strategy for Water Supply and Sanitation. -Implementing partners have been engaged for field mobilization, pro-poor site selection, water safety planning, sanitation and hygiene promotion. -Completion of the WASH Bottleneck Analysis workshops in the remaining five divisions making a total of eight. The information generated through this bottom-up consultative process will be utilized for a joint sector review and integrated national St&#xE4;llningstagande till rapport Statement on report Contribution ID:&#xA0;52170040 2 (3) action planning. -Finalization of the water quality component of the National Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS), which provides the most current source of nationally representative water quality information and benchmarks the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) of water national indicators. -National WASH in Health Care Facilities (HCF) Strategy developed and approved. -National Implementation Plan on Arsenic Mitigation disseminated, and stakeholders sensitized. -WASH and Arsenicosis Technical Committee established to strengthen monitoring and reporting systems between WASH and Health sectors. -During this reporting period, 126,750 women, men and children gained access to arsenic-safe drinking water from 462 new water supply facilities and 355 rehabilitations of existing water facilities. Cumulatively, a total of 130,150 women, men and children gained access to arsenic-safe drinking water from a total of 498 new and 355 rehabilitated water points. This represents 41% of the total target beneficiaries of 316,000 people (including Cox&#x2019;s Bazar- Rohingya Response). From March 2020 on wards Unicef is a leading partner of the Government of Bangladesh in addressing\responding to Covid 19 pandemic and related issues. They are playing vital role in framing policies and guidelines along with the Health Department and Department of Public Health and Engineering and other partners. Unicef also providing awareness and other support to the community and local government through their programms. Progress of activities also reported for Cox\s Bazar component. Some of the activities there were no progress, or are not clear. -No progress reported in Wash in educational facilities. -No progress also in the area linked to open defecation in Camps and host communities The reason they mentioned is restricted field movement due to Covid 19, but they got about 6 months time before Covid starts. The issues will be discussed with UNICEF. - Regarding UNICEFs role in humanitarian coordination in Wash sector in Cox\s Bazar needs also to discuss further in a suitable time. - The issue of continuing distribution of soap, jerrican and water tablets will also be discussed, since these are humanitarian nature of activity.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="52170040" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1040102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1900000000.0" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Bangladesh 2014-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Bangladesh 2014-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
