<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-zw" dstore:index="116" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12789A0101-ZWE-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FOJO/IMS  Zimbabwe Media  Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOJO/IMS ZimMedia21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Fojos program syftar till att st&#xE4;rka kopplingarna mellan mainstreammedia, mediaaktivister, bybaserade organisationer och andra CSO:er. Arbetet kommer att ske i de norra delarna av landet s&#xE5;som provinserna norra och centrala Mashonaland, Manicaland och Masvingo. Tanken &#xE4;r att insatsen ska kompletteras av st&#xF6;det genom Internews som ska arbeta i de s&#xF6;dra provinserna. Po&#xE4;ngen med uppdelningen &#xE4;r att olika spr&#xE5;k talas i respektive omr&#xE5;de och en upplevd gemensam sociopolitisk kontext f&#xF6;renar inom omr&#xE5;dena.

Programmet ska st&#xE4;rka marginaliserade medborgares deltagande och p&#xE5;verkan i samh&#xE4;llsdebatten om demokrati och utvecklingsfr&#xE5;gor genom anv&#xE4;ndandet av nya och innovativa medieformer och kommunikationss&#xE4;tt. Vidare ska programmet fokusera p&#xE5; tillg&#xE5;ng till online-media och d&#xE5; s&#xE4;rskilt sociala media. M&#xF6;jligheterna att skapa och dela inneh&#xE5;ll ska st&#xE4;rkas. F&#xF6;r att komma &#xE5;t problemen med falska nyheter och d&#xE5;ligt utforskade artiklar kommer programmet ha en faktakontrollerande komponent.

Insatsen kommer bl.a. inneh&#xE5;lla f&#xF6;ljande aktiviteter: skapande av lokala plattformar f&#xF6;r information s&#xE5;som nyhetsbrev och online media; fakta-kontrollerande mekanismer; tr&#xE4;ning i gr&#xE4;vande och utredande journalistik; bybaserad/lokalradio; lobbyarbete kring medielagstiftning; en st&#xF6;dfond till hotade/utsatta medieut&#xF6;vare; tr&#xE4;ning f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra professionalism och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande ocks&#xE5; av medieut&#xF6;vare.

Fojo kommer att anv&#xE4;nda sig av en bred ansats som handlar om att tackla de utmaningar som finns genom att arbeta med b&#xE5;de mainstream- och alternativ media. Vidare kommer de att bygga p&#xE5; redan etablerade arbetss&#xE4;tt inom civilsamh&#xE4;llet och lokalsamh&#xE4;llena. De aktiviteter som har nationell r&#xE4;ckvidd, exempelvis lobbyarbete f&#xF6;r medielagsreformer kommer att koordineras med Internews.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
Fojo has applied to the Embassy for funding of 40 MSEK to carry out the &quot;ZimMedia21 Strengthening citizen engagement in marginalised rural and urban communities through innovative media and communication platforms in Zimbabwe programme&quot; in North and Central Mashonaland, Manicaland and Masvingo Provinces during the period 2019-2021. 

The intervention aims at informing citizens (women and men, girls and boys) to freely participate, interact and contribute to democratic governance and development. This is done through outcome 1: Information &amp; communication gap narrowed in targeted marginalized rural and urban communities, with youth&#x2019;s and women&#x2019;s voices amplified and participation increased. Outcome 2: Targeted media professionally and financially strengthened to provide high-quality public interest content with a balanced presence of women and men. Outcome 3: Citizen and rights centered media policy and law reform, and protection of safe journalistic working conditions, supported and enhanced.  Fojo will implement the intervention through local selected media organisations in Zimbabwe. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 40 MSEK and Sida will be the only donor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall ObjectiveInformed citizens (women and men, girls and boys) freely participate, interact and contribute to democratic governance and development.Outcome 1: Information &amp;amp; communication gap narrowed in targeted marginalized rural and urban communities, with youth&#x2019;s and women&#x2019;s voices amplified and participation increased.
Outcome 2: Targeted media professionally and financially strengthened to provide high-quality public interest content with a balanced presence of women and men.Outcome 3: Citizen and rights centred media policy and law reform, and protection of safe journalistic working conditions, supported and enhanced.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medieinstitutet Fojo/Linn&#xE9;universitetet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1465845.7930225742</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1791589.3025831461</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.794636154</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1465845.7930225714</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1791589.3025831468</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">4230163.178544</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">1057540.7946361532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-28">732922.8965112871</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">732922.8965112871</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">380034.094487334</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zimbabwe/agreement---ims_fojo.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/zimbabwe/decision-on-contribution---ims_fojo.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme reached at least 35 districts (20 rural, 6 urban and 9 small towns), through the production of community focused content and the establishment and development of community-based access to information platforms. This enabled the participation of women and young people in dialogue and debate on issues such as social service delivery, water and sanitation and Covid-19 among other issues affecting marginalised communities in Zimbabwe. This was achieved through various activities including ZACRAS community radio programme, the people&#x2019;s bus talk shows by Bustop TV, Magamba&#x2019;s Ghetto cinemas as well as Media Centre and TellZim&#x2019;s citizen journalism platforms (mainly WhatsApp groups and community newspapers). In total 469 citizen journalists, both volunteers and professional journalists, were trained and almost half of them were women. They were drawn from the rural districts of Mashonaland East, Masvingo and Manicaland, excluding Mutare and Harare. Magamba and TellZim partnered to amplify the coverage of local councils and community feedback on council services. Magamba&#x2019;s Open Council and Open Parly initiatives exposed the public to councils and parliamentary meetings and debates in a manner that is unprecedented in Zimbabwe. The different community media platforms served to enhance citizen engagement with their local leadership and drawing leaders&#x2019; attention to pertinent matters. This facilitated a healthy flow of information within the communities and in some cases led to specific challenges being resolved. Furthermore, the ZimMedia21 programme drew the attention of mainstream media to community issues. Through the work of ZUJ and ZINEF, journalists and editors were better exposed to community-related issues and perspectives that often go under reported. The Newsday and the Standard newspapers in particular, improved their coverage of community-related issues, as opposed to predominantly elitist coverage and political propaganda. The programme kept the public informed about fake news and disinformation through the fact-checking and media literacy initiatives of ZimFact. There has been a floodgate of false claims and fake news in the wake of the complex political, social and economic crisis in Zimbabwe, amplified by the Covid-19 pandemic. In the reporting period, ZimFact produced 65 fact reports and 24 fact sheets as a way of keeping credible information in the public domain and holding public officials to account. ZimFact also developed a &#x2018;Promise Checker&#x2019; to track the promises of public officials. The content of the ZimFact reports spanned across economic, political and social issues, including subjects such as matters to do with foreign aid to Zimbabwe, education, family issues such as abortion and marriage, employment levels as well as Covid-19 and its remedies. ZimFact has also raised public awareness on fact-checking through public seminars to buffer citizens against the prevalence of fake stories shared mostly through social media platforms. This was particularly important given the harmful nature of some of the information relating to managing Covid-19 symptoms being circulated on media platforms. Magamba&#x2019;s hackathons proved to be timely and necessary at a period where Zimbabwe and the world became highly dependent on digital solution to meet the challenges presented by Covid-19. Through the hackathons, young people in urban centres created solutions for local government to bridge service delivery issues. For example, Magamba partnered with the city of Harare, Marondera Town Council, the Combined Harare Residents Association (CHRA) and Marondera Residents Trust to implement two hackathons, one in Marondera and one in Harare. This activity consolidated the work established by the Open Council Initiative. The City of Harare is currently in the process of adopting the winning solution from the Harare hackathon to use as its official digital call centre for citizens, and, civil society organisations to report to the Harare Town Clerk and Combined Harare Residents Trust, while the winning solutions in Marondera were approved by the Mayor of the City who will take it forward to be implemented when full council sessions resume. This is expected to improve transparency and accountability in municipalities and citizen access to information. On the advocacy front, the ZimMedia21 programme has been highly successful in the defence of the media rights, media policy and access to information rights. MISA provided essential legal support including engaging lawyers, the police and paying legal fees for journalists arrested during the project period and litigated for access to information rights of citizens, particularly under the Covid-19 lock down where the state exercised repression. Both VMCZ and MISA contributed to the ongoing media law reviews and managed to achieve government concessions towards co-regulation of the media and push back on some of the state excesses in trying to maintain media control. As part of the advocacy effort spanning over the years, Fojo-IMS and its local partners also witnessed the state eventually budging to invite applications for community radio licenses in February 2020.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="12789" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1500000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <title>Zimbabwe 2017-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Zimbabwe 2017-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
