<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-bo" dstore:index="99" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14256A0101-BOL-14050</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Helvetas-Fast Avfall-WASH COVID-19 r&#xE4;ddningsinsatser i Bolivia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Helvetas-Solid Waste-WASH COVID-19 emergency response in Bolivia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to address COVID-19
Governments should consider the management of basic services such as water, sanitation and solid waste as essential public services within the framework of the response to COVID-19, in order to directly minimize impacts on health and the environment (rapid and uncontrolled spread of the virus in cities). 

Management measures should consider all types of waste, including medical, domestic and hazardous waste, because there is a lot of pressure on the water supply service and large quantities of possibly infectious waste (chinstraps, masks, gloves, used or expired medicines and other contaminated items), which can easily be mixed with common waste, increasing the risk exposure of workers in the service providers. Therefore, it is necessary to consider the necessary biosafety measures to minimize such risk.

The disinfection procedures for contact and transit areas in places with a large influx of people, food supply areas, health service infrastructure, and military and police personnel facilities are other key activities that should be taken into account.
 
Finally, another problem that must be addressed is the issue of communication (access to information, training, and awareness) both for health service personnel, technical support teams that have been working on the response, and the population in general, through campaigns, technical assistance, and/or support in the dissemination of existing materials.



Within the framework of the health emergency, HELVETAS (as a humanitarian actor in the country) along with Agua Tuya and SwissContact (the three current partners with the Embassy in different contributions) have requested the financial assistance of the Embassy to support an emergency response in the WASH and solid waste sector. 

The project is aimed at contributing to the prevention and containment of COVID-19 infection with emphasis on the management of environmental sanitation, cleaning and disinfection services in the municipalities of La Paz, El Alto and Montero. The expected amount of the whole contribution is 3 million SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Hanteringen av grundl&#xE4;ggande behov som vatten, sanitet och fast avfall &#xE4;r en v&#xE4;sentlig offentlig service i bek&#xE4;mpningen av Covid-19. S&#xE5;dan service kan minska virusets p&#xE5;verkan p&#xE5; h&#xE4;lsa och milj&#xF6; (framf&#xF6;rallt dess snabba och okontrollerade spridning i st&#xE4;der). 
&#xC5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r hanteringen av olika typer av avfall (mediciniskt, hush&#xE5;lls- och farligt avfall) &#xE4;r ocks&#xE5; betydelsefulla, d&#xE5; s&#xE5;dant avfall annars kan p&#xE5;verka vattenf&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjningen. Det finns ocks&#xE5; en risk f&#xF6;r att smittsamt avfall blandas med vanligt avfall. Smittsamt avfall &#xE4;r exempelvis maskar, handskar, utg&#xE5;ngna mediciner, och diverse produkter som kan b&#xE4;ra smitta. Exponering f&#xF6;r dessa typer av avfall utg&#xF6;r &#xE4;ven en risk f&#xF6;r den personal som uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;ller avfallshantering och sanitetstj&#xE4;nster. Det &#xE4;r d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r viktigt att genomf&#xF6;ra n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndiga &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r bios&#xE4;kerhet i avfallshanteringen i syfte att minska riskerna. 

&#xC5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r desinfektion av kontakt- och transitplatser d&#xE4;r folksamlingar kan bildas (exempelvis matbutiker, sjukhus, samt arbetsplatser f&#xF6;r milit&#xE4;r och polis) &#xE4;r ytterligare en viktig punkt som m&#xE5;ste beaktas.  

Slutligen m&#xE5;ste sv&#xE5;righeter relaterade till behovet av fungerande kommunikation uppm&#xE4;rksammas (tillg&#xE5;ng till information, utbildning och medvetenhet). S&#xE5;dana &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder &#xE4;r av vikt f&#xF6;r personal sysselsatt med h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, smittspridning, samt befolkningen i stort. Behovet av kommunikation kan m&#xF6;tas med upplysningskampanjer, teknisk r&#xE5;dgivning, och/eller st&#xF6;d till spridning av befintlig information. 

I den aktuella situationen har Helvetas (som varande en humanit&#xE4;r akt&#xF6;r i Bolivia) i samarbete med AguaTuya och SwissContact ans&#xF6;kt om ekonomiskt st&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sida f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja kris&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder inom vatten-, sanitet- och avfallssektorerna. Alla tre akt&#xF6;rer &#xE4;r etablerade motparter f&#xF6;r Sida. 

Projektets syfte &#xE4;r att bidra till f&#xF6;rebyggandet och begr&#xE4;nsningen av Covid-19, med fokus p&#xE5; milj&#xF6;sanering, reng&#xF6;ring och desinfektion av offentliga milj&#xF6;er i La Paz, El Alto och Montero. Det f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade bidraget uppg&#xE5;r till tre miljoner svenska kronor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the contribution is to minimize the risk of COVID-19 infection of personnel operating environmental sanitation services, and thus ensure their continuity in spite the health emergency.
&#xA0;
This&#xA0;has been&#xA0;done through the support to the selected municipalities in:
-The development of contingency plans and its implementation through the provision of personal safety garments and other inputs for the protection of workers of environmental sanitation services,
- Providing training in cleaning and disinfection of people&#x2019;s high concentration areas
- Technical assistance for communication and public information processes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helvetas Swiss Intercooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bolivia (Plurinational State of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waste management/disposal</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="11.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.5 - By 2030, significantly reduce the number of deaths and the number of people affected and substantially decrease the direct economic losses relative to global gross domestic product caused by disasters, including water-related disasters, with a focus on protecting the poor and people in vulnerable situations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.5 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligt minska antalet d&#xF6;dsfall och antalet m&#xE4;nniskor som drabbas av katastrofer, inklusive vattenrelaterade katastrofer. &#xC4;ven tillse att de direkta ekonomiska f&#xF6;rlusterna till f&#xF6;ljd av s&#xE5;dana katastrofer, i form av l&#xE4;gre global BNP, minskar v&#xE4;sentligt. S&#xE4;rskilt fokus b&#xF6;r ligga p&#xE5; att skydda de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.50956</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-28">325743.509560572</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project was executed through the HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation (HELVETAS) as the lead institution with Swisscontact and Aguatuya Foundation as the main third parties. Five activities have been planned during the whole implementation: Activity 1 Technical Assistance to Municipalities and WASH utilities in the design and implementation of contingency plans. &#xA0; Helvetas has developed &#x201C;a service continuity tool in the context of COVID-19&#x201D;. Its aim was to achieve continuity of vital services that are provided in municipalities and WASH utilities during the health emergency by limiting the exposure and protecting the personnel performing essential functions. The instrument has been validated in the water and sanitation utility of La Paz and El Alto (EPSAS) which is the biggest provider in Bolivia. It has been implemented in the municipalities of El Alto and the water and sanitation utilities of Montero and La Guardia. &#xA0; Helvetas along with their partners have also developed protocols for the provision of urban cleaning services. These protocols seek to improve the capacity of the municipalities to guarantee the continuity of operations in contexts of health emergencies where their employees are highly exposed to contagion due to the nature of their activities. It has been mainly implemented in the Municipality of La Guardia. &#xA0; Activity 2 Strengthen capacities through training courses to the technical staff, which was at risk of contagion due to their work in environmental sanitation: This specific activity has been carried out by Swisscontact through the National Institute of Health Laboratories (INLASA). The training activities have been developed in 38 health care establishments (including three WASH utilities and municipalities) making a total of 6,135 officials from the health sector and 224 officials from COSMOL and the company that provides waste collection and transportation services in the municipality of La Paz, La Paz Limpia. In order to standardize critical processes in health establishments, specific guidelines have been prepared in order to minimize the risk of this personnel. &#xA0; Activity 3 Provision of protection items (biosecurity inputs) to the technical staff within municipalities and WASH utilities. &#xA0; The project team has contacted the beneficiaries (WASH utilities and Municipalities) to confirm the main necessities for personal protection, defining the key items that were needed. It is important to mention that during the process of purchase, due to the high demand for many of these inputs, the prices of various items (disposable coveralls, chinstraps, among others) were more expensive and there was little availability of the required quantity. However, Helvetas has manged to deal with this situation. During the months of May and June, personal protection items were delivered to the autonomous municipal governments of La Paz and El Alto (for the workers in charge of the final disposal of solid waste generated in the landfills Saka Churu and Villa Ingenio) and EPSAS (for the workers that were working in the front line). &#xA0; In May and July, personal protection items were delivered to COSMOL (the WASH utility of Motero) and COSPLAG LR (the WASH Utility of La Guardia), contributing to the sustainability and continuity of the environmental sanitation services. &#xA0; In the month of July, EPSAS and the municipality of La Paz, given the increase of positive cases among their workers, requested additional support with personal protection elements to guarantee the continuity of work and prevent contagion. To meet this need, funds have been used from the contingency budget line. &#xA0; Activity 4- Provision of equipment and supplies for cleaning and disinfecting places with a high influx of people. &#xA0; In the months of May and June, supplies for cleaning and disinfection of public spaces with a high influx of people in the municipalities of La Paz and El Alto have been delivered. The main areas have been markets and public roads, reaching approximately 180 public spaces. &#xA0; In July, the Autonomous Municipal Government of El Alto, has requested additional support for the provision of &#x201C;granular chlorine&#x201D; to continue the cleaning and disinfection activities in public spaces due to the increase in cases in this city. To cover this need, funds have been used from the budget line for contingencies. &#xA0; In July, supplies for cleaning and disinfection of public spaces with a high influx of people were delivered in the municipalities of La Guardia achieving the disinfection of approximately 30 spaces. The logistics of this specific activity have been coordinated with the Vice Ministry of Civil Defense. &#xA0; &#xA0; Activity 5: Support the generation and dissemination of communication and information campaigns. A communication strategy has been implemented in the municipalities of El Alto, La Paz, La Guardia, Montero, producing differentiated messages to reach vulnerable groups, groups exposed to possible contagion (personnel who clean and disinfect public spaces, hospital waste operators and WASH Utilities) and the general population. The intended message has been oriented to promote a sense of co-responsibility in prevention, solid waste management and in the implementation of cleaning and disinfection measures. All communication actions have included an intercultural, gender and social equity approach. The contents have been disseminated through mass media and social networks (all the details of the messages and its dissemination are specified in the narrative report). &#xA0; &#xA0; Activity 6: Mega&#xA0;Tracking in La Paz This activity has not been planned in the original project document. However, and due to the high rate cases in the city of La Paz, the municipality has requested extra support to carry out this specific task. The Departmental Health Service of La Paz (SEDES) requested HELVETAS&#x2019; support for the transport of personnel to strengthen the operational action of the mega&#xA0;tracing in the city of La Paz. Having a small balance still to be executed and seeing the criticality of the epidemiological curve of contagion by COVID-19 in the department of La Paz, during the month of August, it was considered opportune to support SEDES in this operation of vital importance to contain the spread of the virus, especially in the municipalities of El Alto and La Paz. In this sense, and with a proper coordination within the Embassy, the request was carried out with the provision of transport and communication material on contagion prevention measures. This activity has been extremely important and has led the municipality and the National Government to take adequate measures regarding the de-confinement of cities and subsequent preventive measures based on an adequate strategy. &#xA0; Financial Report &#xA0; The budget execution of the Solid Waste-WASH COVID-19 emergency response in Bolivia Project for the period between April 27 and August 31, 2020 has been done according to the annex C specified in the agreement. As it has been mentioned above, some additional activities have been carried out under the contingency item budget line, in coordination with the Embassy. &#xA0; The accounting base of the project has been made under the modified cash base (mixed)&#x201D; since most of the transactions were recorded under the cash method, except for the last payments pending at the end of the project which were carried out after the activity period ended (audit, etc.). The transactions incurred during the period of activities has been done applying the exchange rate of the single payment: 0.68069691 Bs / SEK (according to the bank). There has been a loss due to exchange differences of around Bs81,502.38 (SEK 107,602.93). This amount has been adjusted in the Contingency item budget line without affecting the expected results. &#xA0; Audit Report No major observations have been found in the audit report. Helvetas has complied with all the requirements.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="14256" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1050303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="990000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Bolivia 2016-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Bolivia 2016-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
