<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-kh" dstore:index="71" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10524A0101-KHM-11110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Capacity Development Partnership Fund III 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Capacity Development Partnership Fund III 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The Capacity Development Partnership Fund (CDPF) was established in 2011 to support key parts of the Cambodian Education Ministry of Education, Youth and Sports&#x2019; (MoEYS) strategic plan for capacity development. The first phase of the fund was operating in 2011-2014 and a second phase in 2015-2017. The two first phases were jointly funded by the EU Delegation in Phnom Penh, Unicef and Sweden. 

The steering committee of the CDPF consists of the State Secretary of the MoEYS, directors of the Ministry&#x2019;s different departments and representatives from the donors. UNICEF together with MoEYS Department of Planning acts as the secretariat of the fund and UNICEF is the fund manager.

The overall objective of the CDPF is to enable effective leadership and management of the education sector through systematic capacity development thereby enabling implementation of the strategic plan for the education sector&#x2019;s development. 

The Policy priorities are: 
1. Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all 
2. Ensure effective leadership and management of education staff at all levels 

The sub-objectives the CDPF Phase III aim to contribute: 
1. To strengthen MoEYS capacity in policy formulation, planning, financing and management of reforms for improved sector performance. 
2. To strengthen capacities at provincial and district levels to plan, manage and monitor education service delivery. 
3. To strengthen school leadership and capacity in relation to planning and management in order to increase participation and learning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Den givargemensamma fonden, Capacity Development Partnership Fund (CDPF), skapades 2011 f&#xF6;r att finansiera centrala delar av Utbildningsministeriets plan f&#xF6;r kapacitetsutveckling. Fondens f&#xF6;rsta fas p&#xE5;gick under 2011 &#x2013; 2014 med en andra fas 2015 &#x2013; 2017. Fondens tv&#xE5; f&#xF6;rsta faser har finansierats gemensamt av EU delegationen i Phnom Penh, UNICEF och Sverige. Sveriges st&#xF6;d uppgick till 30 000 000 SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2015-2016 (PlanIT 51100074) och till 21 000 000 SEK f&#xF6;r 2011-2014 (PlanIT 51100002).

Ordf&#xF6;rande i fondens styrelse &#xE4;r Utbildningsministeriets statssekreterare och vice-ordf&#xF6;rande &#xE4;r EU:s representant. &#xD6;vriga medlemmar i fondens styrelse &#xE4;r Undervisningsministeriets avdelningschefer samt den svenska ambassadens representant. UNICEF administrerar fonden i enlighet med organisationens egna regler och f&#xF6;rordningar. 

CDPFs &#xF6;vergripande syftet &#xE4;r &quot;att fr&#xE4;mja ett effektivt ledarskap och ledning av utbildningssystemet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er genom systematisk kapacitetsutveckling, f&#xF6;r att d&#xE4;rmed bidra till genomf&#xF6;randet av utbildningssektorns strategiska plan, &#x201D;Education Strategic Plan (ESP) 2014-2018.&quot; M&#xE5;let med denna plan &#xE4;r i sin tur att st&#xE4;rka utbildningssystemets kapacitet f&#xF6;r planering, budgetering, revision och finansiell uppf&#xF6;ljning samt utv&#xE4;rdering, f&#xF6;r att effektivt kunna genomf&#xF6;ra &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r &#xF6;kad j&#xE4;mlikhet, samt &#xF6;kad kvalitet i undervisning och l&#xE4;rande samt bidra till en effektivare administration. De effektm&#xE5;l som ska uppn&#xE5;s genom CDPF baseras p&#xE5; ministeriets &#xF6;vergripande kapacitetsutvecklingsplan f&#xF6;r perioden 2014-2018. Denna plan kommer att uppdateras under 2018 parallellt med framtagandet av den nya strategiska planen f&#xF6;r utbildningssektorn 2019-2022. Effektm&#xE5;len &#xE4;r f&#xF6;ljande:

1. Att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka Utbildningsministeriets kapacitet f&#xF6;r planering, uppf&#xF6;ljning samt offentlig finansiell styrning f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra reformer inom sektorn.

2. Att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka kapaciteten p&#xE5; provins- och distriktniv&#xE5; f&#xF6;r att planera, styra och f&#xF6;lja upp effektivt genomf&#xF6;rande av insatser f&#xF6;r h&#xF6;gre utbildningskvalitet, tillg&#xE5;ng till utbildning och &#xF6;kad j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet inom utbildningssystemet. 

3. Att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka skolors kapacitet f&#xF6;r lokal planering, finansiering och uppf&#xF6;ljning med syftet att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra undervisning och l&#xE4;rande och involvera lokalsamh&#xE4;llet i &#xF6;kad utstr&#xE4;ckning i styrning och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. 

Fonden f&#xF6;rvaltas av UNICEF och finansieras med bidrag fr&#xE5;n EU, Sverige och UNICEF.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Childrens&apos; Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="111" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education, Level Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.1 - By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla flickor och pojkar fullbordar avgiftsfri och likv&#xE4;rdig grundskole- och gymnasieutbildning av god kvalitet som leder till relevanta och &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenliga kunskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">3510003.51000351</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1628717.5478028602</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">3510003.510003509</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1628717.5478028608</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">7020007.020007</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">3510003.51000351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">1628717.5478028602</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/cambodia/10524-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/cambodia/10524-decision-on-contribution-to-cdpf-iii-2018-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution, Capacity Development Partnership Fund III 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The second and third years, 2018 and 2019, of the third phase of the Sida, EU, USAID, GPE (Global Partnership for Education) and UNICEF jointly supported fund for capacity development in the education sector (CDPF III) showed considerable progress and the results are in general in line with the expectations put forward in the programme proposal. Under this third phase of CDPF, MoEYS progressed with work at national and subnational levels to deliver a broad range of activities, many of which are linked to key education reforms relating to teacher education and development, school-based management, curriculum development, student assessment and inspection, deconcentration and decentralisation and public financial management (PFM), among others. Under CDPF Phase III, work is conducted under six strategic outcome areas, five of which are reflected in the current MoEYS Capacity Development Master Plan (CDMP). The sixth aiming at increased gender balance at upper management levels.&#xA0; The Covid-19 pandemic has disrupted the work of the CDPF III during the first half of 2020. Some activities planned have not taken place, either postponed or cancelled. A substantial part of the budget has been reallocated to deal with the closure of schools and the instructions during March to July not to physically gather teachers or other MoEYS&#x2019; personal. Instead a number of activities have taken place through on-line media. One of the most significant achievements of CDPF in 2018-2019 was the launch of Cambodia&#x2019;s Education Strategic Plan (ESP) 2019-2023, with accompanied multi-year implementation plans, which will guide education sector programming over the next five years. Several key policy documents and action plans, including the National Policy on School Health, the National Policy on Life-long Learning 2019-2030, the Equity-Focused Primary Scholarship Framework, the Continuous Professional Development (CPD) Framework and Action Plan 2019-2023, the Multilingual Education Action Plan (MEAP) 2 2019-2023 and the Action Plan on Inclusive Education 2019-2023 were also finalized in 2019. These specialised policies and plans will underpin the implementation of the ESP over the medium term. The capacity of the Ministry of Education, Youth and Sport (MoEYS) officials to develop and implement policy; the use of financial management systems, and the use of human resource management systems at national and sub-national levels was strengthened through training. The capacity of school principals, administrators and teachers on school-based management (SBM), financial management, human resource management, inclusive education, science, technology, engineering and math (STEM) teaching skills, multilingual education (MLE) teaching skills, and minimum quality standards on community pre-school (CPS) curricula were strengthened to effectively manage schools and classrooms. These investments, among others, are helping to improve the quality of education service delivery in Cambodia, helping to create ongoing education opportunities for all Cambodia&#x2019;s children. Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 1 on policy and research is mostly on track. CDPF funding enabled MoEYS&#x2019; Department of Policy (DoPo) to carry out five new studies based on emerging priorities of MoEYS and the Royal Government of Cambodia. Two 2018 studies include a study on low completion rates in primary and secondary schools, and analysis of the implementation of life-skills education in lower secondary schools. These research studies were carried out internally, without any external technical support. Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 2 on planning was mostly on track. Much support under this area focused on strengthening the capacities of MoEYS&#x2019; education planners at national and sub-national levels to finalize the national ESP 2019-2023; to develop multi-year implementation plans by sub-sector at national level; and to steer the development of provincial ESPs 2019-2023, aligned with the national ESP. CDPF continued to support and strengthen MoEYS&#x2019; Department of Education Management Information System (EMIS) to ensure the availability of timely, accurate, accessible, relevant, reliable and meaningful quality data for making informed decisions. A series of capacity development workshops and training was conducted to contribute to targets in the EMIS Master Plan 2017-2021. The master plan was revised with technical support from CDPF. Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 3 on financing was mostly on track, with some constraints. CDPF continued to strengthen the capacity of MoEYS&#x2019; Department of Finance (DoF) to improve the Education Financial Management System (EFMS). Investments were made in improving the capacities of national and sub-national budget entities to improve budget formulation and execution and provide timely financial reports to DoF. Furthermore, DoF, with CDPF support, provided harmonised and targeted training to improve budget formulation, implementation and monitoring at the school level in medium-sized schools (both primary and secondary). A focus on this training was to develop school-level knowledge and skills in the use of School Operating Funds, which are set to significantly increase, particularly for disadvantaged schools from 2020 onwards. Focused capacity building efforts were conducted within MoEYS&#x2019; Internal Audit Department, including through the mobilisation of technical assistance to provide on-the-job field audit training, which, in turn, informed the development of a draft audit manual. Despite good progress being made in the audit area, albeit from a low base, overall targets in relation to the auditing of MoEYS&#x2019; central level offices were not achieved. Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 4 on personnel was mostly on track, with some constraints. With CDPF support, MoEYS&#x2019; Department of Personnel (DoPer) mobilized technical assistance to support the development of the Human Resource Management Information System (HRMIS) Master Plan, which is expected to be completed by the second quarter of 2020. The department intends to further develop the HRMIS to improve access to staff data by stakeholders, with the objective of improving the efficiency, effectiveness, equity and fairness of staff management and deployment. The requirements will form part of a five-year budgeted strategic plan for the development of the HRMIS. On-going technical assistance was provided through CDPF to support the establishment and operationalisation of teacher training programmes in Teacher Education Colleges (TECs). A significant part of this work was the preparation of key strategic documents, such as the TEC strategic development plan, and TEC curriculum framework for Bachelor of Arts education, among other documents. Technical assistance was also provided to assist TECs and TTD to develop a pre-service teacher training curriculum, leading to a Bachelor of Education. MoEYS commenced the preparation of a functional review with CDPF support in 2019. The aim of this review is to support the identification and delivery of improvements in the allocation of both functions and capacity across departments and units in MoEYS at the national level. An inception phase for the review was completed in late 2019; and functional mapping of all seven directorates and the major departments within them commenced. Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 5 on equity and quality service delivery was mostly on track, with some constraints. School-based management (SBM) seeks to empower school directors and teachers to build local capacity, and to improve school quality and efficiency through improving planning, budgeting, administration, human resource management, teaching and learning practices. In 2019, with technical assistance mobilised through CDPF, MoEYS further refined and developed an SBM harmonized training package for primary school directors. National and sub-national mentors built their knowledge and skills in relation to SBM through targeted training funded through CDPF. The preparation of a new plan for multilingual education continued into 2019. With support through CDPF, and technical inputs from other partners, a draft MEAP 2019-2023 was produced. The MEAP, with costed activities, was officially approved in August 2019. A continued effort from 2018 was CDPF support to the preparation and finalisation of the Action Plan on Inclusive Education. After several consultative forums with relevant stakeholders, the Action Plan on Inclusive Education 2019-2023 was finalized and approved in July 2019. Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 6 on gender-equitable leadership is constrained. Promoting gender-equitable leadership within MoEYS focuses on integrating gender equity at an institutional level so that gender is considered throughout all aspects of planning, human resource polices and implementation, and developing and implementing professional development training and networking opportunities for women at national and sub-national levels of the ministry. During 2019, UNICEF and MoEYS conducted activities contributing to both strategies. Work on developing and implementing professional development training and networking opportunities for women was somewhat constrained in 2019. However, significant work was done to gain consensus on an activity which will contribute to this second strategy. The Professional Development for the Promotion of Gender Equitable Leadership within MoEYS programme was scoped and agreed by all stakeholders. &#x2026;.. CDPF continued to make significant contribution to progressing MoEYS education reform priorities as outlined in the new ESP. With this sustained investment in building capacities within the education system it is anticipated further good progress will be made in progressing the implementation of reforms. Overall CDPF activities contributed to three of the five education pillars included in the Minister of Education, Youth and Sport&#x2019;s reform agenda; to all six education management reforms, and to other reforms included in the ESP such as: school reform, teacher education institution reform, promotion of digital education, gender mainstreaming and deconcentration and decentralisation. A programme target of 80 per cent of CDPF funds to benefit sub-national level education entities was established during the programme design in 2018. During the 2019 reporting period, an estimated 82 per cent of CDPF funds benefited personnel at sub-national levels of the education system, either directly or indirectly. As a result, the capacity to plan, implement and monitor education service delivery at provincial, district and school level improved significantly, and programme ownership and accountability at sub-national level was strengthened. However, of the officials at central, provincial and district level that benefitted from capacity development activities delivered under CDPF&#x2019;s six strategic outcomes only 20.4 per cent were women. A slightly higher percentage of female participation was observed at central and district levels (22 per cent at both levels) compared to provincial level (19 per cent). The low percentage of female MoEYS beneficiaries is partly due to the low percentage of female staff at management level (above vice chief level) of MoEYS. In 2019 only 22 percent of MoEYS management staff was female, 27 per cent at central level and 19 per cent at sub-national levels.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="10524" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000.0" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Cambodia 2014-2018</title>
    <titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
