<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-ke" dstore:index="212" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11721A0103-KEN-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Political Institutions</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Strengthening Political Institutions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The Oslo Center has submitted a proposal of 15 MSEK to support a project aiming to strengthen political institutions to enhance responsiveness, accountability and transparency in the electorral cycle. The Embassy cooperation partner will work with six political parties, as well as the Office of the Registrar of Political Parties through dialogues, trainings, development of guidelines and other important documents. The project shall support the parties to develop well functioning political party committess in the counties, to enhance efficiency and becoming more responsive to the interests of the citizens, and to speak with &apos;one party voice&apos; in the county governments.The project is prepared to include preparations of their partners to include the interests of the citizens in the constitutional referendum process, should it be carried out.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
Oslocentret har inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan om 15 MSEK f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja ett projekt med syfte att st&#xE4;rka de politiska institutionerna f&#xF6;r att de ska bli mer lyh&#xF6;rda, ansvarstagande och transparenta i hela valcykeln. Ambassadens samarbetspartner ska st&#xF6;dja sex politiska partier, samt partiregistraren genom dialog, utbildning, framtagande av riktlinjer och andra viktiga dokument. Projektet ska st&#xF6;dja partierna till att utveckla v&#xE4;lfungerande partikommitt&#xE9;er p&#xE5; l&#xE4;nsniv&#xE5;, f&#xF6;r att kunna bli mer effektiva i att tillvarata medborgarnas intressen och kunna f&#xF6;ra en partilinje i l&#xE4;nsregeringarna. Skulle den potentiella grundlagsomr&#xF6;stningen bli av &#xE4;r man beredd att inkludera f&#xF6;rberedelser inom sina projektpartners f&#xF6;r att medborgarnas intressen ska tillvaratas i den processen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the project is &apos;Strengthening Political Institutions to Enhance Responsiveness, Accountability, and Transparency in the Electoral Cycle&apos;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Oslo Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.3 - Ensure equal opportunity and reduce inequalities of outcome, including by eliminating discriminatory laws, policies and practices and promoting appropriate legislation, policies and action in this regard.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.3 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika m&#xF6;jligheter och minska f&#xF6;rekomsten av oj&#xE4;mlika utfall, bland annat genom att avskaffa diskriminerande lagstiftning, politik och praxis och fr&#xE4;mja lagstiftning, politik och &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder av l&#xE4;mpligt slag i detta h&#xE4;nseende.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">161243.0372324832</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">161243.0372324832</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">157044.808003</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/11721_AgreementAmendment11721StrengtheningPoliticalInstitutions.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement amendment Strengthening political institutions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/11721_DecisionAmendment11721StrengtheningPoliticalInstitutions.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision Amendment Strengthening Political Institutions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/11721_Agreement2ndamendment11721Strengtheningpoliticalinstitutions.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement 2nd amendment Strengthening political institutions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/11721_Agreement11721StrengtheningPoliticalInstitutions.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Strengthening political institutions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/11721_Decision11721StrengtheningPoliticalInstitutions.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision Strengthening Political Institutions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Several issues during the reporting period shaped the political environment during implementation. These included interalia; proposed amendments of the constitutional and electoral law, reorganization of political parties, political pacts and emergence of new influential political alliances, heated electoral campaigns, the advent of pseudo-class-based political configuration projecting the political establishment in confrontation with the low-income population christened &apos;hustler movement.&apos; The Building Bridges Initiative (BBI), a result of the consultations between President Uhuru Kenyatta and the former Prime Minister Raila Odinga in March 2018, culminated in the drive towards constitutional changes. The amendment of the Constitution of Kenya, 2010, via the BBI process may lead to changes to other Acts of Parliament.&#xA0; The BBI report implementation focuses on four thematic areas: a) Policy Development, b) Legislative Process, c) Administrative Action d) Constitutional Amendment.&#xA0; In November and December 2020, a BBI Steering Committee was established, tasked with collecting signatures as approval for the constitutional changes via the&#xA0;BBI&#xA0;process. The secretariat collected 4.4 million signatures from registered voters and presented them to the&#xA0; electoral management body the Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (IEBC) for verification. The IEBC verified 1.33 million signatures, surpassing&#xA0;the constitutional threshold as per Article 257 of Kenya&apos;s Constitution of 1 million registered voters. During the Covid-19 crisis period, there was intense internal reorganization of political parties and the parliamentary leadership. The internal struggles and reorganization are connected to the political restructuring towards the 2022 elections. The main proponents of the BBI process, are one faction of the ruling Jubilee Party (JP), and the main opposition party, the Orange Democratic Movement (ODM).&#xA0; Both parties reorganized their leadership in the parliament, It is expected that the BBI process and the eventual constitutional amendments will be conducted in parliament and through popular suffrage.&#xA0;This led to&#xA0; breakaway camps in several political parties, it is expected that structural reorganization of political parties and internal wrangles being experienced in 2020 may continue in 2021 and through to the beginning of 2022.&#xA0;These reorganization may affect&#xA0; implementation of activities, especially among parties entering into coalitions, alliances, or leadership wrangles. The bill proposing changes to political parties&apos; primaries law is already in parliament. Other laws that may be amended as a result of the BBI process include the Elections Act, Political Parties Act, Election Campaign Financing Act, and other Acts and regulations touching on elections&apos; conduct.&#xA0; During the reporting period, the Chief Justice issued an advisory to the President to dissolve parliament for failure to to legislate the implementation of the two-thirds gender principle. The implication and impact of this advisory were multifaceted. It was viewed that the Chief Justice expressively put to the fore frustrations the administration of the rule of law has confronted. However, the executive was believed to have politically been emboldened and powers of the usurped in &apos;stick and carrot&apos; situation where the executive could easily manipulate parliament because it had powers to dissolve parliament. Religious institutions have gained traction as new avenues to conduct national politics and conduits for patron-clientelist systems. Kenya&apos;s politics is predominantly ethnically driven, but a new political convocation is cropping up, the paupers( Hustlers) vs. dynasties (establishment) and has steadily gained traction being accepted, especially by the youth and the public believed to be in the economic margins.&#xA0;This narrative might be a sign of a stronger policy focus where economy and class become more prominent. However, there is no compelling evidence that the country is moving away from tribal politics. Oslo Center activities focused on supporting parties to strengthen their institutions by improving internal democracy; strengthening the relationship between County Assembly MCA&apos;s and mainstream parties; and developing guidelines that promote a better understanding of the party&apos;s process. The Oslo Center also worked with the Registrar of Political Parties to internally organize the office to regulate and coach political parties.&#xA0;internal party challenges in the party leadership impacted activities uptake with Ford Kenya and Jubilee Party.&#xA0; Amani National Congress (ANC)party leadership met county assembly members to establish linkages between the national assembly and senate members.&#xA0;&#xA0;As a result, the party resolved to establish a technical committee to develop caucus rules and regulations and organize for the county assembly caucus members&apos; leadership elections.&#xA0;the county assembly members Elections were held elections and four women elected to the caucus leadership.&#xA0; The rules provide that the ANC MCA caucus&apos;s leadership is is representated at the National Executive Committee (NEC) the highest decision making within a political party.&#xA0; ANC also appointed a&#xA0;new Election Board consisting of 6 men and 5 women.&#xA0; The Kenya African National Union (KANU) party&#xA0;Constitution was last revised in 2013. A National Management Committee (NMC) comprised of members of the parliament, women league, and youth league representatives as well as a legal committee was formed to review the KANU Constitution. The draft changes will be presented to the NEC in December 2020. The Wiper Democratic Movement - Kenya held&#xA0;consultative meetings with the National Executive Committee (NEC) and Parliamentary Group (PG) on party constitutional review. The main areas of amendments include membership recruitment, strengthening the elections board, and vetting candidates for the party and national elections. WDM &#x2013; Kenya has embraced technology by using SMS, USSD, and online platforms to register its members. The Office of the Registrar of Political Parties (ORPP)&#xA0;developed a detailed proportional electoral system document and presented to the BBI taskforce on mechanisms to address challenges political parties&#xA0; face during primaries and proposals on achieving the 2/3 gender rules and inclusion of youth, PWD&apos;s and marginalized and minorities. The strategies also explored proposals for changing the electoral system.&#xA0; KANU, WDM-K, and ANC women leagues developed training material for national and county levels.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11721" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
