<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-tz" dstore:index="1738" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-05-04T09:32:22" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-05-04T09:32:23" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5117009808-TZA-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania UNDAP II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Tanzania UNDAP II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
The United Nations Development Assistance Plan (UNDAP) in Tanzania is designed to strengthen the co-ordination and effectiveness of the UN system at national level, as a contribution to Tanzania&apos;s efforts to achieve sustainable poverty reduction and the implementation of human rights. The broad business corresponds to several of the goals set out in the Swedish Development Cooperation Development Strategy Tanzania 2013-2019. Four out of twelve results areas are particularly relevant to the Swedish strategy: good governance / human rights / gender; violence against women and children; female participation and political leadership; as well as economic growth and employment. The Swedish strategy identifies women, children and adolescents as prioritized target groups, which also reflects well in the areas of support chosen by Sida.

UNDAP II is fully in line with the donors&apos; Joint Assistance Strategy for Tanzania (JAST) and with Tanzania&apos;s National Visions (The Tanzania Development Vision 2025 and Zanzibar Vision 2020). UNDAP II is also developed in line with Tanzania&apos;s five-year plan 2015/16 - 2020/21 and with global sustainability and development goals. The program contributes to the UN&apos;s focus on improved results and coherence by bringing together 20 UN agencies&apos; planning, budgeting and reporting in a joint performance framework for Tanzania. UNDAP II therefore, to a certain extent, also reduces duplication for national partners as well as UN organizations.

Swedish support will be provided through One UN Fund, in line with Sweden&apos;s policy to support a coherent and more effective UN work in the countries (UN reform &quot;Delivering as One&quot;, DaO). UNDP is the UN-designated UN body that manages the One UN Fund (through the UNDP office in Dar es Salaam and the headquarters in New York), and the UN Resident Coordinator (UNRC) UN High Representative in Tanzania, why both of them stand as UN signing of SAA with Sida. In line with Sweden&apos;s earnings strategy for Tanzania, the support will not go to UNDAP generally, but as earmarked for the four mentioned results areas.

The funds will be distributed as follows to the following results areas:
- Economic growth and employment: SEK 125,000,000
- Good governance and human rights: 82 500 000 SEK
- Women&apos;s political participation: SEK 50,000,000
- Violence against women and children: 42 500 000 SEK</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
United Nations Development Assistance Plan (UNDAP) i Tanzania &#xE4;r designat f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka FN-systemets samst&#xE4;mmighet och effektivitet p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;, som bidrag till Tanzanias arbete f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar fattigdomsminskning och f&#xF6;rverkligandet av m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter. Den breda verksamheten motsvarar flera av de m&#xE5;l som anges i den svenska resultatstrategin f&#xF6;r utvecklingssamarbetet med Tanzania 2013-2019. Fyra av totalt tolv resultatomr&#xE5;den &#xE4;r s&#xE4;rskilt relevanta f&#xF6;r den svenska strategin: god samh&#xE4;llstyrning/m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter/gender; v&#xE5;ld mot kvinnor och barn; kvinnligt deltagande och politiskt ledarskp; samt ekonomisk tillv&#xE4;xt och syssels&#xE4;ttning. Den svenska strategin identifierar kvinnor, barn och ungdomar som prioriterade m&#xE5;lgrupper vilket ocks&#xE5; reflekteras v&#xE4;l i de omr&#xE5;den f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d som Sida valt.

UNDAP II &#xE4;r helt i linje med givarnas s k Joint Assistance Strategy for Tanzania (JAST) och med Tanzanias nationella visioner (The Tanzania Development Vision 2025 and Zanzibar Vision 2020). UNDAP II &#xE4;r ocks&#xE5; utvecklad i linje med Tanzanias fem&#xE5;rsplan 2015/16 - 2020/21 och med de globala h&#xE5;llbarhets- och utvecklingsm&#xE5;len.  Programmet bidrar till FN:s fokus p&#xE5; f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrade resultat och samst&#xE4;mmighet genom att sammanf&#xF6;ra ett 20-tal FN-organs planering, budgetering och rapportering i ett gemensamt resultatramverk f&#xF6;r Tanzania. UNDAP II minskar d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r i viss utstr&#xE4;ckning &#xE4;ven dubbelarbete f&#xF6;r nationella partner s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l som f&#xF6;r FN organisationer.

Det svenska st&#xF6;det ska ges via One UN Fund, i linje med Sveriges politik att st&#xF6;dja ett sammanh&#xE5;llet och mer effektivt FN-arbete i l&#xE4;nderna (FN-reformen &quot;Delivering as One&quot;, DaO). UNDP &#xE4;r det av FN utsedda FN-organ som administrerar One UN Fund (genom UNDP-kontoret i Dar es Salaam och huvudkontoret i New York), och UN Resident Coordinator  (UNRC) FN:s h&#xF6;gste representant i Tanzania, varf&#xF6;r b&#xE5;da dessa st&#xE5;r som FN:s undertecknande av SAA med Sida. I linje med Sveriges resultatstrategi f&#xF6;r Tanzania kommer st&#xF6;det inte att g&#xE5; generellt till UNDAP, utan som &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkt till de fyra n&#xE4;mnda resultatomr&#xE5;dena.

Medlen kommer att f&#xF6;rdelas enligt nedan till f&#xF6;ljande resultatomr&#xE5;den:
- Ekonomisk tillv&#xE4;xt och anst&#xE4;llning: 125 000 000 SEK  
- God samh&#xE4;llsstyrning och m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter: 82 500 000 SEK 
- Kvinnors politiska deltagande: 50 000 000 SEK
- V&#xE5;ld mot kvinnor och barn: 42 500 000 SEK</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">922939.943754954</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1194392.868388764</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1194392.868388764</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">922939.943754954</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2281502.281502</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">922939.943754954</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/tanzania/decision_undapii0-51170098-.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contract A</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress towards Outcomes results Economic Growth and Employment The outcome area comprises of 13 UN agencies contributing towards three outputs, see below. The outcome group is currently contributing to two Joint Programmes, one in Kigoma (the Kigoma Joint Programme) and one in Zanzibar (the Zanzibar Joint Programme) The outcome group is coordinated by ILO and have a designated person coordinating monitoring and results reporting. The group have monthly meetings where the different UN agencies are present. This is an opportunity for the UN agencies to share lessons learnt and exchange ideas and find synergies between themselves. In March 2019 the outcome group had a joint retreat focusing on the MSD approach to learn from each other and deepen the understanding of the concept. The EoS is present in the outcome meetings and it gives a good opportunity to get an insights of the work of the outcome group. The delivery rate for the outcome Economic Growth and employment for the period 2018-2019&#xA0; is 83% of annual targets fully or close to fully achieved. &#xA0;Output 1 Relevant MDAs and selected LGAs have strengthened capacities to review and implement evidence based economic policies and plans to be business enabling, environmentally sustainable and gender responsive: In Zanzibar, technical and financial assistance contributed to the finalisation of the Agriculture Sector Development Programme and the Youth Development Policy. On mainland inputs supported the finalization of the Microfinance Act and Microfinance Regulations. At sub-national level 33 regional and LGAs were enabled to create national plans, budgets and investments that integrated poverty, environmental and gender concerns. Concrete examples are six Regional Investment Guidelines designed to attract local/foreign investments and nine private partnerships resulting in revenue generating facilities. Training in Gender responsive budgeting have provided eight LGAs better equipped to manage district development funds for women and youth, demonstrated by a 26,5% increase in allocations and utilization over the last two years and the figures rised from TZS 592.8 million to 796.5 million. &#xA0; Input on Output 2 Relevant institutions have enhanced capacities to provide gender-responsive, market-oriented, quality programmes, products and services Following UN technical advice and financial support, 74 institutions with national or local reach delivered market-oriented and gender responsive training programmes and business development support products and services. This includes 8 skills development institutions such as the NCT and ZITOD, leading to the successful graduation of the first batch of 52 apprentices from the Zanzibar Quality Apprenticeship Programme in Hotel Operations. Strengthen the capacity of Tanzania Investment Centre to manage e-regulations platforms, which has made it easier for investors and entrepreneurs to start a business Through trainings and technical advice, 11 LGAs and 3 agricultural training institutions have strengthened capacity to provide agri-business development support including on good agronomic practices, climate-smart agriculture, and entrepreneurship. This will contribute to improved access to quality extension advice for women and men farmers and entrepreneurs. &#xA0; Input on Output 3 Micro, small, medium and large enterprises, in particular those led by women and youth, have strengthened capacities to increase productivity, add value to their products and access markets More than 38&#xA0;000 micro enterprises (both on mainland and Zanzibar) have strengthened capacities to increase productivity, add value to their products and access markets. The assistance from UNDAPII has ranged from providing trainings on GAP and construction of aggregation centres and storage facilities (28, 500 famers have reported a decrease in post-harvest losses from 40% to 27%) to facilitating links between farmers and traders. In Zanzibar, 180 primarily women seaweed farmers were provided with knowledge and skills to embark on sea cucumber farming as a new livelihood opportunity, while training of 40 youth (60% women) on value addition led to improved packaging and increased competitiveness. Access to finance initiatives led to more than 35,220 people (W: 21,504, M: 11,343, Y: 2,373) accessing financial services through savings groups, SACCOS, community banks and commercial banks. Additional 4,170,503 people (55% women) were reached through an IFAD loan. &#xA0; Progress towards Outcomes result Democratic Governance, Human Rights &amp;amp; Gender Equality The outcome area comprises of 4 UN agencies contributing towards three outputs, see below. The outcome group is coordinated by UNDP and it has a designated person who is responsible for coordinating, monitoring and results reporting. The group does meet every now and then, but it is not clear how regularly this occurs and whether all the involved UN agencies are always present. EoS has only been invited to and present at 2 outcome meetings during the period Aug 2018 &#x2013; Aug 2020, which substantially limits the EoS&#x2019; opportunity to get an insight into the work of the outcome group. Minutes from potential meetings where EoS has not been invited have also not been shared. This is a pity since such meetings are an opportunity for the UN agencies to share lessons learnt and exchange ideas and find synergies between themselves, from which the EoS can learn and understand the effectiveness of the outcome group and the work it delivers. &#xA0; Output 1 Citizens of Tanzania especially the most marginalized have increased capacity to engage and participate in policy formulation, implementation and monitoring. During the reporting period, 119 CSOs were supported to engage with parliamentary committees and/or participate in public hearings across a range of issues, including discussions around the Political Parties (Amendment) Bill, the Finance Bill and sectoral budget reviews. The National Assembly was also enabled to better integrate gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment (GEWE) concerns, with support in mainstreaming gender equality in all functions following a gender audit and capacity needs assessment. Follow-up initiatives included the introduction of a HeforShe Advocacy strategy promoting male MP champions for GEWE and the production/dissemination of a handbook on gender mainstreaming and programming. &#xA0; Output 2 The Government of Tanzania has enhanced capacity to comply with International and Regional human rights standards and implement recommendations from human rights mechanisms, including those related to access to justice for women, children and other vulnerable groups. There is a clear recognition that during this period there have been some challenging developments in the country however, despite these developments quite a number of important activities have been advanced under UNDAP II. The UN reports that the Government of Tanzania has increased its capacity to comply with human rights standards during the reporting period, especially in areas related to access to justice for women and children and other vulnerable groups. Legal Aid services were expanded through a range of measures including the roll-out of a MOU between the Ministry of Constitutional and Legal Affairs, Ministry of Home Affairs, Tanzania Police Force and Tanzania Prison Services for improved access by Legal Aid Providers to prisons and other places of detention plus the piloting of a legal aid coordination mechanism which reduced bureaucracy, improved sub-national oversight and provided clear referral pathways. Furthermore, following technical and financial assistance to Tanzania Network of Legal Aid Providers (TANLAP) 127,452 people (84,932 females and 42,550 males) in Kagera region benefitted from legal aid services who would otherwise been left unserved. In addition, access to justice specifically for minors was also improved with UN support. Following trainings of 500+ personnel attached to 130 Juvenile Courts, magistrate adherences to statutes of limitations (adhering to the maximum time after a criminal act within which legal proceeding shall be initiated) was increased and reviews of past cases were undertaken, with fewer children sent to prison as a result. In addition, child protection was integrated into the training curriculum of an estimated 4,500 community-based paralegals and the Zanzibar Kadhi Court Rules were amended to include the best interest of the child and presence of Social Workers during hearings. Further, the Ministry of Health, Community Development, Gender, Elderly and Children (MHCDGEC) signed Community Rehabilitation Programme Guidelines (CRP), formalizing diversion for children in conflict with the law. Rather than focusing on punishment, diversion programmes aim at rehabilitation of the offender and prevention of further offences by seeking to address the underlying factors that contribute to criminal behaviour. Tanzania mainland now has three such CRPs operating independent of UN financial support with six more in development. &#xA0; Output 3 Relevant Governance stakeholders have increased capacities to generate, analyse and use evidence to formulate and implement gender responsive, inclusive policies, strategies and programmes for the most marginalized. With UN support, the Government of Tanzania met their reporting obligations with submissions for the CEDAW Mid Term Review and the Beijing Platform for Action 25+. The Government also presented their 2019 Voluntary National Review (VNR) at the High-Level Political Forum in New York in July 2019. In the lead-up, the MHCDGEC was assisted to engage with the VNR national technical team to produce a Gender Report for the relevant SDGs, thereby ensuring GEWE concerns were strongly represented. The UN also reports that their support has ensured that relevant Governance stakeholders now are more capable of generating, analysing and using evidence to inform policies, strategies and programmes. One important example includes the expansion of the Simplified Birth Registration System (SBRS) for children under five from 11 to 13 regions with approximately 3.6 million now registered and issued with a birth certificate. This is an increase of the overall birth certification rate in the 13 regions from 12.7% (2012) to 42.9% on the mainland and 9.3% (2012) to 80.2% in Zanzibar and represents significant progress under SDG 16.9.1. Another example concerns gender responsive budgeting where relevant stakeholders now have improved their capacity to cost, track and report on public resource allocations following the finalisation of Guidelines to operationalize the Gender and Development Policy (2016) in Zanzibar and the development of a matrix to track resource allocations across MDAs and LGAs developed by the Gender Mainstreaming Working Group-Macro Policy. Progress towards Outcomes results Womens Political Participation and Leadership&#xA0;Interventions under this outcome were intended to increase the number of women who will stand for upcoming elections. During this period some of the key results included: 1. Capacities of 289 key stakeholders (232 women; 57 men) from Mainland and Zanzibar were strengthened on gender gaps in five election related laws through training sessions. 2. Information Lab has been set up to raise awareness on violence against women in politics.The information Laboratory has a role to collect, analyse, disseminate data and raise awareness on VAWP and has been established in collaboration with the University of Dar es Salaam Department of Political Science and the Institute of Gender Studies.&#xA0;A total of 32 women aspirants have been supported by the Information Lab. 3. Capacity of 402 political party leaders (202 women, 200 men) were trained on their role to advance WLPP and hence their capacities strengthened on this area. 4. Three women were appointed to the Ethical Committee by ZEC as a result of policy level advocacy and dialogues with the Zanzibar Electoral Committee. 5. Advocacy through TWPG and WROs undertaken on the inclusion of GEWE principles in the Political Parties (Amendment) Act, 2019. 6. A comprehensive training manual to strengthen capacities of political parties on women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation was developed. furthermore, a comprehensive Training of trainers manual and workbook for women aspiring for political leadership was adopted.  7. Two political parties&#x2019; manifestos have specific provisions indicating commitment to promote WLPP and unofficial data from&#xA0; parliamentary parties indicated an increase of 7% of nominations of women for Parliament positions. 8. In 2019, all the 19 registered political parties adopted a formula to guide the selection of women aspirants for the transformational leadership trainings. 9. A total of 202 women leaders from all registered political parties were trained on their role to promote women&#x2019;s leadership and participation and committed to influence nominations. 10. An assessment on the strength and weaknesses of women wings in political parties was conducted to identify gaps and provide recommendations for improvement.  11. The Tanzania Chapter of African Women Leaders Network was launched on the 26th of February 2020. Over 200 women and young women leaders in politics, academia, research, civil society, civil service, the private sector, women living in rural areas, and the media are members and participated in the launch.  12. A total of 361 Womens Rights Organisations and networks are implementing various interventions to advance women&#x2019;s leadership and political participation in Tanzania Mainland and Zanzibar.  Progress towards Outcome Ending Violence Against Women and Children 1. The Government became a signatory to the WeProtect Statement of Action, which presents opportunities for Tanzania to access global expertise in formulating policies, legislation and programmes to tackle online exploitation and abuse of children. 2. Increased advocacy for the inclusion of interventions (and budgets) to implement the National Plan of Action to End Violence Against Women and Children in the national planning and budgeting guidelines for 2018/2019 resulted in 8 key Ministries committing USD 2million. 3. Increased efforts to strengthen violence prevention and response services resulted in the renovation of six Mainland and 3 Zanzibar Police and Gender Desks. Training of Police Officers was also done in order to build their capacity to provide a comprehensive, respectful and effective response to violence cases. The Tanzania Police Force was also supported to develop national Guidelines on the Gender Responsive Reporting System, which has been disseminated to police stations nationwide. 4. Development of a mobile phobe application that will be linked to the District case management system ( DCMS) and hence improve case and data management as it will enable Social Welfare Officers to receive information on initial investigation of child protection cases. 5. Strengthened capacity of service providers to ensure accessibility and availability of essential services for women survivors of violence and Social workers in Dodoma and Shinyanga assigned to provide psychosocial support for women traders and vendors in the marketplace. 6. Advocacy efforts resulted in reporting of 2,163 cases of violence against women and girls following activities organised by community and youth activists, community development officers and healthcare workers across six districts. furthermore, a total of 14,245 cases of violnce against women were reported at Police Gender and Children Desks in Mainland and 752 cases reported in Zanzibar. 7. In the education sector, the UN partnership with the Ministry of Education and Presidents Office-Regional and Local Government resulted in training of teachers to provide guidance and counselling services and to assist establishment of TUSEME ( Lets Speak Out) Clubs. 2,227 primary schools were reached in Mbeya, Iringa and Njombe. In Zanzibar, 463 Guidance and Counselling Teachers in 232 schools have been trained and 138,912 students recived messages on the prevention and response to violnce.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="51170098" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1061203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000.0" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2020-01-01">
    <title>Tanzania 2020-2024</title>
    <titleSV>Tanzania 2020-2024</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
