<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="sida-so" dstore:index="55" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10577A0101-SOM-43010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 SOMALIA RESILIENCE PROGRAM 2</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 SOMALIA RESILIENS PROGRAM 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The Sida-funded Somalia Resilience Programme (SOMREP) aims to support vulnerable pastoral and farming households in the rural and peri-urban areas of Somalia. SOMREP is implemented by a consortium of 7 international agencies and was established in response to the 2011 drought in hopes to prevent  future disasters. In the context of climatic variability, poverty and the fragile political and security environment in Somalia, it is critical to have the adequate coping mechanisms to withstand recurring shocks and disasters such as drought and conflicts. The programme aims to enable households to adapt, absorb and transform these shocks into something manageble. SOMREP interventions help equip the targeted households  with  with the proper tools, resources and competencies to increase their household productivity. Some of the interventions include resource management, early warning systems, business development, livelihood support, animal husbandry, farming, cash-transfers and other safety-nets and resiliene building efforts.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Det Sida-finansierade Somalia Resilience Programmet (SOMREP) syftar till att st&#xF6;dja s&#xE5;rbara pastorala och jordbrukshush&#xE5;ll i landsbygdsomr&#xE5;dena samt i urbana omr&#xE5;den i Somalia. SOMREP implementeras av ett konsortium best&#xE5;ende av 7 internationella organisationer och bildades i respons till torkan  2011 i hopp om att f&#xF6;rhindra framtida katastrofer. I samband med klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring, fattigdom och den sk&#xF6;ra politiska och s&#xE4;kerhetsmilj&#xF6;n i Somalia &#xE4;r det kritiskt att ha tillr&#xE4;ckliga hanteringsmekanismer f&#xF6;r att motst&#xE5; &#xE5;terkommande chocker och katastrofer s&#xE5;som torka och konflikter. Programmet syftar till att g&#xF6;ra det m&#xF6;jligt f&#xF6;r hush&#xE5;llen att anpassa, absorbera och omvandla dessa chocker till n&#xE5;got hanterbart. SOMREP-insatser hj&#xE4;lper till att utrusta hush&#xE5;llen med passande verktyg, resurser och kompetenser f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka deras hush&#xE5;llsproduktivitet. N&#xE5;gra av insatserna inkluderar resurshantering, tidiga varningssystem, aff&#xE4;rsutveckling, f&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjningsst&#xF6;d, djurh&#xE5;llning, jordbruk, kontant&#xF6;verf&#xF6;ringar och andra s&#xE4;kerhetsn&#xE4;t och resiliensbyggandeinsatser.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the programme is to: increase the resilience of chronically vulnerable people (disaggregated by Age, Gender &amp;amp; Diversity - AGD), HHs, communities and systems in targeted pastoral, agro-pastoral and peri-urban livelihood zones
SomReP proposes to allocate funding for Phase 2 for the next three years from 2018 - 2021 according to 5 Outcome areas:
- Outcome 1: Enhanced risk management and disaster preparedness through community action and contingency planning in Somaliland and Puntland- Outcome 2: Enhanced food security and capacity to meet social needs through sustainable cash-based assistance mechanisms and improved access to social capital - Outcome 3: Enhanced livelihood diversification for women, men, and youth through the restoration and protection of productive assets, value chains and the uptake and adoption of agricultural technology- Outcome 4: Enhanced management and governance of natural resources, including soil and water systems to support sustainable pastoral livelihoods - Outcome 5: Program learning and research generated and shared among relevant stakeholders (including communities, NGOs, and government)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21502" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21502" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.5 - By 2030, build the resilience of the poor and those in vulnerable situations and reduce their exposure and vulnerability to climate-related extreme events and other economic, social and environmental shocks and disasters.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.5 - Till 2030 bygga upp motst&#xE5;ndskraften hos de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer och minska deras utsatthet och s&#xE5;rbarhet f&#xF6;r extrema klimatrelaterade h&#xE4;ndelser och andra ekonomiska, sociala och milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssiga chocker och katastrofer.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.1 - Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.1 - St&#xE4;rka motst&#xE5;ndskraften mot och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatrelaterade faror och naturkatastrofer i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.2 - Achieve higher levels of economic productivity through diversification, technological upgrading and innovation, including through a focus on high-value added and labour-intensive sectors.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.2 - Uppn&#xE5; h&#xF6;gre ekonomisk produktivitet genom diversifiering, teknisk uppgradering och innovation, bland annat genom att fokusera p&#xE5; sektorer med h&#xF6;gt f&#xF6;r&#xE4;dlingsv&#xE4;rde och h&#xF6;g arbetsintensitet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3052884.1252551316</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1558584.2101262799</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4101994.6360902092</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">3052884.125255123</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4101994.63609021</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-9e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1558584.2101262808</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">8566080.436552</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">2418359.6484734397</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">634524.4767816919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">1022777.3532254037</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">535806.7993528562</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/somalia/10577---decision---somrep.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision -SOMREP 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/somalia/10577---agreement-amendment---somrep.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement amendment -SOMREP 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/somalia/10577---decision-on-amendment---somrep.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision amendment -SOMREP 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/somalia/10577---agreement---somrep.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement -SOMREP 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2019 CoP covers 2 interlinked reporting periods:&#xA0; 1. The annual reporting period (1 January 2019-31 December 2019)2. The drought response reporting period (1 November 2019 - 28 February 2020) Results from the annual reporting period (January 2019-December 2019) include: 1.&#xA0; The Gender Sensitive Climate Vulnerability and Capacity Assessment (GCVCA) has been completed followed by the development of village-based contingency plans. With regards to the latter, 73% of 2019 targets have been completed. Unfortunately, the process of developing village-based contingency plans has been interrupted by severe drought that struck Somaliland in mid-2019 and consequently, the community&#x2019;s priorities have shifted to life-saving interventions. &#xA0; 2. A total of 183&#xA0;Village Savings and Loans Associations (VSLAs) groups were established across the project regions, which represents 68% of the annual target. 3. In addition to the establishment of the VSLAs, a total of 87 VSLA groups with 739 individual members have been trained on money saving methodology, fundamental principles and schedule of operations of VSLA. This represents 35% of targeted value for the reporting period. 4. Moreover, 22 groups (11% of 2019 targeted value) with 375 members have been given an additional training on good hygiene practices aimed towards improving the sanitation and hygiene status of the household with the overall objective of changing the behavior and attitude of the beneficiaries. 5. Furthermore, 21 groups (11% of 2019 target value) with 520 members have been trained in life skills and gender empowerment topics while 20 groups (63% of 2019 targeted value) with 360 members have been trained in good nutrition practices. 6. In the reporting period the project has nearly completed (73%) the registration of beneficiaries for Cash for Work (cfW) activities. 94% of targeted beneficiaries implement CfW projects through conditional cash in line with&#xA0;Community Action Adaptation Plans (CAAPs). 7. The project made good progress with establishing Pastoral and Farmer Field Schools (P/FFS), Fishermen&#x2019;s group and related training curricula to enhance livelihood diversification through the restoration and protection of productive assets, value chains and the uptake and adoption of agricultural technologies. The targets set for 2019 in relation to FFS has been achieved at 83%. 100 farmers (100% target) have received relevant training and 76% of targeted farmers in the reporting period received agricultural inputs. Unfortunately, targets in relation to kitchen gardens and youth training and skills development have not been met. Following an initial assessment on youth skills needs and enterprise placement requirements, only 18% of 2019 targeted value were able to graduate during the reporting period. 8. The project team has completed the mapping of demand and supply for water resources for livestock, agricultural and household needs. Unfortunately, only 3% (1 out of 31 targeted structure for 2019) have been rehabilitated during the reporting period. The remaining infrastructure will be rehabilitated in the following year (2020).&#xA0; 9. With regards to program learning and research, the first Annual Resilience Measurement (ARM) study was conducted. Key findings include a significant increase in food security between 2017 and 2019, a strong correlation between HH dietary diversity and VSLA ownership, the existence of gender disparities regarding ownership of assets and the necessity of further inclusion of social, cultural and local factors in respect of targeting beneficiaries. Additionally, the project was able to support the Resilience Innovation Lab (RIL) by conducting meetings with donors and learning institutions. Results from the drought response (1 November 2019 to 28 February 2020) The drought response was a four month emergency intervention from November 2019 to February 2020, and was implemented across Awdal Region (Lughaya), North West (Salahley) and Khatumo village in Odweyne in Somaliland. Core activities implemented included unconditional cash transfers (UCT), cash for work (CfW), water trucking and the construction of a communal berkad. The response was undertaken by 2 of the SOMREP consortium partners, World Vision and DRC. The key achievements were: 1. A total of 828 vulnerable households (520 female, 308 male) were reached with unconditional cash transfers. Three cycles of cash distributions were conducted between November and December 2019 during which each household received $105 per month. 2. In response to the water scarcity endured by the Garaaca community of Lughaya, the programme delivered a total of 880,000 litres of water to 300 households (162 female-headed, 138 male-headed). Each household received 133 litre per day for 22 days. 3. Using community-based targeting, DRC reached 1,025 beneficiaries (468 male, 557 female) through Cash for Work (CfW).&#xA0; Of the total beneficiaries reached (1,025), 500 received three cash payments, while the other 525 received one payment as per the January budget revision. As a result of this, 35 hectares of pastureland was rehabilitated through earth works including terracing, erosion control measures and check dams. 4. In addition, 8 garbage pits were dug to dispose and promote clean environment. Furthermore, the enhanced purchasing power of the beneficiaries helped stimulate the small businesses in the target area as the cash flow was improved through the unconditional and conditional cash transfers to the beneficiaries. 5. To address the recurring water shortages, a communal berkad was constructed with the overall objective of harnessing surface rainwater and storing it for use by both livestock and humans in Khatumo Village. The communal berkad has an estimated water capacity of 467 cubic meter which can serve 800 (323 male, 477 female) beneficiaries (of which 200 beneficiaries are IDPs) and about 6,000 heads of livestock (sheep, goat, camel) for at least 3 months. The newly constructed communal berkad also ensures that beneficiaries are able to access a close water source instead of having to travel long distances. The M&amp;amp;E unit conducted post distribution monitoring assessments (PDMs) after each cycle during the drought response. The aim of the assessment was to get beneficiary perception as well their feedback on the distributions to inform about program quality. According to the PDM findings, beneficiaries reported that they were satisfied with cash as means of support and expressed their preference to receive cash rather than food/goods. COVID-19 Response:&#xA0;Though the drought response intervention was successful, there was a remaining&#xA0; balance of SEK 474,474.66 which SomReP&#xA0;&#xA0;has requested to allocate to support COVID-19 activities mostly related to messaging, hygiene and business facilitation.&#xA0;During the COVID-19 period,&#xA0;&#xA0;SomReP has attempted to leverage its role as a platform to identify and scale best practice by&#xA0;providing standard sanitation interventions, including locally purchased soap coupled with hand-washing stations. &#xA0;Also, the program is piloting the use of internet-enabled tablets as a means to deliver COVID-19 messages through the Early Warning Committees at community level. In addition, the program further&#xA0;aims to develop and disseminate COVID-19 awareness&#xA0;information through the Somalia Resilience Innovation Lab (SomRIL)&#xA0;that is hosted by the programme&#xA0;to&#xA0;deliver&#xA0; hygiene messaging through traditional&#xA0;and social&#xA0;media platforms. SomReP has since supported the development of several videos and accompanying posters, and radio drama, and piloting the use of Surprise Soap (a soap with a toy inside) that has proven to be very effective and supporting behaviour change in hand washing practices especially for children who can be carriers/transimtters of the virus and other infectious diseases.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="10577" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060903" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000.0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <title>Somalia 2018-2022</title>
    <titleSV>Somalia 2018-2022</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
