<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="oneacrefund-activities" dstore:index="6" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-DOS-64562614-XM-DAC-7-PPR-29032/Rwanda</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-DOS-64562614" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading the Charge to Eradicate Rural Poverty</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our prior project with the Dutch Government, &#x201C;Subsistence to Self-Reliance &#x2013; Bringing the Power of Markets to Africa&#x2019;s Lowest-Income Farmers&#x201D; underscored our shared passion for inclusive economic development and showcased the key milestones that we can accomplish together. Core operating support from DGIS facilitated the strategic expansion of One Acre Fund&#x2019;s &#x2018;impact ecosystem.&#x2019; Within two years, we doubled the scale of our farmer network, launched operations in two new country programs (Malawi and Uganda), and rolled out impactful new products like tree planting kits and clean cookstoves at country-wide scale. Simultaneously, we refined our innovative systems-change platform, leveraging our core organizational competencies to improve large-scale public and private actors&#x2019; service to smallholders. This success has now placed One Acre Fund in a position where we can realistically envision moving the needle on hunger and poverty across the entire African continent. Our current project with DGIS, &#x201C;Leading the Charge to Eradicate Rural Poverty,&#x201D; aims to capture this powerful opportunity. The project involves a smartly structured two-part investment spanning September 15, 2018 &#x2013; December 31, 2022: First, DGIS is once again providing critical support to the varied, evolving platforms within our organization that lay the foundation for our growth and impact. Core operating support from DGIS will enhance and extend One Acre Fund&#x2019;s proven model by funding key strategic priorities across our M&amp;E, R&amp;D, and new country expansion units. Secondly, DGIS is also providing working capital to revolutionize One Acre Fund&#x2019;s growth trajectory. This injection to our &#x2018;permanent fund&#x2019; will completely fund our projected expansion of 245,000+ new farm families in 2019, bringing us past the 1 millionth farmer milestone. Crucially, farmers&#x2019; loan repayments will replenish our permanent fund each year, allowing us to re-extend this contribution to provide input loans to an estimated 245,000 farm families (including over 980,000 children) annually. This project will anchor One Acre Fund&#x2019;s expansion to directly serve 1.85 million farm families annually by year-end 2022. Simultaneously, it will help us reach an additional 3.5 million farmers via systems-change partnerships that are expressly designed to transform entire agricultural ecosystems. Together, the reach of these efforts will generate transformative change for rural communities across rural Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda Q4 2020 Country Update: In Rwanda, Q4 spanned both the end of the 2021A season as well as the beginning of the 2021B season (both which correspond to 2021 reporting). Planting for 21A concluded in October, and enrollment for the 21B season occurred in October/November. For the latter season, we enrolled farmers entirely through a mobile phone-based system &#x2014; developed in response to COVID-19 movement restrictions. We also concluded our 2020 tree campaign during the reporting period; through this work, we delivered 15 million agroforestry tree seedlings, plus 135,000 avocado trees.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-DOS-64562614" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Note that while project activities commenced on 2016-01-01, the grant agreement was signed on 2018-10-09.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Whitney McFerron</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Associate, One Acre Fund</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+33660474246</telephone>
   <email>whitney.mcferron@oneacrefund.org</email>
   <website>http://www.oneacrefund.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31150" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31193" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31192" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage divided evenly among the four components of One Acre Fund&apos;s core model.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <related-activity ref="US-DOS-64562614-XM-DAC-7-PPR-29032-1" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core program scale</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared in 2020 Q4 or 2021 Q1, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farm families participating in One Acre Fund&apos;s core program.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="385,000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are excited to report that our Rwanda program is achieving another year of rapid growth, fueled by high farmer demand for our services. In 2019, we served 385,000 farm families &#x2013; putting us on an exciting trajectory to achieve transformative scale countrywide.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="464859">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We reached 618,000 farm families in Rwanda through our core program in 2020, adding 235,000 clients and expanding by 62%. Key to this breakthrough growth included tech solutions for enabling operations in the COVID-19 context &#x2014; in particular, nation-wide scale-up of USSD enrollment has allowed client signup and product ordering without face-to-face contact with our staff. A further key underlying factor in our expansion this year was robust government support; we were encouraged by the government to expand to reach each of Rwanda&#x2019;s agricultural districts where we had not yet established operations. This invitation reflects the government&#x2019;s deep trust in our program and our strong support for government priorities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="TBD"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Systems-Change scale</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared in 2020 Q4 or 2021 Q1, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farm families reached through systems - change unit.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="2340000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">After years of scaling our partnerships, Rwanda has come to present a special opportunity for achieving true whole country change. 1AF now works in every major channel to meet the farmer where she is (core program for farmers who value credit and group engagement, rural retail for farmers who prefer to pay cash for inputs, extension channel for farmers who prefer free services), and across most productivity factors (seed production and demand stimulation, fertilizer demand stimulation, best agricultural practice, poultry, and trees).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2704000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda continues to represent one of our largest, most impactful, and uniquely dynamic programs. Our strong alignment with the Rwandan government&apos;s national priorities continues to boost our long-term goal of reaching every farming household country-wide through our core program or partnerships. In 2020, this work reached over 3 million farmer touchpoints (individual project interactions); projects sought to catalyze local hybrid seed production, improve agricultural extension services, and expand the country&apos;s rural retail sector.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Return on Investment (SROI)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared in 2020 Q4 or 2021 Q1, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared in Q4 or Q1 of subsequent year, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Acre Fund&apos;s key cost-effectiveness measure.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="7.3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, our Rwanda program achieved an SROI of 7.3 - a healthy improvement from our 2018 SROI of 4.9.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6.4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We project that for 2020, our Rwanda program will achieve an SROI of 6-7, meaning that we generated $6-7 in farmer impact for every donor dollar received. Despite the substantial challenges of operating during COVID-19, our 2020 SROI result is only slightly below our 2019 result of 7.3. Movement restrictions and other effects posed extreme financial pressure on subsistence farmers, hurting loan repayment and thus our revenues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final &apos;Actual&apos; figures will be shared in 2020 Q4 or 2021 Q1, upon completion of One Acre Fund&apos;s rigorous evaluation activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The profit boost achieved by farming with One Acre Fund.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="118">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final M&amp;E data indicates that our Rwanda program generated an average impact of $118 per family. In 2019, impact remained very strong, driven by maize and potatoes. Prices were higher than in 2018 for all crops, and bean harvest improvements were also strong.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="116">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are still analyzing data from the 2020 harvest, so our impact estimates remain preliminary. Based on the information we currently have, we foresee a likely impact shortfall relative to 2019 levels ($118) due to a difficult weather year in key operating areas, and challenges delivering training given COVID-19 (e.g., no group trainings, fewer one-on-one visits to farmers fields).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
