<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="acet-activities" dstore:index="5" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-03T23:09:50+00:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-03T21:53:01+00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-11-3803281-Operations</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-11-3803281" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Events and Communication</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">These are core activities associated with organising events for projects,
 communication and disseminating reports. Since the launch of the African Transformation Report in October 2017, communications activities have focused on organizing mini-launch events. Two of such was organised in the United States of America. Across Africa, there were events in Ghana, Cote d&apos;Ivoire, Ethiopia and Botswana. Communication and event activities were also undertaken towards and during the African Transformation Forum in June 2018. During 2018, ACET was tagged on Twitter in a call for applications for the prestigious Prospect Think Tank awards and awarded Best Global Economic Think Tank. We also experienced a significant increase in ACET mentions in both traditional and social media. During the first quarter of 2019, the team uploaded ACET&#x2019;s 2016, 2017 and 2018 annual report on the website. Additionally, six (6) of our reports were uploaded or published together with the Brookings Institution&#x2019;s Foresight Africa 2019 publication. By close of March 2019, ACET had been referenced twenty (18) times in publications by the African Perspective on Global Development and the Institute for Global Dialogue in association with UNISA to mention a few. We also received 11 media mentioning and 14 invitations to participate in non-ACET events in the capacity of speakers, panel moderators and participants. Our flagship report ATR2 (Overview, full report and French version) was downloaded 668 times during the same period. Overall, ACET recorded a total of 844 downloads for all our published papers and reports during the 1st quarter. Click here for the detailed 1st quarter report from the communications department. In Q2 of 2019, ACET published the &#x2018;Future of Work in Africa: Implications for Secondary Education and TVET Systems&#x2019; report. The report explores the impact of changes brought on by the Fourth Industrial Revolution (4IR) on secondary level education and Technical, Vocational education and Training systems. We also uploaded the ATF 2018 Full Report. We published several opinion pieces and blogs. The Director and Senior Advisor at ACET, Rob Floyd, published his piece &#x2018;Quality Infrastructure in Africa: Japan and the CwA&#x2019;, which discusses the Japanese presidency of the G20 and its implications on Africa, especially with regard to the Compact with Africa and the priority of quality infrastructure in Africa. We also published a blog written by Sanjeev Guptaand Mark Plant, titled &#x201C;Enhancing domestic resource mobilisation: what are the real obstacles?&#x2019;. The piece, which was originally published on the website of the Center for Global Development where Gupta is a Visiting Senior Fellow, summarised key issues emerging from a roundtable of finance ministers held during the week of the IMF/World Bank Spring meetings. ACET also co-curated content for the World Economic Forum&#x2019;s African Transformation Maps, which is part of its Transformation Maps series. Media Monitoring ACET was mentioned eight times in two papers - the Business and Financial Times, and the Business Finder. ACET was also mentioned 116 times in online media, including AllAfrica.com, GhanaWeb, The Africa Report, Modern Ghana, Citi News, Myjoyonline.com and the reporter Ethiopia. Information gathered from our google alert revealed a fall in the total number of citations received from 18 in the 1st quarter to 13 this 2nd quarter. ACET procured a team to support the implementation of an ACET communications strategy We published 3 blogs during the 4th quarter of 2019: - The Imperative of Economic Transformation written by Rob Floyd. - The Challenges and Opportunities for Smallholder Voices by Adiel Mbabu - Why industrialisation is vital for the African Continental Free Trade Agreement to succeed by Dr. Arkebe Oqubay In December, we supported the Legatum Institute, an American Think Tank, to launch their Global Economic Openness Index- Ghana Report, a report developed from their Global Economic Openness Index. ACET&#x2019;s website recorded an increase in users from 15K in the second quarter to 20K in the fourth quarter resulting in 24K sessions. ACET&#x2019;s publications were downloaded 436 times in the 3rd quarter and 444 times during the last quarter of 2019. i. The communications team in the review period had three reports published on: &#x2022; Promoting Women and Youth Financial Inclusion for Entrepreneurship and Job Creation: Synthesis Report &#x2022; Promoting Women and Youth Financial Inclusion for Entrepreneurship and Job Creation: Comparative Study of Selected Sub-Saharan African Countries &#x2013; Zambia Country Brief &#x2022; Promoting Women and Youth Financial Inclusion for Entrepreneurship and Job Creation: Comparative Study of Selected Sub-Saharan African Countries &#x2013; Guinea Country Brief We also published 4 articles and blogs as well as 2 discussion papers during the period. A total of 24000 users visited ACET&#x2019;s website, indicating a surge of about 7.3% over the previous quarter. ACET further recorded significant developments on our website and social media page. For instance, the financial inclusion synthesis report was downloaded 1736 times by varying audiences in q1. The link here details our published documents and the occurrence of activities on our website and social media page.
In Q2 2020:
ACET published one main report on Blended Finance as well as several blogs, articles and press releases this quarter. We also advanced significantly in our website and social media activities. Some publications this quarter include

Blogs: 
&#x2022;	How Badly Will the Coronavirus Impact Africa&#x2019;s Economies? By Yohannis Mulu Tessema and John Kojo Osei 
&#x2022;	Fiscal Social Contracts and Domestic Resource Mobilization in Sub-Saharan Africa by Richmond Commodore 
&#x2022;	How Africa Can Fight the Pandemic by Arkebe Oqubay 

Discussion Papers: 
&#x2022;	COVID-19: Ten Policy Priorities for Africa&#x2019;s Recovery, Growth, and Transformation by ACET 

Reports: 
&#x2022;	Strengthening the Local Dimension of Blended Finance by ACET, OECD, ECDPM, CWA 

Press releases 
&#x2022;	TLP to discuss policy priorities for Africa&#x2019;s Post COVID-19 recovery  
&#x2022;	Leadership Group Discusses Priority Issues for African Recovery 
&#x2022;	ACET, IMF To Hold Webinar on Africa&#x2019;s Post-COVID-19 Recovery and Growth 
&#x2022;	Press release: Mavis Owusu-Gyamfi to join ACET in new role of Executive Vice President

Q3 2020
Schools, Skills and Jobs series. 
With information from our recently launched background study for Mastercard Foundation&#x2019;s Secondary Education in Africa Report, ACET produced and published a four-part in-depth series on &#x2018;Schools, Skills and Jobs&#x2019;. The articles published between August 31 and September 28 covered four topics: Africa&#x2019;s Evolving Labour Landscape, High Potential Pathways for Productive Jobs, Getting Schools and Skills Right and Policy Actions for the Future of Work.

Interviews: To enhance our profile and impact on society, ACET granted several interviews. These included interviews with CNBC Africa on policies for Africa&#x2019;s post COIVD-19 recovery, the B&amp;FT and the Institute for New Economic Thinking (INET) on their COVID-19 series. The Belt and Road Portal, a market intelligence and business facilitation platform also interviewed our Director of Research, on the 7th anniversary of the Initiative. This interview marked ACET&#x2019;s status as the only African Think Tank on the Belt and Road Studies Network (BRSN) initiators council. Both the INET and Belt and Road interviews are yet to be published.

Website: The ACET website has been redesigned to ensure that no story goes beyond 30 days on the home page. Analytics from our site suggest that visitors to the site in the third quarter spent on average, one minute and 23 seconds, a 44% increase in time spent from the previous quarter.

While improving engagement on our current site, ACET, supported by the Bewsys website development firm is at an initial phase of building a new and improved website with new features that deliver an optimal user experience.

Q4 2020
In Q4 2020, ACET&#x2019;s communications team published multiple pieces including a blog, two discussion papers, one press release and several event-related news articles. We also continued online and media engagement through our website and social media platforms as detailed below. 
&#x2022;	Blogs: Africa after COVID19: Policy Priorities to drive economic transformation 

&#x2022;	Discussion Papers: 

o	ACET published Strengthening the digital partnership between Africa and Europe, a discussion paper based on special series on Africa-EU relations during the German EU presidency, produced by members of the European Think Tank Group (ETTG) of which ACET is a member. Download the full ETTG paper here. Authors: By Chux Daniels (ACET and the University of Sussex), Benedikt Erforth (DIE), Rob Floyd (ACET), and Chloe Teevan (ECDPM) 
o	Edward K. Brown and George Boateng co &#x2013;authored the paper, The politics of market integration in Africa: Trade agreements, protocols, and the &#x2018;crisis of implementation&#x2019;, which looked at the politics of market integration and how to overcome &#x2018;the crisis f implementation&#x2019;. 
	
&#x2022;	Press releases: ACET Launches Africa&#x2019;s First AI Challenge for Infrastructure 

&#x2022;	Website Statistics: ACET&#x2019;s website also saw 34,000 visitors for the period, many of whom were referred from our social media platforms, particularly LinkedIn. 

&#x2022;	Social Media: Our media platforms gained 674 followers, 600,000 impressions, and 3731 visits combined. 

External/Media Engagements:
o	ACET Senior Director, Dr. Ed Brown joined Dr. Folashad&#xE9; Soul&#xE9; and Dr. Camilla Toulmin for the INET&#x2019;s Commission on Global Economic Transformation (CGET)&#x2019;s COVID-19 and Africa Series. The series engages African/Africa-based economists and experts about their perspectives on economic transformation and how the COVID situation re-shapes the options and pathways for Africa&#x2019;s development. They discussed the effects of COVID-19 on regional integration and economic transformation in Africa, and the role of ACET and African think tanks in advising African governments respond to the crisis. Edward Brown: &#x201C;Growth with &#x2018;DEPTH&#x2019; should guide economic transformation in Africa&#x201D;

o	ACET Senior Fellow Chux Daniels, joined the Foundation for studies and Research on International Development (FERDI) to discuss the role of digital policies and regulations in addressing the inequalities exposed by the COVID-19 pandemic in various sectors. ACET Senior Fellow discusses Digital Policies in Africa at FERDI webinar</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core ACET activities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government of Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Center for Economic Transformation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="20"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="20"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="BW" percentage="20"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="US" percentage="20"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="20"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="91010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">115900</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">63000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">82000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">53050</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">58600</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">754.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">8517.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">16808.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">17543</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">21904.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">36000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC01 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">3280.23</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from Oct to Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC01 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">4709.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated travel/hotel etc cost from Oct to Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET ECO1 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">437.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from Oct to Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET EC01 Q4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">64.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost from Oct to Dec 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">68567.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy costs</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">48000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">173</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Travel costs accumulated</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">22711.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff costs</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">3075.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">456.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cost of workshops and lectures</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">51.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Publication</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-30">33797.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from January to June 2018</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-30">20630.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from January to June 2018</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-30">69030</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultancy cost from July-September</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-30">3470</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff cost from July-September</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-30">1345</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative expenses from July-September</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-30">1328.39</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated administrative costs from January to June 2018</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-30">49.41</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cost of publications</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC01 Q2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">22313.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost for the period April-June 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-31">10869.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from Jan -March 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-31">38472.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from Jan-March 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-31">406.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated cost of lecture and workshop from Jan- March 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Accumulated cost of lecture and workshop from Jan- March 2019">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-31">1865.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost from Jan- March 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC01 Q2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">17585.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated expenditure incurred on communication and publications</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC01 Q2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-30">7902.99</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the second quarter (April-June 2019)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1.ACET EC01 Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">12118</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consltancy cost incurred from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC01 Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">5236</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated Staff cost from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC01 Q2 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">367</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated administrative expenses incurred from April-June 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC01 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">11585</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost for October-December 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC01 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">11052</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost for the period October-December 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC01 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">2500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated administrative expenses for the period October-December 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4.ACET EC01 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">11027</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost for the period October-December 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC01 Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">5494</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from July to September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC02 Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">13184</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from July to September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC01 Q3 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">344</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated administrative expenses incurred from July to September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4. ACET EC01 Q4 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-30">2083</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost from July-September 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-30">2579</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cost of Communication and Publication from July-September</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">12086.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from October-December</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">3622.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated staff cost from October-December</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">241.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative expenses incurred from October-December</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="ACET EC01">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">4919.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated Communication and Publication cost from October-December</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC01 Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">502.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated Administrative expenses from July to Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC01 Q3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-30">236.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost from July to Sept 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1. ACET EC01 Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">14781.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated consultancy cost from Jan-March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2. ACET EC01 Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">360.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cummulative administrative expenses from Jan-March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="3. ACET EC01 Q1 2020">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-31">1499.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accumulated communication and publication cost from Jan-March 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
