<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unitedstates-iq" dstore:index="833" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-11-IQ-SLMAQM20CA2170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combatting COVID 19 Pandemic and Pr</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase capacity to implement procedures to mitigate COVID-19 threat and establish policy institutional knowledge to prepare for future pandemics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LOUISIANA STATE UNIVERSITY A&amp;M</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>075050765</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-11" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of State</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Bureau of International Security and Nonproliferation</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-11" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of State</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-25" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-25" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of State</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Inquiry</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+1 202-647-8471</telephone>
   <email>foreignassistanceweb@state.gov</email>
   <website>http://www.foreignassistance.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2201 C Street Northwest, Washington, DC 20520</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="IQ">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq remains a vital partner to the United States in the fight to degrade and ultimately defeat the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL). Recent military, political, and economic developments have placed a higher importance on U.S. assistance to the government and people of Iraq. The United States remains committed to mutual goals of a secure and stable Iraq, with more inclusive, capable and accountable governance, manifested by more effective provision of public services to all citizens, protection and support to conflict-affected communities, and implementation of targeted economic reforms. U.S. assistance will continue to support the Government of Iraq (GOI) in attaining these goals and responding to urgent needs likely to arise in this fluid environment.To enhance the ability of the GOI to contribute independently and substantively to degrading and defeating ISIL, targeted assistance will build the capacity and professionalism of Iraqi Security Forces (ISF); support the GOI&apos;s efforts to respond to the needs of large numbers of displaced persons, and the communities hosting them; hold and stabilize areas recovered from ISIL; and implement the economic as well as political reforms needed to respond more effectively and equitably to the needs of the Iraqi people. Ensuring the GOI&apos;s active and visible role in responding to stabilization and reconstruction, supporting reforms that enhance the well-being of citizens, and demonstrating the GOI&apos;s commitment to and concrete action toward inclusive, representative, rights-respecting governance will help advance the GOI&apos;s efforts to enhance national and regional stability by bridging the country&apos;s sectarian divide. This is crucial for sustained success against extremists, including ISIL. The GOI must address these challenges in the context of a crippling economic crisis caused in part by a collapse of world oil prices that has resulted in a significant fiscal gap. U.S. assistance will help the GOI access international credit as well as provide technical assistance. Not only will this assistance reinforce the critical structural reforms underway through World Bank and International Monetary Fund programs, but it will help the GOI resource immediate and evolving stabilization needs, as well as the implementation of key economic and other critical reforms needed to promote broad-based economic resilience and growth. Success in this endeavor will have associated positive implications for U.S. business opportunities.Critical, self-directed actions undertaken by the GOI in promoting responsive governance will bolster the efficacy of the U.S. government&apos;s efforts, speed up the adoption of changes, and increase the chances for long-term sustainability of the reforms. U.S. assistance will focus on advancing good governance through strengthening accountable and effective decentralized public administration at the provincial and national levels. Activities will also include efforts to ensure respect for human rights and rule of law, with special attention paid to vulnerable populations such as women, the internally displaced, and religious and ethnic minorities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="10"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-25">1646390</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Original - COOPERATIVE AGREEMENTS</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="15220" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="1001" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Counter-Terrorism</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2019" end="2020"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1075">Non-Proliferation, Anti-Terrorism, Demining and Related Programs, International Security Assistance, State</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://fbo.gov">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federal Business Opportunities</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://grants.gov">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://fpds.gov">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federal Procurement Data System</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2020-09-25"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
