<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-ph" dstore:index="22" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-30T23:49:56" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-19T15:25:35" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-44179</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agila Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cebu Air, Inc. (Cebu Pacific or the Company), with principal address in Cebu, Philippines, is a leading low-cost carrier and one of the largest airlines in the Philippines. In 2019, it carried 22.5 million passengers over 63 destinations. The Company is seeking financing from IFC to participate in its approximately US$500 million capital fundraising plan to (i) strengthen its balance sheet and ensure that it is well-positioned to recover from the impact of COVID-19 and (ii) implement a strategic transformation plan ensuring sustainable operations post-pandemic (the Project).  The outbreak of the COVID-19 pandemic worldwide has had a severe impact on the aviation industry, with almost all players expecting revenue declines of over 50% during 2020 and embarking upon significant downsizing in the near term. The business operations of Cebu Pacific were severely impacted, as its passenger traffic has dropped by as much as 99 percent year-on-year during Q2 2020. In this difficult time, the proposed investment presents an opportunity to enable Cebu Pacific to continue to operate as a key low-cost provider of much needed connectivity across the country as well as the region for both tourism and business travel. Further, supporting a market leading carrier like Cebu Pacific navigate the crisis will aid in the recovery of other economic sectors with close linkages, particularly tourism and also prevent disruptions in regional supply chains.  The proposed IFC investment to the Company consists of an equity-linked investment of up to US$125 million in the form of convertible bond or other similar instrument. The proposed investment includes the potential mobilization of financing from IFC Asset Management Company Emerging Asia Fund.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The investment will support a leading low-cost airline in the Philippines address liquidity pressures due to the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and help maintain access to essential services for passengers and businesses. It will contribute to mitigating disruption to connectivity and help better position the company ramp up services to match growing travel demand as economic activity starts to recover. Beyond the Project, IFC anticipates that the financing will contribute to market resilience of airline sector in Philippines via market enabling channels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEBU AIR, INC.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-44179" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cebu Air, Inc.  Andrew L. Huang  Chief Finance Officer  +632-8-802-7000  Andrew.Huang@cebupacificair.com  Cebu Pacific Building, Domestic Road, Pasay City 1301 Philippines  www.cebupacificair.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         Not Applicable.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PH-Philippines">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Company is headquartered in Manila and the Project is located in Philippines. The Company, as of 2019, flew to 38 domestic destinations and 25 international destinations, through from seven strategically placed hubs: Manila, Cebu, Clark, Kalibo, Iloilo, Davao, and Cagayan de Oro.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.0000000000 122.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="481" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-AA - Air Transportation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $62.50 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/44179">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/44179">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
