<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2662" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-05-01T08:30:02+02:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-05-01T08:30:02+02:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200212</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting public health and social resilience against COVID-19 by strengthening the domestic supply chain of personal protective equipment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the proposed UNIDO project is to promote public health and social resilience against COVID-19 by strengthening the domestic supply chains of Personal Protective Equipment (PPE), disinfectants, and hygiene supplies. This project will tackle the goal through upgrading domestic producers, material suppliers, and other relevant public institutions in terms of 1) production capacity, 2) quality, and 3) business resilience &amp; continuity in emergency situations. In the project, the selected domestic producers and material suppliers will receive hands-on capacity building training by the professional trainers designated by UNIDO, based on the initial capacity assessment conducted in the inception phase. The selection of the beneficiary companies will cover both formal and informal businesses and prioritize micro-, small-, and medium enterprises (MSME), which play a pivotal role in Tanzania&#x2019;s economy.

As a part of the capacity reinforcement, necessary equipment for upgrading and enhancing production capacity will be defined and supplied, where necessary. It has been experienced during the early stage of COVID-19, protective supplies were in a serious shortage everywhere, and it caused a significant problem among health workers and institutions. Therefore, the assistance will help the country to obtain the supply capability of those critical medical and sanitary items so that the goods can reach the people, community, and especially health institutions who are in need. Furthermore, taking into account the widespread of products whose quality is low and not fulfilling quality requirements in accordance with international standards and guidelines issued by the national quality infrastructure, the project will address the enhancement of the product quality by making use of UNIDO&#x2019;s global partnership, such as, ISO and other quality-related authorities.

Importantly, the project will provide not only short-term assistance for the people, hospitals, and medical institutions, who are currently in need for the improved access to PPE, disinfectants, and hygiene supplies, but its successful implementation will also contribute to medium- and long-term humanitarian development of the country and region by anchoring stable public health and bringing stability to both economic activities and livelihood of the people.  This is fully in line with the notion of Humanitarian-Development Nexus, and the project will embody the commitment of the government of Japan across the world. The project encompasses the following outcome and outputs;

Outcome1;
The domestic supply chain of Personal Protective Equipment (PPE), disinfectants, and hygiene supplies improved in terms of 1) production capacity, 2) quality, and 3) business resilience &amp; continuity in emergency situations
Output 1;
Evaluation of the domestic supply chain of Personal Protective Equipment (PPE), disinfectants, and hygiene supplies conducted
Output 2;
Selected local manufacturers (or relevant public organization in the target supply chain) capacitated and upgraded to have improved quantitative and qualitative business capacity
Output 3;
Emergency business continuity plan developed, based on the ISO or equivalent international guidelines for occupational health and safety management (e.g. ISO/PAS 45005:2020) and awareness towards high-risk infectious respiratory diseases, including COVID-19, raised among the domestic supply chain stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200212" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="TZ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-6 35</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">392000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200212-1-02-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">324000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="TZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200212-1-02-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">1766.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="TZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
