<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-9" dstore:index="50" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-40794</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cerba Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFC is looking to provide a long-term loan to support the expansion of Cerba Lancet Africa (CLA or Company), a network of clinical diagnostic laboratories across Sub-Saharan Africa (SSA). The project will be supported by the IDA-Private Sector Window (PSW). CLA, the first pan-African diagnostics group is looking to increase its capacity across the African continent to provide diagnostics services and create well paid jobs in an area with few job opportunities (the Project). Capex will finance the upgrading and expansion of labs in its current network and support acquisitions across Sub-Saharan Africa, including IDA-PSW eligible countries, with the goal of constructing a high-quality pan-African medical diagnostics company.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The most significant Project-level outcomes is patient impact: access to good quality diagnostic services is fundamental in providing improved access and coordination of care. Currently there are many shortcomings across Africa in terms of diagnostic services. There are too few laboratories and those that exist often have poor quality control, with a limited variety of tests. The Project will fill these gaps by (1) increasing the number of patients &amp; collection points. The project plans to expand its lab network to new countries, including IDA-PSW-eligible countries. The project will also increase the number of collection points to the periphery of major cities, resulting in an estimated 0.5 million additional patients and 2.3 million additional tests; (2) introducing more accurate &amp; faster tests: Cerba will aim to expand and strengthen CLA&apos;s systems, and introduce new technology, that will lead to additional and quicker accurate testing by CLA&apos;s pathology labs, reducing costs and the need for multiple tests, and (3) introducing a greater depth of clinical tests into the markets it enters. This will allow for diagnostics of a greater range of diseases, and these diagnostics will support a greater range of treatments. 

Market Impact Assessment - the Project will enable systemic changes by increasing the competitiveness of the diagnostics market in Africa. It will do this by supporting the entry and expansion of CLA into a number of under-developed markets. These markets are characterized by relatively small providers that are under-capitalized and without the systems to ensure consistently accurate tests, as well as by the absence of regulation. CLA&apos;s expansion will place pressure on other laboratories to &quot;up their game&quot; and will demonstrate the value of its business model and so could lead to replication by other companies.

COVID-19 - African countries have fragile health systems &amp; to fight the pandemic, public authorities will need to engage the private sector. CLA is the largest pan-African lab in terms countries covered and is uniquely placed to join national COVID-19 response plans. Its labs will be amongst the few labs able to conduct COVID-19 testing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CERBA LANCET AFRICA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-40794" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cerba Lancet Africa  Mr. Stephane Carre  Chief Executive Officer  +33 6 45 67 34 38  stephane.carre@cerbahealthcare.com  11-13 Rue Ren&#xE9; Jacques, 92130 Issy-les-Moulineaux  http://www.cerbahealthcare.com/</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  Lancet Laboratories Corner    Corner Stanley and   Menton       Richmond, Johannesburg    2090, South Africa</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Africa Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project aims to upgrade and expand CLAs labs which are based in multiple countries in Sub-Saharan Africa, excluding South Africa (6 in IDA-PSW eligible countries): Kenya, Rwanda, Tanzania, Uganda, Ghana, Nigeria, Zambia, Mozambique and Swaziland. The financing will also support acquisitions across Sub-Saharan Africa including IDA-PSW eligible countries.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.0000000000 21.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="COVID-19" vocabulary="99"></tag>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $8.35 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/40794">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/40794">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
