<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2639" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200155</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Response to the COVID-19 crisis through the revitalization of the light industry sector in Armenia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The COVID-19 pandemic is primarily a global health crisis that has far-reaching economic consequences for each and every country affected by it. Worldwide, it is already disrupting millions of people&#x2019;s livelihoods, with disproportionate impact across a variety of industries, thereby jeopardizing the successful achievement of national development strategies. Amid the COVID-19 outbreak, the Armenian Government imposed a nationwide lockdown of nonessential businesses, including Textile/Clothing and Footwear/Leather Goods sectors in the second half of March 2020. As of June 2020, following lockdown measures introduced in many countries, including those where major buyers of Armenian Textile/Clothing and Footwear/Leather Goods sectors are based, Armenian producers have lost the majority of their contracts for March and April and are facing unprecedented pressures and uncertainties regarding opportunities to revitalize their businesses in the upcoming months.

In order to address this unprecedented challenge, there is a high demand for an agile and suitable response towards its socio-economic impacts, in particular concerning fragile health infrastructures and their ability to further contain the spread of the virus.

As a response to the above challenges, UNIDO has formulated a light sector support initiative aiming at supporting the Armenian Government in its efforts to prevent further spread of the novel coronavirus and enhance local SMEs&#x2019; resilience in a post-epidemic context thereby paving the way to improved flexibility and sustainability of the light industries, as well as poverty reduction. Complementary to the ongoing UNIDO project on &quot;Improving competitiveness of export-oriented industries in Armenia through modernization and market access&quot;, the proposed project is expected to produce a supportive impact on the local SMEs operating in the targeted light industries in the times of crisis helping to build a long-term resilience thereof by a) Identifying current needs in medical supplies and technical standards for the production of medical gowns, face masks, overalls, bedlinen and other items in coordination with the Ministry of Health; b) Supporting selected companies with procuring raw materials; c) Supporting the Ministry of Health and other involved institutions in placing orders to companies; d) Ensuring that the production is in line with standards and quality requirements; e) Supporting the provision of medical supplies to the Ministry of Health or other interested national institutions.

The programme will be funded from the UN COVID-19 Response and Recovery Fund, Window 2 &#x201C;Mitigating the Socio-Economic Impact on Vulnerable People and Communities&#x201D; within its priority area &#x201C;Promote digital innovations that boost employment, support livelihoods, and improve the provision of social services in line with COVID-19 response measures&#x201D;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200155" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="AM" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Armenia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.397959 45.019453</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="AM" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yerevan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.18111 44.51361</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">95279.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">7524.02</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200155-1-01-01-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">95279.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1 Employment creation supported</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200155-1-01-01-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">95279.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1 Employment creation supported</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200155-1-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">7524.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1 Employment creation supported</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200155-1-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">7523.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1 Employment creation supported</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
