<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-kz" dstore:index="11" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-04-30T23:49:39" iati-activities:version="2.02" last-updated-datetime="2021-04-22T17:40:16" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-43882</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BOP KMF-FY21</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project consists of a straight senior loan of up to US$25 million denominated in Kazakh tenge (KZT) to Limited Liability Company microfinance Organization KMF (KMF or the Company) to enable KMF to provide much needed local currency funding to micro and small enterprises (MSEs) that have been negatively affected by the COVID-19 pandemic in Kazakhstan, particularly those operating in rural and remote areas (the Project). As of end-2020, the Company had a gross loan portfolio of US$324 million and 222 thousand active clients. The Company owns a network of 14 branches and 110 outlets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholder Effects: Improved access to and quality of finance for microenterprises and SMEs - The income stream of MSMEs, has been severely affected by the lockdowns, increased uncertainty, and a slow-down in economic activity in the wake of the pandemic. As the economy re-opens, MSMEs need access to capital to finance investments in inventory and inputs to resume economic activity, and to adjust business models to the post-crisis economic environment. The project will further support the implementation of a digital transformation of KMF&apos;s products and operations. KMF expects to digitize customer onboarding, therefore enabling a digital and remote loan disbursements and collections for a large share of its MSME customers. The adoption of digital channels and delivery methods have become increasingly important to adapt to customer needs and maintain business operations in the aftermath of the COVID-19 crisis.

Resilience: IFC anticipates that project will support resilience amongst microfinance and base-of-pyramids (BOP) finance providers by helping the market deal with the growing uncertainty and catalyzing investor response. A rise in non-performing loans, and disrupted borrower cash-flows has left banks reluctant to lend directly to BOP segments. Macroeconomic instability and uncertainty on the long-term viability of their operations has led to increased difficulties in accessing the funds needed to support the recovery and growth of their lending operations. By investing in KMF, IFC will demonstrate to other investors the viability of supporting the sustainability and recovery of BOP financial service providers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MICROFINANCE ORGANIZATION KMF LLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-43882" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Limited Liability Company Microfinance Organization KMF  Ms. Elena Skufalyaridi  Treasury Manager  +77273317474  elena.skufa@kmf.kz  50, Nazarbayev ave, Almaty 050004, Republic of Kazakhstan  www.kmf.kz</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kazakhstan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="KZ-Kazakhstan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KMF is headquartered in Almaty, Kazakhstan. The Company has 14 branches and 110 outlets in Almaty, Nur-Sultan, Karaganda, Kokshetau, Kyzylorda, Pavlodar, Semei, Shymkent, Taldykorgan, Taraz, Turkestan, Ust-Kamenogorsk, Kostanay, Aktobe.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.0000000000 68.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522298 &#xA0;&#xA0;ALL OTHER NONDEPOSITORY CREDIT INTERMEDIATION" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-HA - Microfinance and Small Business - Non Commercial Banking</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="COVID-19" vocabulary="99"></tag>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/43882">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/43882">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
