<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" dstore:dataset="danida-all_4" dstore:index="2184" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-237225</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IHP efforts in relation to Ebola-crisis in Sierra Leone, 2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">An grant comprising DKK 3,958,000 to the Danish Emergency Management Agency DEMA/Beredskabsstyrelsen, supporting an international effort to combat an Ebola outbreak in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On September 18, 2015, The World Health Organization (WHO) requested the International Humanitarian Partnership (IHP) for assistance to the Ebola outbreak in Sierra Leone. The WHO requested IHP to assess and address current needs, with a primary focus on the support and facilities needed for the Foreign Medical Teams (FMTs). During September several countries offered FMTs to the international response to the Ebola epidemic in Sierra Leone. Danish Emergency Management Agency (DEMA) and Department For International Development (DFID) offered a joint developed Service Package of a total value of 9.6 million DKK. 
The aim was to support the WHO in optimising the response to the Ebola epidemic in Sierra Leone by providing support services for international medical teams, more specifically; safe accommodation opportunities, medical triage/holding units, training venue facilities and transportation management. 
The main objectives of the project where to: a) establish an Ebola safe accommodation. The tasks consisted of identifying and manage safe accommodation (hotels) for primarily the Cuban Medical Brigade consisting of 165 people, b) establish health and basic security support in the form of at least one pre-fabricated medical holding facility accessible for the international staff near their accommodation facilities, c) provide transport for Foreign Medical Teams (FMT) members primarily the Cubans arriving and departing, and in the normal shifts due to the work at the Ebola Treatment Centres (ECT), d) establishment of a base of operation to support the incoming Ebola responders with logistic support, office and meeting facilities, e) support to Ebola training venue facilitation and transport management to WHO, DFID and others, and f) support to WHO and DFID in the overall Ebola response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014-19946</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014001246</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-237225</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-237225-29172" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
