<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2679" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200283</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO-ILO Cambodia Industry 4.0 Garment Assessment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The coronavirus outbreak has slowed down&#x2019;s Cambodia&#x2019;s GDP growth   and has had severe impacts on its key economic sectors such as garment, footwear and travel goods (GFT) sector. Overall, this sector contributes roughly 60% to manufacturing employment. There are approximately 600 exporting garment factories employing around 750,000 people, and supports roughly 20% of all livelihoods.

COVID-19 has severely affected the supply chains of this sector. From a supply perspective, this pandemic has reduced access to essential inputs from China and exports to their largest markets (Europe and the US) have been curtailed due to closure of retail shops. This is compounded by the EU&#x2019;s decision to partially withdraw Cambodia&#x2019;s EBA trade preferences in August.

The UN COVID-19 MPTF has allocated $50,000 to the countries targeted under the first call, including Cambodia. The allocation should support the UN Resident Coordinator (UNRC) in jumpstarting and coordinating the implementation of the UN Framework for Immediate Socio-Economic Response with the RGC and across partners. This includes creating the evidence base to provide a convincing investment case for supporting unfunded priorities and building a pipeline of programmes under the UN Framework.

To create the momentum to successfully roll out the SERP for Cambodia, the UNRC Office&apos;s $100,000 is therefore available for immediate preparatory work required to design solutions that contribute to building a pipeline of programmes for the socio-economic response. At least three grants of $33,000 each will be available to support preparatory work for pipeline development such as data collection, impact assessments and thematic analysis that can lead to design of joint programs to implement the priorities of the UN SERP for Cambodia and the RGC economic recovery strategy. For each grant, at least two UN agencies should join with the RGC to explore and design solutions.

UNIDO and ILO successfully pitched an idea and secured a grant of US$ 33,000 from the UNRC&apos;s Office. To contribute to the implementation of Pillar 3 and 4 of the SERP, this UNIDO-ILO proposal will contribute to the ongoing efforts to modernize the garment sector through increased digitalization and to give technical support to the implementation of the upcoming Strategy for Cambodia&#x2019;s Garment, Footwear, and Travel Goods Sector (2020-2025) that planned to be launched soon. This garment sector strategy&#x2019;s objectives are to continue strengthening human resources for improved productivity; continue improving labour conditions and worker well-being; promote local and foreign investment in high-value addition industry and high value products; attract investment; and foster diversification of the Cambodian exports.

The expected output of this proposal is to conduct an assessment to determine 1) current and projected use of relevant technologies and automated machines and processes in Cambodia to gain an understanding of how the sector is becoming more digitized, and how that would affect production and human resources; and 2) required skills development interventions to reskill employees.

There is a clear need for support to Cambodia&apos;s GFT sector to ensure its readiness in taking on increased digitization and use of existing and new technology. Most factories in Cambodia operate on a business model that does not take direct orders but through intermediaries or manufacturing groups at headquarters level outside of Cambodia; hence they have less ownership on investment and business operation decisions (also, the sector is almost entirely foreign direct investment, and operating as &#x2018;cut make trim&#x2019; factories); hence don&#x2019;t get the full value of the orders and are short sighted. Additionally, the garment sector is funded almost entirely by foreign direct investment,

UNIDO and the ILO will collaborate with GMAC (Garment Manufacturers Association in Cambodia), and involve manufacturers and ministries in the assessment process &#x2013; Ministry of Labour and Vocational Training, Ministry of Economy and Finance, , Ministry of Industry, Science, Technology and Innovation at MPTC/Innovation Center, and Ministry of Commerce as it is crucial to get inputs and their vision of the industry for the next 5-10 years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200283" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="KH" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.517346 104.96197</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">16630</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200283-0-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">16630</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="KH"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200283-0-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">15903.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="KH"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
