<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="ifcwbg-9" dstore:index="49" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-42706</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Medical Equipment Facility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Africa Medical Equipment Facility (AMEF or the Program) is an up to US$150 million unfunded Risk Sharing Facility (RSF) established by IFC in partnership with local participating financial institutions (PFIs) and original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) to support small and medium-sized healthcare providers (Healthcare SMEs) access up to US$300 million in loans and leases with tenor of up to 7 years and finance the acquisition of much needed medical equipment in Cameroon, C&#xF4;te dIvoire, Kenya, Rwanda, Senegal, Tanzania and Uganda (the Countries).   The Program is expected to receive support from the IDA Private Sector Window (PSW) Blended Finance Facility (BFF) and the Global Financing Facility (GFF) in the form of up to US$18 million and up to US$6 million First Loss Guarantee (Blended Concessional Finance Co-Investment) respectively to facilitate the deployment of the Programs first phase of US$100 million unfunded RSF to generate up to US$200 million of loans and leases in eligible countries. This support is expected to enable the Program to rapidly roll out and reach the healthcare sector in the Countries where access to medical equipment has historically been a challenge and in turn led to poor healthcare delivery and health outcomes. Without the Blended Concessional Finance Co-Investment, IFC will not be able to provide guarantees to the PFIs at a price that allows the PFIs in turn to provide access to finance to the health SMEs at a viable cost.  Under the Program, IFC will seek to work with as many PFIs and OEMs as possible that will meet IFCs due diligence and investment criteria and are interested to participate in the Program with its defined terms and conditions. Any local financial institutions operating in one or several of the Countries and any OEMs with presence either directly or through a duly authorized distributor in one or several of the Countries are encouraged to contact IFC to explore partnership under the Program.&#xA0; IFC is also actively organizing outreaching activities to contact many potential market participants to explain the Programs terms and conditions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholders impact - Change in Healthcare SMEs&apos; access to finance and benefits for patients: IFC anticipates that the Program will enable PFIs to sustainably increase their healthcare SME loan portfolio and risk profile and hence, contribute to increasing access to longer-term finance (up to 7-years tenor), which are financially underserved in these markets. The financing will be used to acquire medical equipment which is expected to improve the effectiveness of the healthcare provided and so contribute to a strengthening of human capital. The development impact is expected to be further strengthened with the IFC Advisory Services provided to selected HSMEs and PFIs and the inclusion of maintenance and servicing of medical equipment by the OEMs. 
Contribution to Market Creation - Competitiveness: The Program will encourage competition among OEMs which could result in equipment prices falling for the benefit of the HSMEs. Through a demonstration channel, PFIs&apos; expansion of their healthcare SME loan portfolios will demonstrate to the wider market in the Program&apos;s Countries that HSMEs form an attractive market segment. The Program is expected to increase the market&apos;s competitiveness as other FIs in the Countries increase their lending to this market segment. There is also potential for the Program to lead to more loans and leasing by OEMs and equipment distributors. The Program is also expected to support the promulgation of technologies in healthcare in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Medical Equipment Facility</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-42706" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-19" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A  N/A  N/A  N/A    N/A  N/A</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Africa Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cameroon, C&#xF4;te dIvoire, Kenya, Rwanda, Senegal, Tanzania and Uganda.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.0000000000 21.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522110" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-AH - Commercial Banking - SME Finance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="COVID-19" vocabulary="99"></tag>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $150.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="912"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/42706">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/42706">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
