<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2661" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200211</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency livelihood support and job creation to mitigate the socio-economic impact of Covid 19 among  internally displaced people and host communities in the Kurdistan Region of Iraq</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to address the socio-economic impact of COVID-19 among IDPs and host communities in KRI by providing emergency livelihood support and job creation. This will enhance economic resilience, sustainable livelihoods and increase well-being. The project approach is based on harnessing the asset base of the project beneficiaries enabling them to establish sustainable livelihoods. First, is harnessing the human capital, who are the beneficiaries themselves. The project will provide skills and entrepreneurship training to improve their technical skills, acquire entrepreneurial knowledge to start/manage the livelihood/micro enterprise of their choice.  The trainings provided under UNIDO&#x2019;s Entrepreneurship Development Programme is expected to develop personal qualities such as willingness and ability to take initiatives, innovation and creativity, readiness to take calculated risks, self-confidence, resiliency in meeting adversities and ability to collaborate among the target beneficiaries.  By learning concepts, such as &#x201C;save, innovate, invest and grow&#x201D;, beneficiaries (both IDPs and host communities) will gain the concept and principles of self-help and mutual support, building their social capital while strengthening their livelihood activities. The intervention will contribute to the formation of an entrepreneurial population at the grassroots level and contribute to bottom-up development of a competitive private sector in the longer term.

Kurdistan known to be the &#x2018;bread-basket of Iraq&#x2019; and recognizing the agriculture potential of the governorates in the region, technical skills related to agribusiness and agri-processing will be promoted and as per interest and needs of the target beneficiaries.  After harnessing the human and social capital, the project will provide physical capital in terms of equipment/asset transfer and infrastructure required for the agribusinesses to be established.  To the extent that it will be feasible, access to land for proposed agribusinesses will also be explored together with the government counterpart organization.  To meet short-term needs for jobs and cash income in the community, infrastructures to be built will utilize labor from the camp or operational area.  The project will organize on-site competency-based technical skills training in areas required for the infrastructure e.g. welding, masonry, plumbing, tiling, etc.

Considering the emergency context and the dire socio-economic condition of IDPs especially in the COVID situation, to ensure self-reliance among IDPs in the camp for additional incomes and/or food support, the project will also introduce the concept of &#x201C;kitchen gardening&#x201D; within the outline of agri-business and agro-processing intervention of UNIDO.  The project will train the beneficiaries on the technical skills and business side of kitchen gardening.  The project will also provide seeds and tools necessary to grow food crops to meet their daily subsistence needs; surplus of which they can sell.  The beneficiaries will be provided with the necessary skills and training required to process the surplus crops for value addition based on the available market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200211" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IQ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.577183 43.667107</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IQ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dihok</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.86709 42.98845</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">853709</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
