<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2636" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency response assistance to the outbreak of the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) in the Islamic Republic of Iran</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In early 2020, the outbreak of new coronavirus (COVID-19) began to spread around the world, and the number of confirmed cases and deaths increased substantially every day, and most of countries faced a very serious situation to fight against the COVID-19. It was declared as a Public Health Emergency of International Concern by WHO on 30 January 2020.

Since the outbreak, the Chinese government has provided emergency medical supplies to nearly 130 countries. On April 16, President Xi Jinping published an article titled &quot;Unity and Cooperation is the Most Powerful Weapon for the International Community to Overcome the Epidemic&quot; on the 8th issue of Journal Qiushi. President Xi said that the Chinese government would unite and cooperate with other countries and provide assistance to the countries, who facing the most serious epidemics, in the principle of &#x201C;Community of shared future for mankind&#x201D;

Iran is one of the developing countries most affected by the outbreak of COVID-19. The first cases of COVID-19 infections were recognized on February 2020 in Qom city in Iran. Based on the latest official statistics of the Ministry of Health and Medical Education, the total number of patients in Iran with COVID-19 reached to 93,657 people and a number of 5,957 deaths were reported on 30 April 2020. Teheran, the capital of the country is the worst affected region.

As the number of confirmed patients increases in an unexpected speed, the medical waste (MW) generated is far beyond the existing capacity for MW management and disposal. There is a serious lack of medical waste disposal equipment. Due to equipment shortages, hospitals have been forced to increase the number of work cycles which will cause the device to malfunction quickly and further reduce the service life of the device. Furthermore, because of the restrictions imposed by the existing sanctions on the supply of parts for equipment, there is a need to ask the international organizations to provide the safe medical waste treatment equipment for hospitals.

On April 1, 2020, His Excellency Mr. Kazem Gharib Abadi, Ambassador and Permanent Representative of Iran to the United Nations and other International Organizations, sent an official interest letter to Mr. Li Yong, Director General of the United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNIDO) to request assistance in developing an emergency project to support the medical waste treatment equipment and relevant trainings, which is the country&#x2019;s priorities to combat against the outbreak of coronavirus.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200151" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iran (Islamic Republic of)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IR" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Republic of Iran</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32 53</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">837799.63</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200151-1-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">696153.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical waste disposal equipment</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IR"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200151-1-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">657737.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical waste disposal equipment</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IR"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200151-1-01-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">141646.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training materials compiled</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IR"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200151-1-01-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">11148.39</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training materials compiled</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IR"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
