<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2663" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-05-01T08:30:02+02:00" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2021-05-01T08:30:02+02:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200213</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting public health and social resilience against COVID-19 by strengthening the domestic supply chain of personal protective equipment under a circular economy approach</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the proposed UNIDO project is to promote public health and social resilience against COVID-19 by strengthening the domestic supply chains of Personal Protective Equipment (PPE), disinfectants, and hygiene supplies under Circular Economy approach. This project will tackle the goal through upgrading domestic producers and material suppliers in terms of 1) production capacity, 2) quality, and 3) business resilience &amp; continuity in emergencies by applying the product design for reuse model. The selection of the beneficiary companies will cover both formal and informal businesses and prioritize micro-, small-, and medium enterprises (MSME), which play a pivotal role in Ghana&#x2019;s economy.

As part of the capacity reinforcement, necessary equipment and technologies for upgrading and enhancing production capacity will be defined and supplied, where necessary, as well as establishing business links to promote new value chain for local material use for greener recovery.  It has been experienced during the early stage of COVID-19 that protective supplies were in a serious shortage everywhere, and it caused a significant problem among health workers and institutions. Therefore, the assistance will help the country to obtain the supply capability of those critical medical and sanitary items so that the goods can reach the people, community, and especially health institutions who are in need. Furthermore, taking into account the widespread of products whose quality is low and not fulfilling quality requirements in accordance with international standard, the project will address the enhancement of the product quality by making use of UNIDO&#x2019;s network and partners of UNIDO Global Quality Standards Programme, including ISO and other quality related authorities.

In addition, an innovative approach of the project is to use plant-based chemicals with antibacterial properties infused into fabrics or threads for facemask and other PPE production, which will contribute to reduce waste generation by applying the reuse model of circular economy practices. These chemicals can also be used for disinfection/hand hygiene products. It will utilize and build upon the achievements from previous projects related to plant-based chemicals implemented by UNIDO in Ghana. Importantly, the project will provide not only short-term assistance for the people, hospitals, and medical institutions, who are currently in need for the improved access to PPE, disinfectants, and hygiene supplies, but its successful implementation will also contribute to medium- and long-term humanitarian development of the country and region by anchoring stable public health and bringing stability to both economic activities and livelihood of the people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200213" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="GH" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.1065 -1.03727</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="GH" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accra</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.55602 -0.1969</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">461000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200213-1-01-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">219000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="GH"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200213-1-01-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">1766.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="GH"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200213-1-01-03-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">189000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 3</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="GH"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200213-1-01-03-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">11621.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 3</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="GH"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
