<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" dstore:dataset="unido-activity" dstore:index="2632" hierarchy="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200138</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preparatory process for the Centre for Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency for Central Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the umbrella of the Global Network of Regional Sustainable Energy Centres (GN-SEC) program, The United Nations Industrial Development Organisation (UNIDO) and the Economic Community of Central African States (ECCAS) are partnering on the establishment of the Centre for Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency for Central Africa (CEREEAC).

The partnership is based on an official request submitted by the ECCAS Secretariat to the UNIDO Director-General in February 2020. In an official response letter the UNIDO Director-General pledged support for the process through the GN-SEC program.
With the creation of the CEREEAC, the GN-SEC will cover all parts of Africa. The centre can closely cooperate with RCREEE, ECREEE, SACREEE and EACREEE on intercontinental issues under the African Union (AU) framework. GN-SEC examples have proven, that the strengthening of regional capacities through a dedicated institution can help to accelerate national clean energy efforts and contribute to better coordination, coherence, equal progress, as well as economies of scale. As other partners, UNIDO has the opportunity to make use of the created regional/continental infrastructure for its technical services, as well as its convening and normative functions.

Currently, UNIDO and ECCAS are implementing a consultative preparatory process, which determines the added value, feasibility as well as the technical and institutional design of the centre. A needs and feasibility assessment and a project document on the first operational phase are under development. Consultants were contracted and a comprehensive stakeholder consultation is underway. A GN-SEC web-page was established under: http://cereeac.gn-sec.net.

In line with the project document, the process has been supported through donor funds of the GN-SEC global project (project ID 180301). Since the CEREEAC establishment becomes now more concrete, a formal UNIDO project request is submitted. Between UNIDO and ECCAS there is agreement to validate the CEREEAC project document in the 2nd quarter of 2020 on the margins of a meeting of Ministers of Energy. The meeting will be organised in partnership with the International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA) and the Africa-EU Energy Partnership (AEEP).

Based on the received comments during the validation workshop, the project document will be finalised. It is intended to sign a first funding agreement in conjunction with Vienna Energy Forum (VEF) in July 2021. A competitive selection process of the host country of the CEREEAC Secretariat will be implemented by ECCAS in partnership with UNIDO. Several ECCAS countries indicated interest to host the centre, incl. the Republic of Congo, Cameroon and Sao Tome and Principe.

From the very beginning, the centre will lie in the ownership of ECCAS. It will operate with a small initial staff base and a network of national focal institutions. In line with the GN-SEC twinning (peer to peer learning) model, UNIDO will support the centre throughout its first operational phase by providing services related to mentoring, institution building and technical program development.

The creation of CEREEAC is fully in line with regional policies of ECCAS and CEMAC. The centre is part of the ECCAS efforts to establish an integrated and inclusive single market for products and services in traditional and emerging sectors, including sustainable energy and cleantech. The establishment of the centre will complement and significantly contribute to the existing efforts of ECCAS to promote energy and transport connectivity in the region. Moreover, it is a demonstrated response of ECCAS to the post COVID-19 green recovery paradigm in international cooperation.

The CEREEAC will contribute to the achievement of the ECCAS Green Economy and Renewable Energy Vision, the ECCAS Vision 2025, as well as the CEMAC White Paper and Energy Policy 2035. Moreover, it contributes to the new ECCAS Industrialisation and Economic Diversification Strategy, which aims to diversify the economies and reduce the dependency on the export of raw materials and primary products (incl. fossil fuels). The temporary oil price drop caused by the COVID-19 crisis has demonstrated the risk of being primarily dependent on the export of oil products.

The CEREEAC project is fully in line with the provided UNIDO support to the Third Industrial Development Decade for Africa (IDDA III) and the African Continental Freetrade Area (AfCFTA). Together, the African GN-SECs can contribute to the implementation of the AfCFTA with regard to harmonised sustainable energy product and service markets. In line with the AfCFTA, the objective is to keep the value chains of sustainable energy manufacturing and servicing as much as possible within the region.

The CEREEAC project has strong links to the other ongoing GN-SEC projects in Africa (e.g. ECREEE, SACREEE, EACREEE, EELA), as well as the GEF funded UNIDO energy portfolio in Central Africa (e.g. Republic of Congo, Sao Tome and Principe, Cameroon). There are particular links to the project (ID 190379), aiming at the establishment of the Oyo Centre of Excellence for Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency in the Republic of Congo. The centre might candidate for the hosting of the regional ECCAS component.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200138" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">49079.75</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="200138-0-01-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">49079.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project document finalised and approved</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="200138-0-01-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-01">5504.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project document finalised and approved</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
