<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="33" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/WASH/NGO/18125</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliver life-saving WASH assistance to reduce acute needs among most vulnerable settlements and communities (including men, women, boys and girls) in Burhakaba a dignified manner</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The humanitarian situation in Somalia is deteriorating due to the devastating impact of flooding, desert locust infestation, the COVID-19 pandemic and ongoing conflict About 5.9 million people are in need of humanitarian assistance, an increase from the 5.2 million reported in 2020. Up to 2.7 million people are expected to be in Crisis (IPC Phase 3) or worse and will face acute food insecurity through mid-2021. An estimated 840,000 children under the age of five are acutely malnourished, 143,000 of them severely and at risk of death. According to Somalia HNO for 2021 the protracted crisis in Somalia, compounded by COVID-19, floods and droughts, has resulted in massive challenges in meeting the WASH needs of the Somali population. According to the JMCNA, approximately 8.9 million people are affected by poor WASH conditions. For 2021, it is estimated that 4.6 million people are in catastrophic (10 per cent), severe (9 per cent) or extreme (18 per cent) need of humanitarian WASH assistance. The 10 per cent of households in catastrophic need mainly face a lack of access to water both in terms of quality and quantity, accompanied by a lack of access to functional sanitation. It is also a cause of relapse for acute diarrheal diseases when treated patients and children return to their communities with limited safe water and sanitation coverage, resulting in limited sustainability of health programs.
According to assessment conducted by BTSC in Nov,2020 findings revealed that majority of the households (63.3%) use unsafe water from a water catchment or a dam as their primary source for drinking water and the said dam has dried up and the cost of 200 litters of water is currently costing between $3-$4 US Dollars which is not affordable to the drought affected communities. Additionally, 43.5% of sampled households do not treat drinking water. The assessment also revealed that only 45% of the resident do have access to latrines and 98% of those latrines are not accessible to people with disabilities. only 37.5% of the assessed families reported to have access to soap.
In the context mentioned above GRRN will implement a WASH cluster-specific intervention aiming (1)Improve access to safe water through water trucking to 10,000 drought affected population in priority sites /settlements/ communities targeting in Bay(Burhakaba). Rehabilitation and/or extension of existing water infrastructures one borehole and 6 shallow wells with hand pump. (2) Construction of water infrastructures including construction of tanks and distribution networks, hybrid solar water pumping system in Burhakaba Borehole (Site selection should aim at reducing the risk of violence against women and children accessing water sources through their participation in discussions). (3)Establishment of gender balanced water management committees for ensuring continuity` of services, appropriate operation and maintenance and as well strengthen women leadership and participation in WASH projects.(4) construction of 60 latrines in settlements (culture sensitive and addressing specific needs of different sex and disabled groups) hosting new displaced population. (5) Hygiene promotion campaigns focusing on hand washing with soap and 1,500 hygiene kits distribution, including female specific hygiene items (sanitary clothes) accompanied by robust hygiene promotion activities. GRRN WASH technical designs adhere to SPHERE standards/Somalia WASH cluster guidelines, mainstreaming protection and disability, gender considerations per IASC guidelines for GBV Interventions in Humanitarian settings, WASH Chapter as well as the environmental protection considerations and securing access to the elderly and those with special needs as per Handicap International Guidelines. The total beneficiaries targeted in this project are 14,000(6,720 women, 4,480 men, 1,680 girls and 1,120 boys) in Burhakaba.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Golweyne Relief and Rehabilitation NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Golweyne Relief and Rehabilitation NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSOM21-WSH-170974-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ugas Abdirahman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>252616539333</telephone>
   <email>ugasabdi@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSOM21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-30">234615.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-30">115384.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18125">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-30">350000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Golweyne Relief and Rehabilitation NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
