<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="27" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/WASH/NGO/18133</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency life-saving WASH assistance to reduce acute needs among most vulnerable settlements and communities in Jalalaqsi district of Hiran Region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The impact of the ongoing drought compounded by economic and social impacts of COVID-19 escalated conflict and forecast of below-average Deyr rainfall from April to June 2021 may result in further deterioration of humanitarian outcomes for affected communities. Thus, in this project, AADSOM will improve access to safe water, sanitation facilities and promote good hygiene practices to reduce the negative impacts of the flood followed by drought in the Jalalaqsi district to 15,000 women, men, boys, and girls including people with disabilities, minorities and most vulnerable underserved and/or hard to reach communities from 5 villages under Jalalaqsi namely Doondheere, Raafey, Habar robe, Cadiley, Sheeloow, Dirggoys east, Buulo Barwaaqo, Baqdaad east and Jalalaqsi town. Key activities AADSOM would like to undertake within this project are the following WASH services:
Water:
- Provision of safe water to 1,000 households representing 6,000 men, women and children affected population through water vendors (water trucking) by using Water Voucher (WV) for a period of 45 days. (Site of the distribution selection by the women/girls should aim at reducing the risk of violence against women and children accessing water sources through their participation in discussions).

- Construction of 5 flood-proof shallow wells with hand pumps in 5 villages in Jalalaqsi district, (Baqdad east, Dirgoys east, Raafey, Dondheere, and Bulo Barwaaqo) with special consideration on disabled and child-friendly accessibility.
- Upgrade one borehole in Jalalaqsi town (Amaana Borehole) Howlwadaag section of Jalalaqsi town, equipped with the hybrid system including rehabilitation of existing water tank, construction of water kiosk for human use, Construction of engine room, and piping network.
- Establishment and capacity building training to gender-balanced 6 WASH committees and 12 Well Operators shared equally by men and women, to ensure continuity of service, operation, and maintenance, coupled training on DDR and conflict resolution mechanisms as cross-cutting.

Hygiene and Sanitation:
Lack of access to adequate and appropriate sanitation and hygiene poses a serious threat to public health. The practice of open defecation is a leading cause of fecal-oral transmission of diseases with children being the most vulnerable. A safe and appropriate latrine accompanied by handwashing with soap provides an effective barrier to the transmission of diseases. The provision of appropriate facilities for defecation is also an essential response for people&#x2019;s dignity, safety, health, and well-being. To improve safe access to sanitation it is necessary to meet standards of privacy and safety of women and girls against GBV using sanitation structures that are locally or culturally acceptable. nevertheless, the disabilities will be given a special design that is appropriate and acceptable for use. in this project, AADSOM will: 

- Conduct comprehensive hygiene promotion compounded with covid-19 awareness campaigns to reach 15,000 men, women, boys, and girls through visiting house to house, schools, health, and feeding centers. 
-Train 10 community hygiene promoters (5 men and 5 women), who will carry out hygiene promotion activities during and after the project is faced out. 
-Distribute 500 HP kits to 500 households with vulnerable men, women, and children, and
- Construct 58 gender-sensitive and flood-proof latrines aimed at ensuring the sustainability of the latrines during floods to the most affected community including 5 latrines especially constructed for disabled people.
To  strengthen the local markets-Based Programming (MBP) approach AADSOM will ensure that:
- The service providers should be selected locally if available.
- The contracted service providers should purchase the required material and equipment in the local market if available.
- The contracted service provider should hire skilled and skilled workers from the local people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulet Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722800129</telephone>
   <email>info@aadsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">300061.71</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18133">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">300061.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
