<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-southsudan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="31" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA3/H/NGO/18025</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency health assistance to IDPs, Returnees and host communities in Aweil South County, Northern. Bahr el. Ghazal South Sudan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Health Organization (IHO) is proposing the implementation of Provision of emergency health assistance to Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs), Returnees and host communities in Aweil South County, Northern. Bahr el. Ghazal South Sudan. Aweil South County has been categorized under IPC Phase 5, meaning the county is faced with &#x201C;catastrophe&#x201D; food insecurity according to the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) analysis released on 18 December 2020 which also projects the same by mid-2021, The analysis estimated 7.24 million people or 60 per cent of the South Sudanese population will face severe acute food insecurity and will need urgent assistance of which many of the families have exhausted their emergency coping strategies. In order to encounter the emergency health needs in Aweil South, Impact Health Organization  proposed project will focus on meeting the health cluster&#x2019;s strategic plan and response objectives by supporting Primary Health Care Unit (PHCU) (Amacrol) and Panadhot  Primary Health Care Unit with outreach site of Majong in Wathmuok Payam Aweil South County to provide Emergency and Basic Life Saving Health Services, Mobilize mobile health care units, (Expanded Programme on Immunization) EPI, Mother and Child HealthMCH services, Basic Emergency Obstetric and Newborn Care (BeMONC) services, Gender Based Violence (GBV)and Mental Health and Psychosocial Support  (MHPSS) services, management of Severe Acute Malnutrition (SAM) with medical complications, health education and hygiene services and reinforcing existing health facilities to increase access to lifesaving healthcare services for acute displacements and the conflict affected host communities, disease outbreak prevention, malnutrition treatment and health Protection response. The project will ensure technical (The project team  such clinician, nurses e.g shall have neccessary skill to provide health services based on the South Sudan Basic Package of Health Services (BPHS) as well proper planning budget monitoring and communication with stakeholders) , operational (the project shall be excuted benchmarking the project objectivies, activities, and targets  as well as health cluster objectives) and coordination to provide quality health services. To ensure coordination, the project will consult with all stakeholders at  state, county, payam and health facilities level and as well as ensure liaison and coordination with national, county health authorities. Supportive supervision and monitoring including mentoring and capacity building will play a key role to provide quality health services. In addition, the project will promote Surveillance, Early warning and Response for Disease Outbreak detection such as Cholera, Measles, Hepatitis, Haemorrhagic fever, etc and response when required. 
The proposed intervention will address the immediate needs of  26750 internally displaced, returnees and host population (5000 Men 9150 Women, 5200 Boys and 7400 Girls), mitigate the risks of Corona virius (COVID-19) through integrated Primary Health Care (PHC) services shall be offered through  Primary Health Care Unit and outreach services which will run 5 days a week by qualified staffs trained prior to project.
To mainstream gender, the project activities are designed to meet the specific needs of women and men and shall collect and analyse sex-disaggregated data and qualitative information to understand roles and needs of women and men. Lastly the project will main stream by avoiding causing harm, ensuring meaningful access to services, accountability (beneficiaries evaluate service they recieve), and participation(community member part of the servce delivery team) and empowerment (beneficaries trained and educated on disease prevention etc).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-HEA-161098-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mwanje Jolem</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211928082382</telephone>
   <email>jolem.mwanje@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bwire Benard</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211926301715</telephone>
   <email>finance@ihosavinglives.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Israel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211924519116</telephone>
   <email>david@ihosavinglives.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.53604490 26.79678490</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-24">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-18025">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-24">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304932702">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-03">180000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
