<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ukraine-allocation-2020" dstore:index="10" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-20/UKR_CBPF/SA1/H-N/NGO/16125</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Life saving&quot; Medical Equipment for the Luhansk Hospitals specialized  in COVID-19.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project consists of supplementing existing medical equipment in several Luhansk Hospitals with life saving equipment certified compatible with the care of COVID-19 symptomatic patients, and in particular, those with simple or acute respiratory distress syndromes which are the main cause of death. The health system in the conflict-affected areas not controlled by the Ukrainian Government of Donetsk and Luhansk (NGCA) faces several distinct patterns of disruption. The bad equipment of hospitals are the most reported difficulties. The hospitals located in NGCA did not receive any support from the Ukrainian Government since 2014 and are only surviving from humanitarian help. In this context, the arrival of the COVID-19 pandemic is creating a large problem to treat the patients affected by the virus. Largely documented by the OCHA, the population of Lugansk has already faced many daily problems for 6 years. And the conflict is still ongoing with bombings and attacks that have increased compared to 2019. The containment measures put in place on March 22, 2020 suspended the movements between the two opponents, except for humanitarian reasons which are not clearly defined on the both sides. The settings and locations where specific essential health care services are delivered may require modification or reconfiguration for reasons including redesignation for management of COVID-19 cases exclusively, or the need to limit provider encounters due to increased demand and/or decreased staff. The &quot;de facto&quot; Ministry of Health of the Separatist Republic of Luhansk organized the plan to receive patients with COVID-19 in 4/6 main hospitals, Hospitals Number 4 and 7 with a capacity of 800 beds including 24 in intensive care for adults and the children&apos;s hospital number 1 and 15 with a capacity of 40 beds, including 7 in intensive care. These 4 hospitals have been organizing for a month in collaboration with the laboratories to ensure that:
- the staff is available (because 40% of the medical staff has left the region since the start of the conflict)
- that medical workers were correctly trained,
- tests are available,
- the FFP2 personal protections are quite numerous,
- isolation and quarantine measures are in place,
- and that the beds in the designated hospitals are equipped to receive symptomatic patients.
It follows from these preparatory measures that the problems relate essentially to the tests, protections, and medical equipment. The inventory of medical equipment has highlighted a huge critical need for ventilators, mobile radiography, pulsioximeters, monitors, portable ultrasound, but also fibroscopes. This critical lack is the base of this project. 
Since 2006, the AICM Foundation has helped 175 hospitals across Ukraine and trained more than 1,300 specialist doctors. More than 500 tonnes of medical equipment, were delivered especially in intensive care centers, dialysis centers and specialized hospitals. Since 2014, the Foundation mainly helped 75 hospitals located in the conflict zone of Ukraine by providing them with medicines, medical supplies and consumables. Knowing many of these hospitals before the conflict allowed AICM to help hospitals in the areas bordering the conflict on the government side as well as on the separatist side. In addition, AICM is a small, very responsive structure with a network of well-known local and international partners and suppliers ready to deliver the life saving equipment in a short term of less than 1 month. AICM has no problem to transfer any help to Luhansk and already transferred in 2018/2019 the equivalent of US $ 700,000 in equipment, medicines and consumables and provided medical trainings for specialists . AICM is also active in the rest of Ukraine in the subject of the COVID-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Humanitaire Internationale AICM Ukraine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Humanitaire Internationale AICM Ukraine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christian CARRER</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380673697250</telephone>
   <email>ccarrer@yahoo.fr</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UKR44">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luhanska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.98548500 39.01766300</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-24">201195.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-16125">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-24">201195.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Humanitaire Internationale AICM Ukraine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304657701">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">201195.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Humanitaire Internationale AICM Ukraine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
