<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-opt-allocation-2020" dstore:index="65" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-05-07T03:11:51.5" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-12-14T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA2NT/HNC/NGO/17489</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing elective surgeries to patients registered on the MoH waiting list &#x2013; Gaza Strip - OPT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite conducting elective surgeries by UHWC to patients scheduled on the MoH waiting lists through the implementation of 2 projects funded by OPT-HF, one of these projects was implemented in 2018-2019 amp targeted 827 patients amp the other is currently being implemented targeting 1,474 patients. And despite implementing such projects by other international amp local institutions, but the need still exists amp the No. of patients increase steadily as a result of the increase in the severity of the accumulated crises faced by the MoH where the most recent was the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic in the Gaza strip, upon which the MoH allocated all its hospitals to deal with emergency amp COVID-19 cases.

In March 2020 the registered patients at the MoH waiting lists reached 6759 patients while currently in Sept. 2020 (according to the MoH) the No. reached 7506 patients, which confirms the urgent need to continue implementing such projects.

In order to contribute to bridging the gaps amp responding to the humanitarian needs of those patients, through this project 828 electives surgeries will be conducted at al Awda Hospital targeting women, men, girls, boys, elderly amp PWD from Northern Gaza Strip amp Gaza governorates. 

The surgical operations will cover the following No. amp specialties:
- 306 ENT
- 322 General 
- 100 urology
- 100 Orthopedic

422 moderate
406 major

The services will include medical examination, lab., radiological services, surgical operation, hospitalization amp post-op follow up. 

A partnership will be continued through this project with the Central Blood Bank Society (CBBS) in order to provide the necessary blood units for patients to save their lives. As through this project, 2000 blood units will be collected and provided to Al Awda Hospital amp other hospitals in the Gaza Strip

In order to achieve the principle of coordination amp complementarily, during the design of this proposal coordination has been done with the HC coordinator amp MoH who emphasized the need amp the importance of this project. Moreover, the idea of the project meets the HRP strategic obj. # 2, Health Cluster obj. # 2, in addition to the 1st Allocation obj.

Believing in the principle of community participation in identifying their most important problems, needs amp priorities, 50 calls were conducted with individuals from the local community from the Northern amp Gaza governorates where the majority of them confirmed the importance of alleviating the suffering of patients who are registered on the MoH waiting list, especially who needs major amp medium operations, as the delay in conducting the surgical operations pose a threat to the lives of patients amp increase their suffering adding to the possibility of having complications.

Another 50 phone calls will be conducted with the project beneficiaries to monitor the project services at the mid of the project. While 50 E-questionnaires will be filled to measure the beneficiaries&apos; satisfaction about the provided services at the end of the project. 

To achieve the principle of protection, the project will target different age groups, including men, women boys amp girls, as well as PWD without discrimination. 

To respond to gender needs, medical staff of both sexes (MampF) will be available. Moreover, pediatric surgeons will be available to respond to the age needs.

In order to protect patients amp medical staff from the transmission of COVID19 infection, several preventive measures will be followed, including the initial examination (IGG, IGM) for the patients before entering the hospital, while PPE will be distributed to the medical staff amp patients inside the hospital.

To reach accurate amp easily accessible information, HIS is in place amp used at Al Awda Hospital. 

The project will be documented through photos amp audio-visual report taking into consideration the dignity amp privacy of patients.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central blood bank society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jehan Al Aklouk</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00972-599731994</telephone>
   <email>jehan.uhwc@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">36224.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">403299.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-17489">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">439523.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304833651">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">263714.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
