<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-afghanistan-allocation-2020" dstore:index="38" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:generated-datetime="2021-05-07T03:06:38.457" iati-activities:version="2.03" last-updated-datetime="2020-11-10T00:00:00" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/RA5/APC/INGO/17222</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved mental health and psycho social well being of caregivers and children in Ghor province in response to conflict, disaster and COVID-19.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children in Afghanistan, especially those already suffering from poverty and inequity, are among the most vulnerable to the harsh socio-economic impacts of COVID-19. Child mortality, malnutrition, forced marriages, sexual abuse other forms of violence, exploitation, and child labor are all common challenges for the average child. With the addition of COVID-19 and its immediate and secondary impacts, children are now more anxious and worried than ever before and at greater risk of facing physical, sexual and emotional violence, especially as poverty rates and hunger in the country rise. A recent World Vision Assessment titled An Assessment of the Socio Economic Impact of COVID-19 on the Most Vulnerable Families in Afghanistan, has shown that almost 50% of caregivers are suffering from negative psychosocial symptoms due to COVID-19 and 30% of children expressed feelings of sadness related to the pandemic. To mitigate negative coping mechanism and enhance the psychosocial wellbeing of children and caregivers, delivery of specialized MHPSS services, as well as an effective case management system is essential. 

In order to ensure sustainability and the capacity of existing community structures is strengthened, WV will focus on working with already formed Faith Leader Forums that comprises of community and faith leaders in Firozkoh, Dowlat yar and Lal Serjangal. In addition, WV will support CPAN with essential capacities related to enhancing the protective environment for boys and girls. The community based approach will include contextualized ToT trainings on PSS, Child Safeguarding and Positive Coping Mechanisms as well as ongoing support in order to empower community leaders and CPAN to have ownership of the program. A specialized MHPSS response will be delivered through awareness sessions and home to home visits, to ensure the most vulnerable caregivers, boys and girls have the opportunity to engage in PSS activities plus receive useful age and gender appropriate information to adopt positive coping mechanisms. Community engagement and risk communications will adhere to guidance shared by the RCCE Working Group. 

The COVID-19 pandemic has exacerbated pre-existing vulnerabilities and further limited access to life-saving services, including case management. The disruption in the environment, socio-economic situation, daily routines and life of the families and communities and the measures put in place to prevent and control the spread of COVID19 heavily affects children&#x2019;s development and well-being. Case management is an essential service which children must have access to in order to ensure they receive the support and services required while they are at heightened risk of abuse, neglect, and exploitation. WV will assess and strengthen the case management system across Ghor province, to support the service delivery of CPAN and other CP actors to deliver a coordinated and effective case management service, based on lessons learnt, best practice and guiding principles. 

Building on established structures, WV will support a total of 4 existing Mobile Health and Nutrition Teams (MHNT) in 3 districts of Ghor. Currently, WV has 2 MHNTs in Firozkoh, 1 MHNT in Dowlat yar, and 1 MHNT in Lal Serjangal. MHNTs provide awareness raising, counseling, treatment, and referrals for mental health and psychosocial disorders using the mhGAP and ISAC guidelines for mental health in emergencies. In addition, WV is currently programming a COVID-19 response in Firozkoh using a community-based approach to mitigate risks and enhance the protective environment of populations. All PSS activities in the project will adhere to the Global Protection Cluster&#x2019;s Guidelines for Restarting PSS Activities in an Emergency Setting.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asuntha Charles</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799-209-720</telephone>
   <email>Asuntha_Charles@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonathan Chifamba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799-490-407</telephone>
   <email>Jonathan_Chifamba@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">119335.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">180660.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-17222">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">299996.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304784971">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-10">239997.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
