<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="1" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/CCCM/NGO/18117</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustained CCCM support to vulnerable IDP settlements in Kahda district in Banadir Region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2020, Somalia had been hit by Multiple threats from Covid-19, locusts, conflict, insecurity, forced evictions, droughts, and flooding. The number of people in need has consistently increased over the last three years, from 4.2 million in 2019 to 5.2 million in 2020 and 5.9 million in 2021 according to the CCCM cluster Acaps review. This is further reflected in the number of displaced people in 2020/2021. 47% of the population of 12.3 million needs some form of humanitarian assistance, including 2.7 million internally displaced persons (IDPs), with an additional half a million displaced on average per year as a result of climatic conditions and conflict. Most displacement-affected persons face multiple or recurrent displacements, with a majority of IDPs having been displaced at least five times previously and very few return to areas of origin. Post-Gu IPC analysis conducted in September 2020 by FEWSNET and partners, indicates that an estimated 1.7 million people are anticipated to be in Crisis (IPC Phase 3), with 0.4 million persons experiencing an emergency (IPC Phase 4). An additional 3.0 million persons are expected to be Stressed (IPC Phase 2), with the current conditions projected to remain unchanged by end of 2020. Projections running into 2021, through May, predict continued Stressed (IPC 2) and Crisis (IPC 3) outcomes to persevere, largely due to continued struggles of affected households to overcome shocks. Households in IDP areas in the Banadir region are facing food consumption gaps and are classified as Crisis (IPC Phase 3), driven by the high cost of living and limited income-earning opportunities. This notwithstanding, the sustained and large-scale humanitarian coordination is preventing more severe outcomes in many regions across Somalia. Camp coordination and camp management is a relatively a concept that&#x2019;s limited within the region and it is of utmost importance that key stakeholders i.e. government officials and humanitarian actors, be sensitized to this concept. 

SCC will implement these activities in 20 IDP sites in Kahda district of Banadir region with over 30,000HHs as per the latest detailed site assessment (DSA), targeting a largely underserved area. Approximately 36000 IDPs (6000 households) will benefit from this proposed intervention, in addition to the community working in these sites including local authorities, clusters, and other NGOs. These numbers might vary due to external factors, which might attract more IDPs, excessive flooding, or conflict with the landowners or the authorities, which may cause IDPs to flee to other areas. Gender will be mainstreamed into the project through the specific consideration of the different needs of women, men, boys, and girls during the design of activities. The project will ensure that all participants have equal access to resources and training. Monitoring and evaluation will be based on gender, age, and diversity dis-segregated data. SCC will implement this intervention in the Kahda district of Banadir region targeting 6000 HHs. Kaxda District is one of the IDP major hubs in Mogadishu that hosts the largest number of IDPs. Throughout the project, the needs of women, girls, men, and boys of all ages will be addressed throughout the planning, implementation and monitoring, and evaluation of the activities. Through regular site monitoring, needs and gaps will be reported and shared with partners and all stakeholders. Particular attention regarding needs will be paid to women and girls who also have to contend with GBV and protection concerns within camp settings. Through this project, SCC will also address the current and newly identified needs by setting up camp coordination structures at the national and, where necessary, regional or district levels, facilitating and supporting the establishment of effective coordination and management in IDP sites while respecting national context and authorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Community Concern</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Community Concern</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdullahi Mohamud Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615987090</telephone>
   <email>abdullahi@scc.org.so</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">134065.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">65934.07</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18117">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Community Concern</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
