<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="10" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/FSC/INGO/18210</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide Emergency response and restoration of livelihood assets related to food and income sources for population affected by multiple shocks in Gedo region Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Critical humanitarian needs persist in Somalia across the different livelihood groups whose vulnerabilities continue to worsen due to the devastating impact of flooding, desert locust infestation, COVID-19 pandemic and escalating conflict. The poor Deyr rains (October to December 2020) led to the inadequate pasture for livestock, water shortage and below average crop production. The deteriorating food security outlook combined with the worsening malnutrition appeals for a rapid, well-targeted and coordinated scale up of responses to save lives and recovery of livelihoods assets. The project aims to improve immediate access to food while restoring livelihood assets related to food and income sources that have been impacted by water shortages through conditional cash transfers to enhance livelihood opportunities and rehabilitation of water infrastructures and provision of fodder seeds (Sudan grass) in agro-pastoral and pastoral villages in Belet-Hawa district, Gedo region. 
The project will target 815 vulnerable drought affected agro-pastoral and pastoral households among women, men, boys, girls, including female headed households who are classified under IPC 3 amp 4. The detrimental effects of the current shocks have severely and directly affected rural communities whose sources of food, income and water are diminishing and increasingly at risk leading to household food insecurity, increase in debt levels among poor households and a severe reduction in access to safe water for both domestic and livestock use. Additionally, the affected households rely on food purchase from local markets, have weak purchasing power due to limited income and lack access to credit services due to cumulative debts. 
COOPI prioritizes respect for the rights, dignity and safety of the people affected by crisis and is committed to taking account of, giving account to, and being held to account by the populations benefiting from the intervention. During implementation process, target communities, especially women, girls and the disabled will be included in community representative committees and decision making processes In selection of beneficiaries, registrations, verifications and monitoring exercises so as ensure that the most marginalized and vulnerable are represented and have influence. The project will be guided by the principles of DO NO HARM, ensuring safety and dignity of target population is upheld and at the same time providing for accountability, participation and empowerment. In order to improve household immediate access to food, conditional cash transfer will be provided to 815 affected household including girls, pregnant and lactating women, boys and men to enable them immediately access food, water, healthcare, and other basic services.
To restore livelihood assets of households, 815 beneficiaries will engage in cash for work activities construction and/or rehabilitation of water catchments and water harvesting structures (soil bunds), 150 households among the CFW beneficiaries will also be provided with fodder seeds (Sudan grass) in the areas where soil bunds structures have been constructed to regenerate pasture to ensure availability of fodder for livestock. This activity aims at restoring livestock assets of the communities and envisages reducing workload and stress on women and girls who are responsible for feeding livestock. In addition, gender based violence and exploitation malpractices associated with in search of livestock feeds and water for long distances will be mitigated through the proposed activity. In summary the following activities will be carried out:
1. Provide conditional cash transfer to 815 households in Belet-Hawa district to increase household purchasing power and rehabilitate livelihood assets and water sources.
2. Support to fodder production through provision of Sudan grass seeds) for 150 affected households in Belet-Hawa district.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione Internazionale - COOPI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione Internazionale - COOPI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhsin Abdi  Sheikh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252612624388/+2540725288944</telephone>
   <email>program.nairobi@coopi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deka Wasame</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254702034276</telephone>
   <email>rep.nairobi@coopi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-04">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18210">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-04">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperazione Internazionale - COOPI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
