<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-myanmar-allocation-2020" dstore:index="15" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-20/DDA-3415/SA1/H-P/INGO/16767</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensuring Inclusive GBV and Health Services for IDPs and Conflict-Affected Communities in Kachin and Northern Shan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In partnership with Kachin Baptist Convention (KBC), the International Rescue Committee (IRC) will implement a 12-month project to provide life-saving GBV, mental health and psychosocial support (MHPSS), and healthcare services to IDPs and conflict-affected host communities across 15 townships in Kachin and northern Shan state (NSS) (protection only).     Overall, 3,588 men, 36932 women, 2,744 boys, and 20,985 girls will be directly reached, including 2,955 persons with disabilities (PWDs). 

The IRC has implemented a Women&#x2019;s Protection and Empowerment program across 10 townships in NSS and Southern Kachin state since January 2016 and expanded programming in 2019 to 5 additional townships in Kachin (in partnership with KBC). Under this proposal, IRC and its partners will leverage existing resources to widen the coverage of case management, MHPSS, referrals, and emergency assistance to women and girls experiencing GBV and exposed to protection risks. These services will be delivered through multiple modalities including static Women and Girl Wellness Centers (WGWCs) and mobile GBV teams who will provide services through temporary safe spaces in hard-to-reach and remote locations to minimize physical barriers to access. Furthermore, IRC&#x2019;s GBV hotline in NSS and KBC&#x2019;s GBV hotline in Kachin will continue to be implemented under this project. To ensure inclusive services, especially during COVID-19, the hotline serves three critical functions: 1) it enables survivors to quickly receive emotional support, and crisis intervention and safety planning 2) it provides referrals and information on community-based resources and 3) it provides technical support to IDP camp-based caseworkers and community and CSO Focal Points who provide GBV prevention and response services to the communities they reside in, thus ensuring community-driven service delivery. 

In order to enhance the mental well-being, physical and legal safety of vulnerable women and girls, IRC and KBC will also conduct safety audits and community mapping life-skills building and girl empowerment activities GBV, and anti-trafficking education and other risk mitigation actions. Prevention and engagement activities with the larger community, including men and boys, will take place to ensure they understand the risks women and girls face and the importance of community support and accountability. In additional, IRC will continue its coordination with local organization for persons with disabilities, Golden Pearl, in NSS, and Humanity amp Inclusion in Kachin, in the management and referral of cases for PWDs. The specific geographies targeted for these activities - Hseni, Hsipaw, Kutkai, Lashio, Manton, Muse, Namkhan, Namtu, Nawnghkio, Tangyan in NSS and -Myitkyina, Waingmaw, Mansi and Sumpraburn   in Kachin - align directly with the Allocation Strategy Paper and reflect locations where IRC and its partners have existing programming and access. 

The project     also aims to improve the health status of IDPs and conflict-affected communities in Kachin through the delivery of inclusive and essential health care via one  IRC and two KBC   mobile health team. This includes integrated primary, and sexual reproductive health care services, cash assistance for life-saving emergency referrals integrated community management of childhood diseases community health education including COVID-19 risk communication nutrition screening and services GBV clinical care and individual and family counselling services offered through a health counsellor embedded within IRC&#x2019;s mobile health team. Operational in targeted locations since 2019, IRC and KBC will increase the depth of its existing health activities across targeted IDP camps and conflict-affected community in Waingmaw and Chipwi. Without the continued support of MHF, health service delivery in these locations are at risk of not continuing, at a time where government and ethnic health systems are under strain during COVID-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention (KBC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Naomi Rennard</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Directors - Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 (0) 9892272908</telephone>
   <email>Naomi.Rennard@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maju Brang Nu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Program Coordinator - KBC HDD</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+95 (0) 790430658</telephone>
   <email>hpc.kbchdd@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Malut Naw Tawng</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager - KBC HMD</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+950924201527</telephone>
   <email>malutnawtawng@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR001">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00000000 97.50000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="MMR015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shan (North)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>23.50285400 98.14198900</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-14">136460.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-14">274047.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-16767">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-14">410508</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304739200">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-17">164203.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
