<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="17" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/Nut/NGO/18155</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of integrated management and prevention of Acute Malnutrition to reduce morbidity and mortality in children less than five years as well as PLW in priority gap areas in Lasanod District of Sool region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite marginal improvements from &#x2018;critical&#x2019; levels in the overall nutrition situation in Somalia, malnutrition rates among children remained precarious at &#x2018;serious levels. Of concern were populations with critical prevalence of acute malnutrition above the threshold of 15 per cent, mainly in Northern Inland Pastoral Livelihood Zone (Lasanod District), as well as internally displaced persons (IDPs) due to food insecurity, high morbidity, low immunization and Vitamin-A supplementation, and poor care practices. ANPPCANSOM emergency response plan will scale up treatment of malnutrition and reach an estimated caseload of 1,407 SAM representing 50% of the nutrition cluster SAM burden of 2,806 in Lasanod District. 
The project will provide facility-based and community based (BNSP) covering both curative and preventative interventions targeting children U5 years (boys and girls) and pregnant and lactating women. It will support the identification, referral and treatment of children suffering from moderate and severe acute malnutrition while SAM cases with medical complications will be referred to the Lasanod Stabilization Center run by MSF using standard referral forms. ANPPCANSOM will support and manage 3 health centers (Tuulo Samakaab, Halhaliye, Dan )and 2 mobile teams  covering 20 remote sites (Biriqodey, Bixin, Burowadal, Buulal, Fardhidin, Gacandar, Garac Lagu Dhal, God Qaboobe, Higlo Fiqi, Faleeryale  Canjiid, Laas Magugle, Jidbaale, Kalax, Sango Jabiye, Karin Dabayl, Saha Gebogebo, Buq-Xaar, Adhicadeeye, Akuule) within Lasanod district. 
In order to ensure the sustainability of nutrition interventions, local technical capacity will be strengthened by integrating SAM management into the Primary Health Care system through the functional MCHs. Additionally, the capacity of nutrition staff will be strengthened for effective service delivery at facility and community level. 
ANPPCANSOM will maintain treatment outcomes consistent with Sphere standards using the combined protocol for the management of acute malnutrition in close consultation and coordination with Somalia Nutrition Cluster, Somaliland Nutrition Working Group and other nutrition partners including MOHD, UNICEF and WFP. ANPPCANSOM will build on and sustain the delivery of a holistic basic nutrition services package (BNSP) in priority to the target communities including internally displaced people and their host communities and other socially marginalized groups in pastoral and hard to reach in Lasanod district areas while ensuring the inclusion of treatment, promotion and prevention components in this project. 
The project will support community mobilization and screening as well as micro-nutrient supplementation for PLW (multiple micro-nutrients and Iron folate) and Vitamin A supplementation for children between 6-59 months. It will also provide de-worming for children 12-59 months and pregnant women in the 2nd and 3rd trimester as well as counselling and promotion on infant and young child feeding compounded with health and hygiene promotion. Moreover, measles immunization will be provided to infants living within the catchment areas of the target health centers who are not immunized against measles. Systematic defaulter tracing for immunization services will also be conducted at community level. 

In order to strengthen the accountability with affected population, we will introduce mother-led MUAC approach to increase detection, identification and early referral of malnourished children. ANPPCANSOM will train mothers to use MUAC tapes to enable mothers screen, detect oedema and self-referral of their children to nutrition sites.
Likewise, the project will give particular emphasis on the current COVID-19 pandemic prevention measure to contain the spread of the virus. Gender and protection activities will be effectively mainstreamed into the project. Every effort will be made to ensure equity and to reach the most vulnerable population in Lasanod District.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Network for the Prevention and Protection Against Child Abuse and Neglect in Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Network for the Prevention and Protection Against Child Abuse and Neglect in Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khadar Mahmoud Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 252 63 4424497</telephone>
   <email>khadar.ahmed@anppcansom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samuel Otieno John</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 636816691</telephone>
   <email>samuel.otieno@anppcansom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9675">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.72400000 47.52900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">134060.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">65931.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18155">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">199991.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Network for the Prevention and Protection Against Child Abuse and Neglect in Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
