<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="104" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/WASH-NFI/ES-P-H-N/INGO/17581</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated multi-sectoral and emergency response for improved living conditions of IDPs in Somali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDP communities living in Siti Zone of the Somali Region in Ethiopia continue to face multi-sectoral critical gaps in services, while existing vulnerabilities are exacerbated by the outbreak of COVID-19. IDP site living conditions are characterized by overcrowding, critically affecting the ability to practice key COVID-19 mitigation behavioral strategies such as social distancing while simultaneously lacking access to adequate and safe water sources, and basic health services. The acute malnutrition caseload and infectious disease burden are significantly high according to data obtained from the Gablalu Woreda Health office for the past three months. The compounding effects of these factors result in IDP communities constituting key vulnerability groups within the context disease outbreaks, while further facing increased exposure to protection risks due to inadequate service provision and overcrowding. 
The Consortium, composed of WHH, ACTED, Mercy Corps and UNISOD aims to address key gaps in service provision through the delivery of an integrated and multi-sectoral response in Hariso IDP site, contributing towards HRP Strategic Objective 1 &#x2018;the physical and mental wellbeing of 5.7 million crisis-affected people is improved&#x2019;, and HRP Strategic Objective 2, &#x2018;5.7 million of the most vulnerable crisis-affected people are supported with basic services,&#x2019; as well as aligning with specific sectoral objectives. The intervention will contribute towards achieving these objectives by delivering services that ensure improved access to safe and adequate WASH facilities, provision of site management services (SMS), delivery of multi-sectoral shelter/ non-food item kits to target the most basic household needs, as well as provision of basic health services including medical consultation and treatment, maternal health services, routine immunization for children, disease outbreak response in collaboration with the local health facilities and referral services to the nearest health facilities whenever inpatient care is needed. This integrated approach will reduce the morbidity and mortality associated with undernutrition and increased illnesses of IDPS with no access to primary health care services and basic nutrition, facilitate provision of sufficient, safe and accessible water to IDP communities..  To ensure successful and effective delivery, the Action will be implemented in Consortium, led by WHH as administrative grant holder and will be responsible for overall monitoring and compliance related issues, include but go beyond,: ensuring contractual obligations are followed, guidelines and procedures are adhered to and visibility and communications are addressed overseeing the overall operation and follow up the and  monitoring of the projects along with the consortium members (ACTED, Mercy Corps  and UNISSOD) including joint field monitoring and organizing regular meetings among the  consortium members. WHH as lead agency will compile narrative and financial reports ( including verification  of expenditure support documents )   from  the three consortium members and submit quality report to EHF/OCHA..  ACTED  will be leading on overarching management for all activities within Protection, WASH and Shelter/NFI with UNISOD spearheading WASH service delivery. In particular, UNISOD is directly implementing activities related to the distribution of ES and multisector kits, WASH activities including the distribution of handwashing stations and community hygiene promotion. ACTED will lead on the CCCM component of this proposed project as well as providing direct management, oversight and technical support to UNISOD.  Mercy Corps in parallel leading on the delivery of the Health and Nutrition activities a partnership designed to build on complementarities of experience and technical capacities while providing comprehensive assistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe e.V. (German Agro Action)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe e.V. (German Agro Action)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNITED SOCIETY FOR SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Matthias Spaeth</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0920656697</telephone>
   <email>Matthias.Spaeth@welthungerhilfe.de</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yosef Kassahun</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Response Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911861848</telephone>
   <email>Yosef.Kassahun@welthungerhilfe.de</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>43.32903576 6.92946999</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="35" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="18" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="19" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">699916.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17581">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-20">699916.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe e.V. (German Agro Action)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304888697">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-22">559933.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe e.V. (German Agro Action)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
