<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities>
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-ethiopia-allocation-2020" dstore:index="66" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/H/INGO/17541</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Health Response to communities affected by climate change and conflict in Amhara and Oromia Regions; Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project planned to respond to the Health, needs of IDPs, returnees, and host communities in Oromia and Amhara regions who have been affected by climate change conflict, Acute food insecurity and the COVID-19 pandemic. Drought, flash flood, shortage of clean water and occurrence of other emergencies such as Deseret locust infection (DLI) in the proposed woredas has led to emergence of multiple public health concerns such as outbreak of human disease epidemics(measles, Cholera, scabies), undernutrition and other health problems. The proposed areas of intervention in Oromia hosted significant number of displaced people (22600) while the existing primary health care services are downing because of multiple factors such as tribal conflict, insecurity, shortage of resources, and emergence of the COVID-19 pandemic. This situation has been raising the need for humanitarian response intervention primarily Health, and Nutrition among others. The proposed areas in Amhara region also affected by climate change drought and flash flood which has raised the level of food insecurity and exhausted the resilience of the community. The government of Ethiopia in coordination with UN agencies and INGOs has been providing support. Yet, the support is far less than the need and the strain of local resources and health service provision continue to exist because of the influx of IDPs among other factors such as DLI. CARE has reviewed the woreda prioritization list prepared by the health cluster and confirmed that the proposed woredas are among the top priority woredas for emergency health response. 

CARE proposes Emergency Health, project to respond to the needs of IDPs, and host communities in Wachile of Borena zone and East and West Belesa of Central Gonder zone who have been affected by climate change. Hence, this proposal entails emergency health response for all the woredas in central gonder zone and Wachile of Borena zone Oromia. The proposed woredas of intervention are among the woredas affected by multiple humanitarian crisis such as disease outbreak, high cases of under nutrition and debilitated food security situation.  In addition, the woredas are remote from the zonal capital and hardly reached with primary health care services. Indicative to this, the Penta valent vaccine coverage in East Belesa, West Belesa, and Wachile is 56, 62, and 77% which is much less than the nationally acceptable coverage 98%. Similarly the surveillance activity is weak that immediately reportable diseases are not regularly surveyed and reported upward the structure. This project identified supper specific activities that are proved to be beyond the capacity of local government and provide direct support while strengthening the primary health service delivery system to most health facilities through coaching and mentoring. The action emphasize inaccessible sites and organize outreach program where primary health care service will be provided to remote seated communities through MHNT. CARE will also focus on building local capacity to consistently deliver Health services in line with local priorities and the recommendation from FMOH and National Health Cluster. This response will focus on strengthening the provision primary health care immunization, consultation and treatment of common illnesses and other maternal and child health services such FP, Surveillance and antenatal consultation and referral. 

With this action, CARE plans to reach the following beneficiaries: 
1000 conflict induced IDPs 150 men, 350 women, and 500 boy and girl children seated at different  kebeles of Wachile &#x2013;(Borena zone) will have  access to PHC service including consultation and treatment.
5667 individuals 850 men, 1983 women and 2834 boys and girl children living in remote kebeles of the target woredas will have access to PHC service including consultation and treatment 
10551 persons will get health education and COVID-19 prevention and control message</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Esther Watts</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 116 183 294</telephone>
   <email>ether.watts@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elizabeth Milten</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency program Coordinater</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>251 911 237 582</telephone>
   <email>elizabeth.milten@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amhara</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.04353749 11.56495271</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>38.76512402 7.50805539</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">14586.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">150418.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17541">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">165004.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304833947">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">165004.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
