<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity dstore:dataset="unocha-cbpf-somalia-allocation-2021" dstore:index="21" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:dstore="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/dstore" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/H-Nut/NGO/18209</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of integrated lifesaving health and nutrition services to cisis affected population in Buuhoodle district of Togdheer region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The humanitarian situation is deteriorating due to the devastating impact of flooding, desert locust infestation, the COVID-19 pandemic and ongoing conflict About 5.9 million people are in need of humanitarian assistance, an increase from the 5.2 million reported in 2020. Up to 2.7 million people are expected to be in Crisis (IPC Phase 3) or worse and will face acute food insecurity through mid-2021. An estimated 840,000 children under the age of five are acutely malnourished, 143,000 of them severely and at risk of death. Food security is expected to worsen. The project is in line with Somalia Humanitarian Fund (SHF) Standard Allocation and will provide integrated life-saving emergency primary health care and nutrition needs of flood-affected women, men, boys and girls of proposed project targets in Buuhoodle district. NODO is proposing 12-month integrated Health and Nutrition project targeting the most affected populations in Buuhoodle district reaching a total of 15,250 persons including 11,200 women, 1,500 Men, 1,350 girls and  1200 boys)

Health: The proposed project will support 3 static and 1 mobile IERT centres in Buuhoodle district. NODO plans to deliver an integrated package of promotive, preventive and curative maternal, newborn amp child health services and scale-up outbreak early warning and response and case management of epidemic prone diseases through IERT response team as part of the efforts to support the flood affected communities in Buuhoodle. The project aims to maintain the static and mobile clinics in Buuhoodle IDP and host community&#x2019;s sites and scale up the health care through skilled health professionals. NODO through this project will provide regular medical supplies and life-saving drugs to established health facilities, establish referral mechanisms and improve the coverage of measles vaccinations, support safe motherhood and reproductive health while also ensuring readiness to prevent and respond to outbreaks such as malaria, measles or AWD/Cholera and promote health update through health education and beneficiary sensitization

Nutrition: The proposed nutrition activities will be integrated with the health interventions with the aim of addressing underlying causes of high levels malnutrition as well as to enable early identification of SAM cases for treatment  1 mobile and 3 fixed in targeted IDPs and host community in the most affected areas in Buuhoodle district. This program will establish a strong community network through competent community nutrition volunteers for early detection/case finding and referral of children and pregnant and lactating mothers with acute malnutrition. In addition to the treatment of acute malnutrition, the project will be promoting positive infant and young child feeding (IYCF) practice by providing IYCF promotion and counselling. NODO is strong partner for the nutrition cluster and therefore, will have close coordination with other partners in the district for identification of vulnerable communities and avoiding overlapping of responses. Through this project, a total 15,250 most affected individuals in Buuhoodle will have access to a package of Emergency lifesaving integrated health and nutrition services for twelve months&#x2019; period. The mobile team will provide comprehensive community screening, identification, treatment and referral services from community, IDP areas to the fixed OTP and SC to improve access to the integrated package for the vulnerable community prioritizing rapid referral of the most critical cases (priority will be given to under 5 children and pregnant and lactating women), it shall also capacity building of nutrition staff on IMAM, infant young child feeding best practices, IYCF. Referral of malnourished children with complicated cases will be done to the OTP integrated with PHC services managed by NODO and other actors in the program areas thus providing more holistic opportunity to the target beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nomadic Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nomadic Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haji Omar Abdiqani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252907645170</telephone>
   <email>Nomadicorg1@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9676">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Togdheer</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.40000000 45.43300000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-29">234615.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-29">115384.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18209">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-29">350000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nomadic Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
